<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275490</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Spray Characterization of Ethanol Gasoline Blends and Comparison to a CFD Model for a Gasoline Direct Injector</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Matsumoto</surname>
                  <given-names>Atsushi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Wayne State Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Moore</surname>
                  <given-names>Wayne R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Delphi Powertrain Systems</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lai</surname>
                  <given-names>Ming-Chia</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Wayne State Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zheng</surname>
                  <given-names>Yi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Wayne State Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Foster</surname>
                  <given-names>Matthew</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Delphi Powertrain Systems</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Xie</surname>
                  <given-names>Xing-Bin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ.Wayne State</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yen</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Delphi Powertrain Systems</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Confer</surname>
                  <given-names>Keith</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Delphi Powertrain Systems</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hopkins</surname>
                  <given-names>Eunjoo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Delphi Powertrain Systems</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>402</fpage>
         <lpage>425</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275490"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Operation of flex fuel vehicles requires operation with a range of fuel properties. The significant differences in the heat of vaporization and energy density of E0-E100 fuels and the effect on spray development need to be fully comprehended when developing engine control strategies. Limited enthalpy for fuel vaporization needs to be accounted for when developing injection strategies for cold start, homogeneous and stratified operation.</p>
            <p>Spray imaging of multi-hole gasoline injectors with fuels ranging from E0 to E100 and environmental conditions that represent engine operating points from ambient cold start to hot conditions was performed in a spray chamber. Schlieren visualization technique was used to characterize the sprays and the results were compared with Laser Mie scattering and Back-lighting technique. Open chamber experiments were utilized to provide input and validation of a CFD model. In addition to the fuel variation and operating conditions three different injectors were investigated with differences in static flow rate and internal nozzle geometry. This empirical data was used in the initial development of a robust CFD model for predicting spray behaviors from a multi-hole gasoline direct injector. Comparisons of spray penetration were made between the optimized CFD model and the empirical results. Image processing techniques were presented for characterizing the spray images to quantify the penetration and the vapor cloud development.</p>
            <p>3D-CFD numerical simulation is commonly used in order to make selections of engine injection in the early design period. In this article, the spray behavior was predicted by CONVERGE, The characteristics of the spray tip penetration and mass of the liquid and vapor phases were calculated under different temperature and pressure conditions,</p>
            <p>Testing was also conducted at realistic chamber operating conditions for stratified operation. In these test the piston crown geometry was included in the spray chamber to evaluate fuel impingement effects. Schlieren imaging provided insight into the effect of spray impingement resulting in spray bounce and fuel puddles.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christie, M.J., Fortino, N., and Yilmaz, H., “Parameter Optimization of a Turbo Charged Direct Injection Flex Fuel SI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):123-133, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kapus, P.E., Fuerhapter, A., Fuchs, H., and Fraidl, G.K., “Ethanol Direct Injection on Turbocharged SI Engines - Potential and Challenges,”. SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1408, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marriott, C.D., Wiles, M.A., Gwidt, J.M., and Parrish, S.E., “Development of a Naturally Aspirated Spark Ignition Direct-Injection Flex-Fuel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1): 267-295, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hung, D.L.S., Zhu, G.G., Winkelman, J.R., Stuecken, T. et al., “A High Speed Flow Visualization Study of Fuel Spray Pattern Effect on Mixture Formation in a Low Pressure Direct Injection Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1411, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamamoto, S., Tanaka, D., Sato, K., and Yokoe, M., “Keys to Understanding Spray-guided Combustion of a Narrow-spacing Gasoline Direct Injection SI Engine with a Centrally Mounted Multi-hole Injector,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1408-1419, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gold, M., Li, G., Sapsford, S., and Stokes, J., “Application of Optical Techniques to the Study of Mixture Preparation in Direct Injection Gasoline Engines and Validation of a CFD Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0538, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, F., Lai M.-C., and Harrington D.L., Automotive spark-ignited direct-injection gasoline engines. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 1999. 25: p. 437-562.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersson, M. and Wärnberg J., Application of laserinduced fluorescence for imaging sprays of model fuels emulating gasoline and gasoline/ethanol blends. ICLASS 2009, 11th Triennial International Annual Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taniguchi, S., Yoshida, K., and Tsukasaki, Y., “Feasibility Study of Ethanol Applications to A Direct Injection Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-2037, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wallner, T. and Miers, S.A., “Combustion Behavior of Gasoline and Gasoline/Ethanol Blends in a Modern Direct- Injection 4-Cylinder Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0077, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, F.-Q., Yoo, J.-H., Liu, Y., and Lai, M.-Ch., “Spray Dynamics of High Pressure Fuel Injectors for DI Gasoline Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 961925, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Honda, T., Kawamoto, M., Katashiba, H., Sumida, M. et al., “A Study of Mixture Formation and Combustion for Spray Guided DISI,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0046, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mitroglou, N., Nouri, J.M., Yan, Y., Gavaises, M. et al., “Spray Structure Generated by Multi-Hole Injectors for Gasoline Direct-Injection Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1417, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, J.S., et al., Visualization and Measurement of a Narrow-Cone DI Gasoline Spray for the Impingement Analysis. International Journal of Automotive Technology, 2004. 5: p. 221-238.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M., Kook, S., and Williams, T.C., “Visualization of Diesel Spray Penetration, Cool-Flame, Ignition, High-Temperature Combustion, and Soot Formation Using High-Speed Imaging,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 439-459, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnaud, E., et al., A Fluid Motion Estimator for Schlieren Image Velocimetry. ECCV 2006, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2006. 3951: p. 198-210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pastor, J.V., Garcia, J.M., Pastor, J.M., and Zapata, L.D., “Evaporating Diesel Spray Visualization using a Double-pass Shadowgraphy/Schlieren imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0026, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hori, T., Senda, J., Kuge, T., and Fujimoto, H.G., “Large Eddy Simulation of Non-Evaporative and Evaporative Diesel Spray in Constant Volume Vessel by Use of KIVALES,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3334, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yi, Y. and DeMinco, C.M., “Numerical Investigation of Mixture Preparation in a GDI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3375, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weber, J., Peters, N., Pawlowski, A., Kneer, R. et al., “Diesel Spray Characterization Using a Micro-Genetic Algorithm and Optical Measurements,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1115, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Joh, M., Huh, K.Y., Yoo, J.-H., and Lai, M.-C., “Numerical Prediction and Validation of Fuel Spray Behavior in a Gasoline Direct-Injection Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3668, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Rourke, P.J. and Amsden, A.A., “The TAB Method for Numerical Calculation of Spray Droplet Breakup,” SAE Technical Paper 872089, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ricart, L.M., Reitz R.D., and Deck J., Comparisons of Diesel Spray Liquid Penetration and Vapor Fuel Distribution With In-Cylinder Optical Measurements, Transactions of the ASME, 2000. 122: p. 588-595.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weber, J., Spiekermann, P., and Peters, N., “Model Calibration for Spray Penetration and Mixture Formation in a High Pressure Fuel Spray Using a Micro-Genetic Algorithm and Optical Data,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2099, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, S.H., et al., A study on the fuel injection and atomization characteristics of soybean oil methyl ester (SME). International Journal of Heat and Fluid Flow, 2009. 30: p. 108-116.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R.D., Modeling Atomization Processes in High- Pressure Vaporizing Sprays. Atomization and Spray Technology, 1987. 3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmidt, D.P. and Rutland C.J., A New Droplet Collision Algorithm. Journal of Computational Physics, 2000. 164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Richards, K.J., Senecal P.K., and Pomraning E., CONVERGE™ (Version 1.3). 2008, Middleton, WI: Convergent Science, Inc.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, A.B., Mather, D., and Reitz, R.D., “Modeling the Effects of Drop Drag and Breakup on Fuel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 930072, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z. and Reitz R.D., Turbulence Modeling of Internal Combustion Engines Using RNG k -e Models. Combust. Sci. and Tech, 1995. 106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R.D. and Bracco F.V., Mechanisms of Breakup of Round Liquid Jets. Encyclopedia of Fluid Mechanics. 1986, Houston, TX: Gulf Pub.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xin, J., Ricart L., and Reitz R.D., Computer Modeling of Diesel Spray Atomization and Combustion. Combust. Sci. and Tech., 1998. 137.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serras-Pereira, J., Aleiferis, P.G., Richardson, D., and Wallace, S., “Spray Development in a Direct-Injection Spark- Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-2712, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hattori, H., Narumiya, K., Tsue, M., and Kadota, T., “Analysis of Initial Breakup Mechanism of Diesel Spray Injected into High-Pressure Ambience,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0528, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gold, M., Stokes, J., Morgan, R., Heikal, M. et al., “Air- Fuel Mixing in a Homogeneous Charge DI Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0968, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wada, Y., Nishimura, Y., Yamaguchi, A., Magara, N. et al., “Controlling PCCI Combustion with Mixed Fuel - Application of Flashing Spray to Early Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0624, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Romunde, Z., Aleiferis, P.G., Cracknett, R.F., and Walmsley, H.L., “Effect of Fuel Properties on Spray Development from a Multi-Hole DISI Engine Injector,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4032, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mojtabi, M., et al., The Effect of Flash Boiling on Breakup and Atomisation in GDI Sprays. ILASS08-006, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">National Institute of Standards and Technology 2008; Available from: http://webbook.nist.gov.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H. and Arai, M., “Structures of Fuel Spray in Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 900475, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
