<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">48568603</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>When Are Modifications of Securitized Loans Beneficial to Investors?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gonzalo</surname>
                  <given-names>Maturana</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>


         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>November 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">30</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">11</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e48503769</issue-id>
         <fpage>3824</fpage>
         <lpage>3857</lpage>

         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© The Author 2017</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/48568603"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Loan modification is widely discussed as an alternative to foreclosure, but little research has focused on quantifying its effect on loan performance. I quantify this effect early in the housing crisis by exploiting exogenous variation in the incentives to modify securitized nonagency loans. An additional modification reduces loan losses by 35.8% relative to the average loss; this reduction suggests that the marginal benefit of modification likely exceeded the marginal cost. Consistent with the idea that high-income borrowers may be better equipped to withstand bad economic times, I find that modifications are especially beneficial when borrowers have larger loans.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Adelino, M., K. Gerardi, and P. S. Willen. 2013. Why don’t lenders renegotiate more home mortgages? Redefaults, self-cures and securitization. Journal of Monetary Economics 60:835–53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Agarwal, S., G. Amromin, I. Ben-David, S. Chomsisengphet, and D. D. Evanoff. 2011. The role of securitization in mortgage renegotiation. Journal of Financial Economics 102:559–78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Agarwal, S., G. Amromin, I. Ben-David, S. Chomsisengphet, T. Piskorski, and A. Seru. 2017. Policy intervention in debt renegotiation: Evidence from the home affordable modification program. Journal of Political Economy 125:654–712.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Amromin, G., J. Huang, C. Sialm, and E. Zhong. 2013. Complex mortgages. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Angrist, J. D. and J.-S. Pischke. 2009. Mostly Harmless Econometrics. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Asquith, P., R. Gertner, and D. Scharfstein. 1994. Anatomy of financial distress: An examination of junk-bond issuers. Quarterly Journal of Economics 109:625–58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Ben-David, I. 2011. Financial constraints and inflated home prices during the real estate boom. American Economic Journal: Applied Economics 3:55–87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Beneish, M. D. and E. Press. 1993. Costs of technical violation of accounting-based debt covenants. Accounting Review 68:233–57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Bernanke, Ben S. 2008. Speech at the Federal Reserve System conference on housing and mortgage markets, December 4, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Bound, J., D. A. Jaeger, and R. M. Baker. 1995. Problems with instrumental variables estimation when the correlation between the instruments and the endogenous explanatory variable is weak. Journal of the American Statistical Association 90:443–50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Campbell, J. Y., S. Giglio, and P. Pathak. 2011. Forced sales and house prices. American Economic Review 101:2108–31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Congressional Oversight Panel. 2009. Foreclosure crisis: Working toward a solution. March oversight report. U. S. Congress.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Cordell, L. R., K. Dynan, A. Lehnert, N. Liang, and E. Mauskopf. 2009. Designing loan modifications to address the mortgage crisis and the making home affordable program. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Demiroglu, C. and C. James. 2012. How important is having skin in the game? Originator-sponsor affiliation and losses on mortgage-backed securities. Review of Financial Studies 25:3217–58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Eggert, K. 2007. Comment on MichaelA. Stegman et al. s Preventive servicing is good for business and affordable homeownership policy: What prevents loan modifications? Housing Policy Debate 18:279–97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Fannie Mae. 2008. Announcement 08-20. August 11.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Freddy Mac 2008. Bulletin to all Freddie Mac sellers and servicers. July 31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Gan, Y. H. and C. Mayer. 2007. Agency conflicts, asset substitution, and securitization. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Gilson, S. C., K. John, and L. H. Lang. 1990. Troubled debt restructurings: An empirical study of private reorganization of firms in default. Journal of Financial Economics 27:315–53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Goodman, L. S., S. Li, D. J. Lucas, T. A. Zimmerman, and F. J. Fabozzi. 2008. Subprime mortgage credit derivatives. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Haughwout, A., E. Okah, and J. Tracy. 2009. Second chances: Subprime mortgage modification and re-default. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Hembre, E. 2014. HAMP, home attachment, and mortgage default. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Inside Mortgage Finance 2012. Mortgage market statistical annual.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Kruger, S. 2016. The effect of mortgage securitization on foreclosure and modification. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Levitin, A. J. and T. Twomey. 2011. Mortgage servicing. Yale Journal on Regulation 28:1–90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Madar, J., V. Been, andA. Armstrong. 2009. Transforming foreclosed properties into community assets. Working Paper, New York University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Mayer, C., E. Morrison, and T. Piskorski. 2009. Anew proposal for loan modifications. Yale Journal on Regulation 26:417–29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Mayer, C., E. Morrison, T. Piskorski, andA. Gupta. 2014. Mortgage modification and strategic behavior: Evidence from a legal settlement with countrywide. American Economic Review 104:2830–57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Morgenson, G. 2010. Flawed paperwork aggravates a foreclosure crisis. New York Times, October 3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Mortgage Bankers Association. June 2007. Delinquencies and foreclosures increase in latest MBA National Delinquency Survey.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Piskorski, T., Seru, A., and V. Vig. 2010. Securitization and distressed loan renegotiation: Evidence from the subprime mortgage crisis. Journal of Financial Economics 97:369–97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Posner, E. A. and L. Zingales. 2009. A loan modification approach to the housing crisis. American Law and Economics Review 11:575–607.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Quercia, R. G. and L. Ding. 2009. Loan modifications and redefault risk: An examination of short-term impacts. Cityscape 11:171–93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Scharlemann, T. C. and S. H. Shore. 2016. The effect of negative equity on mortgage default: Evidence from HAMP’s Principal Reduction Alternative. Review of Financial Studies 29:2850–83.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Staiger, D. and J. H. Stock. 1997. Instrumental variables regression with weak instruments. Econometrica 65: 557–86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Thompson, D. E. 2011. Foreclosing modifications: How servicer incentives discourage loan modifications. Washington Law Review 86:755–840.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Mortgage servicers at year-end 2007</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Data summary</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Nonagency loan modifications by servicer type This figure shows the likelihood of modification for each month within six months of the loans becoming 60 + days delinquent. Loans are categorized by the type of servicer holding the servicing rights at the time the loan became delinquent. “Both-market servicers” includes servicers that manage loans both from mortgage-backed securities of government-sponsored enterprises (GSEs) and from nonagency mortgage-backed securities. “Non-agencyonly servicers” includes servicers that mostly manage nonagency loans. The step line shows the total number of mortgages in the United States that are delinquent 60 + days (foreclosure initiations are not included). The vertical line indicates the month during which Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac increased modification incentives in the GSE market. The gray area delimits when the modification rate becomes affected by the incentive fee. U. S.-level figures are calculated from the Mortgage Bankers Association’s National Delinquency Survey.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>First stage: The effect of the incentive fee on modification rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Total GSE loan modifications This figure shows the total number of modifications in the GSE market by quarter as reported by Inside Mortgage Finance. The vertical line indicates the quarter when the incentive fee in the GSE market was implemented.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>GSE loan modifications of both-market servicers This figure shows the modification activity of both-market servicers in the GSE market by month. Data come from Fannie Mae’s and Freddie Mac’s Single-Family Loan Performance Datasets. The both-market servicers identified in the data sets are Bank of America, CitiMortgage, Countrywide, JP Morgan, Metlife, National City, PHH Mortgage, PNC, Suntrust, RFC-GMAC, WAMU, and Wells Fargo. Only loans that became 60 + days delinquent and that were serviced by the previous set of servicers are considered. Panel A shows likelihood of modification for each month within six months of the loans becoming 60 + days delinquent. The step line in panel A shows the total number of modifications within six months of delinquency, and the vertical line indicates the month during which Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac increased modification incentives in the GSE market and the gray area delimits when the modification rate becomes affected by the incentive fee. Panel B shows the total number of modifications performed by the twelve servicers by month. The vertical line indicates the month during which Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac increased modification incentives in the GSE market.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Reduced-form regression</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Second stage: Loan losses on modification</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Instrumental variable regressions using alternative dependent variables</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Reduced-form regressions with interactions</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Instrumental variable regressions by concession size</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
