<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">reviespafinacont</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50009991</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Revista Española de Financiación y Contabilidad</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administarción de Empresas</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">02102412</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">38</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">141</issue>
         <issue-id>i24717601</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24718076</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Características del consejo de administración e información en materia de Responsabilidad Social Corporativa / Characteristics of the board of directors and information in matters of corporate social responsability</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>José Manuel Prado</given-names>
                  <surname>Lorenzo</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Isabel María García</given-names>
                  <surname>Sánchez</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Isabel</given-names>
                  <surname>Gallego-Álvarez</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>107</fpage>
         <lpage>135</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2001 Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administración de Empresas</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24718076"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Determinados comportamientos medioambientales y sociales han incrementado la presión social sobre la actividad económica de las empresas. Para paliar sus efectos, éstas han generado una vía de legitimación: la divulgación de información sobre responsabilidad social corporativa. El presente trabajo tiene como objetivo establecer la relación existente entre ciertas características del Consejo de Administración y la divulgación de información social corporativa. Los resultados obtenidos evidencian un importante efecto positivo de la independencia y la diversidad del Consejo en las prácticas divulgativas, impulsado básicamente por los consejeros independientes; mientras que la diversidad de la organización influye negativamente en distintas fases de las mismas. Por el contrario, no se detecta incidencia alguna de su nivel de actividad y de la reputación de su Presidente. Certain environmental and social behaviours have caused an increase in the social pressure felt by corporations when doing business. To palliate this pressure, companies have generated a means of legitimising their behaviour: the reporting of corporate social responsibility. The objective of this article is to test for the existence of relations between certain characteristics of the board of directors and the reporting of corporate social information. The results obtained show an important effect of the independence and diversity of the board in reporting practices, the independent members being the main promoters of such initiatives. On the contrary, board activity and the reputation of its Chairman have no effect, whereas the diversity of the organization signifies a move backward in different stages of the process.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>spa</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1807e216a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1807e223" publication-type="other">
García
Sánchez y Prado Lorenzo (2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1807e233a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1807e240" publication-type="other">
Adams (2002)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>BIBLIOGRAFÍA</title>
        <ref id="d1807e256a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e260" publication-type="other">
Abdelsalam, 0. H.; Bryant, S. M., y Street, D. L. 2007. An Examination of the Comprehensiveness of Cor-
porate Internet Reporting Provided by London-Listed Companies. International Accounting Research
6 (2): 1-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e273a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e277" publication-type="other">
Adams, C. A. 2002. Internal organisational factors influencing corporate social and ethical reporting.
Accounting, Auditing and Accountability 15 (2): 223-250.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e287a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e291" publication-type="other">
Adams, C. A., y Harte, G. 1998. The changing portrayal of the employment of women in British banks
«and retails companies» corporate annual reports. Accounting, Organizations and Society 23 (8):
781-812.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e304a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e308" publication-type="other">
Adams, C. A., y Kuasirikun, N. 2000. A comparative analysis of corporate reporting on ethical issues by
UK and German chemical and pharmaceutical companies. European Accounting Review 9 (1): 53-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e319a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e323" publication-type="other">
Adams, C. A.; Hill, W. Y., y Roberts, C. B. 1995. Environmental employee and ethical reporting in Euro-
pe, ACCA Research Report 41. Chartered Association of Certified Accountants. London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e333a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e337" publication-type="other">
— 1998. Corporate social reporting practices in Western Europe: Legitimating corporate behaviour?
British Accounting Review 30 (1): 1-21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e347a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e351" publication-type="other">
Andrés, P.; Azofra, V., y López, F. 2005. Corporate Boards in OECD Countries: Size, Composition. Functio-
ning and Effectiveness. Corporate Governance: An International Review 13 (2): 197-210.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e361a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e365" publication-type="other">
Andrews, B. H.; Gul, F. A.; Guthrie; J. E., y Teoh, H. Y. 1989. A note on corporate social disclosure prac-
tices in developing countries: the case of Malaysia and Singapore. British Accounting Review 21 (4):
371-376.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e378a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e382" publication-type="other">
Arcuel, P. 2003. La divulgación de la información social y medioambiental en la gran empresa espa-
ñola en el período 1994-1998: Situación actual y perspectivas. Revista Española de Financiación y
Contabilidad XXXII (117): 571-601.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e395a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e399" publication-type="other">
Archel, P., y Lizarraga, F. 2001. Algunos determinantes de la información medioambiental divulgada
por las empresas españolas cotizadas. Revista de Contabilidad 4 (7): 129-153.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e410a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e414" publication-type="other">
Beasley, M. S. 1996. An empirical analysis of the relation between the board of directors composition
and financial statement fraud. The Accounting Review 71: 443-465.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e424a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e428" publication-type="other">
Belkaoui, A., y Karpik, P. 1989. Determinants of the corporate decision to disclose social information.
Accounting, Auditing and Accountability Journal 2 (1): 36-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e438a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e442" publication-type="other">
Bernardi, R. A.; Bosco, S. M., y Vassil, K. M. 2006. Does female representation on boards of director
associate with Fortune's 100 Best Companies to work for list? Business and Society 45: 235-248.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e452a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e456" publication-type="other">
Betz, M.; O'Connel, L., y Shepard, J. M. 1989. Gender differences in proclivity for unethical behaviour.
Journal of Business Ethics 8: 321-324.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e466a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e470" publication-type="other">
Campbell, D. J. 2000. Legitimacy theory or managerial reality construction? Corporate social disclosu-
res in Marks and Spencer Pic corporate reports, 1969-1997. Accounting Forum 24 (1): 80-100.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e480a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e484" publication-type="other">
Carter, D. A.; Simkins, B. J., y Simpson, W. G. 2003. Corporate Governance, Board Diversity and Firm
Value. The Financial Review 38: 33-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e495a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e499" publication-type="other">
Chen, C., y Jagci, B. 2000. Association between Independent non-executive Directors, Family Control
and Financial Disclosures in Hong Kong. Journal of Accounting and Public Policy 19: 285-310.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e509a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e513" publication-type="other">
Cheng, E., y Courtenay, S. 2006. Board Composition, Regulatory Regime and untary Disclosure. The
International Journal of Accounting 41: 262-289.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e523a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e527" publication-type="other">
Cowen, S.; Ferreri, L, y Parker, L. D. 1987. The impact of corporate characteristics on social responsi-
bility disclosure: A typology and frequency-based analysis. Accounting, Organizations and Society 12
(2): 111-122.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e540a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e544" publication-type="other">
Debreceny, R.; Gray, G. L, y Rahman, A. 2002. The determinants of Internet financial reporting. Journal
of Accounting and Public Policy 21: 371-394.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e554a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e558" publication-type="other">
Deegan, C., y Gordon, B. 1996. A study of the environmental disclosure practices of Australian corpora-
tions. Accounting and Business Research 26 (3): 187-199.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e568a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e572" publication-type="other">
— y Rankin, M. 1996. Do Australian companies report environmental news objectively? An analysis of
environmental disclosures by firms prosecuted successfully by the Environmental Protection Authori-
ty. Accounting, Auditing and Accountability Journal 9 (2): 50-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e586a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e590" publication-type="other">
Freedman, M., y Jagci, B. 1988. An analysis of the association between pollution disclosure and econo-
mic performance. Accounting, Auditing and Accountability Journal 1 (2): 43-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e600a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e604" publication-type="other">
Gales, L. M., y Kesner, I. F. 1994. An analysis of board of directors size and composition in bankrupt
organisations. Journal of Business Research 30: 271-282.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e614a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e618" publication-type="other">
Gallego Álvarez, I.: García Sánchez, I. M., y Rodriguez Domínguez, L. (2008): Voluntary and compulsory
information disclosed online: Effect of industry concentration and other explanatory factors. Online
Information Review 32 (5): 596-622.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e631a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e635" publication-type="other">
García Ayuso, M, y Larrinaga, C. 2003. Environmental disclosure in Spain: Corporate characteristics
and media exposure. Revista Española de Financiación y Contabilidad/Spanish Journal of Finance
and Accounting XXXII (115): 184-214.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e648a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e652" publication-type="other">
García Sánchez, I. M., y Prado Lorenzo, J. M. (2008): Determinant factors in the degree of implementa-
tion of Local Agenda 21 in the European Union. Sustainable Development 16 (1): 17-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e662a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e666" publication-type="other">
Gray, R. H.; Javad, M.; Power, D., y Sinclair, C. D. 2001. Social and environmental disclosures and cor-
porate characteristics: A research note and extension. Journal of Business, Finance &amp; Accounting 28
(3 y 4): 327-356.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e680a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e684" publication-type="other">
Gray, R. H.; Javad, M.; Power, D., y Sinclair, C. D.; Kouhy, R., y Lavers, S. 1995. Methodological themes:
constructing a research database of social and environmental reporting by UK companies. Accoun-
ting, Auditing and Accountability Journal 8 (2): 78-101.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e697a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e701" publication-type="other">
Gray, R. H.; Javad, M.; Power, D.; Sinclair, C. D.; Koijiiy, R.; Lavers, S.; Owen, D. L., y Maunders, K. T. 1987.
Corporate social reporting: Accounting &amp; Accountability. Hemel Hempstead: Prentice-Hall.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e711a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e715" publication-type="other">
Guthrie, J., y Parker, L. D. 1989. Corporate social reporting; a rebuttal of legitimacy theory. Accounting
and Business Research 19 (76): 343-352.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e725a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e729" publication-type="other">
— 1990. Corporate social disclosure practice: a comparative international analysis. Advances in Pu-
blic Interest Accounting 3:159-175.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e739a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e743" publication-type="other">
Hackston, D., y Milne, M. J. 1996. Some determinants of social and environmental disclosures in New
Zealand companies. Accounting, Auditing and Accountability Journal 9 (1): 77-108.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e753a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e757" publication-type="other">
Haniffa, R. M., y Cooke, T. E. 2005. The impact of culture and governance on corporate social reporting.
Journal of Accounting and Public Policy 24: 391-430.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e768a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e772" publication-type="other">
Hang, H.; Cheng, M., y Gray, S. J. 2007. Corporate Governance and Board Composition: Diversity and
Independence of Australian Boards. Corporate Governance 15 (2): 194-207.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e782a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e786" publication-type="other">
Harris, J. 1989. Ethical values and decision processes of male and female business students. Journal
of Education for Business 64: 234-238.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e796a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e800" publication-type="other">
HH.I.Man, A. J.; Zardkoohi, A., y Bierman, L. 1999. Corporate political strategies and firm performance:
indications of firm-specific benefits from personal service in the US government. Strategic Manage-
ment Journal 20: 67-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e813a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e817" publication-type="other">
Husillos Carqués, F. J. 2007. Una aproximación desde la teoría de la legitimidad a la información
medioambiental revelada por las empresas españolas cotizadas. Revista Española de Financiación y
Contabilidad XXXVI (133): 97-122.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e830a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e834" publication-type="other">
Ibrahim, N. A., y Angelidis, J. P. 1991.Effects of board members' gender on level of investment in strate-
gic management and corporate social responsiveness orientation. Proceedings of the Northeast Deci-
sion Sciences Institutes: 208-210.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e847a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e851" publication-type="other">
— 1995. The corporate social responsiveness orientation of board members: Are there differences
between inside and outside directors? Journal of Business Ethics 14 (5): 405-419.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e862a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e866" publication-type="other">
Jensen, M. C. 1986. The agency costs of free cash flow. American Economic Review-Papers and Pro-
ceedings 76: 326-329.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e876a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e880" publication-type="other">
Jensen, M. C., y Mecklinc, W. H. 1976. Theory of the firm: Managerial behaviour, agency cost and ow-
nership structure. Journal of Financial Economics 3: 305-360.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e890a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e894" publication-type="other">
Kanagaretnam, K.; Lobo, G. J., y Whalen, D. J. 2007. Does good corporate governance reduce informa-
tion asymmetry around quarterly earnings announcement. Journal of Accounting and Public Policy
26 (4): 497-522.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e907a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e911" publication-type="other">
Karamanou, I., y Vafeas, N. 2005. The Association between Corporate Boards, Audit Committees, and Ma-
nagement Earnings Forecasts: An Empirical Analysis. Journal of Accounting Research 43 (3): 453-486.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e921a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e925" publication-type="other">
Lane, J. C. 1995. Ethics of business students: some marketing perspectives. Journal of Business Ethics
14: 571-580.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e935a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e939" publication-type="other">
Larrán, M., y García-Meca, E. 2004. La relevancia de la información no-financiera en la estrategia
empresarial de divulgación unitaria: percepciones empresa-analista sobre su utilidad. Revista Valen-
ciana de Economía y Hacienda 12:127-145.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e953a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e957" publication-type="other">
Larrán, M.; García-Meca, E., y Giner, B. 2002. The use of the Internet for corporate reporting by Spanish
companies. The International Journal of Digital Accounting Research 2: 53-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e967a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e971" publication-type="other">
Lim, S.; Matolcsy, Z., y Chow. D. 2007. The Association between Board Composition and Different Types
of untary Disclosure. European Accounting Review 16 (3): 555-583.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e981a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e985" publication-type="other">
Lindblom, C. K. 1994. The implications of organizational legitimacy for corporate social performance
and disclosure, paper presented at the Critical Perspectives on Accounting Conference. New York.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e995a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e999" publication-type="other">
Lipton, M., y Lorsch, J. W. 1992. A modest proposal for improved corporate governance. Business
Lawyer 48 (1): 59-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1009a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1013" publication-type="other">
Mahoney, L. S., y Thorn, L. 2006. An examination of the structure of executive compensation and corpo-
rate social responsibility: A Canadian investigation. Journal of Business Ethics 69:149-162.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1023a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1027" publication-type="other">
Moneva, J. M., y Llena, F. 1996. Análisis de la información sobre responsabilidad social en las em-
presas industriales que cotizan en bolsa. Revista Española de Financiación y Contabilidad XXVI
(87): 361-401.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1041a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1045" publication-type="other">
— 2000. Environmental disclosures in the annual reports of large companies in Spain. The European
Accounting Review 9 (1): 7-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1055a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1059" publication-type="other">
Neu, D.; Warsame, H., y Pedwell, K. 1998. Managing public impressions: Environmental disclosures in
annual reports. Accounting, Organizations and Society 23 (3): 265-282.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1069a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1073" publication-type="other">
Niskala, M, y Pretes, M. 1995. Environmental reporting in Finland: A note on the use of annual reports.
Accounting, Organizations and Society 20 (6): 457-466.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1083a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1087" publication-type="other">
O'Neill, H.; Saunders, C., y Mccarthy, A. 1989. Board members' background characteristics and their
level of corporate social responsiveness: A multivariate investigation. Academy of Management Best
Papers Proceedings-. 32-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1100a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1104" publication-type="other">
Patten, D. 1991. Exposure, legitimacy and social disclosure. Journal of Accounting and Public Policy
10 (4): 297-308.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1114a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1118" publication-type="other">
— 1992. Intra-industry environmental disclosures in response to the Alaskan oil spill: a note on legi-
timacy theory. Accounting, Organizations and Society 17 (5): 471-475.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1129a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1133" publication-type="other">
Pfeffer, J., y Salancik, G. R. 1978. The external control of organizations: A resource dependence pers-
pective. New York. Harper Row.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1143a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1147" publication-type="other">
Prado Lorenzo, J. M.; Gallego Álvarez, I.; García Sánchez, I. M., y Rodriguez Domínguez, L. 2008. Social Res-
ponsibility in Spain: Practices and Motivations in firms. Management Decision 46 (8): 1247-1271.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1157a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1161" publication-type="other">
Roberts, R. W. 1992. Determinants of corporate social responsibility disclosure: an application of stake-
holder theory. Accounting, Organizations and Society 17 (6): 595-612.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1171a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1175" publication-type="other">
Robinson, G., y Dechant, K. 1997. Building A Business Case for Diversity. Academy of Management
Executive 11 (3): 21-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1185a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1189" publication-type="other">
Sonnenfeld, J. 1981. Executive apologies for price fixing: Role biased perceptions of causality. Academy
of Management Journal 24 (1): 192-198.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1199a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1203" publication-type="other">
Suchman, M. C. 1995. Managing legitimacy: Strategic and institutional approaches. Academy of Mana-
gement Review 20 (3): 571-610.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1214a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1218" publication-type="other">
Trotman, K. T„ y Bradley, G. W. 1981. Associations between social responsibility disclosure and charac-
teristics of companies. Accounting, Organizations and Society 6 (4): 355-362.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1228a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1232" publication-type="other">
Tsaukis, J„ y Ortiz-Buonafina, M. 1990. Ethical beliefs: differences of males and females. Journal of
Business Ethics 9: 509-517.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1242a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1246" publication-type="other">
Williams, R. J. 2003. Women on Corporate Boards of Directors and their Influence on Corporate Phi-
lanthropy. Journal of Business Ethics 42 (1): 1-10.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1256a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1260" publication-type="other">
Wilmshurst, T. D., y Frost, G. R. 2000. Corporate environmental reporting. A test of legitimacy theory,
Accounting, Auditing and Accountability Journal 13 (1): 10-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1270a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1274" publication-type="other">
Xie, B.; Davidson, W, y Dadalt, P. 2003. Earning Management and Corporate Governance: the Role of
the Board and the Audit Committee. Journal of Corporate Finance 9: 295-315.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1284a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1288" publication-type="other">
Zahra, S. A., y Stanton, W. W. 1988. The implications of Board of Directors' composition on corporate
strategy and performance. International Journal of Management 5 (2): 229-236.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1807e1299a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1807e1303" publication-type="other">
Zyglidopoulos, S. C. 2003. The issue life-cycle: Implications for reputation for social performance and
organizational legitimacy. Corporate Reputation Review 6: 70-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


