<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277780</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effect of Valve Timing and Residual Gas Dilution on Flame Development Characteristics in a Spark Ignition Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Xu</surname>
                  <given-names>Kang</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tianjin Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Xie</surname>
                  <given-names>Hui</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tianjin Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wan</surname>
                  <given-names>Minggang</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tianjin Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chen</surname>
                  <given-names>Tao</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tianjin Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhao</surname>
                  <given-names>Hua</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Brunel Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>May 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277742</issue-id>
         <fpage>488</fpage>
         <lpage>499</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277780"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The goal of this research was to study and quantify the effect of exhaust valve timing and residual gas dilution on in-cylinder flow patterns, flame propagation and heat release characteristics in a spark ignition engine. Experiments were carried out in a recently developed single cylinder optical engine. Particle image velocimetry (PIV) was applied to measuring and evaluating the in-cylinder flow field. Detailed analysis of flame images combined with heat release data was presented for several engine operating conditions, giving insight into the combustion process in terms of visible flame area and flame expansion speed. Results from PIV measurement indicates that the limited alteration of the in-cylinder bulk flow could be observed with the variation of exhaust valve timing. The in-cylinder fluctuating kinetic energies and their Coefficient of Variations (COVs) decrease with the advance of the exhaust valve timing. Analysis based on the chemiluminescence imaging and the in-cylinder pressure shows that faster flame kernel formation and less distortion of flame shape in the early flame development stage could be obtained by the initial advance of exhaust valve timing, which benefits the combustion event by advancing the combustion timing and shortening the ignition delay and combustion duration without much increase in Coefficient of Variation of Indicated Mean Effective Pressure (<italic>COV<sub>IMEP</sub>
               </italic>). By further advancing the exhaust valve timing to 32 CA Before Top Dead Center (BTDC), the combustion severely deteriorates with retarded combustion timing and higher cyclic variations, caused by the higher dilution level and lower fluctuation kinetic energy.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontana, G. and Galloni, E. “Experimental analysis of a sparkignition engine using exhaust gas recycle at WOT operation”. Applied Energy, 87 (2010): 2187-2193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei, H., Zhu, T., Shu, G., Tan, L. et al. “Gasoline engine exhaust gas recirculation - A review”. Applied Energy, 99 (2012): 534-544.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sasaki, S., Sawada, D., Ueda, T. and Sami, H. “Effects of EGR on direct injection gasoline combustion”. JSAE Review, 19 (1997): 223-228.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tomazic, D. and Pfeifer, A., “Cooled EGR - A Must or an Option for 2002/04,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0962, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0962.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diana, S., Giglio, V., Iorio, B., and Police, G., “A Strategy to Improve the Efficiency of Stoichiometric Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 961953, 1996, doi:10.4271/961953.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galloni, E., Fontana, G. and Palmaccio, R. “Numerical analysis of EGR techniques in a turbocharged spark- ignition engine”. Applied Thermal Engineering, 39 (2012): 95-104.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ibrahim, A. and Bari, B. “An experimental investigation on the use of EGR in a supercharged natural gas SI engine”. Fuel, 89 (2010): 1721-1730.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontana, G. and Galloni, E. “Experimental analysis of a sparkignition engine using exhaust gas recycle at WOT operation”. Applied Energy, 87 (2010): 2187-2193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontana, G. and Galloni, E. “Variable valve timing for fuel economy improvement in a small spark-ignition engine”. Appl Energy, 86 (2009): 96-105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bai, Y., Wang, Z. and Wang, J. “Part-load characteristics of direct injection spark ignition engine using exhaust gas trap”. Applied Energy, 87 (2010): 2640-2646.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xie, H., Li, L., Chen, T., Yu, W., et al. “Study on spark assisted compression ignition (SACI) combustion with positive valve overlap at medium-high load”. Applied Energy, 101 (2013): 622-633.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, H.F., Seo, K. and Zhao, H. “Combustion and emission analysis of the direct DME injection enabled and controlled autoignition gasoline combustion engine operation”. Fuel, 107 (2013): 800-814.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urushihara, T., Hiraya, K., Kakuhou, A., and Itoh, T., “Expansion of HCCI Operating Region by the Combination of Direct Fuel Injection, Negative Valve Overlap and Internal Fuel Reformation,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0749, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01- 0749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koopmans, L., Ogink, R., and Denbratt, I., “Direct Gasoline Injection in the Negative Valve Overlap of a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01- 1854, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1854.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duffour, F., Vangraefschèpe, F., Knop, V., and de Francqueville, L., “Influence of the Valve-lift Strategy in a CAI™ Engine using Exhaust Gas Re-Breathing - Part 1: Experimental Results and 0D Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0299, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0299.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knop, V., de Francqueville, L., Duffour, F., and Vangraefschèpe, F., “Influence of the Valve-lift Strategy in a CAI™ Engine using Exhaust Gas Re-Breathing - Part 2: Optical Diagnostics and 3D CFD Results,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):271-288, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0495.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Persson, H., Hultqvist, A., Johansson, B., and Remón, A., “Investigation of the Early Flame Development in Spark Assisted HCCI Combustion Using High Speed Chemiluminescence Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0212, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, K.-H., and Kim, K. “Influence of initial combustion in SI engine on following combustion stage and cycle-by-cycle variations in combustion process”. International Journal of Automotive Technology, 2(2001): 25-31</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galloni, E. “Analyses about parameters that affect cyclic variation in a spark ignition engine”. Applied Thermal Engineering, 29 (2009): 1131-1137.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adomeit, P., Lang, O., Pischinger, S., Aymanns, R. et al., “Analysis of Cyclic Fluctuations of Charge Motion and Mixture Formation in a DISI Engine in Stratified Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2007- 01-1412, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goryntsev, D., Sadiki, A., Klein, M., and Janicka, J. “Large eddy simulation based analysis of the effects of cycle-to-cycle variations on air-fuel mixing in realistic DISI IC-engines”. Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 32 (2009): 2759-2766.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, F., Taketomi, M., Nishida, K., and Hiroyasu, H., “PLIF Measurements of the Cyclic Variation of Mixture Concentration in a SI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 940988, 1994, doi:10.4271/940988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Enotiadis A. C., Vafidis C. and Whitelaw J. H.. “Interpretation of cyclic flow variations in motored internal combustion engines”. Experiments in Fluids, 10 (1990):77-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cosadia, I, Boree, J, Charnay, G and Dumont P. “Cyclic variations of the swirling flow in a diesel transparent engine”, Experimental in Fluids 41 (2006):115-134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang T.Y., Peng Z.J. and Wang G.D., “In-cylinder air motion characteristics with variable valve lift in a spark ignition engine. Part 1: swirl flow”, Journal of Automobile Engineering, 225 (2011):479-497.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu Daming, Wang Tianyou, Jia Ming, and Wang Gangde. “Cycleto- cycle variation analysis of in-cylinder flow in a gasoline engine with variable valve lift”, Experiments in Fluids, 53 (2012):585-602.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pera, C., Chevillard, S. and Reveillon, J. “Effects of residual burnt gas heterogeneity on early flame propagation and on cyclic variability in spark-ignited engines”. Combustion and Flame, 160 (2013):1020-1032.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, Y, Zhao, H, Ladommatos N. “Analysis of large-scale flow characteristics in a four-valve spark ignition engine”. Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part C: Journal of Mechanical Engineering Science, 216 (2002):923-938.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Le Coz, J., Henriot, S., and Pinchon, P., “An Experimental and Computational Analysis of the Flow Field in a Four- Valve Spark Ignition Engine-Focus on Cycle-Resolved Turbulence,” SAE Technical Paper 900056, 1990, doi:10.4271/900056.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fansler, T. and French, D., “Cycle-Resolved Laser- Velocimetry Measurements in a Reentrant-Bowl-in-Piston Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 880377, 1988, doi:10.4271/880377.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, Y., Liu, S., Shi, S.-X. and Feng, M. “An investigation of incylinder tumbling motion in a four-valve spark ignition engine”. Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D. Journal of Automobile Engineering, 215 (2001): 273- 284.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marc, D., Boree, J., Bazile, R., and Charnay, G., “Tumbling Vortex Flow in a Model Square Piston Compression Machine: PIV and LDV Measurements,” SAE Technical Paper 972834, 1997, doi:10.4271/972834.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li Y., Zhao H., Leach, B. and Ma, T. “Characterization of an incylinder flow structure in a high-tumble SI engine”. International Journal of Engine Research, 5 (2004):375-400.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aleiferis, P. G., Hardalupas, Y. and Taylor, A.M.K.P. “Flame chemiluminescence studies of cyclic combustion variations and airto- fuel ratio of the reacting mixture in a lean-burn stratified-charge spark-ignition engine”. Combust. Flame, 136 (2004): 72-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gillespie L., Ph.D. thesis, University of Leeds, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B. 1988. Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals. McGraw-Hill Book Co., New York, Chap. 9. pp. 406-409.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H., Peng, Z., Williams, J., and Ladommatos, N., “Understanding the Effects of Recycled Burnt Gases on the Controlled Autoignition (CAI) Combustion in Four-Stroke Gasoline Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3607, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3607.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
