<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26789712</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Assessing a Hybrid Supercharged Engine for Diluted Combustion Using a Dynamic Drive Cycle Simulation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nazari</surname>
                  <given-names>Shima</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Middleton</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sugimori</surname>
                  <given-names>Kanji</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Siegel</surname>
                  <given-names>Jason</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Stefanopoulou</surname>
                  <given-names>Anna</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">WCX18 Best Papers Special Issue</issue-title>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26789698</issue-id>
         <fpage>351</fpage>
         <lpage>368</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26789712"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This study uses full drive cycle simulation to compare the fuel consumption of a vehicle with a turbocharged (TC) engine to the same vehicle with an alternative boosting technology, namely, a hybrid supercharger, in which a planetary gear mechanism governs the power split to the supercharger between the crankshaft and a 48 V 5 kW electric motor. Conventional mechanically driven superchargers or electric superchargers have been proposed to improve the dynamic response of boosted engines, but their projected fuel efficiency benefit depends heavily on the engine transient response and driver/cycle aggressiveness. The fuel consumption benefits depend on the closed-loop engine responsiveness, the control tuning, and the torque reserve needed for each technology. To perform drive cycle analyses, a control strategy is designed that minimizes the boost reserve and employs high rates of combustion dilution via exhaust gas recirculation (EGR). The fully dynamic drive cycle results are compared to steady state (SS) GT-Power projections, using residence time spent in various SS operating points. The fuel consumption benefits enabled by the hybrid supercharger are simulated for the three standard drive cycles, FTP75, HWFET, and US06, and various drivers’ aggressiveness, showing a maximum of 5% improvement.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">National Highway Traffic Safety Administration U.S. Department of Transportation, “Midterm Evaluation of Light-Duty Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Emission Standards and Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards for Model Years 2022-2025,” 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">National Research Council and others, Cost, Effectiveness, and Deployment of Fuel Economy Technologies for Light-Duty Vehicles (National Academies Press, 2015).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Potteau, S., Lutz, P., Leroux, S., Moroz, S. et al., “Cooled EGR for a Turbo SI Engine to Reduce Knocking and Fuel Consumption,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-3978, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-3978.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Siokos, K., Koli, R., Prucka, R., Schwanke, J. et al., “Assessment of Cooled Low Pressure EGR in a Turbocharged Direct Injection Gasoline Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(4):1535-1543, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1253.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Alger, T., Gingrich, J., Roberts, C., and Mangold, B., “Cooled Exhaust-Gas Recirculation for Fuel Economy and Emissions Improvement in Gasoline Engines,” International Journal of Engine Research 12(3):252-264, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Kaiser, M., Krueger, U., Harris, R., and Cruff, L., “‘Doing More with Less’-The Fuel Economy Benefits of Cooled EGR on a Direct Injected Spark Ignited Boosted Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0589, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0589.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Nazari, S., Martz, J., and Stefanopoulou, A., “Minimum Backpressure Wastegate Control for a Boosted Gasoline Engine with Low Pressure External EGR,” in Dynamic Systems and Control Conference, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Nazari, S., Middleton, R., Martz, J., and Stefanopoulou, A., “The Elusive Consequence of Slow Engine Response on Drive Cycle Fuel Efficiency,” in American Control Conference, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">McBroom, S., Smithson, R.A., Urista, R., and Chadwell, C., “Effects of Variable Speed Supercharging Using a Continuously Variable Planetary on Fuel Economy and Low Speed Torque,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(4):1717-1728, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1737.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">King, J., Heaney, M., Saward, J., Fraser, A. et al., “HyBoost: An Intelligently Electrified Optimised Downsized Gasoline Engine Concept,” in Proceedings of the FISITA 2012 World Automotive Congress, 2013, Springer, 483-496.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Pallotti, P., Torella, E., New, J., Criddle, M. et al., “Application of an Electric Boosting System to a Small, Four- Cylinder S.I. Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-32-0039, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-32-0039.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Nazari, S., Kiwan, R., Tsourapas, V., and Stefanopoulou, A., “A Coordinated Boost Control in a Twincharged Spark Ignition Engine with High External Dilution,” in Dynamic Systems and Control Conference, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Middleton, R.J., Gupta, O.G.H., Chang, H.-Y., Lavoie, G. et al., “Fuel Efficiency Estimates for Future Light Duty Vehicles, Part B: Powertrain Technology and Drive Cycle Fuel Economy,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0905, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0905.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Eriksson, L., Frei, S., Onder, C., and Guzzella, L., “Control and Optimization of Turbocharged Spark Ignited Engines,” IFAC Proceedings Volumes 35(1):283-288, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Gorzelic, P., Hellström, E., Stefanopoulou, A., Jiang, L. et al., “A Coordinated Approach for Throttle and Wastegate Control in Turbocharged Spark Ignition Engines,” in Control and Decision Conference (CCDC), 2012 24th Chinese, 2012, IEEE, 1524-1529.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Middleton, R.J., “Voronoi Partitions for Assessing Fuel Consumption of Advanced Technology Engines: An Approximation of Full Vehicle Simulation on a Drive Cycle,” SAE Technical Paper 2018-01-0317, 2018, doi:10.4271/2018-01-0317.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">“TVS V400 Specifications,” https://www.eaton.com/us/en-us/catalog/engine-solutions/tvs-v400.specifications.html, accessed: 01-16-2019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">“1.6 L Ecoboost Engine Geometry,” http://dsportmag.com/the-tech/ford-ecoboost-1-6l-analysis-turbocharged-directinjection- ccvtc/, accessed 2017-10-27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Nazari, S., Siegel, J., and Stefanopoulou, A., “Optimal Energy Management for a Mild Hybrid Vehicle with Electric and Hybrid Engine Boosting Systems,” IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology, 2019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">GT-Suite Manual, G.-P. U. “GT-Suite version 7.5,” 2016, Gamma Technologies Inc., https://www.gtisoft.com.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Middleton, R.J., Gupta, O.G.H., Chang, H.-Y., Lavoie, G. et al., “Fuel Efficiency Estimates for Future Light Duty Vehicles, Part A: Engine Technology and Efficiency,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0906, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0906.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Bonatesta, F., Waters, B., and Shayler, P., “Burn Angles and form Factors for Wiebe Function Fits to Mass Fraction Burned Curves of a Spark Ignition Engine with Variable Valve Timing,” International Journal of Engine Research 11(2):177-186, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Hoepke, B., Jannsen, S., Kasseris, E., and Cheng, W.K., “EGR Effects on Boosted SI Engine Operation and Knock Integral Correlation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):547-559, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0707.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Eriksson, L. and Nielsen, L., Modeling and Control of Engines and Drivelines (John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Nazari, S., Siegel, J., and Stefanopoulou, A., “Control of Hybrid Boosting in Highly Diluted Internal Combustion Engines,” IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, 2019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Guzzella, L. and Onder, C., Introduction to Modeling and Control of Internal Combustion Engine Systems (Springer Science &amp; Business Media, 2009).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Stuhldreher, M., Schenk, C., Brakora, J., Hawkins, D. et al., “Downsized Boosted Engine Benchmarking and Results,” SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1266, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Nuesch, S.P., Analysis and Control of Multimode Combustion Switching Sequence (2015), 35-51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Åström, K.J. and Wittenmark, B., Computer-Controlled Systems: Theory and Design (Prentice-Hall, 1997).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Wiese, A.P., Stefanopoulou, A.G., Karnik, A.Y., and Buckland, J.H., “Model Predictive Control for Low Pressure Exhaust Gas Recirculation with scavenging,” in American Control Conference (ACC) 2017, 2017, IEEE, 3638-3643.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Bai, S., Maguire, J., and Peng, H., Dynamic Analysis and Control System Design of Automatic Transmissions. Vol. 21 (Warrendale: SAE International, 2013).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Geometry of the studied engine [18].</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Schematic view of the engine platforms studied, (a) baseline TC engine, (b) hybrid supercharged engine.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Schematic view of the hybrid supercharging system with different nodes speed, ω, and torque, τ.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>The GT-Power predicted BSFC versus experimental values: (a) BSFC for the baseline TC engine without cEGR for 1500 rpm and 2000 rpm engine speeds and a range of loads, along with the model error, (b) the percentage reduction in BSFC for different concentrations of cEGR at two operating points, 9 bar BMEP 1500 rpm and 11 bar BMEP 2000 rpm.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>The GT-Power predicted CA50 for different spark timing and cEGR concentrations versus the experimental values for 5 bar BMEP 1500 rpm.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Mean value engine model steady state comparison to experimental data. (a) BMEP, (b) intake manifold pressure.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Mean value engine model transient performance compared to experiments. (a) BMEP, (b) intake manifold pressure.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Steady state fuel consumption plots. (a) baseline turbocharged engine BSFC, (b) hybrid supercharged engine BSFC, (c) the relative engine BSFC improvement with hybrid supercharging, (d) the relative engine BSFC improvement with hybrid supercharging and 20% cEGR.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>EGR effect on fuel consumption of hybrid supercharged engine. (a) EGR benefits for HS engine, (b) supercharger consumed power at different operating points.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Top level block diagram of the vehicle longitudinal model.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Block diagram of powertrain controllers. (a) Turbocharged engine controllers, (b) hybrid supercharged engine controllers.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Hybrid supercharged engine transient response comparison to baseline TC engine at 2000 rpm engine speed.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Hybrid supercharger speed, torque, and power during the transient maneuver in Figure 11.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Engine operating points and their residence time for the US06, HWFET, and FTP75 drive cycles fuel consumption estimation based on visitation method.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Predicted fuel economy numbers for hybrid supercharged and baseline TC engine using steady state projections, relative FC improvement of HS engine compared to TC engine (in parenthesis).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Full dynamic drive cycle simulation results summary, relative FC improvement of HS engine compared to TC engine (in parenthesis).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Comparing the predicted steady state (SS) fuel consumption benefit of hybrid supercharging (HS) and cEGR to the transient drive cycle simulation results (Trans).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Drive cycle speed profile and supercharger usage during each drive cycle, (a) the US06 drive cycle, (b) the HWFET drive cycle, and (c) the FTP75 drive cycle.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Engine visitation points density based on the consumed fuel, (a) TC engine visited points for the US06 drive cycle, (b) TC engine visited points for the FTP75 drive cycle, (c) hybrid supercharged engine visited points for the US06 drive cycle, and (d) hybrid supercharged engine visited points for the FTP75 drive cycle.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Hybrid supercharging fuel consumption benefit sensitivity to driver aggressiveness, driver gains multiplied by α<sub>d</sub> = 1, 1.5, 3.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Hybrid supercharger energy use during different drive cycles.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Hybrid supercharger performance during drive cycles, (a) a segment of the US06, (b) a segment of the HWFET.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Vehicle and drivetrain model block diagram.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Vehicle parameters for MY2015 Ford Escape.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE A.2</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>Gear shift, u<sub>g</sub>, and clutch position, u<sub>c</sub>, for the vehicle with HS engine during the US06 drive cycle.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE A.3</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Driver model, (a) driver gain selection logic, (b) driver gains.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
