<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">jeducfina</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000843</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Journal of Education Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>University of Illinois Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00989495</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19446470</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">40</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i24459395</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24459431</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Guaranteed Tuition Policies and State General Appropriations for Higher Education: A Difference-in-Difference Analysis</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Jennifer A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Delaney</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Tyler D.</given-names>
                  <surname>Kearney</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>359</fpage>
         <lpage>390</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015 Board of Directors of the Journal of Education Finance, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24459431"/>
      
      
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d2576393e202a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2576393e209" publication-type="other">
Because each institution is able to manage its own guaranteed tuition program, there is some vari-
ance in program details by campus. Illinois State University voluntarily includes fees in their guarantee
(However, we argue that ISUs fee guarantee is very weak since the "University reserves the right to
impose new or special fee assessments as it deems necessary" http://studentaccounts.illinoisstate.edu/
downloads/TruthinTuitionProcedures3-28-12.pdf). Western Illinois University includes tuition, fees, and
room and board in its guarantee making it the most extensive program in the state. Every institution
voluntarily extends a guarantee to nonresident students except for Northern Illinois University and
Governors State University. Chicago State University extends its guarantee to six years or 120 hours.
Northern Illinois University offers its guaranteed for nine semesters (and does not count summer en-
rollment towards this total). Governors State University offers its guarantee for 11 terms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2576393e244a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2576393e251" publication-type="other">
This time period coincides with a significant recessionary period in the U.S. business cycle. How-
ever, prior work shows no significant decreases in state general appropriations for higher education
during the period due to the "maintenance of effort provision" and the federal stimulus funds provided
through the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act (ARRA) of 2009 (Delaney 2014). Because of
ARRA, the behavior of states and institutions is not expected to shift substantially with changes in the
business cycle throughout the period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2576393e274a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2576393e281" publication-type="other">
There does appear to be one state (MN) on an unusual trend in Figure 3, but Illinois (the solid line)
appears to be very similar to the general trend for all other states during these years.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2576393e291a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2576393e298" publication-type="other">
The Delta Cost Project has developed a longitudinal version of IPEDS. However, Delta Cost Project
data are not used in this work due to the treatment of parent/child campuses in the datasets. In the Delta
Cost Project datasets, multi-campus systems are presented as one institution. This is problematic for our
study since we are interested in state appropriations for each campus. For example, the University of
Illinois—a three campus system in the treatment group of the study—is reported as a single institution
in the Delta Cost Project dataset. Hence, we selected IPEDS datasets for use in this study. One challenge
in using the IPEDS data as a cross-sectional time series is that not all of the variables used in this analysis
were collected for all of the years in our dataset (from 2000-2012). In two cases (with state appropria-
tions and gross Pell grants) one single variable was unable to be used and two nearly identical measures
were combined in order to create a continuous measure for every year of the dataset. The definition of
the variables did not fundamentally change and in both cases one variable was available for the years
2000-2001 and a second variable was available for the years 2002-2012. A detailed listing of the com-
bined variable names and descriptions is available in Table 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2576393e344a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2576393e351" publication-type="other">
Institutional tuition levels are not included as an institutional control in the model, because tuition
and state general appropriations are likely to be endogenous.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2576393e361a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2576393e368" publication-type="other">
This study uses the following IPEDS variables for these restrictions: iclevel, coded as 1 (four or
more years); control, coded as 1 (Public); sector, coded as 1 (Public, 4-year or above); cyactive, coded as
1 (Yes); deggrant, coded as 1 (Degree-granting); ugoffer, coded as 1 (undergraduate degree or certificate
offering); obereg, to drop institutions coded as 0 (U.S. Service schools); and opeflag, to restrict the data-
set to exclude non-Title IV eligible institutions (coded as 5, 6, or 7).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2576393e387a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2576393e394" publication-type="other">
This study uses the 2000 Carnegie classification system (not the 2010 revised system), because it
offers a more straightforward classification scheme and was in place for the majority of the years of the
dataset.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2576393e407a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2576393e414" publication-type="other">
These institutions are: Clarion University of Pennsylvania-Venango Campus, CUNY Graduate
School and University Center, Lincoln University of Pennsylvania, Pennsylvania State University-Penn
St Harrisburg, Pennsylvania State University-Main Campus, Rutgers University-Camden, Rutgers
University-New Brunswick, Rutgers University-Newark, SUNY Institute of Technology at Utica-Rome,
Temple University, Texas A &amp; M University-Texarkana, University of Baltimore, University of Califor-
nia-San Francisco, University Of Delaware, University of Houston-Clear Lake, University of Houston-
Victoria, University of Maryland-Baltimore, and University of Pittsburgh-Main Campus.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2576393e440a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2576393e447" publication-type="other">
In addition, one-year of observations for four institutions was dropped from the dataset due to
likely data errors. Observations that showed an unusually high out-of-state enrollment percent were
dropped. In none of the other years of observations did any of these institutions have an out-of-state
enrollment value greater than 27% or 1400 students. Hence observations that reported greater than
85% or more than 3000 in a single year out-of-state students were dropped. These included East Central
University in 2000, Grand Valley State University in 2001, University of South Florida in 2003, and the
University of Washington-Seattle Campus in 2000.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2576393e473a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2576393e480" publication-type="other">
A list of institutions included in the analysis is available from the authors by request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2576393e488a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2576393e495" publication-type="other">
In order to identify this subset of states, we use the Education Commission of the States (ECS)
Postsecondary Governance Structures Database, which is based on McGuinness (1997). Our data come
from Tandberg (personal communication, October 21, 2013). Because governance structure changes
are rare within the states, we chose a single year, 2004 (the year before the Illinois guaranteed tuition
law went into effect), to identify the states with Coordinating/Planning Governing Boards. More in-
formation on this measure and the categories used can be found in Table 1. States that are included in
this category of Coordinating/Planning Board governance structure are: Alabama, Arkansas, Colorado,
Connecticut, Idaho, Illinois, Kansas, Kentucky, Louisiana, Massachusetts, Minnesota, North Dakota,
New Hampshire, Nevada, New York, Ohio, Rhode Island, South Dakota, Tennessee, and Washington.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2576393e527a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2576393e534" publication-type="other">
Based on the 2000 Carnegie classification system Illinois institutions are categorized as follows:
Masters Colleges and Universities I = Chicago State University, Eastern Illinois University, Western Il-
linois University, Governors State University, Northeastern Illinois University, University of Illinois at
Springfield, Southern Illinois University - Edwardsville; Doctoral/Research Universities—Extensive =
University of Illinois at Chicago, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Northern Illinois Uni-
versity, Southern Illinois University - Carbondale; Doctoral/Research Universities—Intensive = Illinois
State University. No Illinois institutions change categories in the dataset during the time period of the
analysis and these are the only three types of public four-year institutions operating in Illinois during
the time period of this study.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2576393e566a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2576393e573" publication-type="other">
This robustness check excludes institutions from the dataset that independently instituted any
type of price guarantee (in-state, out-of-state tuition, or fees) in any year. These nine excluded public
institutions are: Missouri Southern State University, Norfolk State University, Northern Arizona Univer-
sity, Tarleton State University, University of Colorado at Boulder, University of Kansas, The University
of Texas at Dallas, and The University of Texas at El Paso. The IPEDS variables used to implement this
restriction are chgltgtd, chg2tgtd, chg3tgtd, chglfgtd, chg2fgtd, and chg3fgtd. Because the guaranteed
tuition program in Oklahoma was instituted by a state law, all Oklahoma institutions remain in the
dataset.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d2576393e611a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e615" publication-type="other">
Angrist, J. D„ &amp; Krueger, A. B. 1999. Empirical strategies in labor economics. In O. Ashenfelter
&amp; D. Card (Eds.), Handbook of labor economics, Volume 3 (pp. 1277-1366). Amsterdam The
Netherlands: Elsevier Science.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e628a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e632" publication-type="other">
Angrist, J. D., &amp; Pischke, J. S. 2009. Mostly harmless econometrics: An empiricist's companion.
Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e642a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e646" publication-type="other">
American Recovery and Reinvestment Act (ARRA) of 2009 (public law 111-5). Available from
http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/BILLS-l llhrlenr/pdf/BILLS-1 llhrlenr.pdf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e656a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e660" publication-type="other">
Betts, Julian R„ and Laurel L. McFarland. 1995. Safe port in a storm: The impact of labor market
conditions on community college enrollments. The Journal of Human Resources. 30 (4): 741-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e671a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e675" publication-type="other">
Cellini, Stephanie. 2008. Causal inference and omitted variable bias in financial aid research: As-
sessing solutions. Review of Higher Education. 31 (3): 329-354.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e685a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e689" publication-type="other">
Clotfelter, Charles T. 1976. Public spending for higher education: An empirical test of two hypoth-
eses. Public Finance = Finances Publiques. 31 (2): 177-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e699a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e703" publication-type="other">
College Board. 2011. Trends in college pricing: 2011. Available from: http://trends.collegeboard.org/
downloads/College_Pricing_2011.pdf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e713a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e717" publication-type="other">
Delaney, Jennifer A. 2014. The role of state policy in promoting college affordability. The annals of
the American Academy of Political and Social Science. 655, 56-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e727a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e731" publication-type="other">
Delaney, Jennifer A. &amp; Doyle, William R. 2007. The role of higher education in state budgets. In D.
E. Heller, &amp; K. M. Shaw (Eds.), State postsecondary education research: New methods to inform
policy and practice (p. 55-76). Sterling, Virginia: Stylus Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e744a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e748" publication-type="other">
Delaney, Jennifer A. &amp; Doyle, William R. 2011. State spending on higher education: Testing the
balance wheel over time. Journal of Education Finance, 36(4), 343-368.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e759a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e763" publication-type="other">
Delaney, Jennifer A. &amp; Kearney, Tyler D. 2014a. "The impact of guaranteed tuition policies on
postsecondary tuition levels: A difference-in-difference approach" paper presented at the As-
sociation for Institutional Research Annual Forum. Orlando, FL.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e776a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e780" publication-type="other">
Delaney, Jennifer A. &amp; Kearney, Tyler D. 2014b. "Alternative student-based revenue streams for
higher education institutions: A difference-in-difference analysis using guaranteed tuition poli-
cies" Paper presented at the Association for the Study of Higher Education Annual Conference.
Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e796a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e800" publication-type="other">
Doyle, William R. 2012. The politics of public college tuition and state financial aid. The Journal of
Higher Education. 83 (5): 617-647.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e810a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e814" publication-type="other">
Fethke, G. 2005. Strategic determination of higher education subsidies and tuitions. Economics of
Education Review. 24: 601-609.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e824a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e828" publication-type="other">
Friedberg, Leora. 1998. Did unilateral divorce raise divorce rates? Evidence from panel data.
American Economic Review. 88 (3): 608-627.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e838a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e842" publication-type="other">
Hauptman, Arthur M. 1990. The tuition dilemma: Assessing new ways to pay for college. Washing-
ton, DC: The Brookings Institution.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e853a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e857" publication-type="other">
Heller, Donald E. 1997. Student price response in higher education: An update to Leslie and
Brinkman. Journal of Higher Education, 68(6): 624-659.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e867a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e871" publication-type="other">
Heller, Donald E. 2001. The state and public higher education policy: Affordability, access, and ac-
countability. Baltimore, MD: The Johns Hopkins University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e881a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e885" publication-type="other">
Hossler, Donald, Lund, J. P., Ramin, J., Westfall, S., &amp; Irish, S. 1997. State funding for higher educa-
tion: The Sisyphean Task. Journal of Higher Education, 68 (2), 160-190.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e895a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e899" publication-type="other">
Hovey, Harold. A. 1999. State spending for higher education in the next decade: The battle to sustain
current support. San Jose, CA: California State Policy Research, Inc.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e909a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e913" publication-type="other">
Humphreys, Brad R. 2000. Do business cycles affect state appropriations to higher education?
Southern Economic Journal. 67 (2): 398-413.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e923a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e927" publication-type="other">
Illinois Public Act 093-0228. 2003. Available from http://www.ilga.gov/legislation/publicacts/full-
text.asp?Name=093-0228.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e938a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e942" publication-type="other">
Institute for Higher Education Policy. 1999. The tuition puzzle: Putting the pieces together. Wash-
ington, DC.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e952a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e956" publication-type="other">
Integrated Postsecondary Education Data System [IPEDS] n.d. IPEDS Data Center [Data file].
Available from http://nces.ed.gov/ipeds/datacenter/.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e966a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e970" publication-type="other">
Jacobson, Louis. S., Robert J. LaLonde, 8c Daniel G. Sullivan. 1993. Earnings losses of displaced
workers. American Economic Review. 83 (4): 685-709.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e980a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e984" publication-type="other">
Kane, Thomas J. 1999. The price of admission: Rethinking how Americans pay for college. Washing-
ton, D.C.: Brookings Institution Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e994a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e998" publication-type="other">
Kane, Thomas. J., Peter Orszag, 8c David L. Gunter. 2003. State fiscal constraints and higher educa-
tion spending: The role of Medicaid and the business cycle. Washington, DC: Brookings Insti-
tution.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1011a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1015" publication-type="other">
Kiley, Kevin. 4 June 2013. The New 'New Normal'. Inside Higher Ed. Available from http://www.in-
sidehighered.com/news/2013/06/04/appropriations-increases-and-tuition-freezes-reshape-state-
funding-picture.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1029a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1033" publication-type="other">
Kim, Jane J. 27 July 2004. Putting a cap on tuition expenses: some colleges freeze costs until stu-
dents graduate, ending steep yearly hikes. The Wall Street Journal, p D2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1043a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1047" publication-type="other">
Kim, Mikyong. M., 8c Ko, Jangwan. 2014. The impacts of state control policies on college tuition
increase. Educational Policy, doi: 10.1177/0895904813518100.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1057a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1061" publication-type="other">
Koshal, R. K., 8c Koshal, M. 2000. State appropriation and higher education tuition: What is the
relationship? Education Economics. 8 (1): 81-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1071a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1075" publication-type="other">
Krogstad, Jens 11 November 2012. State colleges look at tuition freeze to recoup funding. The USA
Today. Available from http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2012/ll/ll/state-universi-
ties-tuition-freeze-budget-cuts/1698379/</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1088a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1092" publication-type="other">
Leslie, Larry. L. 8c Garey Ramey. 1986. State appropriations and enrollments: Does enrollment
growth still pay? The Journal of Higher Education. 57 (1): 1-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1102a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1106" publication-type="other">
Lowry, R. C. 2001. The effects of state political interests and campus outputs on public university
revenues. Economics of Education Review, 20 (2), 105-119.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1117a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1121" publication-type="other">
McLendon Michael K., James C. Hearn, 8c Christina G. Mokher. 2009. Partisans, professionals
and power: The role of political factors in state higher education funding. The Journal of Higher
Education. 80 (6): 686-713.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1134a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1138" publication-type="other">
Morphew, Christopher C. Jan/Feb 2007. Fixed-tuition pricing: A solution that may be worse than
the problem. Change: The Magazine of Higher Learning. 39 (10): 34-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1148a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1152" publication-type="other">
National Association of Independent Colleges and Universities [NAICU]. n.d. Special Initiatives.
Enhancing Affordability. Fixed-Tuition Guarantees. Available from http://www.naicu.edu/spe-
cial_initiatives/affordability/about/#Fixedtuitionl3 (accessed 21 July 2013).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1165a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1169" publication-type="other">
National Association of State Budget Officers. 2013. Improving Postsecondary Education through
the Budget Process: Challenges and Opportunities. Available from http://www.nasbo.org/high-
er-education-report-2013 (accessed 21 July 2013).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1182a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1186" publication-type="other">
Oklahoma State Regents for Higher Education. December 2011. FY 2011-12 tuition impact anal-
ysis report. Available from http://www.okhighered.org/studies-reports/tuition-impact-analy-
sis-ll-12.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1199a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1203" publication-type="other">
Okunade, Albert A. 2004. What factors influence state appropriations for public higher education
in the United States? Journal of Education Finance. 30 (2): 123-138.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1214a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1218" publication-type="other">
Peterson, Robert G. 1976. Environmental and political determinants of state higher education ap-
propriations policies. The Journal of Higher Education. 47 (5): 523-542.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1228a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1232" publication-type="other">
Reed, Allen. 28 January 2014. Texas A&amp;M System Board of Regents to consider tuition changes.
theeagle.com. Available from http://www.theeagle.com/news/local/article_21b896ba-27d9-57d0-
abdl-8851eb5bebf4.html?TNNoMobile (accessed on 5 May 2014).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1245a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1249" publication-type="other">
Rizzo, Michael J. 2003. A (less than) zero sum game? State funding for public education: How public
higher education institutions have lost. Doctoral Dissertation, Cornell University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1259a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1263" publication-type="other">
Robertson, Alan D. 2007. Measuring the impact of guaranteed tuition plans on enrollment at a
minority serving public institution. (Doctoral dissertation). Retrieved from Proquest. (UMI
No. 3255868).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1276a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1280" publication-type="other">
Rusk, James J., 8c Larry L. Leslie. 1978. The setting of tuition in public higher education. The Jour-
nal of Higher Education. 49: 531-547.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1290a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1294" publication-type="other">
Supiano, Beckie. 24 April 2009. The psychology of college pricing. The Chronicle of Higher Educa-
tion. A4-A4.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1305a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1309" publication-type="other">
Tandberg, David A. 8c Casey Griffith. 2013. "State support of higher education: Data, measures,
findings, and directions for future research" In M. B. Paulsen (Ed.) Higher Education: Handbook
of Theory and Research, 28: 613-685.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1322a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1326" publication-type="other">
Thomson, Susan C. Fall 2005. "Truth in tuition": Illinois' novel answer to skyrocketing rates. Na-
tional CrossTalk. 161-166.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1336a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1340" publication-type="other">
Thorne, Christopher, 8c Scott W. Wright. 19 April 1999. Guaranteed tuition programs gaining in
popularity across the country. Community College Week. 11: 8.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1350a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1354" publication-type="other">
Toutkoushian, Robert K. 8c Paula Hollis. 1998. Using panel data to examine legislative demand for
higher education. Education Economics 6 (2): 141-157.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1364a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1368" publication-type="other">
Troutt, Marvin D., Thaddeus McEwen, 8c Bee K. Yew. 1995. Some modeling considerations in
deciding multi-year guaranteed tuition rates. Journal for Higher Education Management. 11:
19-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1381a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1385" publication-type="other">
Ura, Alexa. 5 December 2012. Bill on fixed tuition rates aims to increase affordability of education.
The Daily Texan. Available from http://www.dailytexanonline.com/news/2012/12/04/biU-on-
fixed-tuition-rates-aims-to-increase-affordability-of-education.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2576393e1399a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2576393e1403" publication-type="other">
Ward, Mike. 2012. Perry outlines plan to lock in college fees. Austin American-Statesman. Avail-
able from http://www.statesman.com/news/news/local/perry-outlines-plan-to-lock-in-college-
fees/nSLZb/.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


