<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830701</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830704</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>ARE INTERNATIONAL BONDS HOTTER THAN LOANS? / LES OBLIGATIONS INTERNATIONALES SONT-ELLES PLUS EN DEMANDE QUE LES PRÊTS?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>William</given-names>
                  <surname>Miles</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1999</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>407</fpage>
         <lpage>432</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830704"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The surge of capital to developing countries in the 1990's has been characterized by a rise in portfolio bond and equity flows and a sharp decline in the bank lending which dominated during the 1970's and 1980's. Concern has been expressed that the new inflows are "hotter" than bank credit, in that they are more subject to a quick shut-off. This volatility may explain a large part of the turmoil in emerging market finance this decade. Previous work has focused on very broad categories of capital flows, but the relative volatility of more specific classes of financing has not been examined. This paper fills this gap by comparing bonds to bank loans. Bonds and bank credit are suited for comparison, as they are both contractual debt instruments. Moreover, bonds are the majority "new" source of financial capital for emerging markets, with substantially greater volume than equity, while loans represent the "old" form of inflow. A contrast of the two therefore sheds light on how the volatility of the financial environment for emerging markets has changed over the last two decades. Prior to any estimation, there are theoretical reasons to believe that bonds are indeed hotter than loans. This stems from bondholders not developing the close relationships with borrowers that bankers are thought to cultivate. To examine the issue formally, statistical tests for unit roots and ARCH effects are performed, and VARs are run between loans and bonds. The results indicate that fears about the volatility of bonds are justified. L'essor du capital des pays en voie de developpement dans les années 1990 a été caractérisé par une hausse des portefeuilles des obligations et du flux des valeurs et du déclin accentué des prêts bancaires qui avaient dominé durant les années 70 et les années 80. Des inquiétudes avaient été exprimées que les nouveaux flux de rentrées sont plus en demande que les crédits bancaires, vu qu'ils sont plus sujets à une interruption rapide. Cette volatilité peut expliquer en grande partie le trouble du marché financier émergent de cette décade. Un travail antérieur s'était concentré sur de très larges catégories du flux du capital, mais la volatilité relative de classes plus spécifiques de financement n'a pas été examinée. Cette étude remplit cette lacune en comparant les obligations aux prêts bancaires. Les obligations et le crédit bancaire se prêtent à la comparaison vu que les deux sont des instruments de dettes contractuelles. De plus les obligations sont la "nouvelle" source majoritaire du capital financier des marchés émergents avec un volume subtantiellement supérieur à la valeur, alors que les prêts représentent la "vieille" forme du flux de rentrées. Par conséquent un contraste des deux expliquerait comment la volatilité de l'environnement financier des marchés émergents a changé durant les deux dernières décades. Avant toute autre estimation, il se trouve des raisons théoriques pour croire que les obligations sont certainement plus en demande que les prêts. Ceci vient du fait que les porteurs d'obligations ne développent pas les relations étroites avec les emprunteurs que les banquiers sont supposés avoir cultiver. Pour formellement éxaminer cette question, des tests statistiques pour des racines unitaires et les effets d'ARCH sont effectués, et des VARs sont faits entre les prêts et les obligations. Les résultats indiquent que les peurs sur la volatilité des obligations sont fondées.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d29e291a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e298" publication-type="other">
The Economist, August 30, 1997, pp. 53-54.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e305a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e312" publication-type="other">
Chuhan, Punam, Stijn Claessens and Nlandu Mamingi "Equity and Bond Flows to Asia and Latin America:
The Role of Country and Global Factors", July 1993, World Bank Policy Research Working Paper No. 1160,
p.7.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e325a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e332" publication-type="other">
Kwiatowski, Denis, Peter C.B. Phillips, Peter Schmidt, and Yongcheol Shin "Testing the Null Hypothesis of
Stationarity Against the Alternative of a Unit Root: How Sure are We that Economic Time Series Have a Unit
Root?", Journal of Econometrics, Vol. 54, No. 3, pp. 159-178.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d29e354a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e358" publication-type="other">
Baer, Werner and Kent Hargis, "Forms of External Capital, Sovereignty and Economic Development in Latin
America", University of Illinois Office of Research Working Paper No. 97-0102, 1997.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e368a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e372" publication-type="other">
Bird, Graham and Nicholas Snowden, "From Banks to Bonds: A Problem Resolved? A Perspective on the
LDC Debt Literature" Journal of International Development, Vol. 9, No. 2, 1997, pp. 207-220.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e382a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e386" publication-type="other">
Calvo, Guillermo and Enrique Mendoza, "Reflections on Mexico's Balance of Payments Crisis: Chronicle of a
Death Foretold", Journal of International Economics, Vol. 41, No. 3, 1996, pp. 235-264.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e396a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e400" publication-type="other">
Calvo, Guillermo, Leonardo Leiderman and Carmen Reinhart, "Capital Inflows and Real Exchange Rate Ap-
preciation in Latin America", IMF Staff Papers, Vol. 40, No. 1, 1993, pp. 108-151.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e411a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e415" publication-type="other">
Chow, Edward, "Debt Rescheduling and the Choice Between Bonds and Loans for LDCs' Foreign Debt",
Open Economies Review, Vol. 5, No. 2, 1994, pp. 139-154.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e425a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e429" publication-type="other">
Chuhan, Punam, Stijn Claessens and Nlandu Mamingi, "Equity and Bond Flows to Asia and Latin America:
The Role of Global and Country Factors", World Bank Policy Research Working Paper, No. 1160, 1993.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e439a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e443" publication-type="other">
Chuhan, Punam, Gabriel Perez-Quiros and Helen Popper, "International Capital Flows: Do Short-Term Invest-
ment and Direct Investment Differ?", World Bank Working Paper, 1997.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e453a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e457" publication-type="other">
Claessens, Stijn, Michael P. Dooley and Andrew Warner, "Portfolio Capital Flows: Hot of Cold", World Bank
Economic Review, Vol. 9, No. 1, 1995, pp. 153-174.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e467a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e471" publication-type="other">
Cline, William R., International Debt Reexamined, Institute for International Economics, Washington, D.C.,
1995.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e481a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e485" publication-type="other">
Edwards, Sebastian, "The Pricing of Bonds and Bank Loans in International Markets: An Empirical Analysis of
Developing Countries' Foreign Borrowing", European Economic Review, Vol. 30, No. 3, 1986, pp. 565-
589.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e499a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e503" publication-type="other">
Eichengreen, Barry and Richard Portes, "Dealing with Debt: The 1930's and the 1980's", in Ishrat Husain and
Ishac Diwan, eds. Dealing with the Debt Crisis, World Bank, Washington, D.C., 1989, pp. 69-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e513a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e517" publication-type="other">
Folkerts-Landau, David, "The Changing Role of International Bank Lending in Development Finance", IMF
Staff Papers, Vol. 32, 1985, pp. 316-333.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e527a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e531" publication-type="other">
Garcia, Marcio and Alexandre Barcinski, "Capital Flows to Brazil in the Nineties: Macroeconomic Aspects and
the Effectiveness of Capital Controls", Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance, Vol. 38, No. 3,
1998, pp. 319-357.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e544a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e548" publication-type="other">
Gavin, Michael, Ricardo Hausmann, and Leonardo Leiderman, "The Macroeconomics of Capital Flows to La-
tin America: Experience and Policy Issues", Inter-American Development Bank Working Paper No. 310,
1995.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e561a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e565" publication-type="other">
Kwiatowski, Denis, Peter C.B. Phillips, Peter Schmidt and Yongcheol Shin, "Testing the Null Hypothesis of
Stationarity Against the Alternative of a Unit Root: How Sure are We that Economic Time Series Have a
Unit Root?", Journal of Econometrics, Vol. 54, No.3, 1992, pp. 159-178.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e578a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e582" publication-type="other">
Sims, Christopher, "Macroeconomics and Reality", Econometrica, Vol. 48, No. 1, 1980, pp. 1-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


