<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">militaryengineer</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018902</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Military Engineer</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of American Military Engineers (SAME)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00263982</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25786431</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26354370</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>LEADER PROFILE</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Nation’s Indispensable Reserve</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Talley</surname>
                  <given-names>Jeffrey W.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Lt. Gen. Jeffrey W. Talley, Ph.D., P.E., BCEE, D.WRE, USA, became Chief of Army Reserve and Commanding General of the U.S. Army Reserve Command in June 2012. He graduated from Louisiana State University in 1981 with a Regular Army commission in the Corps of Engineers. During over 31 years of active and reserve service, he has commanded units at every echelon, from platoon to division-level, with duty in Korea, Kuwait, Iraq, and the United States. In February 2003, Gen. Talley deployed in support of Operation Enduring Freedom/Operation Iraqi Freedom as Chief of Operations, 416th Engineer Command, Coalition Joint Forces Land Component Command. He then served in the Pentagon as a Strategic Planner in the Deputy Directorate for the War on Terrorism, Strategic Plans &amp; Policy Directorate (J-5), Joint Chiefs of Staff. In January 2008, he deployed in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom as Commander, 926th Engineer Brigade, 4th Infantry Division, Multi-National Division-Baghdad and the Baghdad Provincial Engineer. From June 2009–April 2012 he was Commanding General, 84th Training Command, Fort Knox, Ky. Prior to his return to active military service, Gen. Talley was President &amp; CEO and Co-Founder of Environmental Technology Solutions (ETS Partners), as well as an Adjunct Professor at The Johns Hopkins University. Other civilian experiences include leadership positions at Southern Methodist University, the University of Notre Dame, Malcolm Pirnie Inc., and the Corps of Engineers. He holds a Ph.D. in Civil and Environmental Engineering from Carnegie Mellon University and an Executive M.B.A. from the University of Oxford. He also holds multiple master’s degrees in Strategic Studies, Environmental Engineering and Science, Liberal Arts (History and Philosophy), and Religious Studies.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>NOVEMBER-DECEMBER 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>106</volume>
         <issue>692</issue>
         <issue-id>e26354361</issue-id>
         <fpage>50</fpage>
         <lpage>52</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2014 The Society of American Military Engineers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26354370"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
