<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277948</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Diffusive Air Jet Combustion Chamber and Its Effect on DI Diesel Engine Combustion and Exhaust Emissions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kamat</surname>
                  <given-names>Prakash</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Aghav</surname>
                  <given-names>Yogesh</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gokhale</surname>
                  <given-names>Nitin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kumar</surname>
                  <given-names>M N</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Kirloskar Oil Engines Ltd</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>January 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277910</issue-id>
         <fpage>369</fpage>
         <lpage>379</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International and Copyright © SAEINDIA</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277948"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>An innovative Diffusive Air Jet (DAJ) Combustion Chamber concept has been introduced in the present work. The DAJ Combustion Chamber design is based on the study of rate of heat release (ROHR) curve and its correlation with emission generation. The objective is to lower the trade-off between NOx and soot without sacrificing fuel economy of Direct Injection (DI) diesel engine. DAJ Combustion Chamber modifies ROHR curve to the desired one so that it lowers engine out emissions. To study its effect, a large bore, six cylinder engine with mechanical fuel injection system has been used. Three dimensional simulation software is used for the model calibration of basic reentrant cavity. Local emissions and ROHR curve have been studied using reentrant cavity shape. It has been modified to DAJ Combustion Chamber using Air Jet Chambers (AJCs). AJCs are positioned in the three dimensional model in such a way that they affect local in-cylinder emissions. Combustion in the DAJ combustion chamber has been studied at two different load conditions at the same engine speed. The results obtained with DAJ Combustion Chamber have been validated experimentally for the selected multi cylinder engine. In this paper simulation and experimental results with basic reentrant cavity and DAJ Combustion Chamber have been discussed in detail. Effectiveness of DAJ combustion chamber is further explored during experimentation which has been covered in this paper.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piexoto Vinicious, Combustion Optimization of a Diesel Engine with EGR system using 1D and 3D simulation tools, ECM 2009 fourth european combustion conference, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Risi A., Manieri D. F., and Laforgia D., A Theoretical Investigation on the Effects of Combustion Chamber Geometry and Engine Speed on Soot and NOx Emissions ASME, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Risi, A., Donateo, T., and Laforgia, D., “Optimization of the Combustion Chamber of Direct Injection Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1064, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1064.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shi, Y. and Reitz, R., “Assessment of Optimization Methodologies to Study the Effects of Bowl Geometry, Spray Targeting and Swirl Ratio for a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine Operated at High-Load,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):537-557, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0949.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamat, P., Aghav, Y., Gokhale, N., Helchel, V. et al., “Effect of Combustion System Parameters on DI Diesel Engine Performance and Exhaust Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-2745, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2745.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colin O. and Benkenida A. The 3-Zones Extended Coherent Flame Model (ECFM3Z) for Computing Premixed/Diffusion Combustion, Oil and Gas Science - Rev. IFP, Vol. 59. 6, 593-609, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AVL FIRE Engine Simulation Reference Manuals, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bockhorn, H. ed., Soot Formation in Combustion Mechanisms and Models, Springer.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lakshminarayanan P.A., Aghav Y. V., Modeling Diesel Combustion, 1st Edition- Springer, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
