<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830665</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830672</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE EMPIRICAL DETERMINANTS OF DIRECT FOREIGN INVESTMENT IN PAKISTAN / LES CAUSES DÉTERMINANTES DES INVESTISSEMENTS ÉTRANGERS DIRECTS AU PAKISTAN</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Mohammed</given-names>
                  <surname>Nishat</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Anjum</given-names>
                  <surname>Aqeel</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1998</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>471</fpage>
         <lpage>479</lpage>
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830672"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>There is an increasing role of foreign direct investment in the economies of many growing developing countries. Pakistan like many other developing countries faces significant international competition in attracting foreign private investment. This paper attempts to empirically identify the determinants of direct foreign investment in Pakistan during the period 1961 to 1994. The study selects many demand side economic, social and political parameters which reflect the general investment climate and are crucial to attract or unattract the private foreign investment. From our findings it is evident that political stability, peaceful law and order situation, level of technical labor force and mineral resouce exploitation do attract foreign investors. The existing liberal policies by the government during last decade have been successful in attracting foreign direct investment in Pakistan. Dans maintes pays en voie de développement, les investissement étrangers directs jouent un rôle de plus un plus important. Le Pakistan, comme beaucoup d'autres pays en voie de développement, doit faire face à une concurrence internationale importante quand il s'agit d'attier ce type d'investissements. Cet étude se propose d'identifier de manière empirique les déterminantes des investissements étrangers directs au Pakistan dans la période 1961-1994. À cet effet, les auteurs ont choisi une série de paramètres économiques du côté de la demande, de paramètres sociaux et de paramètres politiques qui témoignent du climat d'investissement général du pays et qui sont d'importance cruciale quand il est question d'attirer ou de ne pas attirer les investissements étrangers privés. Les résultats de cet étude confirment que la stabilité politique, l'ordre public, le niveau technique de la main d'oeuvre et l'exploitation des ressources minières sont des facteurs importants d'attraction des investisseurs étrangers et que les politiques libérales mises en place par le gouvernement dans la dernière décennie ont réussi à attirer les investissements étrangers directs au Pakistan.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d43e138a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e145" publication-type="other">
Hasan, A and M. Nishat (1989), "Determinants of Multinational Investments in Pakistan: An Exploratory Analysis",
Pakistan Economic and Social Review, No. 1.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e155a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e162" publication-type="other">
Lim, D. (1983), "Fiscal Incentives and Direct Foreign Investment in Less Developing Countries". Journal of
Development Studies, vol. 19, No. 2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e172a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e179" publication-type="other">
Nishat, M. and N. Bilgrami (1991), "The Impact of Migrant Worker's Remittances on Pakistan Economy", Pakistan
Economic and Social Review, vol. 29, No. 1.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e189a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e196" publication-type="other">
Nishat, M. and N. Bilgrami (1994), "Remittances Behaviour of Pakistani Migrants Living in Middle East", draft,
AERC</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e207a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e214" publication-type="other">
Root, F. and R. Ahmed (1979). "Empirical Determinants of Manufacturing Direct Investment in Less Developed
Countries", Economic Development and Cultural Change, vol. 27, No. 4.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e224a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e231" publication-type="other">
Tsai, Pan-Long (1991), "Determinants of foreign Direct Investment in Taiwan: An Alternative Approach with Time
series Data", World Development vol. 19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


