<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277900</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Comparative Low Speed Pre-Ignition (LSPI) Study in Downsized SI Gasoline and CI Diesel-Methane Dual Fuel Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zaccardi</surname>
                  <given-names>Jean-Marc</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Serrano</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>IFP Energies Nouvelles</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>October 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277873</issue-id>
         <fpage>1931</fpage>
         <lpage>1944</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277900"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Low speed pre-ignition (LSPI) in downsized spark-ignition engines has been studied for more than a decade but no definitive explanation has been found regarding the exact sources of auto-ignition. No single mechanism can explain all the occurrences of LSPI and that each engine should be considered as a particular case supporting different conditions for auto-ignition.</p>
            <p>In a different context, dual fuel Diesel-Methane engines have been more recently studied in large to medium bore compression ignition engines. However, if Dual Fuel combustion is less knock sensitive, LSPI remains one of the main limitations of low-end torque also for dual fuel engines. Indeed, in some cases, premature ignition of CNG can be observed before the Diesel pilot injection as LSPI can classically be observed before the spark in gasoline engines.</p>
            <p>This article aims at highlighting the similarities and discrepancies between LSPI phenomena in SI gasoline and dual fuel engines. The comparison of both cases bring a novel perspective on some proposed LSPI mechanisms in literature and help in understanding possible conflicting theories.</p>
            <p>The first essential characteristic of dual fuel engines lies in the use of a gaseous fuel (port-injected in the studied case). The mixture homogeneity within the combustion chamber is thus expected to be much better than with a liquid fuel. Compared to classical direct injection gasoline engines, fuel impacts on the walls don’t exist and fuel / lubricant interactions must be reassessed as if to explain LSPI.</p>
            <p>The high octane number and auto-ignition delay times of methane must also be considered but counterbalanced by the high compression ratios used. Critical conditions for auto-ignitive LSPI can thus be compared for SI and dual fuel engines.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duffour, F., Ternel, C., and Pagot, A., “IFP Energies Nouvelles Approach for Dual Fuel Diesel-Gasoline Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0065, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0065.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serrano, D.; Lecointe, B.; Exploring the Potential of Dual Fuel Diesel-CNG Combustion for Passenger Car Fisita World Automotive Congress, F2012-B01-025, 2012, doi:10.1007/978-3- 642-33777-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serrano, D., Obiols, J., and Lecointe, B., “Optimization of Dual Fuel Diesel-Methane Operation on a Production Passenger Car Engine - Thermodynamic Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 2013- 01-2505, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sahoo, B.B.; Sahoo, N.; Saha, U.K.; Effect of Engine Parameters and Type of Gaseous Fuel on the Performance of Dual Fuel Gas Diesel Engines - A Critical Review. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 13 (2009) pp. 1151-1184, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.bbr.2011.03.031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Königsson, F., Stalhammar, P., and Angstrom, H., “Characterization and Potential of Dual Fuel Combustion in a Modern Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-2223, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-2223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Königsson, F., Kuyper, J., Stalhammar, P., and Angstrom, H., “The Influence of Crevices on Hydrocarbon Emissions from a Diesel- Methane Dual Fuel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):751-765, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0848.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carlucci, A.P.; Laforgia, D.; Saracino, R.; Toto, G.; Combustion and Emissions Control in Diesel-Methane Dual Fuel Engines: the Effects of Methane Supply Method Combined with Variable In-Cylinder Charge Bulk Motion. Energy Conversion and Management 52 (2011) 3004-3017, 2011, doi:10.1016/S0196- 8904(03)00150-X.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishiyama, T., Kang, J., Ozawa, Y., and Sako, T., “Improvement of Performance and Reduction of Exhaust Emissions by Pilot- Fuel-Injection Control in a Lean-Burning Natural-Gas Dual- Fuel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):243-253, 2012, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Königsson, F., Stalhammar, P., and Angstrom, H., “Controlling the Injector Tip Temperature in a Diesel Dual Fuel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0826, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0826.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Selim, M.Y.E.; Sensitivity of Dual Fuel Engine Combustion and Knocking Limits to Gaseous Fuel Combustion. Energy Conversion And Management 45(3), pp. 411-425, 2004, doi:10.1016/S0196- 8904(03)00150-X.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Königsson, F.; Advancing the Limits of Dual Fuel Combustion. Licentiate Thesis Report, KTH Royal Institute of Technology, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eichlseder, H.; Grabner, P.; Hadl, K.; Hepp, C.; Luef, R.; Dual Fuel Concepts for Mobile Application. 34. Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inoue, T., Inoue, Y., and Ishikawa, M., “Abnormal Combustion in a Highly Boosted SI Engine - The Occurrence of Super Knock,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1141, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01- 1141.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smallbone, A.; Bhave, A.; Advanced Simulations of “Knocking” and “Mega-Knocking” Combustion Events in Highly Boosted DISI Engines. 10th International Symposium on Combustion Diagnostics, Baden-Baden, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amann, M., Alger, T., and Mehta, D., “The Effect of EGR on Low- Speed Pre-Ignition in Boosted SI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):235-245, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0339.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zaccardi, J.-M.; Escudié, D.; Overview of The Main Mechanisms Triggering Low-Speed Pre-Ignition in Spark-Ignition Engines. Int. J. Engine Res., doi:10.1177/1468087414530965.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahnz, C.; Spicher, U.; Irregular combustion in supercharged spark ignition engines - pre-ignition and other phenomena. Int. J. Engine Res. Vol. 11, pp. 485-498, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spicher, U.; History and Diagnostics of Irregular Combustion in Spark Ignition Engines. The 8th International Conference on Modeling and Diagnostics for Advanced Engine Systems, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dronniou, N., Kashdan, J., Lecointe, B., Sauve, K. et al., “Optical Investigation of Dual-fuel CNG/Diesel Combustion Strategies to Reduce CO2 Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):873-887, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1313.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zaccardi, J.-M.; Pagot, A.; Statistical observations on pre-ignition in SI engines. 3rd Conference on Knocking at Gasoline Engines - Irregular Combustion, Berlin, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Livengood, J.C.; Wu, P.C.; Correlation of Autoignition Phenomena in Internal Combustion Engines and Rapid Compression Machines. Proceedings of the Fifth International Symposium on Combustion, pp. 347-356, 1955.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vangraefschepe, F.; Zaccardi, J.-M.; Analysis of destructive abnormal combustions appearing at high load and low engine speed on high performance gasoline engines. SIA Conference : The Spark Ignition Engine of the Future, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adomeit, P.; Thewes, M.; Ewald, J.; Günther, M.; Morcinkowski, B., Pischinger, S.; Effect of Fuel and Combustion System on the Pre-Ignition of Boosted SI Engines. 34th International Vienna Motor Symposium, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rothenberger, P.; Zahdeh, A.; Anbarasu, M.; Göbel, T.; Simon, J.S.; Soldan, S.S.; Experimental Pre-Ignition Investigations of Boosted Spark Ignition Engines in Combination with Light- Intensified High Speed Camera and CFD. IAV Conference Knocking at Gasoline Engines - Irregular Combustion, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Freeland, P.; Taylor, J.; Oudenijeweme, D.; Stansfield, P.; Warth, M.; Advanced technologies for downsized direct injection gasoline engines. THIESEL Conference on Thermo and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Direct Injection Engines, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoffmeyer, H., Montefrancesco, E., Beck, L., Willand, J. et al., “CARE - CAtalytic Reformated Exhaust Gases in Turbocharged DISI-Engines,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1):139-148, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0503.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yasueda, S.; Takasaki, K.; Tajima, H.; The Abnormal Combustion caused by Lubricating Oil on High BMEP Gas Engines. Der Arbeitsprozess des Verbrennungsmotors, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yasueda, S.; Takasaki, K.; Tajima, H.; Abnormal Combustion caused by Lubricating Oil in High BMEP Gas Engines. MTZ Motortechnische Zeitschrift Industrial (MTZ Special Edition), pp. 34-39, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
