<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465378</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465385</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Limited and Varying Consumer Attention: Evidence from Shocks to the Salience of Bank Overdraft Fees</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Victor</given-names>
                  <surname>Stango</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Jonathan</given-names>
                  <surname>Zinman</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>990</fpage>
         <lpage>1030</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465385"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We explore dynamics of limited attention in the $35 billion market for checking overdrafts, using survey content as shocks to the salience of overdraft fees. Conditional on selection into surveys, individuals who face overdraft-related questions are less likely to incur a fee in the survey month. Taking multiple overdraft surveys builds a "stock" of attention that reduces overdrafts for up to two years. The effects are significant among consumers with lower education and financial literacy. Individuals avoid overdrafts by making fewer low-balance debit transactions and cancelling automatic recurring withdrawals. The results raise new questions about consumer financial protection policy.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d64e300a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e307" publication-type="other">
We measure financial literacy using responses to a question from a survey consumers complete when they are
registering their accounts in the panel: "I know more than most people when it comes to managing my money
and investments [agree/disagree/neutral]."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e320a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e327" publication-type="other">
Even if one assumes that the panelists who avoid overdrafts are those closest to the extensive margin (i.e., those
with one or two overdrafts in a month rather than many), applying the treatment effect of six overdraft-related
surveys in a two-year period generates a 19% reduction in the total dollar amount of overdraft fees paid in our
sample. That percentage multiplied by the dollar amount of overdraft fees paid annually ($35 billion) implies a
roughly $7 billion reduction in overdraft fees paid. This figure is illustrative only: one should be cautious about
extrapolating our results to the entire U.S. population of deposit account-holders.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e350a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e357" publication-type="other">
If surveys change behavior, this raises ethical and methodological issues about relying on surveys to measure
behavior and elicit behavioral parameters. We distinguish between being surveyed per se, about topics related to
the target behaviors of interest, and being asked more directly about the target behavior of interest, in the sense
of questions that are administered by a party with a vested interest in the target behavior (e.g., a firm selling the
product under study), and/or questions that ask respondents about their intent or likelihood of engaging in the
target behavior. See Zwane et al. (2011) for discussions of the evidence on how surveys affect behavior.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e380a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e387" publication-type="other">
Persuasive advertising is an important application of priming effects; e.g., Bertrand et al. (2010) find that small
changes in uninformative ad content have large effects on the take-up of expensive consumer loans.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e398a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e405" publication-type="other">
See also and Lee and Malmendier (2011) for theory and empirics on limited attention in auctions; Lacetera,
Pope, and Sydnor (2012) on limited attention in the car market; and Alba, Hutchinson, and Lynch (1991), Eliaz
and Spiegler (2011), and Koszegi and Szeidl (2013) on consideration sets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e418a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e425" publication-type="other">
A Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) report (Burrhouse et al. 2008) provides an extensive description
of bank overdraft pricing and policies during our sample period, and we draw heavily on that report here. For
additional institutional details on the United States and the United Kingdom, see U.S. General Accounting Office
(2008) and Armstrong and Vickers (2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e441a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e448" publication-type="other">
The internal limit varies across banks, across customers within banks, and even for a given customer over time.
Most large banks use fraud/default protection software similar to that used by credit card companies; if a particular
account displays suspicious behavior, or behavior suggesting a high likelihood that the customer plans to default
on the negative balance, the bank will start to decline overdraft transactions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e464a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e471" publication-type="other">
See, e.g., http://www.responsiblelending.org/overdraft-loans/research-analysis/quick-facts-on-overdraft-loans.html.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e478a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e485" publication-type="other">
Other Forrester/Lightspeed panels track consumer behavior of interest to market researchers, such as the use and
purchases of new technology. Those panels are widely used by industry researchers and academics; see, e.g.,
Goolsbee (2000, 2001), Prince (2008), and Kolko (2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e498a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e505" publication-type="other">
The central problem is that we observe fees only when they are incurred. Thus, an account with no fees (or
a period without fees) may have either standard overdraft service or overdraft protection. It is also difficult to
use fees paid to infer what overdraft service a customer has. For example, the majority of accounts in which an
overdraft protection fee has been incurred later incur a standard overdraft fee—presumably because the linked
account has been depleted or hit its limit.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e525a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e532" publication-type="other">
The available balance is what the consumer may withdraw before an overdraft. The current balance is the available
balance plus holds on the account and netting out pending debits/credits.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e542a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e549" publication-type="other">
Table A1 provides more information on the time series of participation in the panel month by month. We observe
transactions in January 2006, but we do not use those data in the empirical work because we often condition on
lagged monthly information—which is first available as of February 2006.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e562a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e571" publication-type="other">
We note that this type of self-report has two issues that warrant mention, drawing heavily on Hastings, Madrian,
and Skimmyhorn (2012). First, individual self-reports and actual financial decisions do not always correlate
strongly (Karlan and Zinman 2008; Collins et al. 2009; Hastings and Mitchell 2011) Second, consumers may be
overconfident about their skill level (Agnew and Szykman 2005; Organization for Economic Co-operation and
Development 2005), although this is not evident in our data, where self-assessed financial literacy is centered on
average. Despite these issues, prior work has found that self-assessed financial capabilities and more objective
measures of financial literacy are indeed positively correlated (e.g., Lusardi and Mitchell 2009; Parker et al.
2012), and that self-reported financial literacy or confidence often has independent predictive power for financial
outcomes relative to more objective test-based measures of financial literacy (e.g., Van Rooij, Lusardi, and
Alessie 2011; Allgood and Walstad 2012). We suspect that any bias introduced by the self-report works against
finding a significant difference between the responses of low- vs. high-financial literacy consumers to attention
shocks, given that prior findings on overconfidence suggest that most misclassification would be true-low literacy
consumers classifying themselves as self-reported higher-literacy consumers.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e616a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e623" publication-type="other">
There is some ambiguity on Lightspeed's/Forrester's part about whether their recorded survey dates reflect dates
by which surveys were administered (e-mailed to panelists), dates by which surveys were completed by panelists,
or dates by which Lightspeed received the completed survey data. The survey months we assign reflect our best
attempts, in concert with Lightspeed, to pin down the date by which the panelist completed the survey. See below
for a discussion of how we explored and dealt with this uncertainty empirically.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e642a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e649" publication-type="other">
Response rates across surveys vary for several reasons. The set of panelists varies over time and may introduce
differences in average panelist-level propensity for taking surveys. Some surveys are left "open" online longer
than others. And there are small variations from survey to survey in prizes/compensation for participating.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e662a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e669" publication-type="other">
Example of spending control question: "I like being in control of my spending [agree/disagree scale]." Example
of balance-monitoring question: "How often do you log into your [Q1 BANK] banking website specifically to
look at your account balance?" Example of other fee question: "Debit cards have too many fees associated with
them [agree/disagree scale]."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e686a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e693" publication-type="other">
The "OD Survey" group includes all overdraft (OD)-related surveys, including the overdraft-focused survey.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e700a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e707" publication-type="other">
The "No OD survey" data therefore average across panelist-months in which an overdraft survey was offered but
the panelist did not take the survey, and panelist-months in which a non-overdraft survey was offered—whether
the panelist took that survey or not. All of these observations contribute to the identifying variation in our data. We
include all eligible observations in the figure, meaning that the panel is unbalanced (as it is in the econometrics
below).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e726a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e733" publication-type="other">
The study by Agarwal et al. (2009) is a nice exception, drawing on administrative data from multiple financial
institutions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e743a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e750" publication-type="other">
In terms of overdraft frequency, it is difficult to compare our administrative data with self-reported
overdraft behavior. In our data, 16% of panelist-months have one or more overdrafts, and roughly half
of panelists have at least one overdraft over the three-year sample period. The FINRA National Financial
Capability Survey reports that 23% of respondents self-declare as incurring overdrafts "occasionally." See
http://www.usfinancialcapability.org/downloads/NFCS_2009_Natl_Full_Report.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e769a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e776" publication-type="other">
Lusardi and Tufano's Table 4 suggests that only 13% of the U.S. population rate themselves as having below-
average overall financial knowledge.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e786a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e793" publication-type="other">
Conditional (fixed effect) logit models yield nearly identical results, and are in most specifications more precisely
estimated (meaning that the coefficients of interest are statistically significant at levels greater than what we
discuss below). The model also includes a dummy equal to one if the month is the panelist's last in the sample.
We typically observe transactions for only part of the month in such instances, meaning that overdrafts are less
common.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e813a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e820" publication-type="other">
Within survey months there is variation in survey-taking; in one month, we have variation in survey-taking and
survey content, because both an overdraft-related and a generic survey were offered. Clustering on survey-month
is not recommended because we have fewer than 50 clusters on that dimension.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e833a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e842" publication-type="other">
Ninety-five percent of those who click through to an overdraft-related survey answer at least one overdraft-related
question. The remaining 5% may have actually been exposed to the questions in the sense of seeing them, but not
responding. To the extent that some survey-"takers" are not actually exposed to the survey content of interest,
our estimates are intent-to-treat effects, and lower bounds on treatment-on-the-treated effects, under standard
assumptions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e861a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e868" publication-type="other">
We have estimated alternate specifications of the "immediate" effect, motivated by the fact that we do not
observe the survey date precisely. If we include the lagged value of TookOD, that coefficient is positive but not
statistically significant (see Figure 3). It is possible that panelists avoid overdrafts in the near term by pushing
expenses forward into the next month, which is what one might expect if expenses are less discretionary in the
short run; see Table 7 for evidence on this point.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e887a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e894" publication-type="other">
We have also estimated specifications including leads of overdraft-survey and any-survey taking; these variables
tend to be insignificant and do not change the results. We include panelists who never take any survey, despite
having panelist fixed effects, to help identify the estimates on the non-survey variables.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e907a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e914" publication-type="other">
We have also estimated specifications that control (flexibly) for the number of months a panelist has appeared
in the panel. These variables are not significant correlates of overdrafting and tend to reduce the precision of the
estimates on the variables of interest. The "months-in-sample" variables are included (and significant) in some
of the specifications we discuss later regarding Tables 7 and 8.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e930a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e937" publication-type="other">
In unreported results we implement various corrections for the lagged dependent variable bias (Anderson-Hsiao-
and Arellano-Bond-type instruments). Doing so leaves the primary results qualitatively unaffected.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e948a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e955" publication-type="other">
Mechanically, the immediate effect is the sum of the coefficients on the two immediate survey variables,
subtracting any bias from selection into surveys.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e965a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e972" publication-type="other">
The relationship between generic survey-taking and overdrafts is nonlinear: there is little relationship until roughly
the fifth survey, and then the likelihood of an overdraft rises. For 7-12 generic surveys taken, the likelihood of
an overdraft averages 5% higher than baseline. Results beyond that (13+ surveys) are noisy.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e985a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e992" publication-type="other">
One could view Table 4, column 6, as the reduced form of a two-stage model in which the first stage explains
whether the account comes "close to the edge," and the second stage examines overdrafts conditional on being
close to the edge. We considered estimating such a model, but have no strong candidates for an exclusion
restriction that would identify the model. We do examine whether taking overdraft-related surveys affects how
often accounts come close to the edge, in Table 7.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e1011a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e1018" publication-type="other">
The results are similar, quantitatively and qualitatively, if we split the sample along similar lines using any of
the other specifications in the latter columns of Table 4.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e1028a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e1035" publication-type="other">
We have also estimated pooled specifications in which we include income, education, and literacy interacted with
the survey variables. Doing so reduces efficiency because income, education, and literacy are highly correlated,
but we find similar results: there are strong effects in the low-income/education/literacy group, with mixed results
regarding whether the higher-income/education/literacy groups display statistically different effects.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e1051a1310">
            <label>34</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e1058" publication-type="other">
We have attempted to estimate whether questions about credit card fees are associated with changes in overdrafts,
but lack the power to identify an effect (no credit card fee questions appear on surveys without questions about
overdraft fees). We have also estimated whether even more tangential questions—about, for example, loan
payments—are associated with changes in overdrafts, but find no effects.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e1075a1310">
            <label>35</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e1082" publication-type="other">
Stango and Zinman (2011) highlight enforcement challenges involved in mandated disclosure in consumer
lending. Barr, Mullainathan, and Shafir (2008) make a similar point regarding mandated default options; the
lender "moves last" and has incentives to get the consumer to undo the default (e.g., "just initial here" to opt in
to standard overdraft service).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d64e1107a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1111" publication-type="other">
Agarwal, S., J. Driscoll, X. Gabaix, and D. Laibson. 2009. The age of reason: Financial decisions over the
lifecycle with implications for regulation. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, Fall, 51-117.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1121a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1125" publication-type="other">
. 2011. Learning in the credit card market. Available from SSRN website at http://ssrn.com/
abstract= 1091623.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1135a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1139" publication-type="other">
Agnew, J. R., and L. R. Szykman. 2005. Asset allocation and information overload: The influence of information
display, asset choice, and investor experience. Journal of Behavioral Finance 6:57-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1149a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1153" publication-type="other">
Alba, J., J. W. Hutchinson, and J. G Lynch. 1991. Memory and decision making. In Handbook of Consumer
Behavior (pp. 1-49). Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1164a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1168" publication-type="other">
Allgood, S., and W. Walstad. 2012. The effects of perceived and actual financial literacy on financial behaviors.
Available from SSRN website at http://ssrn.com/ abstract=2191606.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1178a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1182" publication-type="other">
American Bankers Association. 2007. 80 percent of consumers have not paid overdraft fees in past year, says
ABA survey. Press Release.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1192a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1196" publication-type="other">
Armstrong, M., and J. Vickers. 2012. Consumer protection and contingent charges. Journal of Economic
Literature 50:477-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1206a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1210" publication-type="other">
Barber, B., and T. Odean. 2008. All that glitters: The effect of attention on the buying behavior of individual and
institutional investors. Review of Financial Studies 21:785-818.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1220a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1224" publication-type="other">
Barr, M., S. Mullainathan, and E. Shafir. 2008. Behaviorally informed financial services regulation. New
American Foundation White Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1234a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1238" publication-type="other">
Bertrand, M., D. Karlan, S. Mullainathan, E. Shafir, and J. Zinman. 2010. What's advertising content worth?
Evidence from a consumer credit marketing field experiment. Quarterly Journal of Economics 125:263-305.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1249a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1253" publication-type="other">
Burrhouse, S., P. Cashman, R. Cordeiro, T. Critchfield, Y. Lee, V. Pawelski, and K. Samolyk. 2008. FDIC study
of bank overdraft programs. Available from FDIC website at: http://www.fdic.gov/bank/analytical/overdraft/
FDIC 138_Report_Final_v508.pdf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1266a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1270" publication-type="other">
Center for Responsible Lending. 2009. Overdraft fees and opting in: A survey of consumer preferences. Available
from Center for Responsible Lending website at: http://www.responsiblelending.org/overdraft-loans/research-
analysis/consumer-preference-opt-in.pdf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1283a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1287" publication-type="other">
. 2010. National bank regulator enabled overdraft abuses. CRL Policy Brief.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1294a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1298" publication-type="other">
Chartrand, T., J. Huber, B. Shiv, and R. Tanner. 2008. Nonconscious goals and consumer choice. Journal of
Consumer Research 35:189-201.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1308a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1312" publication-type="other">
Collins, J. M., R. N. Gorey, M. D. Schmeiser, C. A. Baker, and D. Ziegler. 2009. Building indicators measures:
Analysis and recommendations. Baltimore: Annie E. Casey Foundation.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1322a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1326" publication-type="other">
Consumer Financial Protection Bureau. 2013. CFPB study of overdraft programs: A white paper of initial data
findings. Available from http://files.consumerfinance.gOv/f/201306_cfpb_whitepaper_overdraft-practices.pdf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1337a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1341" publication-type="other">
DeliaVigna, S. 2009. Psychology and economics: Evidence from the field. Journal of Economic Literature
47:315-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1351a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1355" publication-type="other">
DellaVigna, S., and J. Pollet. 2009. Investor inattention and Friday earnings announcements. Journal of Finance
64:709-^49. doi: 10.1111/j. 1540-6261.2009.01447.x</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1365a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1369" publication-type="other">
Dholakia, U. 2010. A critical review of question-behavior effect research. In Review of Marketing Research, vol.
7 (pp. 147-99). Armonk, NY: M. E. Sharpe.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1379a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1383" publication-type="other">
Eliaz, K., and R. Spiegler. 2011. Consideration sets and competitive marketing. Review of Economic Studies
78:235-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1393a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1397" publication-type="other">
Fishman, M., and K. Hagerty. 2003. Mandatory versus voluntary disclosure in markets with informed and
uninformed consumers. Journal of Law, Economics, and Organization 19:45-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1407a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1411" publication-type="other">
Gabaix, X., and D. Laibson. 2006. Shrouded attributes, consumer myopia, and information suppression in
competitive markets. Quarterly Journal of Economics 121:505-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1422a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1426" publication-type="other">
Glaser, M., M. Weber, and T. Langer. 2010. Overconfidence of professionals and lay people: Individual differences
within and between tasks? Working Paper available at http://www.wiwi.unifrankfurt.de/professoren/schlag/
dgf2009/Contribution 168.pdf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1439a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1443" publication-type="other">
Goolsbee, A. 2000. In a world without borders: The impact of taxes on internet commerce. Quarterly Journal of
Economics 115:561-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1453a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1457" publication-type="other">
. 2001. Competition in the computer industry: Online versus retail. Journal of Industrial Economics
49:487-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1467a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1471" publication-type="other">
Grubb, M. 2012. Consumer inattention and bill-shock regulation. Available from SSRN website at
http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id= 1983518.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1481a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1485" publication-type="other">
Haselhuhn, M., D. Pope, M. Schweitzer, and P. Fishman. 2012. The impact of personal experience on behavior:
Evidence from video-rental fines. Management Science 58:35-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1495a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1499" publication-type="other">
Hastings, J. S., B. C. Madrian, and W. L. Skimmyhorn. 2012. Financial literacy, financial education, and
economic outcomes. Annual Review of Economics 5:347-73. doi: 10.1146/annurev-economics-082312-125807.
http://dx.doi.org/10.1146/annurev-economics-082312-125807.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1513a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1517" publication-type="other">
Hastings, J. S., and O. Mitchell. 2011. How financial literacy and impatience shape retirement wealth and
investment behaviors. NBER Working Paper 16740. Available at http://www.nber.org/papers/wl6740.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1527a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1531" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, D., S. S. Lim, and S. H. Teoh. 2009. Driven to distraction: Extraneous events and underreaction to
earnings news. Journal of Finance 64:2289-2325. doi: 10.1111/j.l 540-6261.2009.01501.x</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1541a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1545" publication-type="other">
. 2011. Limited investor attention and stock market misreactions to accounting information. Review of
Asset Pricing Studies 1:35-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1555a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1559" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, D., and S. H. Teoh. 2003. Limited attention, information disclosure, and financial reporting. Journal
of Accounting and Economics 36:337-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1569a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1573" publication-type="other">
Karlan, D., M. McConnell, S. Mullainathan, and J. Zinman. 2012. Getting to the top of mind: How reminders
increase saving. NBER Working paper 16205, available at http://www.nber.org/papers/wl6205</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1583a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1587" publication-type="other">
Karlan, D., and J. Zinman. 2008. Lying about borrowing. Journal of the European Economic Association
6:510-21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1598a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1602" publication-type="other">
Khorana, A., H. Servaes, and P. Tufano. 2009. Mutual fund fees around the world. Review of Financial Studies
22:1279-1310.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1612a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1616" publication-type="other">
Kolko, J. 2010. A new measure of U.S. residential broadband availability. Telecommunications Policy 34:
132-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1626a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1630" publication-type="other">
Koszegi, B., and A. Szeidl. 2013. A model of focusing in economic choice. Quarterly Journal of Economics
128:53-104.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1640a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1644" publication-type="other">
Lacetera, N., D. Pope, and J. Sydnor. 2012. Heuristic thinking and limited attention in the car market. American
Economic Review 102:2206-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1654a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1658" publication-type="other">
LeBoeuf, R., E. Shafir, and J. B. Bayuk. 2010. The conflicting choices of alternating selves. Organizational
Behavior and Human Decision Processes 111:48-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1668a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1672" publication-type="other">
Lee, Y. H., and U. Malmendier. 2011. The bidder's curse. American Economic Review 101:749-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1680a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1684" publication-type="other">
Lusardi, A., and O. Mitchell. 2009. How ordinary consumers make complex economic decisions: Financial
literacy and retirement readiness. NBER Working Paper 15350.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1694a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1698" publication-type="other">
Lusardi, A., and P. Tufano. 2009. Debt literacy, financial experience, and overindebtedness. NBER Working
Paper No. 14808.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1708a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1712" publication-type="other">
Malkiel, B. G 2013. Asset management fees and the growth of finance. Journal of Economic Perspectives
27:97-108.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1722a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1726" publication-type="other">
Organisation for Economie Co-operation and Development. 2005. Improving financial literacy: Analysis of issues
and policies. Paris: OECD Publications.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1736a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1740" publication-type="other">
Parker, A. M., W. B. Bruin, J. Yoong, and R. Willis. 2012. Inappropriate confidence and retirement planning:
Four studies with a national sample. Journal of Behavioral Decision Making 25:382-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1750a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1754" publication-type="other">
Parrish, L. 2008. Consumers want informed choice on overdraft fees and banking options. Center for Responsible
Lending. Available from Center for Responsible Lending website at http://www.responsiblelending.org/
overdraft-loans/research-analysis/final-caravan-survey-4-16-08.pdf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1768a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1772" publication-type="other">
Peng, L., and W. Xiong. 2006. Investor attention, overconfidence and category learning. Journal of Financial
Economics 80:563-602.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1782a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1786" publication-type="other">
Prince, J. 2008. Repeat purchase amid rapid quality improvement: Structural estimation of demand for personal
computers. Journal of Economics and Management Strategy 17:1-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1796a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1800" publication-type="other">
Sela, A., and B. Shiv. 2009. Unraveling priming: When does the same prime active a goal versus a trait? Journal
of Consumer Research 36:418-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1810a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1814" publication-type="other">
Stango, V., and J. Zinman. 2009. What do consumers really pay on their checking and credit card accounts?
Explicit, implicit, and avoidable costs. American Economic Review Papers and Proceedings 99:424—29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1824a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1828" publication-type="other">
. 2011. Fuzzy math, disclosure regulation, and credit market outcomes: Evidence from truth-in-lending
reform. Review of Financial Studies 24:506-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1838a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1842" publication-type="other">
Stavins, J. 1999. Checking accounts: What do banks offer and what do consumers value? New England Economic
Review (March/April): 3-13.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1853a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1857" publication-type="other">
U.S. General Accounting Office. 2008. Federal banking regulators could better ensure that consumers have
required disclosure documents prior to opening checking or savings accounts. Publication no. GAO-08-281.
Washington, DC: U.S. General Accounting Office. Available at http://www.gao.gov/products/GAO-08-281.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1870a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1874" publication-type="other">
Van Rooij, M., A. Lusardi, and R. Alessie. 2011. Financial literacy and stock market participation. Journal of
Financial Economics 101:449-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1884a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1888" publication-type="other">
Zinman, J. 2009. Where is the missing credit card debt? Clues and implications. Review of Income and Wealth
55:249-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1898a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1902" publication-type="other">
Zwane, A., J. Zinman, E. Van Dusen, W. Pariente, C. Null, E. Miguel, M. Kremer, et al. 2011. Being surveyed can
change later behavior and related parameter estimates. Proceedings of the National Academy of Science 10:1-6.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


