<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023218</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Fiscal Rules, Transparency, and Accountability</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Consequences of State Balanced Budget Restrictions</article-title>
            <subtitle>Fiscal Constraints or Accounting Manipulations?</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Costello</surname>
                  <given-names>Anna M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>
                  <addr-line>Sloan School of Management</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>100 Main Street, E62-683</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>Cambridge, MA 02142</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>617-324-3894</addr-line>
               </aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Petacchi</surname>
                  <given-names>Reining</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>
                  <addr-line>Sloan School of Management</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>100 Main Street, E62-669</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>Cambridge, MA 02142</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>617-253-7084</addr-line>
               </aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Weber</surname>
                  <given-names>Joseph</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>
                  <addr-line>Sloan School of Management</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>100 Main Street, E62-667</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>Cambridge, MA 02142</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>617-253-4310</addr-line>
               </aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>42</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023218"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Although balanced budgets are widely used throughout the world, there is considerable debate on whether they are effective. Poterba (1997) provides two theories on the effectiveness of balanced budget restrictions. The institutional irrelevance view suggests that balanced budget rules are ineffective, as governments can circumvent budget rules through accounting manipulations. Alternatively, the public choice view argues that balanced budgets represent important constraints on political actors. In this paper we provide evidence on these contrasting theories by investigating the extent to which states cut expenditures and/or raise taxes to meet the budget or whether they use accounting gimmicks to comply with budget requirements. Our evidence is consistent with both theories; we find that when facing fiscal problems, states use a combination of expenditure cuts <italic>and</italic> accounting gimmicks like inter-fund transfers and selling assets to meet the budget. A $100 per capita deficit induces states with strong anti-deficit rules to transfer $20 into the governmental funds, to sell $6.10 public assets, and to reduce expenditures by $48.40. We find that the fiscal response to deficits varies based on the size of the deficit; states react to small deficits by increasing taxes and cutting expenditures, and states respond to large deficits using a combination of tax increases, expenditure cuts, and asset sales. Jointly, our results suggest that balanced budget restrictions do provide constraints on political actors, but they also result in the use of accounting gimmicks like fund sweeps and asset sales.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alt, James E., and Robert C. Lowry, 1994. “Dividend government, fiscal institutions, and budget deficits: Evidence from the states.” American Political Science Review 88, 4: 811-828.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Becker, S., Green, D., 1962. “Budgeting and Employee Behavior.” The Journal of Business 35, 4: 392-402.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bohn, H., Inman, R.P., 1996. “Balanced-budget rules and public deficits: evidence from the U.S. States.” Carnegie-Rochester Conference Series on Public Policy 45: 13-76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bouwens, J., Kroos, P., 2011. Target ratcheting and effort reduction. Journal of Accounting and Economics 51, 171-185.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Core, John, Wayne R. Guay, and Rodrigo S. Verdi, 2006. “Agency problems of excess endowment holdings in non-for-profit firms.” Journal of Accounting and Economics 41: 307-333.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gold, Steven D., 1983. “Recent developments in state finances.” National Tax Journal 36: 1-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gore, Angela K., 2009. “Why Do Cities Hoard Cash? Determinants and Implications of Municipal Cash Holdings.” The Accounting Review 84, 1: 183-207.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gore, Angela K., 2012. “Do Governments Hide Resources from Unions? The Influence of Public Sector Unions on Financial Reporting Choices.” Unpublished Working Paper. Avaliable at: http://ssrn.com/abstract=2127755.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Granof, Michael H, and Ives, Martin, 1996. “Let's get serious about balanced budgets.” The Government Accountants Journal 45.3: 24-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hou, Yilin, and Daniel L. Smith, 2006. “A framework for understanding state balanced budget requirement systems: Reexamining distinctive features and an operational definition.” Public Budgeting &amp; Finance 26: 22-45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ives, Martin. 1996. “Gimmicks, manipulations, one-shots - Where are the accountants?” The Government Accountants Journal 45.1: 40-43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leone, A. J. and S. Rock, 2002. Empirical Tests of Budget Ratcheting and its effect on Manager;s Disretionary Accrual Choices. Journal of Accounting and Economics 33 (1): 43-67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murphy, Kevin J., 2000. “Performance standards in incentive contracts.” Journal of Accounting and Economics 30 (3): 245-278.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NASBO, 2008. “Budget processes in the states.” Washington, D. C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NCSL, 2010. “NCSL Fiscal Brief: State Balanced Budget Provisions.” Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, Mitchell A., 2009. “Estimating standard errors in finance panel data sets: Comparing approaches.” Review of Financial Studies 22: 435-480.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Poterba, James M., 1994. “State Responses to Fiscal Crises: The Effects of budgetary Institutions and Politics.” Journal of Political Economy, 102(4): 799-821.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Poterba, James M., 1997. “Do Budget Rules Work?” Unpublished working paper, Available at http://www.nber.org/papers/w5550.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rogers, William, 1993. “Regression standard errors in clustered samples.” Stata Technical Bulletin 13: 19-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. General Accounting Office, 1985. “Budget issues: State balanced budget practices.” Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. General Accounting Office, 1993. “Balanced Budget Requirements: State Experiences and Implications for the Federal Government.” Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Whitney, Meredith, 2013. “Fate of the States.” The Portfolio/Penguin Group Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zimmerman, J., 2001. “Conjectures Regarding Empirical Managerial Accounting Research.” Journal of Accounting and Economics 32: 411-427.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article>
