<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278241</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Spin Loss Computation for Open Clutch Using CFD</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jammulamadaka</surname>
                  <given-names>Anand K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gaokar</surname>
                  <given-names>Prajal</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>GM Technical Center India Ltd. - General Motors Company</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1536</fpage>
         <lpage>1544</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278241"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Open clutch spin loss computation is of interest for new clutch designs. It is desirable to minimize open clutch spin loss. Spin loss in automatic transmission clutches is mainly due to the viscous shear of the transmission fluid. Depending on the relative rotational speed of the plates the spin loss varies. At low rotational speeds the gap between the plates is filled with ATF (Automatic Transmission Fluid) and spin loss increases linearly with the rotational speed. At higher speeds the ATF layer, which is held together primarily by surface tension, begins to breakdown due to higher centrifugal forces and air pockets form at outward radial locations of the clutch plates. This results in a decrease in spin loss for the open clutch. CFD (computational fluid dynamics) modeling is an attractive option in calculating the spin loss for an open clutch. Not only can a CFD model give an accurate estimation of the magnitude and trend of spin loss variation but it can also compare various groove designs. This is a significant advantage compared to some existing analytical methods for spin loss estimation of open clutches, as they are limited to either groove-less designs or designs with radial grooves. This work describes a 3D CFD modeling procedure that yields spin loss computations of sufficiently high accuracy by improvements made to some stated procedures in literature. Effect of variation of design parameters such as number of grooves, flow rates, etc, is studied.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aphale, C. R., Cho, J., Schultz, W. W., Ceccio, S. L., Yoshioka, T., &amp; Hiraki, H., “Modeling and Parametric Study of Torque in Open Clutch Plates,” Transactions of the ASME, 128, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yuan, Y., Liu, E. A., and Hill, J., “An Improved Hydrodynamic Model for Open Wet Transmission Clutches,” Journal of Fluids Engineering, 129:333-337, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yuan, Y., Attibele, P., and Dong, Y., “CFD Simulation of the Flows Within Disengaged Wet Clutches of an Automatic Transmission,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0320, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0320.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schade, C.W., “Effects of Transmission Fluid on Clutch Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 710734, 1971, doi: 10.4271/710734.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jibin, H., Zengxiong, P., and Yuan, S., “Drag Torque Prediction Model for the Wet Clutches,” Chinese Journal of Mechanical Engineering, 22 (2), 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kato, Y., Murasugi, T., and Hirano, H., “Fuel Economy Improvement Through Tribological Analysis of the Wet Clutches and Brakes of an Automatic Transmission,” Society of Automotive Engineers of Japan, 16 (12), 57-60, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mikael, H., “Apparatus for measurement of engagement characteristics of a wet clutch,” Wear, 213, 140-147, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Lam, R.C., Chen, Y.F., and Yabe, H., “Modeling of Heat Transfer and Fluid Hydrodynamics for a Multidisc Wet Clutch,” SAE Technical Paper 950898, 1995, doi: 10.4271/950898.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kitabayashi, H., Li, C. Y., &amp; Hiraki, H., “Analysis of Various Factors Affecting Drag Torque in Multiple-Plate Wet Clutches,” JSAE 20030331, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
