<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285040</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Numerical Fracture Analysis Considering Forming Effect and Element Size Regularization for Automotive Seat Structures</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kim</surname>
                  <given-names>Dae-Young</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Han</surname>
                  <given-names>Yongtak</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Shin</surname>
                  <given-names>Sahnghoon</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Yook</surname>
                  <given-names>Hyungsub</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Das Corp.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285020</issue-id>
         <fpage>287</fpage>
         <lpage>295</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285040"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The aim of this paper is to apply an advanced fracture model and to evaluate its applicability in automotive seat structures. A Generalized Incremental Stress-State dependent damage Model (GISSMO), which was one of the advanced fracture models implemented in LS-DYNA, was adopted as a fracture model. A description of the damage parameter identification process with material tests was introduced in this study. The GISSMO adopts most of the fracture factors, and was introduced in previous works. In order to evaluate the fracture strain in various stress states, uniaxial tension, simple shear-tension, notched-tension, and biaxial tension tests were carried out. The GISSMO damage parameters were calculated and identified using reverse analysis method and theoretical equations with some numerical fitting techniques. The results were compared with material test results, and it was evaluated that the values might be applicable to the seat frame model. In addition, it was found that the effects of element size and manufacturing (forming) are large with regard to fracture behavior. In particular, the seat rail has a residual stress owing to the bending process in the forming step. From these simulation results, the material parameters were applied to the full seat structure. Various models showed good agreement with the experimental fracture strength and crack propagation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chauffray, M., Delattre, G. and Guerin, L., “Prediction of Failure on High Strength Steel in Seat Mechanisms Simulation,” 8th European LSDYNA User Conference, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nguyen, N. T., Kim, D. Y. and Kim, H. Y., “A Continuous Damage Fracture Model to Predict Formability of Sheet Metal,” Fatigue Fract. Eng. M. 36(3):202-216, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, D. Y., Nguyen, N. T. and Kim, H. Y., “A Comparative Study of Failure Criteria in Sheet Metal Forming Analysis,” XI International Conference on Computational Plasticity, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nguyen, N., Kim, D., and Kim, H., "A Modified McClintock Criterion Considering the Third Stress Invariant," SAE Technical Paper 2011-28- 0084, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-28-0084.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bai, Y. and Wierzbicki, T., “A New Model of Metal Plasticity and Fracture with Pressure and Lode Dependence,” Int. J. Plasticity 24:1071-1096, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wierzbicki, T., Bao, Y., Lee, Y. W. and Bai, Y., “Calibration and Evaluation of Seven Fracture Models,” Int. J. Mech. Sci. 47:719-743, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xue, L., “Ductile Fracture Modeling: Theory, Experimental Investigation and Numerical Verification,” Ph.D. thesis, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barsoum, I. and Faleskog, J., “Rupture Mechanisms in Combined Tension and Shear Experiments,” Int. J. Solids Struct. 44:1768-1786, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xue, L., “Constitutive Modeling of Void Shearing Effect in Ductile Fracture of Porous Materials,” Eng. Fract. Mech. 75:3343-3366, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrade, F., Haufe, A., Feucht, M., Bohm, R. and Bois, P. D., “Prediction of Dynamic Material Failure, Part II: Application with GISSMO in LS-DYNA,” 10th European LS-DYNA Conference, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chinzei, S. and Naito, J., “The Numerical Failure Prediction by the Damage GISSMO in Various Materials of Sheet Metal,” 10th European LS-DYNA Conference, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Falkinger, G. and Simon, P., “An Investication of Modeling Approaches for Material Instability of Aluminum Sheet Metal using the GISSMOModel,” 10th European LS-DYNA Conference, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Livermore Software Technology Corporation (LSTC), “LS-DYNA Keyword User’s Manual,” LSTC, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xue, L. and Wierzbicki, T., “Ductile Fracture Characterization of Aluminum Alloy 2024-T351 Using Damage Plasticity Theory,” Int. J. Appl. Mech. 1(2):267-304, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sinne, S., Klose, H., Dura Brisa, V., J. and Partheymuller, P., “Comprehensive Correlation of Seat Track Assembly -From Forming to Assembly Test-,” 10th European LS-DYNA Conference, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ping, H., Mingzeng, L., Xiangkui Z. and Guozhe., S., “Adaptive mesh optimization for improved One-Step Forming,” AIP Conf. Proc., 1532, 883, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
