<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">33</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186602</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44440405</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Hi-Duty Spark-Plug Testing</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>A. L.</given-names>
                  <surname>Beall</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>L. M.</given-names>
                  <surname>Townsend</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1938</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>465</fpage>
         <lpage>471</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44440405"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>AS an engine under development is not a tool which can be used for the testing and rejection of questionable spark-plugs, some test is necessary to parallel the engine development so that suitable spark-plugs are available for it when it enters service. This paper describes a preliminary singlecylinder engine test method for spark-plugs which evaluates the quality not only most essential but the most difficult to secure, namely, resistance to preignition. Teste were made on two types of engine – a liquid-cooled, single-cylinder test engine and an air-cooled, single-cylinder test engine. Operating conditions were selected with regard for satisfactory performance plus the ability to heat the spark-plug. A large number of plugs were tested, some of identical design, and many of them were re-run several times as a check on the reproducibility of the test method. In addition to the preignition test, a full-scale engine type test, a ground fouling test, a flight fouling test, and a starting-ability test are recommended, with bench tests at intervals and measurement of electrode erosion and wear as a check on the probable useful life and ability of the sparkplug to measure up to the requirements of flight service.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


