<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Wiley</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26605595</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effect of the UK Coalition Government’s Tax and Benefit Changes on Household Incomes and Work Incentives</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Adam</surname>
                  <given-names>Stuart</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Browne</surname>
                  <given-names>James</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Elming</surname>
                  <given-names>William</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">36</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26605589</issue-id>
         <fpage>375</fpage>
         <lpage>402</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26605595"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The coalition government that was in office in the UK between May 2010 and May 2015 introduced a sizeable package of tax and benefit reforms to reduce the UK’s large budget deficit. We use a microsimulation model that includes a broader range of policy measures than previous studies to estimate how these reforms affected both household incomes and work incentives. We find that lower-income working-age households and the very richest have lost the most, while working-age households without children in the upper-middle of the income distribution actually gained from these reforms. Some results of our analysis are, however, highly sensitive to the choice of ‘no reform’ baseline. This is particularly true of how much pensioners have gained or lost from the reforms, since this depends critically on whether the basic state pension is increased in line with earnings or prices in the ‘no reform’ scenario. When analysing the impact of these reforms on individuals’ work incentives, we find that the coalition’s changes have slightly strengthened work incentives. The participation tax rate has, on average, been reduced by 3 percentage points, perhaps a less significant strengthening of incentives than might have been expected given the scale of the coalition’s benefit cuts. However, this average effect disguises considerable variation across the population; indeed, the majority of workers have seen the incentive to increase their earnings weaken, not strengthen, as a result of the coalition’s reforms.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Adam, S. and Browne, J. (2010), ‘Redistribution, work incentives and thirty years of UK tax and benefit reform’, Institute for Fiscal Studies (IFS), Working Paper no. W10/24(http://www.ifs.org.uk/wps/wp1024.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Adam, S. and Browne, J. (2015), ‘Do the UK government’s welfare reforms make work pay?’, paper presented at ECFIN Workshop on ‘Expenditure-Based Consolidation: Experiences and Outcomes’, 20 January (http://ec.europa.eu/economy_finance/events/2015/20150120-ecfin_workshop/documents/session_32_en.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Adam, S. and Phillips, D. (2013), An Ex-Ante Analysis of the Effects of the UK Government’s Welfare Reforms on Labour Supply in Wales, Report no. R75, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies (http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/6586).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Adam, S. and Roantree, B. (2015), ‘The coalition government’s record on tax’, Institute for Fiscal Studies (IFS), Briefing Note no. BN167 (http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/7642).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Blundell, R. and Hoynes, H. (2004), ‘Has “in-work” benefit reform helped the labor market?’, in D. Card, R. Blundell and R. B. Freeman (eds), Seeking a Premier Economy: The Economic Effects of British Economic Reforms, 1980–2000, Chicago, IL: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Brewer, M., Browne, J. and Jin, W. (2012), ‘Universal credit: a preliminary analysis of its impact on incomes and work incentives’, Fiscal Studies, vol. 33, pp. 39–71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Browne, J. and Elming, W. (2015), ‘The effect of the coalition’s tax and benefit changes on household incomes and work incentives’, Institute for Fiscal Studies (IFS), Briefing Note no. BN159 (http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/7534).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Browne, J. and Phillips, D. (2010), ‘Tax and benefit reforms under Labour’, Institute for Fiscal Studies (IFS), Briefing Note no. BN88 (http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/4807).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Clark, T. and Leicester, A. (2004), ‘Inequality and two decades of British tax and benefit reforms’, Fiscal Studies, vol. 25, pp. 129–58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">De Agostini, P., Hills, J. and Sutherland, H. (2014), ‘Were we really all in it together? The distributional effects of the UK coalition government’s tax-benefit policy changes’, Social Policy in a Cold Climate Working Paper no. 10 (http://sticerd.lse.ac.uk/dps/case/spcc/wp10.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">De Agostini, Paulus, A., Sutherland, H. and Tasseva, I. (2014), ‘The effect of tax-benefit changes on the income distribution in EUcountries since the beginning of the economic crisis’, EUROMOD Working Paper no. EM9/14 (https://www.iser.essex.ac.uk/research/publications/workingpapers/euromod/em9-14.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Emmerson, C. and Tetlow, G. (2015), ‘Public finances under the coalition’, in C. Emmerson, P. Johnson and R. Joyce (eds), The IFS Green Budget: February 2015, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies (http://www.ifs.org.uk/uploads/gb/gb2015/ch1_gb2015.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Figari, F., Paulus, A. and Sutherland, H. (2015), ‘The design of fiscal consolidation measures in the European Union: distributional effects and implications for macroeconomic recovery’, EUROMOD Working Paper no. EM5/15 (https://www.iser.essex.ac.uk/research/publications/working-papers/euromod/em5-15.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Giles, C. and McCrae, J. (1995), ‘TAXBEN: the IFS microsimulation tax and benefit model’, Institute for Fiscal Studies (IFS), Working Paper no. W95/19 (http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/572).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Heckman, J. (1979), ‘Sample selection bias as a specification error’, Econometrica, vol. 47, pp. 153–61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">HM Treasury (2015), Impact on Households: Distributional Analysis to Accompany Budget 2015 (https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/413877/distributional_analysis_budget_2015.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Hood, A. and Oakley, L. (2014), ‘The social security system: long-term trends and recent changes’, Institute for Fiscal Studies (IFS), Briefing Note no. BN156 (http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/7438).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Hood, A. and Phillips, D. (2015), ‘Benefit spending and reforms: the coalition government’s record’, Institute for Fiscal Studies (IFS), Briefing Note no. BN160 (http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/7535).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Jara, H. X. and Tumino, A. (2013), ‘Tax-benefit systems, income distribution and work incentives in the European Union’, EUROMOD Working Paper no. EM7/13 (https://www.iser.essex.ac.uk/research/publications/working-papers/euromod/em7-13.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Saez, E., Slemrod, J. and Giertz, S. (2012), ‘The elasticity of taxable income with respect to marginal tax rates: a critical review’, Journal of Economic Literature, vol. 50, pp. 3–50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">UK Statistics Authority (2013), Assessment of Compliance with the Code of Practice for Official Statistics: The Retail Prices Index, Assessment Report no. 246 (http://www.statis ticsauthority.gov.uk/assessment/assessment/assessment-reports/assessment-report-246- - -the-retail-prices-index.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Key measures included in our analysis, with revenue estimates for 2015–16</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Impact of tax and benefit reforms introduced between May 2010 and May 2015 by income decile</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Impact of modelled tax and benefit reforms introduced between May 2010 and May 2015 by income decile and household type</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Impact of modelled tax and benefit reforms introduced between May 2010 and May 2015 relative to a CPI-indexed baseline by income decile</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Impact of modelled tax and benefit reforms introduced between May 2010 and May 2015 relative to a CPI-indexed baseline by income decile and household type</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Impact of the coalition’s tax and benefit reforms on the average participation tax rate of different groups</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Variation in the impact of tax and benefit changes on individuals’ participation tax
rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Impact of the coalition’s tax and benefit reforms on the average effective marginal tax rate of different groups of workers</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Variation in the impact of tax and benefit changes on workers’ effective marginal tax rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
