<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277571</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Onboard Optimisation of Engine Emissions and Consumption According to Diesel Fuel Quality</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hermitte</surname>
                  <given-names>Eric</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>SP3H</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lunati</surname>
                  <given-names>Alain</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>SP3H</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Delebinski</surname>
                  <given-names>Thaddaeus</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>December 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277559</issue-id>
         <fpage>1661</fpage>
         <lpage>1683</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277571"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In response to the demand to lower CO2 emission, all engine developers face the challenge of drastically reducing fuel consumption. At the same time, they will need to meet future exhaust emission legislation by simultaneously employing internal measures and after treatment systems.</p>
            <p>Additionally, they will have to deal with increasing fuel variability. As different properties can lead to very different behavior in engine operation, information onboard the vehicle providing the fuel composition would allow to adjust engine operating parameters accordingly, to make the most beneficial use of the available fuel quality. This will be obvious considering future diesel fuels blends, or the ever increasing amount of biodiesel content mixed into Diesel fuel, but could already be interesting considering existing fuel variability faced in Europe or America.</p>
            <p>In this context, an innovative Fuel Quality Sensor technology [1] [2] has been developed: it provides detailed information about the molecular structure of the diesel fuel flowing to the engine as well as its biodiesel content.</p>
            <p>In the context of the presented study, a matrix of 10 diesel fuels representative of real world fuel variability and including future trends in biodiesel introduction has been prepared, and systematically tested on a modern single cylinder engine, with a fully flexible engine parameters management.</p>
            <p>First step was to test all fuels with basic Engine Control Unit (ECU) settings optimized for EN590 fuel, showing the impact of fuel variability on engine emissions and specific fuel consumption.</p>
            <p>Second step was to investigate influence of several engine parameter (pilot and main injection, EGR rate, …) in order to understand the ways to optimise ECU settings for each fuel blend.</p>
            <p>The final step will be a compensating algorithm, enabling the engine to run different fuel qualities with optimized emissions, fuel consumption and running behavior, using information from the Fuel Quality Sensor.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fournel, J., Lunati, A., and Dementhon, J., “Optimization of internal combustion processes using an on-board fuel micro analyzer,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1830, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1830.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lunati, A. and Fournel, J., “Innovative on Board Optical Sensor Dedicated to Measure Water, Alcohols and Ethers Content in Biofuels for Flexfuel Engine Optimization,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2451, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2451.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FULTON, B. - Ford Motor Company - DEER Conference - Detroit - August 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MOSCONI, J.J. - TOTAL - The European Fuels Conference - Paris - March 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SCHNÜPKE, H., SORSCHE, P. - Daimler Chrysler - Hart's Fuel Conference - Beijing - November 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Milpied, J., Uhrich, M., Patissier, B., and Bernasconi, L., “Applications of Tuning Fork Resonators for Engine Oil, Fuel, Biodiesel Fuel and Urea Quality Monitoring,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(2):45-53, 2010, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2639.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CHRYSLER Corp - “Flexible Fuels Sensor System” - US patent n °5150653 - Sept 1992</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CHRYSLER Corp - “Flexible Fuels Sensor System” - US patent n °5150653 - Sept 1992</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CHRYSLER Corp - “Flexible Fuels Sensor System” - US patent n °5150653 - Sept 1992</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SIEMENS Corp - “Fuel Sensor”- US patent n°20030020494 - Jan 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pontoppidan, M. and Montanari, G., “New developments of the 3rd generation SFS-Flex system to meet PL5/6 emission requirements.,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-36-0159, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-36-0159.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guido, C., Beatrice, C., Di Iorio, S., Napolitano, P. et al., “Assessment of Closed-Loop Combustion Control Capability for Biodiesel Blending Detection and Combustion Impact Mitigation for an Euro5 Automotive Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1193, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">PASQUINI, Celio, BRAZ, J. - “Near Infrared Spectroscopy: Fundamentals, Practical Aspects and Analytical Applications” - Chem. Soc., Vol. 14, No. 2, 198-219, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OSBORNE, B. G. - “Near-infrared Spectroscopy in Food Analysis” - Encyclopaedia of Analytical Chemistry pp120-143 - ISBN 0471 97670 9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">PARKER, M. E, STEELE, D., SMITH, M.J.C. - “Vibrational Absorption Intensities in Chemical Analysis. The Near-Infrared Spectra of Methyl Branched Alkanes” - J. Phys. Chem. A 1997, 101, 9618-9631</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LACHENAL, G - « Analyse par spectroscopie proche infrarouge (PIR) et applications aux polymères » - ANALYSIS MAGAZINE, 1998, 26- N° 4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM D6623-01 - Test Method for Determination of Individual Components in Spark Ignition Engine Fuels by High Resolution Gas Chromatography</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM D5845-01 (2006) - Standard Test Method for Determination of MTBE, ETBE, TAME, DIPE, Methanol, Ethanol and tert-Butanol in Gasoline by Infrared Spectroscopy</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM D4815-04 - Standard Test Method for Determination of MTBE, ETBE, TAME, DIPE, tertiary-Amyl Alcohol and C1 to C4 Alcohols in Gasoline by Gas Chromatography</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patent WO2006100377 - Method for optimizing operating parameters of a combustion engine - SP3H, LUNATI, A., FOURNEL, J.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lunati, A. and Galtier, O., “Determination Of Mixture Of Methanol And Ethanol Blends In Gasoline Fuels Using A Miniaturized NIR Flex Fuel Sensor,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1988, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ESPINOSA, A, LAMBERT, D, VALLEUR, M - “Use NIR technology to optimize plant operations” - Hydrocarbon Processing, feb 1995, pp. 86-92</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maly, R., Schaefer, V., Hass, H., Cahill, G. et al., “Optimum Diesel Fuel for Future Clean Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0035, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0035.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Crepeau, G., Gaillard, P., van der Merwe, D., and Schaberg, P., “Engine Impacts and Opportunities of Various Fuels, Including GTL and FAME: Toward Specific Engine Calibration?,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1787, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1787.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GERINI, A, MONTAGNE, X - Institut Français du Pétrole - « Analyse de la sensibilité aux paramètres gazoles d'un moteur diesel automobile à injection directe »- Article 706, Revue Ingénieurs de l'Automobile</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nishiumi, R., Yasuda, A., Tsukasaki, Y., and Tanaka, T., “Effects of Cetane Number and Distillation Characteristics of Paraffinic Diesel Fuels on PM Emission from a DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2960, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2960.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawano, D., Ishii, H., Goto, Y., Noda, A. et al., “Optimization of Engine System for Application of Biodiesel Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-2028, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-2028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montgomery, D.C., Peck, E.A., “Linear Regression Analysis”, John Wiley, 1984</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown, C.W., et al. “Matrix Representations and Criteria for Selecting Analytical Wavelengths for Multicomponent Spectroscopic Analysis”, Anal. Chem., 54(9), 1472-1479, 1982</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marteens, H., Naes, T., “Mulivariate Calibration”, John Wiley, 1989</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
