<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26169183</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Novel Indirect Health Indicator Extraction Based on Charging Data for Lithium-Ion Batteries Remaining Useful Life Prognostics</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Gao</surname>
                  <given-names>Dong</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Huang</surname>
                  <given-names>MiaoHua</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Xie</surname>
                  <given-names>Jiangang</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Wuhan University of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>July 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>6</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26169161</issue-id>
         <fpage>183</fpage>
         <lpage>193</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169183"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In order to solve the environmental pollution and energy crisis, Electric Vehicles (EVs) have been developed rapidly. Lithium-ion (Li-ion) battery is the key power supply equipment for EVs, and the scientific and accurate prediction of its Remaining Useful Life (RUL) has become a hot topic in the field of new energy research. The internal resistance and capacity are often used to characterize the Li-ion battery State of Health (SOH) from which RUL is obtained. However, in practical applications, it is difficult to obtain internal resistance and capacity information by using the non-intrusive measurement method. Therefore, it is necessary to extract the measurable parameters to characterize the degradation of Li-ion battery. At present, the methods of extracting health indicators based on measurable parameters have gained preliminary results, but most of them are derived from the Li-ion battery discharging data.</p>
            <p>In this paper, a novel indirect Health Indicator (HI) is extracted from the charging data to quantify Li-ion battery fading. In particular, the Box-Cox transformation is adopted to improve the correlation between the extracted HI and the capacity, which is then quantified by the Pearson and Spearman correlation analysis. Furthermore, Extreme Learning Machine (ELM) is proposed to predict the Li-ion battery RUL based on the novel HI. The forecast results validate the effectiveness and efficiency of our presented method in Li-ion battery RUL prognostic and degradation modeling.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He W., Williard N., Osterman M., and Pecht M., “Prognostics of lithiumion batteries based on Dempster-Shafer theory and the Bayesian Monte Carlo method,” J. Power Sources, vol. 196, no. 23, pp. 10314-10321,Dec. 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saha B., Goebel K., Poll S., and Christophersen J., “Prognostics methods for battery health monitoring using a Bayesian framework,” IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas., vol. 58, no. 2, pp. 291-296, Feb. 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang Q, White R E. Capacity fade analysis of a lithium ion cell[J]. Journal of Power Sources, 2008, 179(2): 793-798.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Virkar A V. A model for degradation of electrochemical devices based on linear non-equilibrium thermodynamics and its application to lithium ion batteries[J]. Journal of Power Sources, 2011, 196(14): 5970-5984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee J L, Chemistruck A, Plett G L. One-dimensional physics-based reduced-order model of lithium-ion dynamics[J]. Journal of Power Sources, 2012, 220: 430-448.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miao Q, Xie L, Cui H, et al. Remaining useful life prediction of lithiumion battery with unscented particle filter technique[J]. Microelectronics Reliability, 2013, 53: 805-810.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xing Y, Ma E W M, Tsui K L, et al. An ensemble model for predicting the remaining useful performance of lithium-ion batteries[J]. Microelectronics Reliability, 2013, 53: 811-820.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Long B, Xian W, Jiang L, et al. An improved autoregressive model by particle swarm optimization for prognostics of lithium-ion batteries[J]. Microelectronics Reliability, 2013, 53(6): 821-831.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu J., Saxena A, Goebel K. An adaptive recurrent neural network for remaining useful life prediction of lithium-ion batteries[C]. Annual conference of the Prognostics and Health Management Society, 2010: 1-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rezvani, M., AbuAli M., PhD, Lee, S., Lee, J. et al., "A Comparative Analysis of Techniques for Electric Vehicle Battery Prognostics and Health Management (PHM)," SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-2247, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-2247.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andre D, Nuhic A, Soczka-Guth T, et al. Comparative study of a structured neural network and an extended Kalman filter for state of health determination of lithium-ion batteries in hybrid electric vehicles[J]. Engineering Applications of Artificial Intelligence, 2013, 26(3): 951-961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patil M A, Tagade P, Hariharan K S, et al. A novel multistage Support Vector Machine based approach for Li ion battery remaining useful life estimation[J]. Applied Energy, 2015, 159: 285-297.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klass V, Behm M, Lindbergh G. A support vector machine-based stateof- health estimation method for lithium-ion batteries under electric vehicle operation[J]. Journal of Power Sources, 2014, 270: 262-272.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weng C, Cui Y, Sun J, et al. On-board state of health monitoring of lithium-ion batteries using incremental capacity analysis with support vector regression[J]. Journal of Power Sources, 2013, 235: 36-44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu D, Pang J, Zhou J, et al. Prognostics for state of health estimation of lithium-ion batteries based on combination Gaussian process functional regression[J]. Microelectronics Reliability, 2013, 53(6): 832-839.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, Z., Huang, M., Chen, Y., and Zhu, S., "Prediction of Lithium-ion Battery's Remaining Useful Life Based on Relevance Vector Machine," SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 5(1):30-40, 2016, doi:10.4271/2015-01-9147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li H, Pan D, Chen C L P. Intelligent prognostics for battery health monitoring using the mean entropy and relevance vector machine[J]. IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics: Systems, 2014, 44(7): 851-862.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhou Y, Huang M. Lithium-ion batteries remaining useful life prediction based on a mixture of empirical mode decomposition and ARIMA model[J]. Microelectronics Reliability, 2016, 65: 265-273.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng X, Fang H. An integrated unscented kalman filter and relevance vector regression approach for lithium-ion battery remaining useful life and short-term capacity prediction[J]. Reliability Engineering &amp; System Safety, 2015, 144: 74-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dong H, Jin X, Lou Y, et al. Lithium-ion battery state of health monitoring and remaining useful life prediction based on support vector regressionparticle filter[J]. Journal of Power Sources, 2014, 271: 114-123.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jiang Y, Liu Z, Luo H, et al. ELM indirect prediction method for the remaining life of lithium-ion battery[J]. Journal of Electronic Measurement &amp; Instrumentation, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xia M, Zhang Y C, Weng L G, et al. Fashion retailing forecasting based on extreme learning machine with adaptive metrics of inputs[J]. Knowledge-Based Systems, 2012, 36: 253-259.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang D, Miao Q, Pecht M. Prognostics of lithium-ion batteries based on relevance vectors and a conditional three-parameter capacity degradation model[J]. Journal of Power Sources, 2013, 239: 253-264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goebel K, Saha B, Saxena A, et al. Prognostics in battery health management[J]. IEEE instrumentation &amp; measurement magazine, 2008, 11(4): 33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liao L, Köttig F. Review of hybrid prognostics approaches for remaining useful life prediction of engineered systems, and an application to battery life prediction[J]. IEEE Transactions on Reliability, 2014, 63(1): 191-207.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Widodo A, Shim M C, Caesarendra W, et al. Intelligent prognostics for battery health monitoring based on sample entropy[J]. Expert Systems with Applications, 2011, 38(9): 11763-11769.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu D, Wang H, Peng Y, et al. Satellite Lithium-Ion Battery Remaining Cycle Life Prediction with Novel Indirect Health Indicator Extraction[J]. Energies, 2013, 6(8): 3654-3668.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhou Y, Huang M, Chen Y, et al. A novel health indicator for on-line lithium-ion batteries remaining useful life prediction[J]. Journal of Power Sources, 2016, 321: 1-10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang L, Zhao L, Su X, et al. A lithium-ion battery RUL prognosis method using temperature changing rate[C]//Prognostics and Health Management (ICPHM), 2016 IEEE International Conference on. IEEE, 2016: 1-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang G B, Zhu Q Y, Siew C K. Extreme learning machine: a new learning scheme of feedforward neural networks[C]//Neural Networks, 2004. Proceedings. 2004 IEEE International Joint Conference on. IEEE, 2004, 2: 985-990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang G B, Zhu Q Y, Siew C K. Extreme learning machine: theory and applications[J]. Neurocomputing, 2006, 70(1): 489-501.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang G B, Zhou H, Ding X, et al. Extreme learning machine for regression and multiclass classification[J]. IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics, Part B (Cybernetics), 2012, 42(2): 513-529.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Box G E P, Cox D R. An analysis of transformations[J]. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society. Series B (Methodological), 1964: 211-252.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sakia R M. The Box-Cox transformation technique: a review[J]. The statistician, 1992: 169-178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saha B, Goebel K, Poll S, et al. Prognostics methods for battery health monitoring using a Bayesian framework[J]. IEEE Transactions on Instrumentation and Measurement, 2009, 58(2): 291-296.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhou J, Liu D, Peng Y, et al. An optimized Relevance Vector Machine with incremental learning strategy for lithium-ion battery remaining useful life estimation[C]//Instrumentation and Measurement Technology Conference. IEEE, 2013:561-565.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu D, Xie W, Liao H, et al. An Integrated Probabilistic Approach to Lithium-Ion Battery Remaining Useful Life Estimation[J]. IEEE Transactions on Instrumentation &amp; Measurement, 2015, 64(3):660-670.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
