<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278014</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of Emission Control Systems to Enable High NOₓ Conversion on Heavy Duty Diesel Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Naseri</surname>
                  <given-names>Mojghan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Aydin</surname>
                  <given-names>Ceren</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mulla</surname>
                  <given-names>Shadab</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Conway</surname>
                  <given-names>Raymond</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chatterjee</surname>
                  <given-names>Sougato</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Johnson Matthey Inc.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>June 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277995</issue-id>
         <fpage>1144</fpage>
         <lpage>1151</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278014"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Selective Catalytic Reduction (SCR) systems have been demonstrated as effective solutions for controlling NOₓ emissions from Heavy Duty diesel engines. Future HD diesel engines are being designed for higher engine out NOₓ to improve fuel economy, while discussions are in progress for tightening NOₓ emissions from HD engines post 2020. This will require increasingly higher NOₓ conversions across the emission control system and will challenge the current aftertreatment designs. Typical 2010/2013 Heavy Duty systems include a diesel oxidation catalyst (DOC) along with a catalyzed diesel particulate filter (CDPF) in addition to the SCR sub-assembly. For future aftertreatment designs, advanced technologies such as cold start concept (dCSC™) catalyst, SCR coated on filter (SCRF® hereafter referred to as SCR-DPF) and SCR coated on high porous flow through substrates can be utilized to achieve high NOₓ conversions, in combination with improved control strategies.</p>
            <p>The objective of this work is to evaluate different advanced emission control system options in order to meet future high NOₓ conversions.</p>
            <p>First, high performance NOₓ control system architecture was designed by using a combination of dCSC catalyst, SCR-DPF filter system and high performance SCR on high porosity substrates. In this architecture, dCSC technology stores NOₓ during cold start when system is cold for any SCR reaction and then releases when the system warms up to allow NOₓ reduction across the SCR-DPF filter. The SCR-DPF filter enables lower temperature NOₓ conversion due to its location closer to the turbo and improved SCR coating. Finally the advance SCR on high porosity substrate provides additional NOₓ reduction to achieve overall very high NOₓ control.</p>
            <p>Second, the impact of different parameters on the system performance was studied. This included, changes in engine out NOₓ concentration, early availability of ammonia, different dosing strategies and rapid catalyst warm up during cold start.</p>
            <p>Tests were carried out on a HD engine under transient test cycles. The results indicated that NOₓ conversion can be significantly improved using the proposed design in combination with early availability of ammonia in the system. In addition, implementation of thermal management improved the NOₓ conversion at lower temperature. The results of this work demonstrated that such systems along with improvement in control strategies can provide &gt;95% NOₓ conversion under cold FTP transient cycle and will allow diesel engines to meet future emission regulations and fuel economy.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H., Mulla, S., Weigert, E., Camm, K. et al., “Cold Start Concept (CSC™): A Novel Catalyst for Cold Start Emission Control,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(2):372-381, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0535.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, J., Paratore, M., and Brown, D., “Evaluation of Cu-Based SCR/DPF Technology for Diesel Exhaust Emission Control,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):96-101, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0072.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang, R., Chen, H.Y., Fedeyko, J.M., Andersen, P.J. Thermal Durability and Deactivation of Cu-zeolite SCR Catalyst. 20th North American Catalysis Society Meeting, June 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naseri, M., Chatterjee, S., Castagnola, M., Chen, H. et al., “Development of SCR on Diesel Particulate Filter System for Heavy Duty Applications,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1798-1809, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawakami, A., Mizutani, T., Shibagaki, Y., Yuuki, K. et al., “High Porosity DPF Design for Integrated SCR Functions,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0843, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pless, J., Naseri, M., Klink, W., Spreitzer, G. et al., “Development of SCR on High Porosity Substrates for Heavy Duty and Off- Road Applications,” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 7(1):177-185, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1521.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Umehara, K., Yamada, T., Hijikata, T., Ichikawa, Y. et al., “Effective Catalyst layout for ultra thin-wall and high cell-density ceramic substrate,” SAE Technical Paper 973118, 1997, doi:10.4271/973118.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hirose, S., Yamamoto, H., Suenobu, H., Sakamoto, H. et al., “Development of High Porosity Cordierite Honeycomb Substrate for SCR Application to Realize High NOx Conversion Efficiency and System Compactness,” SAE Int. J. Mater. Manf. 7(3):682-687, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1528.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naseri, M., Conway, R., Hess, H., Aydin, C. et al., “Development of Emission Control Systems to Enable High NOx Conversion on Heavy Duty Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1525, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1525.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
