<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285029</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>IIoT-Enabled Production System for Composite Intensive Vehicle Manufacturing</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Yerra</surname>
                  <given-names>Veera Aditya</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>CU-ICAR Clemson University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Pilla</surname>
                  <given-names>Srikanth</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Clemson University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285020</issue-id>
         <fpage>209</fpage>
         <lpage>214</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285029"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The advancements in automation, big data computing and high bandwidth networking has expedited the realization of Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT). IIoT has made inroads into many sectors including automotive, semiconductors, electronics, etc. Particularly, it has created numerous opportunities in the automotive manufacturing sector to realize the new aura of platform concepts such as smart material flow control. This paper provides a thought provoking application of IIoT in automotive composites body shop. By creating a digital twin for every physical part, we no longer need to adhere to the conventional manufacturing processes and layouts, thus opening up new opportunities in terms of equipment and space utilization. The century-old philosophy of the assembly line might not be the best layout for vehicle manufacturing, thus proposing a novel assembly grid layout inspired from a colony of ants working to accomplish a common goal. Value added time per part are compared between the traditional and proposed manufacturing process layout using virtual plant simulation tools. This value added time is directly proportional to operating and capital cost. Moreover, the study proposes real-time multilayer communication that has the potential to vastly improves tasks such as inventory management, proactive/preventive maintenance, inline quality control, flexibility to part variabilities and design development.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Transportation O., “Corporate Average Fuel Economy for MY 2017-MY 2025 Passenger Cars and Light Trucks,” no. August, pp. 1-1178, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“BMW i3 Teardown and Benchmarking Study”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cole G. S. and Sherman a. M., “Light weight materials for automotive applications,” Mater. Charact., vol. 35, no. 1, pp. 3-;9, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boysen N., Fliedner M., and Scholl A., “Assembly line balancing: Which model to use when?,” Int. J. Prod. Econ., vol. 111, no. 2, pp. 509- 528, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qu T., Lei S. P., Wang Z. Z., Nie D. X., Chen X., and Huang G. Q., “IoTbased real-time production logistics synchronization system under smart cloud manufacturing,” Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol., vol. 84, no. 1-4, pp. 147-164, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Michalos G., Makris S., Papakostas N., Mourtzis D., and Chryssolouris G., “Automotive assembly technologies review: challenges and outlook for a flexible and adaptive approach,” CIRP J. Manuf. Sci. Technol., vol. 2, no. 2, pp. 81-91, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
