<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939537</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Taxation with Non-Standard Utility Functions</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Will a Refund of an Advance Tax Payment Promote Tax Compliance?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>yong</surname>
                  <given-names>Fan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>haonan</surname>
                  <given-names>Li</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>xiaoyu</surname>
                  <given-names>Xi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939537"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The expected utility theory and the prospect theory are the two basic theories used to analyze tax compliance decisions, indicating that the taxpayers are more concerned about the expected value, or more concerned with the change value relative to the reference point, respectively. However, these two basic theories have different views on the advance tax payment which is widely applied in the design of tax system. The prospect theory proposes that the prepaid tax refund promotes tax compliance. This conclusion has been supported by a large number of studies based on experimental data, but a few questions are not taken seriously. Recent studies of expected utility theory have, however, found that the direction of this effect is uncertain. This paper uses real evidence to reexamine the effect of prepaid tax refund on tax compliance. Compared with previous indirect and experimental studies, this paper uses a more convincing 2013 data set from China’s <italic>National Tax Survey</italic>, which includes key direct data such as enterprise audit tax and preliminary tax, and uses instrumental variables to eliminate endogeneity. This research shows that: (1) The tax refund will reduce the tax compliance, which is different from the earlier conclusion: The advance tax payment will promote tax compliance under the prospect theory, and only under the expected utility theory this result may appear, so the taxpayer pays more attention to the expected value under this evidence; (2) When extending the tax refund range of the sample, the effect of reduction on tax compliance was reduced. This evidence indirectly indicates that the size of the tax refund may affect the taxpayers' attention pertaining to the expected value or the change value relative to the reference point; (3) A preliminary tax system should be as accurate as possible in estimating the income, reducing the deviation between prepaid and actual tax, which can improve the enterprise tax compliance. This paper provides important counterexamples and opportunities to reflect on the theory of tax compliance.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>Reference</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Acemoglu, D., Johnson, S., Robinson, J. &amp; Thaicharoen, Y. (2003). Institutional causes, macroeconomic symptoms: volatility, crises and growth. Journal of Monetary Economics, 50(1), 49-123.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Adams, C. &amp; Webley, P. (2001). Small business owners' attitudes on VAT compliance in the UK. Journal of Economic Psychology, 22(2), 195-216.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Allingham, M. G. &amp; Sandmo, A. (1972). Income tax evasion: a theoretical analysis. Journal of Public Economics, 1(3-4), 323-338.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Alm, J., McClelland, G. H. &amp; Schulze, W. D. (1992). Why do people pay taxes?. Journal of Public Economics, 48(1), 21-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Benford, F. (1938). The Law of Anomalous Numbers. Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, 78(4), 551-572.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Christian, C. W. &amp; Gupta, S. (1993). New Evidence on 'Secondary Evasion'. Journal of the American Taxation Association, 15(1), 72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Copeland, P. V. &amp; Cuccia, A. D. (2002). Multiple Determinants of Framing Referents in Tax Reporting and Compliance. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes, 88(1), 499-526.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Cullis, J., Jones, P. &amp; Lewis, A. (2006). Tax framing, Instrumentality and individual differences: Are there two different cultures?. Journal of Economic Psychology, 27(2), 304-320.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Kahneman, D. &amp; Tversky, A. (1979). Prospect Theory: An Analysis of Decision under Risk. Econometrica, 47(2), 263-291.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Dhami, S. &amp; al-Nowaihi, A. (2007). Why do people pay taxes? Prospect theory versus expected utility theory. Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization, 64(1), 171-192.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Miguel, E., Satyanath, S. &amp; Sergenti, E. (2004). Economic Shocks and Civil Conflict: An Instrumental Variables Approach. Journal of Political Economy, 112(4), 725-753.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Elffers, H. &amp; Hessing, D. J. (1997). Influencing the prospects of tax evasion. Journal of Economic Psychology, 18(2-3), 289-304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Saez, E. (2010). Do Taxpayers Bunch at Kink Points?. American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 2(3), 180-212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Fan, Z. &amp; Tian, B. (2016). Collusion foe Evasion: Evidence from Rotation of NTB’s Directors in China. Quarterly Journal of Economics, 15(04), 1303-1328.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Alm, J., Martinez-Vazquez, J. &amp; McClellan, C. (2016). Corruption and Firm Tax Evasion. Working Papers 1624, Tulane University, Department of Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Andreoni, J., Erard, B. &amp; Feinstein, J. (1998). Tax Compliance Journal of Economic Literature, 36(2), 818-860.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Morita, K. (2014). Advance Tax Payment And Tax Evasion: Expected Utility Analysis. The Singapore Economic Review (SER), 59(02), 1-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Kirchler, E. &amp; Maciejovsky, B. (2001). Tax compliance within the context of gain and loss situations, expected and current asset position, and profession. Journal of Economic Psychology, 22(2), 173-194.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Pin, K. and Chu, C. Y. C. (2005). Internal Control versus External Manipulation: A Model of Corporate Income Tax Evasion. RAND Journal of Economics, 36(1), 151-164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Lu, Y., He Q. &amp; Xue C. (2016). Impact of Law Enforcement on Financial Development across Chinese Regions. Economic Study, 51(07), 118-131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Bernasconi, M. &amp; Zanardi, A. (2004). Tax Evasion, Tax Rates, and Reference Dependence. FinanzArchiv: Public Finance Analysis, 60(3), 422-422.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Nigrini, M. J. (1996). A Taxpayer Compliance Application of Benford's Law. Journal Of The American Taxation Association, 18(1), 72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Nigrini, M. J. (2017). Audit Sampling Using Benford's Law: A Review of the Literature with Some New Perspectives. Journal Of Emerging Technologies In Accounting, 14(2), 29-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Engström, P., Nordblom, K., Ohlsson, H. &amp; Persson, A. (2015). Tax Compliance and Loss Aversion. American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 7(4), 132-164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Bayer, R. &amp; Kupzowa, J. (2006). Corporate Tax Evasion and Extortionist Governments. School of Economics Working Papers 2006-08, University of Adelaide, School of Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Robben, H. S. J., Webley, P., Elffers, H. &amp; Hessing, D. J. (1990). Decision frames, opportunity and tax evasion : An experimental approach. Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization, 14(3), 353-361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Schmidt, D. R. (2001). The prospects of taxpayer agreement with aggressive tax advice. Journal of Economic Psychology, 22(2), 157-172.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">King, S. &amp; Sheffrin, S. (2002). Tax Evasion and Equity Theory: An Investigative Approach. International Tax and Public Finance, 9(4), 505-521.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Slemrod, J. &amp; Yitzhaki, S. (2002). Tax avoidance, evasion, and administration. Handbook of Public Economics. 22(3), 1423-1470.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Tang J. (2014). Combining the Characteristics of Small and Micro Enterprises and Improving the Preferential Tax Policy of Small and Micro Enterprises. Financial Study, 9, 24-27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Webley, P., Robben, H., Elffers, H., and Hessing, D. J. (1991). Tax evasion: an experimental approach. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Yaniv, G. (1999). Tax Compliance and Advance Tax Payments: A Prospect Theory Analysis. National Tax Journal, 52(4), 753-764</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>The taxable income distribution in 2013 for small and micro enterprise samples from 2012</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Summary Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Changes in Actual Tax Rates Resulting from Changes in the Status of Preferential Policies for Small and Micro Enterprises - Changes in Taxable Income</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig.2</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>The state changes involved in the selected instrumental variables</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>First-stage regression results for instrumental variables</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Regression of Tax Compliance and Instrumental Variables</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Tax Compliance and Operating Conditions</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig.3</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Distribution of Taxable Income of Enterprises in 2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig.4</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Distribution of taxable income between 0 and 1 million CNY in 2013 in enterprises</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>"Benford" test of "Artificial Trend" in Enterprises</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Tax Compliance and Actual Tax Rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>The Effect of Tax Refund on Tax Compliance</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>The Regression Outputs of Expansion of Tax Refund</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>The Regression Output of the Robustness Test</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
