<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">natitaxjour</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50005631</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>National Tax Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00280283</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19447477</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26349702</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE MOST UNKINDEST CUT OF ALL? STATE SPENDING ON HEALTH, EDUCATION, AND WELFARE DURING RECESSIONS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Richard T.</given-names>
                  <surname>Boylan</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Vivian</given-names>
                  <surname>Ho</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">70</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i26349696</issue-id>
         <fpage>329</fpage>
         <lpage>366</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2017 National Tax Association-Tax Institute of America</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26349702"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The dramatic deterioration in state finances during the Great Recession raised concerns regarding government's ability to support community health and education. Because recessions differentially affect states with different tax structures, we could examine the effect of changes in state revenues on expenditures while controlling for demand-side factors that influence program utilization. We find that state revenue declines lead to short and long terms cuts in children's Medicaid benefits, and declines in elderly Medicaid enrollment. Larger cuts (nominal and proportional) in education spending versus Medicaid occurred. We suggest institutional, political, and economic constraints that may determine program cuts.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1122e185a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e192" publication-type="other">
National Association of State Budget Officers, 2007 State Expenditures Report, Washington, DC, 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e199a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e206" publication-type="other">
See http://www.gao.gov/products/GAO-12-713T and http://www.acf.hhs.gov/programs/ofa/policy/
pi-ofa/1997/pi9709.htm, accessed May 14,2012.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e216a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e223" publication-type="other">
Other papers have examined which expenditures programs are affected by the business cycle (for instance,
Hines Jr., Hoynes, and Krueger, 2001; Hercowitz and Strawczynski, 2004; Kane, Orszag, and Apostolov,
2005). However, we expect the business cycle to affect both revenues and the demand for government
services. Thus, without a measure of revenue swings it is difficult to attribute changes in expenditures
to revenue shortfalls versus changes in the demand for government services. In our paper we examine a
much larger portion of state budgets (general revenues versus just general fund revenues) over a much
longer time interval ( 1989-2012). 4"Not only is it difficult in some states to determine the constitutional or
statutory authority (for the balanced budget requirements), but often it is also unclear what the enforcement
mechanism is" (National Conference of State Legislatures, 2010, p. 10).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e255a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e262" publication-type="other">
"Not only is it difficult in some states to determine the constitutional or statutory authority (for the bal-
anced budget requirements), but often it is also unclear what the enforcement mechanism is" (National
Conference of State Legislatures, 2010, p. 10).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e276a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e283" publication-type="other">
The laws increased marginal rates by 1/4 percent, reduced the dependent exemption credit, but provided
for a new homebuyer tax credit.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e293a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e300" publication-type="other">
Bruce, Fox, and Tuttle (2006) show that the income elasticity of a tax depends on many characteristics
that are not easily summarized with a few variables. Further in some states the sales tax is more volatile
than the income tax, while in others the opposite is true.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e313a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e320" publication-type="other">
Data on state Medicaid expenditures account for adjustments to Federal Medical Assistance Percent-
age (FMAP) rates as part of the 2009 American Recovery and Reinvestment Act (see www.ffis.
org/452501/455501.html).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e333a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e340" publication-type="other">
"General revenues" should not be confused with "general fund revenues" which are substantially lower
than general revenues, since they do not include earmarked funds, such as lottery revenue designated for
school spending. Further, balanced budget requirements usually impose restrictions on only general fund
revenues and expenditures. In an alternate specification that examines the robustness of our results, we
estimate Equation (1) using fixed effects instead of first differences and obtain similar results. For this case,
we specify balances in levels, as drawn from the National Association of State Budget Officers, Fiscal
Survey of States.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e366a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e373" publication-type="other">
State expenditures on buildings for schools are included in the "Capital, interest &amp; transportation" com-
ponent of general expenditures, and not under "Education."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e383a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e390" publication-type="other">
This category includes outpatient health services, other than hospital care, treatment and immunization
clinics, mosquito abatement, and so on.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e401a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e408" publication-type="other">
Although AFDC/TANF is a federal program, states finance a significant fraction of the program (e.g., 32
percent in 2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e418a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e425" publication-type="other">
: The individual controls are sex, race, Hispanic origin, age, living in a metropolitan area, family size, the log
of family income, whether the household owns or rents, whether a family member in unemployed, highest
level of education of a family member, income as a share of the federal poverty level, and the interaction
of whether the family earns less than 133 percent of the poverty level, and the individual is less than six
years old.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e444a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e451" publication-type="other">
We follow Corcoran et al. (2004) in assuming that increases in spending occur within one to five years
after the court decision. Thus, the variable "School finance court order" is equal to one in years 1 through
5 after a state court order.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e464a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e471" publication-type="other">
State fixed effects are accounted for by estimating the model in first differences, while state trends are
accounted for by estimating the model in second differences.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e481a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e488" publication-type="other">
Unfortunately, we do not have a measure of revenue swings for local governments. We focus on programs
where states contribute the bulk of spending. States share education spending with the federal government
and local entities. For this category, we report the effects of revenue swings on both state and overall
spending.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e504a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e511" publication-type="other">
U.S. Census Division, Data Base on Historical Finances of State and Local Governments: "Government
Finances," August 2010. However, state revenues include intergovernmental grants received from the
federal government and local governments, while state expenditures include intergovernmental grants
awarded by the state to the federal government and local governments. In 2008, 24 percent of state ex-
penditures consisted of intergovernmental grants, while intergovernmental grants comprised 27 percent
of state revenues.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e535a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e542" publication-type="other">
Other expenditures include environmental expenditures, lump sum contributions for employee fringe
benefits, economic development, and government-wide insurance policies.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e552a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e559" publication-type="other">
Revenue swings that exceed three times their standard deviation are omitted from the graph (North Dakota
2011-2012, Vermont 1999, Wyoming 2006-2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e569a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e576" publication-type="other">
Specifically, the standard deviation of the change in personal income is $917, the mean value of personal
income per capita is $30,051, and 3.1 percent = 917/30,051.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e586a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e593" publication-type="other">
We may be concerned that the relation between the changes in balances and welfare expenditures would
change with the enactment of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act.
However, we obtain qualitatively the same results when we examine the years before and after 1997.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e606a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e613" publication-type="other">
TANF was designated as a block grant program in 1996, and states are required to spend an amount equal
to at least 75 percent of the amount contributed by the federal government. The amount contributed by
the federal government has not changed since 1996. In 2010, 14 states were within $10 million of their
"maintenance of effort" minimum.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e629a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e636" publication-type="other">
See http://www.kaiserfamilyfoundation.files.wordpress.com/2013/0 l/medicaid-an-overview-of-spending-
on.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e647a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e654" publication-type="other">
The ARRAtemporarily increased FMAP rates for state Medicaid programs, while requiring states to main-
tain eligibility requirements. However, states could cut optional services (e.g., dental services, physical
therapy, prosthetic devices), and some elderly could have chosen not to enroll in Medicaid when these
services were cut from the program.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e670a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e677" publication-type="other">
We divide by 1,000 since the regression are in $1,000.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e684a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e691" publication-type="other">
The coefficient estimates for all the control variables are available from the authors upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e698a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e705" publication-type="other">
Tables for these results are available from the authors upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e712a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e719" publication-type="other">
For this case, we specify balances as the sum of balances and rainy day funds (in levels), as drawn from
the National Association of State Budget Officers, Fiscal Survey of the States.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e729a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e736" publication-type="other">
Again, for brevity, these results are not included in the tables, but are available from the authors upon
request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1122e747a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1122e754" publication-type="other">
That is, changes in revenues net of enacted changes in taxes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d1122e770a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e774" publication-type="other">
Alt, James Ε., and Robert C. Lowry, 1994. "Divided Government, Fiscal Institutions, and Budget
Deficits: Evidence from the States." American Political Science Review 88 (4), 811-828.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e784a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e788" publication-type="other">
Baicker, Katherine, 2001. "Government Decision-Making and the Incidence of Federal Mandates."
Journal of Public Economics 82 (2), 147-194.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e798a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e802" publication-type="other">
Baicker, Katherine, and Nora Gordon, 2006. "The Effect of State Education Finance Reform on
Total Local Resources." Journal of Public Economics 90 (8-9), 1519-1535.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e812a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e816" publication-type="other">
Barro, Robert J., 1979. "On the Determination of the Public Debt "Journal of Political Economy
87 (5), 940-971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e827a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e831" publication-type="other">
Besley, Timothy, Torsten Persson, and Daneil M. Sturm, 2010. "Political Competition, Policy
and Growth: Theory and Evidence from the United States." Review of Economic Studies 77 (4),
1329-1352.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e844a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e848" publication-type="other">
Boylan, Richard T., and Naci Mocan, 2014. "Intended and Unintended Consequences of Prison
Reform." Journal of Law, Economics, &amp; Organization 30 (3), 558-586.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e858a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e862" publication-type="other">
Bruce, Donald, William F. Fox, and M. H. Tuttle, 2006. "Tax Base Elasticities: A Multi-State
Analysis of Long-Run and Short-Run Dynamics." Southern Economic Journal 73 (2), 315-341.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e872a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e876" publication-type="other">
Buchanan, James M., and Richard E. Wagner, 1978. "Fiscal Responsibility in Constitutional
Democracy." Studies in Public Choice 1, 79-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e886a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e890" publication-type="other">
Card, David, and A. Abigail Payne, 2002. "School Finance Reform, the Distribution of School
Spending, and the Distribution of Student Test Scores." Journal of Public Economics 83 ( 1), 49-
82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e903a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e907" publication-type="other">
Case, Anne, Angela Fertig, and Christina Paxson, 2005. "The Lasting Impact of Childhood Health
and Circumstance." Journal of Health Economics 24 (2), 365-389.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e918a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e922" publication-type="other">
Clark, Kim, 2010. "The Great Recession's Toll on Higher Education." U.S. News &amp; World Report,
September 10, https://www.usnews.eom/education/articles/2010/09/10/the-great-recessions-toll-
on-higher-education.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e935a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e939" publication-type="other">
Corcoran, Sean, William Evans, Jennifer Godwin, Sheila Murray, and Robert Schwab, 2004.
"The Changing Distribution of Education Finance, 1972 to 1997." In Neckerman, Kathryn M.
(ed.), Social Inequality, 433-466. The Russell Sage Foundation, New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e952a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e956" publication-type="other">
Coughlin, Teresa Α., and Stephen Zuckerman, 2005. "Three Years of State Fiscal Struggles: How
Did Medicaid and SCHIP Fare? Web Exclusive" Health Affairs, W385-W398.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e966a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e970" publication-type="other">
Courtot, Brigette, Teresa A. Coughlin, and Emily Lawton, 2012. Medicaid and CHIP Managed
Care Payment Methods and Spending in 20 States. Final Report to the Office of the Assistant,
Seretary for Planning and Evaluation, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. Urban
Institute, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e986a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e990" publication-type="other">
Currie, Janet M., 2009. "Healthy, Wealthy, and Wise: Socioeconomic Status, Poor Health in
Childhood, and Human Capital Development." Journal of Economic Literature 47 (1), 87-122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1000a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1004" publication-type="other">
Currie, Janet M., Jonathan Gruber, and Michael Fischer, 1995. "Physician Payments and Infant
Mortality: Evidence from Medicaid Fee Policy." American Economic Review 85 (2), 106-111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1015a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1019" publication-type="other">
Gamkhar, Shama, 2000. "Is the Response of State and Local Highway Spending Symmetric
to Increases and Decreases in Federal Highway Grants9" Public Finance Review 28 (1), 3-25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1029a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1033" publication-type="other">
Gavin, Michael, and Roberto Perotti, 1997. "Fiscal Policy in Latm America." NBER Macroeco-
nomics Annual 12, 11-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1043a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1047" publication-type="other">
Gray, Bradley, 2001. "Do Medicaid Physician Fees for Prenatal Services Affect Birth Outcomes?"
Journal of Health Economics 20 (4), 571-590.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1057a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1061" publication-type="other">
Hercowitz, Zvi, and Michel Strawczynski, 2004. "Cyclical Ratcheting in Government Spending:
Evidence from the OECD." Review of Economics and Statistics 86 (1), 353-361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1071a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1075" publication-type="other">
Hines Jr., James R., Hilary Hoynes, and Alan B. Krueger, 2001. "Another Look at Whether a
Rising Tide Lifts All Boats." In Krueger, Alan B., and Robert M. Solow (eds), The Roaring Nine-
ties: Can Full Employment be Sustained?, 493-507. Russell Sage Foundation, New York, NY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1088a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1092" publication-type="other">
Hoynes, Hilary Williamson, 2000. "Local Labor Markets and Welfare Spells: Do Demand Condi-
tions Matter?" Review of Economics and Statistics 82 (3), 351-368.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1103a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1107" publication-type="other">
Hoyt, William H., and Eugenia Froedge Toma, 1993. "Lobbying Expenditures and Government
Output: The ΝΕΑ and Public Education." Southern Economic Journal 60 (2), 405-417.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1117a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1121" publication-type="other">
Jackson, C. Kirabo, Rucker Johnson, and Claudia Persico, 2014. "The Effect of School Finance
Reforms on the Distribution of Spending, Academic Achievement, and Adult Outcomes." NBER
Working Paper No. 20118, National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1134a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1138" publication-type="other">
Kaiser Family Foundation, 2009. "American Recovery and Reinvestment Act (ARRA): Medicaid
and Health Care Provisions." The Henry J. Kaiser Family Foundation, Menlo Park, CA, http://
kff.org/medicaid/fact-sheet/american-recovery-and-reinvestment-act-arra-medicaid/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1151a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1155" publication-type="other">
Kane, Thomas J., Peter R. Orszag, and Emil Apostolov, 2005. "Higher Education Appropriations
and Public Universities: The Role of Medicaid and the Business Cycle." Brookings- Wharton on
Urban Affairs, 99-146. Brookings Institution Press, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1168a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1172" publication-type="other">
King, Miriam, Steven Ruggles, J. Trent Alexander, Sarah Flood, Katie Genadek, Matthew B.
Schroeder, Brandon Trampe, and Rebecca Vick, 2010. "Integrated Public Use Microdata Series,
Current Population Survey: Version 3.0." [Machine-readable database]. University of Minnesota,
Minneapolis, MN.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1188a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1192" publication-type="other">
Krauss, Clifford, 2009. "Governors Fear Added Costs in Health Care Overhaul " Acw York Times,
Β1, August 6, http://www.nytimes.com/2009/08/07/business/07medicaid.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1203a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1207" publication-type="other">
Landsberg, Mitchell, 2009. "Budget Cuts Push Some Classrooms Way over Capacity." Los Angeles
Times, September 20, http://articles.latimes.com/2009/sep/20/local/me-ed-cuts20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1217a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1221" publication-type="other">
Lucas, Robert E., and Nancy L. Stokey, 1983. "Optimal Fiscal and Monetary Policy in an Economy
without Capital." Journal of Monetary Economics 12 (1), 55-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1231a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1235" publication-type="other">
Lukens, Gideon, 2014. "State Variation in Health Care Spending and the Politics of State Medicaid
Policy." Journal of Health Politics, Policy and Law 39 (6), 1213-1251.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1245a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1249" publication-type="other">
Luttmer, Erzo F. P., 2001. "Group Loyalty and the Taste for Redistribution." Journal of Political
Economy 109 (3), 500-528.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1259a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1263" publication-type="other">
Mattoon, Rick, and Leslie McGranahan, 2008. "Revenue Bubbles and Structural Deficits: What's
a State to Do?" Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago Working Paper No. 2008-15, Federal Reserve
Bank of Chicago, Chicago, IL.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1276a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1280" publication-type="other">
McNichol, Elizabeth, and Kwame Boadi, 2011. "Why and How States Should Strengthen Their
Rainy Day Funds." Center on Budget and Policy Priorities, Washington, DC, http://www.cbpp.
org/research/why-and-how-states-should-strengthen-their-rainy-day-funds.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1294a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1298" publication-type="other">
Murray, Sheila E., William N. Evans, and Robert M. Schwab, 1998. "Education-Finance Reform
and the Distribution of Education Resources." American Economic Review 88 (4), 789-812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1308a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1312" publication-type="other">
National Association of State Budget Officers, 2013. State Budgeting and Lessons Learned
from the Economic Downturn. Analysis and Commentary from State Budget Officers. NASBO,
Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1325a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1329" publication-type="other">
National Conference of State Legislatures, 2010. NCSL Fiscal Brief: State Balanced Budget
Provisions. NCSL, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1339a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1343" publication-type="other">
Pear, Robert, 2011. "Cuts Leave Patients with Medicaid Cards, but No Specialist to See." New
York Times, Al, April 1, http://www.nytimes.com/201 l/04/02/health/policy/02medicaid.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1353a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1357" publication-type="other">
Poterba, James M., 1994. "State Responses to Fiscal Crises: The Effects of Budgetary Institutions
and Politics." Journal of Political Economy 102 (4), 799-821.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1367a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1371" publication-type="other">
Poterba, James M., 1997. "Demographic Structure and the Political Economy of Public Educa-
tion." Journal of Policy Analysis and Management 16 (1), 48-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1382a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1386" publication-type="other">
Pracht, Etienne Ε., and William J. Moore, 2003. "Interest Groups and State Medicaid Drug
Programs." Journal of Health Politics, Policy and Law 28 (1), 9-39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1396a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1400" publication-type="other">
Reed, W. Robert, 2006. "Democrats, Republicans, and Taxes: Evidence That Political Parties
Matter." Journal of Public Economics 90 (4-5), 725-750.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1410a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1414" publication-type="other">
Reschovsky, Andrew, 2004. "The Impact of State Government Fiscal Crises on Local Govern-
ments and Schools." State &amp; Local Government Review 36 (2), 86-102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1424a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1428" publication-type="other">
Rose, Shanna, 2010. "Institutions and Fiscal Sustainability." National Tax Journal 63 (4), 807-
837.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1438a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1442" publication-type="other">
Rudowitz, Robin, and Caryn Marks, 2008. "Medicaid in a Declining Economy: Limited Ap-
proaches for States to Control Spending." Kaiser Commission on Medicaid and the Uninsured,
The Henry J. Kaiser Family Foundation, Menlo Park, CA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1455a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1459" publication-type="other">
Sack, Kevin, 2010. "As Medicaid Payments Shrink, Patients Are Abandoned."New York Times,
Al, March 16, http://www.nytimes.com/2010/03/16/health/policy/16medicaid.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1470a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1474" publication-type="other">
Saez, Emmanuel, Joel B. Slemrod, and Seth H. Giertz, 2012. "The Elasticity of Taxable Income
with Respect to Marginal Tax Rates: A Critical Review." Journal of Economic Literature 50
(1), 3-50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1487a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1491" publication-type="other">
Sen, Bisakha, Justin Blackburn, Michael A. Morrisey, Meredith L. Kilgore, David J. Becker,
Cathy Caldwell, and Nir Menachemi, 2012. "Did Copayment Changes Reduce Health Service
Utilization among CHIP Enrollees? Evidence from Alabama." Health Services Research 47 (4),
1603-1620.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1507a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1511" publication-type="other">
Skinner, Jonathan, 2012. "Causes and Consequences of Regional Variations in Health Care." In
Pauly, Mark V., Thomas G. Mcguire, and Pedro P. Barros (eds.), Handbook of Health Economics,
volume 2, chapter 2,45-93. Elsevier, Waltham, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1524a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1528" publication-type="other">
Sloan, Frank Α., Emily Streyer Carlisle, John R. Rattliff, and Justin Trogdon, 2005. "Determi-
nants of States' Allocations of the Master Settlement Agreement Payments." Journal of Health
Politics, Policy and Law 30 (4), 643-686.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1541a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1545" publication-type="other">
Stine, William F., 1994. "Is Local Government Revenue Response to Federal Aid Symmetrical?
Evidence from Pennsylvania County Governments in an Era of Retrenchment." National Tax
Journal 47 (4), 799-816.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1122e1558a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1122e1562" publication-type="other">
Zerzan, Judy, Tina Edlund, Lisa Krois, and Jeanene Smith, 2007. "The Demise of Oregon's
Medically Needy Program: Effects of Losing Prescription Drug Coverage." Journal of General
Internal Medicine 22 (6), 847-851.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
