<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26562343</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Co-Simulation Study of the Split-Crankshaft Engine’s Electromechanical Clutch Unit</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Karmann</surname>
                  <given-names>Stephan Bernhard</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>LVK TUM</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Rösler</surname>
                  <given-names>Sebastian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>LVK TUM</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Wachtmeister</surname>
                  <given-names>Georg</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>LVK TUM</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Fischer</surname>
                  <given-names>Patrick Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FZG TUM</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Pflaum</surname>
                  <given-names>Hermann</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FZG TUM</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Stahl</surname>
                  <given-names>Karsten</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FZG TUM</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>February 2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>11</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e26562337</issue-id>
         <fpage>79</fpage>
         <lpage>94</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26562343"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The main objective of active downsizing is to increase the power train efficiency. In order to consistently enhance an approach of active downsizing, it is inevitable to disable and additionally to disengage part of the overall engine displacement volume. The disengagement avoids the friction loss of the piston group as well as its crank- and valve-train section. Therefore, this beneficial approach, the Split-Crankshaft Engine (SCE) is currently under development at the Chair of Internal Combustion Engines in cooperation with the Gear Research Centre (FZG), at the Technical University of Munich.</p> 
            <p>The SCE concept consists of two partial internal combustion engines, which are arranged inline. The Primary Engine (PE) is permanently running while the Secondary Engine (SE) can be switched on and off load-dependently during driving operation. Within the switching process, the electromechanically actuated Split-Clutch Unit (SCU) realizes the run-up of the SE as well as the angular synchronization of both partial engines. Hence, the fuel saving potential of the SCE rests upon raising the load points and additionally saving the whole friction losses of the non-fired cylinders. A detailed full vehicle simulation determines the SCE’s fuel saving potential. All fundamental investigations concerning the whole concepts functionality are based on testing rig and simulative studies.</p> 
            <p>This paper gives a precise description of the mechanical structure of the SCU itself and its mode of operation, followed by the detailed modelling specifications of the whole SCU mechanism. The integration of the Simulink® based SCU’s simulation model into the GT-Suite® based full vehicle simulation via co-simulation is shown subsequently. The SCU’s system performance is discussed according to the results of exclusive preliminary investigations within the full vehicle environment using standardized driving cycles.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label> 
            <kwd>Split-Crankshaft Engine (SCE)</kwd> 
            <kwd>Combustion engine with a disengageable crankshaft</kwd> 
            <kwd>Active downsizing</kwd> 
            <kwd>Split-Clutch Unit (SCU)</kwd> 
            <kwd>Electromechanical clutch actuation</kwd> 
            <kwd>Alternative powertrain</kwd> 
            <kwd>Simulation of electromechanical clutch actuation</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heil, B., Weining, H.K., Karl, G., Panten, D., and Wunderlich, K., “Verbrauch und Emissionen - Reduzierungskonzepte beim Ottomotor,” MTZ 62(11):900- 915, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kadunic, S. et al., “Ladeluftkühlung mittels Abgasenergienutzung zur Wirkungsgradsteigerung von Ottomotoren,” MTZ 75(1):80-87, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Golloch, R., Downsizing bei Verbrennungsmotoren: Ein wirkungsvolles Konzept zur Kraftstoffverbrauchssenkung, (Berlin, Heidelberg, Springer-Verlag, 2005).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergmaier, J., Wachtmeister, G., Fischer, P.D., Pflaum, H. et al., Splitmotor: Konzept für einen Verbrennungsmotor mit geteilter, abschaltbarer Kurbelwelle, in 14. Internationales Stuttgarter Symposium: Automobil- und Motorentechnik, Springer Fachmedien Wiesbaden, 2014, 953-970, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ihlemann, A. and Nitz, N., “Cylinder Deactivation,” in Schaeffler, (Ed.), Solving the Powertrain Puzzle, (Wiesbaden, Germany, Springer Fachmedien Wiesbaden GmBH, 2014), 173-187.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Middendorf, H., Theobald, J., Lang, L., and Hartel, K., “Der 1,4- L-TSI-Ottomotor mit Zylinderabschaltung,” in ATZ/MTZ- Fachbuch, (Wiesbaden, Springer Vieweg, 2013), 110-115.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eisazadeh-Far, K. and Younkins, M., “Fuel Economy Gains through Dynamic-Skip-Fire in Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0672, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016- 01-0672.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Philipps, H.L., “Split Engine Clutch,” U.S. Patent 4555003 A, 1985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Kaniut, “Selbstsynchronisierende Kupplung für Split- Umwelt-Motoren mit 360° bzw. 720° Synchronisierungsintervallen,” DE000004036492A1, Deutschland, Mai 21, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fischer, P.D., Pflaum, H., Stahl, K., Bergmaier, J. et al., “Concept of a Clutch Unit for a Split-Crankshaft ICE,” in Eighth International CTI Symposium and Exhibition, Rochester, MI, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rösler, S., Fischer, P.D., Pflaum, H., Wachtmeister, G. et al., “Experimental Implementation of an Internal Combustion Engine with a Disengageable Crankshaft - The Split- Crankshaft Engine,” in FISITA 2016 36th World Automotive Congress, Busan, Korea, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fischer, P.D., Rösler, S., Pflaum, H., Stahl, K. et al., “Design, Simulation Study and Preliminary Experimental Results of the Electromechanical Clutch Unit for the Split-Crankshaft Engine,” in FISITA 2016 36th World Automotive Congress, Busan, Korea, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stahl, K., Höhn, B.-R., Otto, H.-P., Bäumler, R. et al., “Electro Mechanically Actuated Torque Sensing Multidisc Clutch for Automatic Transmissions: Electro Mechanic Powershift Clutch,” in Conference on Future Automotive Technology: Focus Electromobility, Springer Fachmedien Wiesbaden GmBH, Wiesbaden, Germany, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bunge, T. and Hänel, B., "Tragfähigkeit und Geometrie von Plankerbverzahnungen", Abschlussbericht, Forschungsvorhaben Nr. FVA 392/I+II.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haessig, D.A. and Friedland, B., “On the Modeling and Simulation of Friction,” J. Dyn. Sys., Meas., Control 113(3):354, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rao, G., “Modellierung und Simulation des Systemverhaltens nasslaufender Lamellenkupplungen, Dissertation, Technische Universität Dresden, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SKF, http://www.boie.de/ftp/pub/skf/6000_I_DE/6000-I_DE_00_04_Friction.pdf, accessed Apr. 16, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fesefeldt, T.F., “Ganzheitliche Betrachtung zur Auswah der Starteinrichtung des Verbrennungsmotors eines Parallel- Hybrids mit Trennkupplung, Dissertation, Technische Universität Darmstadt, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kramer, U., “Potentialanalyse des Direktstarts für den Einsatz in einem Stopp-Start-System an einem Ottomotor mit strahlgeführter Benzin-Direkteinspritzung unter besonderer Berücksichtigung des Motorauslaufvorgangs, Dissertation, Universität Duisburg, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
