<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816599</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>U.S. Fiscal Policy Past, Present, and Future (Macro and Fiscal Policy)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Fiscal Policy Changes and Aggregate Demand in the U.S. Before, During and Following the Great Recession</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cashin</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lenney</surname>
                  <given-names>Jamie</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lutz</surname>
                  <given-names>Byron</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Peterman</surname>
                  <given-names>William</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816599"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We examine the effect of federal and subnational fiscal policy changes on aggregate demand in the U.S. by introducing the fiscal effect (FE) measure. FE can be decomposed into three components. Discretionary FE quantifies the effect of discretionary or legislated policy changes. Cyclical FE captures the effect of the automatic stabilizers—changes in government taxes and spending arising from the business cycle. Residual FE measures the effect of all changes in government revenues and outlays which cannot be categorized as either discretionary or cyclical; for example, it captures the effect of the secular increase in entitlement program spending due to the aging of the population. We use FE to examine the contribution of fiscal policy changes to growth in real GDP over the course of the Great Recession and current expansion. We compare this contribution to the contributions to growth in aggregate demand made by fiscal policy changes over past expansions. In doing so, we highlight that the strong support of government policy to GDP growth during the Great Recession was followed by a historically weak contribution over the course of the current expansion.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Agarwal, Sumit, Chunlin Liu, and Nicholas S. Souleles (2007) “The Reaction of Consumer Spending and Debt to Tax Rebates-Evidence from Consumer Credit Data.” Journal of Political Economy 115 (6): 986-1019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Auerbach, Alan. (1988). “Capital Gains Taxation in the United States.” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 2, 595-631.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Auerbach, Alan J. (2000). “Formation of Fiscal Policy: The Experience of the Past Twenty-Five Years.” Federal Reserve Bank of New York Economic Policy Review, 6(1): 9-23</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Auerbach, Alan J. (2003). “Fiscal Policy, Past and Present,” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, 1, pp. 75-122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Auerbach, Alan J.and Yuriy Gorodnichenko (2012). “Measuring the Output Responses to Fiscal Policy,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 4(2), 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Blanchard, Olivier and Roberto Perotti (2002). “An Empirical Characterization of the Dynamic Effects of Changes in Government Spending and Taxes on Output,” The Quarterly Journal of Economics, Oxford University Press, 117(4):1329-1368.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Blundell, Richard, Luigi Pistaferri, and I. Preston (2008). “Consumption Inequality and Partial Insurance,” American Economic Review, 98, 1887-1921.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Brayton, Flint, Thomas Laubach, and David Reifschneider, “The FRB/US Model: A Tool for Macroeconomic Policy Analysis”, FEDS Notes, April 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Broda, Christian and Jonathan A. Parker. (2014). The Economic Stimulus Payments of 2008 and the aggregate demand for consumption, Journal of Monetary Economics, 68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Burnside, Martin Eichenbaum, and Jonas Fisher. (2004). “Fiscal Shocks and their Consequences,” Journal of Economic Theory, 115.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Campell, John and N. Gregory Mankiw. (1989). “Consumption, Income and Interest Rates: Reinterpreting the Time Series Evidence,” in NBER Macroeconomics Annual, Volume 4, Olivier J. Blanchard and Stanley Fischer, eds.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Cavallo, Michele, (2005). “Government Employment Expenditure and the Effects of Fiscal Policy Shocks,”Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Cashin, David and Takashi Unayama (2016). “The Impact of a Permanent Income Shock on Consumption: Evidence from Japan’s 2014 VAT Increase,” Discussion Paper 16052, Research Institute of Economy, Trade, and Industry (RIETI).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">CBO, “The Budget and Economic Outlook: 2016 to 2026,” January 25, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Chirinko, Robert S., Steven M. Fazzari, and Andrew P. Meyer (1999). “How Responsive is Business Capital Formation to its User Cost? An Exploration with Micro Data,” Journal of Public Economics, 74:53-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Cohen, Darrell S. and Jason G. Cummins (2006). “A Retrospective Evaluation of the Effects of Temporary Partial Expensing,” FEDS Working Paper No. 2006-19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Cummins, Jason G., Kevin A. Hassett, and Glenn R. Hubbard (1994). “A Reconsideration of Investment Behavior Using Tax Reforms as Natural Experiments,” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, 2:1-74</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Davis, M. A., Palumbo, M. G., &amp; Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (U.S.). (2001). “A primer on the economics and time series econometrics of wealth effects”. Washington, D.C: Divisions of Research &amp; Statistics and Monetary Affairs, Federal Reserve Board.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">deLeeuw, Frank, Thomas Holloway, Darwin Johnson, David McClain, and Charles Waite (1980). “The High-Employment Budget: New Estimates, 1955-1980.” Survey of Current Business (November): 13-43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Dobridge, Christine L. (2016). “Fiscal Stimulus and Firms: A Tale of Two Recessions,” FEDS Working Paper No. 2016-013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Edelberg, Wendy, Martin Eichenbaum, and Jonas D. M. Fisher. (1999). “Understanding Shock to Government Purchases,” Review of Economic Dynamics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Favero, Carlo and Francesco Giavazzi (2012). “Measuring Tax Multipliers: The Narrative Method in Fiscal VARs,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 4(2), 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Follette, Glenn, Andrea Kusko and Byron Lutz, “State and Local Finances and the Macroeconomy: The High-Employment Budget and Fiscal Impetus”, National Tax Journal, Vol. LXI, No. 3, September 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Follette, Glenn, and Byron Lutz (2011). "Fiscal Policy in the United States: Automatic Stabilizers, Discretionary Fiscal Policy Actions, and the Economy," Fiscal Policy: Lessons from the Crisis vol. Feb. Perugia: Banca d'Italia, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Hassett, Kevin A. and R. Glenn Hubbard (2002). “Tax Policy and Business Investment,” Handbook of Public Economics, 3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Hines, James R., “State Fiscal Policies and Transitory Income Fluctuations,” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, Fall 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">House, Christopher L. and Matthew D. Shapiro (2008). “Temporary Investment Tax Incentives: Theory with Evidence from Bonus Depreciation,” American Economic Review, 98(3):736-768.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Jappelli, Tulio and Luigi Pistaferri (2006). “Intertemporal Choice and Consumption Mobility,” Journal of the European Economic Association, 4:75-115.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Jappelli, Tulio and Luigi Pistaferri (2010). “The Consumption Response to Income Changes,”Annual Review of Economics, Annual Reviews, vol. 2, no. 1, pages 479-506.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Jappelli, Tulio and Luigi Pistaferri (2011). “Financial Integration and Consumption Smoothing,” The Economic Journal, 121:678-706.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Johnson, David S., Jonathan A. Parker, and Nicholas S. Souleles. (2006). “Household Expenditure and the Income Tax Rebates of 2001.” American Economic Review, 96(5): 1589-610.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Kaplan, Greg, Giovanni L. Violante, and Justin Wiedner (2014). “The Wealthy Hand-to-Mouth,” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, Spring 2014, pages 77-153.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Lucas, Deborah, “Credit Policy as Fiscal Policy”, Brookings Papers on Ec4onomic Activity, BPEA Conference Draft, March 10-11, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Lutz, Byron, “The Connection Between House Price Appreciation and Property Tax Revenue,” National Tax Journal, LXI, No. 3, Sept. 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Lutz, Byron, Raven Molloy and Hui Shan “The Housing Crisis and State and Local Government Tax Revenue: Five Channels,” Regional Science and Urban Economics, July 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Mankiw, N. Gregory. (2000). “The Savers-Spenders Theory of Fiscal Policy, American Economic Review, 90(2).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Mertens, Karel and Morten O. Ravn. (2012). “Empirical Evidence on the Aggregate Effects of Anticipated and Unanticipated US Tax Policy Shocks,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 4(2), 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Miller, Preston and Larry Ozanne (2000). “Forecasting Capital Gains Realizations,” Technical Paper Series 2000-5, Congressional Budget Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Misra, Kanishka and Paolo Surico (2014). “Consumption, Income Changes, and Heterogeneity: Evidence from Two Fiscal Stimulus Programs,” American Economic Journal: Macroeconomics, vol. 6, no. 4, pages 84-106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">OECD, “Economic Outlook,” June 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Parker, Jonathan A. (1999). “The Reaction of Household Consumption to Predictable Changes in Social Security Taxes.” American Economic Review, 89(4): 959-73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Parker, Jonathan A., Nicholas Souleles, David S. Johnson, and Robert McClelland (2013). “Consumer Spending and the Economic Stimulus Payments of 2008,” American Economic Review, vol. 103, no. 6, pages 2530-2553.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Patel, Elena, Nathan Seegert, and Matthew Grady Smith (2015). “At a Loss: The Real and Reporting Elasticity of Corporate Taxable Income,” Available at SSRN: http://ssrn.com/abstract=2608166.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Perotti, Roberto. (2012). “The Effects of Tax Shocks on Output: Not So Large, But Not Small Either.” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 4(2), 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Pistaferri, Luigi (2001). "Superior Information, Income Shocks, and the Permanent Income Hypothesis,” The Review of Economics and Statistics, 83(3), 465-476.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Ramey, Valerie. (2011), “Identifying Government Spending Shocks: It’s All in the Timing,”Quarterly Journal of Economics, 126:1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Ramey, Valerie and Matthew Shapiro. (1998). “Costly Capital Reallocation and the Effects of Government Spending,” Carnegie-Rochester Conference Series on Public Policy, 48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Romer, Christina and David Romer, (2010). “The Macroeconomic Effects of Tax Changes: Estimates Based on a New Measure of Fiscal Shocks.” American Economic Review, 100.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Russek, Frank and Kim Kowalewski (2015). ”How CBO Estimates Automatic Stabilizers,” CBO Working Paper Series.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Shapiro, Matthew D. and Slemrod, Joel. (1995). “Consumer Response to the Timing of Income: Evidence from a Change in Tax Withholding.” American Economic Review, 85(1), pp. 274-83.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Shea, John. (1995). “Union Contracts and the Life-Cycle/Permanent-Income Hypothesis.” American Economic Review, 85(1), pp. 186-200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Sheiner, Louise (2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Sinn, Hans-Werner (1991). “Taxation and the Cost of Capital: The “Old” View, the “New” View, and Another View,” Chapter in Tax Policy and the Economy, Volume 5, pages 25-54, National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Souleles, Nicholas S. (1999). “The Response of Household Consumption to Income Tax Refunds.” American Economic Review, 89(4): 947-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">U.S. Congressional Budget Office (2011). “Improving CBO’s Methodology for Projecting Individual Income Tax Revenues,” Washington D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">U.S. Congressional Budget Office (2016). The Budget and Economic Outlook. Washington D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Wilcox, David. (1989). “Social security benefits, consumption expenditure, and the life cycle hypothesis.” Journal of Political Economy, 97:288-304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Yagan, Danny (2015). "Capital Tax Reform and the Real Economy: The Effects of the 2003 Dividend Tax Cut,” American Economic Review, 105(12): 3531-3563.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Zidar, Owen. (2015). “Tax Cuts for Whom? Heterogeneous Effects of Income Tax Changes on Growth and Employment,” NBER Working Paper #21035.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Zwick, Eric and James Mahon (Forthcoming). “Tax Policy and Heterogeneous Investment Behavior,” American Economic Review.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Estimates β<sub>j</sub> of sensitivity of tax base to the business cycle</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Elasticity of cyclically-sensitive taxes to their base</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1.</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>MPC Selections</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Fiscal Effects over the Cycle</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Correlation between Components of Fiscal Effect</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2.</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3.</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4.</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5.</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6.</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7.</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8.</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 9.</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 10.</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 11.</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>FRB/US Estimates of Marginal Propensity to Consume Out of Permanent Shocks</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Alternate MPC Selection</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Comparison of Fiscal Effect</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A.1</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A.2</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Elasticity of AGI to NIPA Personal Income</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A.3</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Counterfactual GDP and Public Debt</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Total Fiscal Effect</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Discretionary Fiscal Effect</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Cyclical Fiscal Effect</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Residual Fiscal Effect</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
