<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278000</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Determine Air-Fuel Ratio Imbalance Cylinder Identification with an Oxygen Sensor</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Qiao</surname>
                  <given-names>Ningsheng</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Krishnamurthy</surname>
                  <given-names>Chandrasekar</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Moore</surname>
                  <given-names>Nicholas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Continental Automotive Systems US Inc</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>June 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277995</issue-id>
         <fpage>1005</fpage>
         <lpage>1011</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278000"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Air-fuel ratio cylinder imbalance is a condition where the air-fuel ratio in one or more cylinders is different than the other cylinders. When air-fuel ratio cylinder imbalance occurs in one or more cylinders the fuel delivery system is unable to maintain a proper vehicle emission level.</p>
            <p>It is required for on-board diagnostics to detect air-fuel ratio cylinder imbalance levels which cause the fuel delivery system to be unable to maintain vehicle emissions at or below 1.5 times of any of the applicable FTP (Federal Test Procedure) emission standards. Currently California Air Resources Board (CARB) only requires on-board diagnostics to detect exhaust bank specific air-fuel ratio cylinder imbalance. In the near future CARB will require on-board diagnostics to detect cylinder specific air-fuel ratio cylinder imbalance. This paper presents a non-intrusive approach on determining single cylinder air-fuel ratio imbalance identification (ID) with an oxygen sensor. It employs digital filtering technique to extract the air-fuel ratio cylinder imbalance signals from existing upstream oxygen sensor voltage signals on single or dual exhaust bank engines. The filtered oxygen sensor voltage signals are processed with mathematical manipulation in order to determine the imbalanced cylinder. The oxygen sensor can be a binary or wide range type, however only the binary type is considered here. Different filter coefficients should be used for different types of oxygen sensors.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wiens Travis, Burton Rich, Schoenau Greg, Sulatisky Mike, et al. “Experimental Determination of Transport Delay in a Spark Ignition Engine.” Technical Paper MISC-167, Saskatchewan Research Council, Saskatoon, 2006, Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Order Analysis, Order Tracking, and Filtered Orders,” Data Physics Corporation 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kainz, J. and Smith, J., “Individual Cylinder Fuel Control with a Switching Oxygen Sensor,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0546, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0546.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maloney Peter, “Developing a Period-Based Air-fuel Ratio Controller with a Low Cost Switching Sensor”. Mathworks Newsletters, September 2014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
