<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">19</volume>
         <issue-id>i40198652</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44722877</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>CALIFORNIA AIR-CLEANER TESTS, 1924 SERIES</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>A H</given-names>
                  <surname>Hoffman</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1924</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>145</fpage>
         <lpage>170</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright, 1926, Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44722877"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>References are made to published results of similar tests of air-cleaner devices conducted in 1922, and the scope of the 1924 tests is described. Road tests of air-cleaners were carried out and the tabulated data are presented. Efforts were made to find out how much dust the engine would draw in if the cleaner and connections were removed and to catch and weigh the dust the air-cleaner under test failed to catch. Dust was raised by a car running about 50 ft. ahead of the test-car and, to produce heavy dust-conditions, the road was dragged with a chain attached to the car and forming a loop behind it. The leading drivers maintained as nearly as possible a constant speed of 25 m.p.h. and chose the dustiest part of the road, following the same course on all the rounds. The specific items of the 1924 program were (a) to continue the testing work begun in 1922, (b) to devise a satisfactory method of testing types of air-cleaner that cannot well be tested by the 1922 method, (c) to determine how much dust an automobile or truck encounters in service and (d) to find out how the use of air-cleaners affects the rate of engine wear. After describing the "absolute" air-cleaner used in connection with the air-cleaners under test, standard dust for testing purposes and Fuller's earth are discussed, as are also some tests made of the latter substance. Road-tests are treated generally and specifically, road-test and laboratory-test comparisons are made, and the 32 air-cleaners submitted for test are described, together with tabular data of the results obtained while testing them.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


