<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284921</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Advanced Knock Detection for Diesel/Natural Gas Engine Operation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kirsten</surname>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Graz University of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pirker</surname>
                  <given-names>Gerhard</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>LEC GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Redtenbacher</surname>
                  <given-names>Christoph</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>LEC GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wimmer</surname>
                  <given-names>Andreas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Graz University of Technology/LEC GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chmela</surname>
                  <given-names>Franz</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FVT GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>September 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284904</issue-id>
         <fpage>1571</fpage>
         <lpage>1583</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284921"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>As emission limits become increasingly stringent and the price of gaseous fuels decreases, more emphasis is being placed on promoting gas engines. In the field of large engines for power generation, dual fuel combustion concepts that run on diesel/natural gas are particularly attractive. Knock in diesel/natural gas dual fuel engines is a well known yet not fully understood complex phenomenon that requires consideration in any attempt to increase load and efficiency. Thus combustion concept development requires a reliable yet robust methodology for detecting knock in order to ensure knock-free engine operation.</p>
            <p>Operating parameters such as rail pressure, start of injection and amount of diesel injected are the factors that influence oscillations in the in-cylinder pressure trace after the start of combustion. Oscillations in the pre-mixed combustion phase, or ringing, are caused by the rapid conversion of large parts of the injected diesel. This effect may lead to misinterpreting non-knocking combustion cycles determined from the in-cylinder pressure trace data or knock sensor data.</p>
            <p>This paper describes a new knock detection methodology based on the in-cylinder pressure trace and knock sensor data applied to a diesel/natural gas dual fuel large engine. The approach compares oscillations in the pre-mixed diesel combustion phase to oscillations in the main combustion phase. Parameters that provoke oscillations (rail pressure, start of injection and amount of diesel injected) as well as other parameters influencing knock (IMEP, excess air ratio, manifold air temperature, methane number and compression ratio) are investigated and discussed. This specific approach requires only two steady threshold limits to cover all these parameters influencing knock and to distinguish between knocking and non-knocking combustion cycles.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wimmer, A., Chmela, F., Kirsten, M. et al., „LEC-GPN - A new Index for Assessing the Knock Behavior of Gaseous Fuels for Large Engines, IVA, Berlin</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J., "Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsurushima, T., Kunishima, E., Asaumi, Y., Aoyagi, Y. et al., "The Effect of Knock on Heat Loss in Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0108, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002- 01-0108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karim, G., Zhaoda, Y.: “Modeling of the Combustion Process in a Dual Fuel Direct Injection Engine”, ASME, 1990</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Worret, R., Bernhardt, S., Schwarz, F., and Spicher, U., "Application of Different Cylinder Pressure Based Knock Detection Methods in Spark Ignition Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1668, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1668.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vancoillie, J., Sileghem, L., and Verhelst, S., "Development and Validation of a Knock Prediction Model for Methanol-Fuelled SI Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1312, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013- 01-1312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sileghem, L., Wallner, T., Verhelst, S., „A Quasi-Dimentional Model for SI Engines Fueled With Gasoline -Alcohol blends: Knock modeling”, Fuel, 140(2015)217-226, Elsevier, 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saikaly, K., Le Corre, O., Rahmouni, C., Truffet, L, et al., “Preventive Knock Protection Technique for Stationary SI Engines fueled by Natural Gas”, Fuel Processing Technology 91 (2010)641-652, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pipitone, E., Beccari, S., “Calibration of a Knock Prediction Model for the Combustion of Gasoline-Natural Gas Mixtures”, ASME, ICEF2009- 14057, Lucerne, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, A., Anderson, D., Hoffman, M., Filipi, Z. et al., “An Evaluation of Knock Determination Techniques for Diesel-Natural Gas Dual Fuel Engines”, SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-2695, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014- 01-2695.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shahlari, A. and Ghandhi, J., “A Comparison of Engine Knock Metrics, SAE Technical Paper, 2012-32-0007, 2012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guimaraes, D.A., Digital Transmission - A Simulation-Aided Introduction with VisSim/Comm, Heidelberg - New York: Springer, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siano, D., Panza, M., and D'Agostino, D., "Knock Detection Based on MAPO Analysis, AR Model and Discrete Wavelet Transform Applied to the In-Cylinder Pressure Data: Results and Comparison," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(1):1-13, 2015, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2547.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shu, G., Pan, J., Wei, H., „Analysis of Onset and Severity of Knock in SI Engine Based on In-Cylinder Pressure Oscillations”, Applied Thermal Engineering, 51(2013)1297-1306, Elsevier, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brecq, G. and Le Corre, O., "Modeling of In-cylinder Pressure Oscillations under Knocking Conditions: Introduction to Pressure Envelope Curve," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1126, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, L., Li, T., Yin, T., et al., “A Predictive Model for Knock Onset in Spark-Ignition Engines”, Energy Conversion and Management, 87(2014)946-955, Elsevier, 2014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adolph, N., “Messung des Klopfens an Ottomotoren”, Ph.D.-Thesis, Rheinisch-Westfälische Technische Hochschule Aachen, 1983</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhen, X, Wang, Y, Xu, S., et al., “The Engine Knock Analysis - An Overview”, Applied Energy, 92(2012)628-636, Elsevier, 2012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brecq, G. Bellettre, J., Tazerout, M., “A New Indicator for Knock Detection in Gas SI Engine”, International Journal of Thermal Science, 42(2003)9523-532, Elsevier, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chun, K. and Heywood, J., "Characterization of Knock in a Spark-Ignition Engine," SAE Technical Paper 890156, 1989, doi:10.4271/890156.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
