<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284805</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Analyzing the Cycle-to-Cycle Variations of Vapor and Liquid Phases of Evaporating SIDI Sprays via Proper Orthogonal Decomposition Technique</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wu</surname>
                  <given-names>Shengqi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Shanghai Jiao Tong University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Xu</surname>
                  <given-names>Min</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Shanghai Jiao Tong University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hung</surname>
                  <given-names>David L.S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Michigan-Shanghai Jiao Tong University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Tianyun</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>School of Mechanical Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong Univers</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pan</surname>
                  <given-names>Hujie</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>School of Mechanical Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong Univers</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284791</issue-id>
         <fpage>193</fpage>
         <lpage>200</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE Japan and Copyright © SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284805"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In this study, the spray characteristics of three multi-hole injectors, namely a 2-hole injector, a 4-hole injector, and a 6-hole injector were investigated under various superheated conditions. Fuel pressure was kept constant at 10MPa. Fuel temperature varied from 20°C to 85°C, and back pressure ranged from 20kPa to 100kPa. Both liquid phase and vapor phase of the spray were investigated via laser induced exciplex fluorescence technique. Proper orthogonal decomposition technique was applied to analyze the cycle-to-cycle variations of the liquid phase and vapor phase of the fuel spray separately. Effects of fuel temperature, back pressure, superheated degree and nozzle number on spray variation were revealed. It shows that higher fuel temperature led to a more stable spray due to enhanced evaporation which eliminated the fluctuating structures along the spray periphery. Higher back pressure led to higher spray variation due to increased interaction between spray and ambient air. In addition, flash boiling sprays were more stable than non-flash boiling sprays. The spray variation of the 6-hole injector was the smallest under all test conditions. It was because a symmetrical hole distribution contributed to a more stable spray structure. Asymmetrically distributed holes would lead to larger spray variation under transition conditions due to more pronounced ambient air effects.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, F., Lai, M. C., and Harrington, D. L., “Automotive spark-ignited direct-injection gasoline engines”, Prog. Energy Combust. Sci., Vol. 25, No. 5, pp. 437-562, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Senda, J., Wada, Y., Kawano, D., and Fujimoto, H., “Improvement of combustion and emissions in diesel engines by means of enhanced mixture formation based on flash boiling of mixed fuel”, Int. J. Engine Res., Vol. 9, No. 1, pp: 15-27, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">She J. P., “Experimental study on improvement on diesel combustion and emissions using flash boiling injection”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2010-01-0341, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeng, W., Xu, M., Zhang, G., Zhang, Y. Y., and Cleary, D. J., “Atomization and vaporization for flash-boiling multi-hole sprays with alcohol fuels”, Fuel, Vol. 95, pp: 287-297, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, M., Zhang, Y., Zeng, W., Zhang, G. et al., “Flash Boiling: Easy and Better Way to Generate Ideal Sprays than the High Injection Pressure,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(1):137-148, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1614.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhong, J., Hung, D. L. S., Wang, Z. K., Zhang, Y. Y., and Xu, M., “Comparing the cycle-to-cycle variations of pulsing spray characteristics by means of ensemble image and probability presence image analysis techniques”, Proceedings of 12th Triennial International Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems, Heidelberg, Germany, Sept. 2-6, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ozdor, N., Dulger, M., and Sher, E., “Cyclic variability in spark ignition engines a literature survey”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 940987, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marchi, A., Nouri, J., Yan, Y., and Arcoumanis, C., “Spray stability of outwards opening pintle injectors for stratified direct injection spark ignition engine operation”, Int. J. Engine Res., Vol. 11, No. 6, pp. 413- 437, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H., Reuss, D., and Sick, V., “Analysis of misfires in a direct injection engine using proper orthogonal decomposition”, Exp. Fluids, Vol. 51, No. 4, pp. 1139-1151, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeng, W., Xu, M., Zhang, M., Zhang, Y. Y., and Cleary, D. J., “Macroscopic characteristics for direct-injection multi-hole sprays using dimensionless analysis”, Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science, Vol. 40, pp: 81-92, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeng, W., Xu, M., Zhang, Y. Y., and Wang, Z. K., “Laser sheet dropsizing of evaporating sprays using simultaneous LIEF/MIE techniques”, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute Vol. 34, No. 1, pp: 1677-1685, 2013. Wu et al/SAE Int. J. Engines/Volume 9, Issue 1 (April 2016) 199</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, G., Xu, M., Zhang, Y. Y., Zhang, M., and Cleary, D. J., “Macroscopic characterization of flash-boiling multi-hole sprays using planar laser induced exciplex fluorescence technique. Part I. On-axis spray structure”, Atomization and Sprays, Vol. 22, issue 10, pp: 861-878, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, G., Xu, M., Zhang, Y. Y., Zhang, M., and Cleary, D. J., “Macroscopic characterization of flash-boiling multi-hole sprays using planar laser induced exciplex fluorescence technique. Part II. Crosssectional spray structure”, Atomization and Sprays, Vol. 23, issue 3, pp: 265-278, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, M., Xu, M., Zhang, Y., Zhang, G., and Cleary, D. J., Flow-field Investigation of Multi-hole Superheated Sprays Using High-speed PIV. Part I. Cross-sectional Direction, Atomization and Sprays, Vol. 22, issue 11, pp: 983-995, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, M., Xu, M., Zhang, Y., Zhang, G., and Cleary, D. J., “Flow-field Investigation of Multi-hole Superheated Sprays Using High-speed PIV. Part II. Axial Direction”, Atomization and Sprays, Vol. 23, issue 2, pp: 119-140, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hung, D. L. S., Chmiel, D. M., and Markle, L. E., Application of an imaging-based diagnostic technique to quantify the fuel spray variations in a direct-injection spark-ignition engine, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2003-01-0062, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H., Hung, D. L. S., Xu, M., and Zhong, J., “Analyzing the cycleto- cycle variations of pulsing spray characteristics by means of the proper orthogonal decomposition”, Atomization and Sprays, Vol. 23, No. 7, pp: 623-641, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
