<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26789703</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Three-Dimensional Simulation of Water Management for High-Performance Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
                  <given-names>Guobin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jiao</surname>
                  <given-names>Kui</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">WCX18 Best Papers Special Issue</issue-title>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26789698</issue-id>
         <fpage>233</fpage>
         <lpage>248</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26789703"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Proton exchange membrane fuel cell (PEMFC) is widely regarded as the most promising candidate for the next generation power source of automobile, after the pure battery electric vehicle. In this study, the gas and liquid two-phase flow in channels and porous electrodes inside PEMFC coupled with electrochemical reaction is simulated in detail, in which the anisotropic gas diffusion layer (GDL) is also considered. In the simulation, the inlet reactant gas molar concentration is calculated based on the real inlet pressure, which is more practical than specifying a constant value in previous simulation. Meanwhile, the effect of electro-osmotic drag on membrane water content distribution is treated to be a convection term in the conservation equation, instead of a source term as usually used. It can be concluded in the simulation that increasing the cathode stoichiometry ratio can facilitate the liquid water removal process in cathode channel and therefore decrease the liquid saturation in porous electrodes. It is also found that the higher the contact angle at the interface of bipolar plate (BP) and channel, the less the liquid water in channel and the higher the PEMFC performance. Moreover, increasing the contact angle of cathode GDL will increase the liquid saturation in cathode microporous layer (MPL) and catalyst layer (CL) and the membrane water content in membrane and CL but decrease the liquid amount in cathode GDL. Meanwhile, decreasing the cathode humidity appropriately is helpful to improve the PEMFC performance because of the increase of oxygen concentration when the anode humidity is sufficient (e.g., 1.0). However, if not, it will decrease with the decrement of cathode humidity.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Hao, D., Hou, Y., Shen, J., and Ma, L., “Effect of Road- Induced Vibration on Gas-Tightness of Vehicular Fuel Cell Stack,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-1186, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-1186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Xie, X., Zhang, G., Zhou, J., and Jiao, K., “Experimental and Theoretical Analysis of Ionomer/Carbon Ratio Effect on PEM Fuel Cell Cold Start Operation,” Int J Hydrogen Energ 42(17):12521-12530, 2017, doi:10.1016/j. ijhydene.2017.02.183.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Jiao, K. and Ni, M., “Challenges and Opportunities in Modelling of Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells (PEMFC),” Int J Energ Res, doi:10.1002/er.3798.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Mizutani, N. and Ishibashi, K., “Enhancing PtCo Electrode Catalyst Performance for Fuel Cell Vehicle Application,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-1187, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-1187.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Zhang, T., Wang, P., Chen, H. et al., “A Review of Automotive Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell Degradation Under Start-Stop Operating Condition,” Appl Energy 223:249-262, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Hu, X., Jiang, J., Egardt, B. et al., “Advanced Power-Source Integration in Hybrid Electric Vehicles: Multicriteria Optimization Approach,” IEEE Trans Ind Electron 62(12):7847-7858, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Piffard, M., Gerard, M., Da Fonseca, R. et al., “Sliding Mode Observer for Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell: Automotive Application,” J Power Sources 388:71-77, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Jiao, K. and Li, X., “Water Transport in Polymer Electrolyte Membrane Fuel Cells,” Prog Energ Combust 37(3):221-291, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.pecs.2010.06.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Li, H., Tang, Y., Wang, Z., Shi, Z. et al., “A Review of Water Flooding Issues in the Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell,” J Power Sources 178(1):103-117, 2008, doi:10.1016/j. jpowsour.2007.12.068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Sasabe, T., Tsushima, S., and Hirai, S., “In-Situ Visualization of Liquid Water in an Operating PEMFC by Soft X-Ray Radiography,” Int J Hydrogen Energ 35(20):11119-11128, 2010, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2010.06.050.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Meyer, Q., Ashton, S., Boillat, P., Cochet, M. et al., “Effect of Gas Diffusion Layer Properties on Water Distribution Across Air-Cooled, Open-Cathode Polymer Electrolyte Fuel Cells: A Combined Ex-Situ X-Ray Tomography and In-Operando Neutron Imaging Study,” Electrochim Acta 211:478-487, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.electacta.2016.06.068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Deevanhxay, P., Sasabe, T., Tsushima, S., and Hirai, S., “In Situ Diagnostic of Liquid Water Distribution in Cathode Catalyst Layer in an Operating PEMFC by High-Resolution Soft X-Ray Radiography,” Electrochem Commun 22:33-36, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.elecom.2012.05.028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Park, J., Li, X., Tran, D., Abdel-Baset, T. et al., “Neutron Imaging Investigation of Liquid Water Distribution in and the Performance of a PEM Fuel Cell,” Int J Hydrogen Energ 33(13):3373-3384, 2008, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2008.03.019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Hickner, M.A., Siegel, N.P., Chen, K.S., Hussey, D.S. et al., “Understanding Liquid Water Distribution and Removal Phenomena in an Operating PEMFC via Neutron Radiography,” J Electrochem Soc 155(3):B294-B302, 2008, doi:10.1149/1.2825298.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Chen, Y.S., Peng, H., Hussey, D.S., Jacobson, D.L. et al., “Water Distribution Measurement for a PEMFC through Neutron Radiography,” J Power Sources 170(2):376-386, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.jpowsour.2007.03.076.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Ous, T. and Arcoumanis, C., “Visualisation of Water Accumulation in the Flow Channels of PEMFC Under Various Operating Conditions,” J Power Sources 187(1):182-189, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.jpowsour.2008.10.072.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Nishida, K., Yokoi, Y., Asa, M., and Tsushima, S., “Quantitative Estimation of Water Vapor Distribution in Low-Humidity Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell Using Humidity Test Paper,” J Power Sources 234:111-118, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.jpowsour.2013.01.160.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Salva, J.A., Iranzo, A., Rosa, F., and Tapia, E., “Experimental Validation of the Polarization Curve and the Temperature Distribution in a PEMFC Stack Using a One Dimensional Analytical Model,” Int J Hydrogen Energ 41(45):20615-20632, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2016.09.152.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Liu, J.X., Guo, H., Ye, F., and Ma, C., “Two-Dimensional Analytical Model of a Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell,” Energy 119:299-308, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2016.12.075.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Han, B., Ni, M., and Meng, H., “Three-Dimensional Lattice Boltzmann Simulation of Liquid Water Transport in Porous Layer of PEMFC,” Entropy 18(1):17, 2015, doi:10.3390/e18010017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Kim, D.J., Park, C.H., and Nam, S.Y., “Molecular Dynamics Simulations of Modified PEEK Polymeric Membrane for Fuel Cell Application,” Int J Hydrogen Energ 41(18):7641-7648, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2015.12.220.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Qin, Y., Li, X., Jiao, K. et al., “Effective Removal and Transport of Water in a PEM Fuel Cell Flow Channel having a Hydrophilic Plate,” Appl Energ 113:116-126, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Hou, Y., Zhang, G., Qin, Y., Du, Q. et al., “Numerical Simulation of Gas Liquid Two-Phase Flow in Anode Channel of Low-Temperature Fuel Cells,” Int J Hydrogen Energ 42(5):3250-3258, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2013.06.053.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Jiao, K., Zhou, B., and Quan, P., “Liquid Water Transport in Parallel Serpentine Channels with Manifolds on Cathode Side of a PEM Fuel Cell Stack,” J Power Sources 154(1):124-137, 2006, doi:10.1016/j.jpowsour.2005.04.003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Ferreira, R.B., Falcão, D.S., Oliveira, V.B. et al., “1D + 3D Two-Phase Flow Numerical Model of a Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell,” Appl Energy 203:474-495, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Niu, Z., Wang, R., Jiao, K., Du, Q. et al., “Direct Numerical Simulation of Low Reynolds Number Turbulent Air-Water Transport in Fuel Cell Flow Channel,” Sci Bull 62(1):31-39, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.scib.2016.11.010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Niu, Z., Jiao, K., Zhang, F., Du, Q. et al., “Direct Numerical Simulation of Two-Phase Turbulent Flow in Fuel Cell Flow Channel,” Int J Hydrogen Energ 41(4):3147-3152, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2015.11.026.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Zhang, G. and Jiao, K., “Multi-Phase Models For Water and Thermal Management of Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell: A Review,” J Power Sources 391:120-133, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Cao, T.F., Lin, H., Chen, L., He, Y. et al., “Numerical Investigation of the Coupled Water and Thermal Management in PEM Fuel Cell,” Appl Energ 112:1115-1125, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2013.02.031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Zhou, Y., Jiao, K., Du, Q., Yin, Y. et al., “Gas Diffusion Layer Deformation and its Effect on the Transport Characteristics and Performance of Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell,” Int J Hydrogen Energ 38(29):12891-12903, 2013, doi:10.1016/j. ijhydene.2013.05.150.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Ferreira, R.B., Falcão, D.S., Oliveira, V.B., and Pinto, A.M.F.R., “Numerical Simulations of Two-Phase Flow in Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells Using the Volume of Fluid Method-A Review,” J Power Sources 277:329-342, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.jpowsour.2014.11.124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Zhang, G., Fan, L., Sun, J., and Jiao, K., “A 3D Model of PEMFC Considering Detailed Multiphase Flow and Anisotropic Transport Properties,” Int J Heat Mass Tran 115:714-724, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2017.07.102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Ye, Q. and Van Nguyen, T., “Three-Dimensional Simulation of Liquid Water Distribution in a PEMFC with Experimentally Measured Capillary Functions,” J. Electrochem Soc 154(12):B1242-B1251, 2007, doi:10.1149/1.2783775.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Meng, H., “Numerical Studies of Liquid Water Behaviors in PEM Fuel Cell Cathode Considering Transport Across Different Porous Layers,” Int J Hydrogen Energ 35(11):5569-5579, 2010, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2010.03.073.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Deng, H., Jiao, D., Zu, M., Chen, J. et al., “Modeling of Passive Alkaline Membrane Direct Methanol Fuel Cell,” Electrochim Acta 154:430-446, 2015, doi:10.1016/j. electacta.2014.12.044.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Kim, K.H., Lee, K.Y., Lee, S.Y. et al., “The Effects of Relative Humidity on the Performances of PEMFC MEAs with Various Nafion® Ionomer Contents,” Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 35(23):13104-13110, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Ozen, D.N., Timurkutluk, B., and Altinisik, K., “Effects of Operation Temperature and Reactant Gas Humidity Levels on Performance of PEM Fuel Cells,” Renew Sustain Energy Rev 59:1298-1306, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Cao, T.F., Lin, H., Chen, L. et al., “Numerical Investigation of the Coupled Water and Thermal Management in PEM Fuel Cell,” Appl Energy 112:1115-1125, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Wang, L. and Liu, H., “Separate Measurement of Current Density Under the Channel and the Shoulder in PEM Fuel Cells,” J Power Sources 180(1):365-372, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Cao, T.F., Mu, Y.T., Ding, J., Lin, H. et al., “Modeling the Temperature Distribution and Performance of a PEM Fuel Cell with Thermal Contact Resistance,” Int J Heat Mass Transf 87:544-556, 2015, doi:10.1016/j. ijheatmasstransfer.2015.04.010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Perng, S.W. and Wu, H.W., “A Three-Dimensional Numerical Investigation of Trapezoid Baffles Effect on Non-Isothermal Reactant Transport and Cell Net Power in a PEMFC,” Appl Energ 143:81-95, 2015, doi:10.1016/j. apenergy.2014.12.059.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Springer, T.E., Zawodzinski, T.A., and Gottesfeld, S., “Polymer Electrolyte Fuel Cell Model,” J Electrochem Soc 138(8):2334-2342, 1991, doi:10.1149/1.2085971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Computational domain.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Design parameters.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Operating conditions.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>GDL anisotropic transport equations.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Transport properties.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Source terms in conservation equations.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Boundary conditions.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>The effect of inlet pressure on inlet oxygen concentration: (a) the pressure in cathode channel, (b) the inlet oxygen concentration.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>The membrane water distribution (RHₐ = RH<sub>c</sub> = 0.75).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>The effect of cathode stoichiometric ratio on liquid distribution in cathode channel.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>The effect of cathode stoichiometric ratio on liquid distribution in porous electrodes.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>The liquid volume fraction distribution at BP/Channel interface under different surface contact angles.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>The average oxygen molar concentration in porous electrodes.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>The effect of GDL contact angle: (a) liquid saturation in porous electrodes, (b) membrane water.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>The effect of cathode relative humidity.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
