<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277762</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Modeling Internal Combustion Engine with Thermo-Chemical Recuperation of the Waste Heat by Methanol Steam Reforming</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Poran</surname>
                  <given-names>Arnon</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Artoul</surname>
                  <given-names>Moris</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sheintuch</surname>
                  <given-names>Moshe</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tartakovsky</surname>
                  <given-names>Leonid</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Technion Israel Inst. of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>May 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277742</issue-id>
         <fpage>234</fpage>
         <lpage>242</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277762"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper describes a model for the simulation of the joint operation of internal combustion engine (ICE) with methanol reformer when the ICE is fed by the methanol steam reforming (SRM) products and the energy of the exhaust gases is utilized to sustain endothermic SRM reactions. This approach enables ICE feeding by a gaseous fuel with very favorable properties, thus leading to increase in the overall energy efficiency of the vehicle and emissions reduction.</p>
            <p>Previous modeling attempts were focused either on the performance of ICE fueled with SRM products or on the reforming process simulation and reactor design. It is clear that the engine performance is affected by the composition of the reforming products and the reforming products are affected by the exhaust gas temperature, composition and flow rate. Due to the tight interrelations between the two main parts of the considered ICE-reformer system, it is desirable to create a single model that simulates joint operation of the ICE and the SRM reactor. Such a model is built with the GT-Power software. It employs published catalytic reactions kinetics. The reformer model is validated using experimental results from a small scale model reactor.</p>
            <p>The developed model can be used for the performance optimization of the whole ICE - reformer system including design of the reactor. Simulations with a reformer bed geometry of counter current, multiple tubes performed using the developed model show that heat-transfer is limiting the reformer size, requiring 1.5 m² for complete methanol conversion in lean operation of a 75 kW ICE. Moreover the model can be applied to predict a transient behavior of the system owing to the time dependent approach implemented in the reformer and engine calculations.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Energy Agency, World energy outlook 2011. OECD/IEA, Paris, France, 9 November 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chakravarthy VK, Daw CS, Pihl JA., Conklin JC. “Study of the Theoretical Potential of Thermochemical Exhaust Heat Recuperation for Internal Combustion Engines.” Energy Fuels, 2010: 1529-1537.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petterson, L. Sjostrom, K. “Decomposed Methanol as a Fuel-A review.” Combust, Sci. and Tech., 1991: 265-303.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Finegold, Joseph G. “Dissociated Methanol Vehicle Test Results.” Inst of Gas Technology, 1984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sakai, T., Yamaguchi, I., Asano, M., Ayusawa, T. et al., “Transient Performance Development on Dissociated Methanol Fueled Passenger Car,” 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brinkman, N. and Stebar, R., “A Comparison of Methanol and Dissociated Methanol Illustrating Effects of Fuel Properties on Engine Efficiency-Experiments and Thermodynamic Analyses,” SAE Technical Paper 850217, 1985, doi:10.4271/850217.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morgenstern D.A., Fornango J.P, “Low-Temperature Reforming of Ethanol over Copper-Plated Raney Nickel: A New Route to Sustainable Hydrogen for Transportation,” Energy and Fuels, vo. 19, (2005), 1708-16</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morgenstern, D., Wheeler, J., and Stein, R., “High Efficiency, Low Feedgas NOx, and Improved Cold Start Enabled by Low- Temperature Ethanol Reforming,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):529- 545, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0621.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sall, E.D. Morgenstern, D.A. Fornango, J.P. Taylor, J.W. et al. “Reforming of Ethanol with Exhaust Heat at Automotive Scale” Energy &amp; Fuels 2013 27 (9), 5579-5588</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoffmann, W., Wong, V., Cheng, W., and Morgenstern, D., “A New Approach to Ethanol Utilization: High Efficiency and Low NOx in an Engine Operating on Simulated Reformed Ethanol,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2415, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2415.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tartakovsky, L., Mosyak, A. and Zvirin, Y., “Energy analysis of ethanol steam reforming for internal combustion engine”, Int. J. Energy Research 37: 259-267, 2013, doi:10.1002/er.1908.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tartakovsky, L., Baibikov, V., Gutman, M., Mosyak, A. et al., “Performance Analysis of SI Engine Fueled by Ethanol Steam Reforming Products,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1992, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tartakovsky, L., Baibikov, V., and Veinblat, M., “Comparative Performance Analysis of SI Engine Fed by Ethanol and Methanol Reforming Products,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-2617, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2617.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tesser, R. Di Serio, M. and Santacesaria, E. “Methanol steam reforming: A comparison of different kinetics in the simulation of a packed bed reactor,” Chem. Eng. J. 154(1-3):69-75, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Choi, Y. Stenger, H.G. Appl. Catal. B 38 (2002) 259.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Purnama, H., Ressler T., Jentoft R. E., Soerijanto H., Schlogl R., and Schomacker R. “CO formation/selectivity for Steam Reforming of Methanol with a Commercial CuO/ZnO/Al2O3 Catalyst.” Applied Catalysis A: General 259, no. 1 (2004): 83-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Agrell, J. Birgersson, H. Boutonnet, M. “Steam Reforming of Methanol Over a Cu/ZnO/Al2O3 Catalyst: A Kinetic Analysis and Strategies for Suppression of CO Formation.” Elsevier, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Agarwal, V. Patel, S.; Pant, K. K. “H2 production by steam reforming of methanol over Cu/ZnO/Al2O3 catalysts: transient deactivation kinetics modeling”, Appl. Catalysis. A. 2005, 155, 279</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santacesaria, E. Carrá, S., “Kinetics of catalytic steam reforming of methanol in a cstr reactor,” Applied Catalysis 5(3):345-358, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, J.K. Ko, J.B. Kim, D.H. “Methanol steam reforming over Cu/ZnO/Al2O3 catalyst: kinetics and effectiveness factor.” Applied Catalysis 278 (2004): 25-35</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Srinivasan A. and Depcik C., “One-Dimensional Pseudo- Homogeneous Packed-Bed Reactor Modeling: I. Chemical Species Equation and Effective Diffusivity,” Chem. Eng. Technol. 36(1):22- 32, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wakao, N. Kaguei, S. “Heat and Mass Transfer in Packed Beds”, Topics in Chemical Engineering, Vol. 1, Taylor &amp; Francis, New York 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nield, D.A. Bejan, A. Convection in Porous Media, 3rd ed., Springer-Verlag, New York 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Younis, L. J. Inst. Energy 2006, 79 (4), 222-227 DOI:10.1179/174602206X148874</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Finlayson, B. A. Chem. Eng. Sci. 1971, 26 (7), 1081-1091. DOI:10.1016/0009-2509(71)80022-2</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosenhow, W.M. and Hertnett, J.P. handbook of heat transfer. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1972.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ribeiro, A.M. Neto, P. and Pinho, C., “Mean Porosity and Pressure Drop Measurements In Packed Beds Of Monosized Spheres : Side Wall Effects”, International Review of Chemical Engineering, Vol. 2, No. 1, PP. 40-46, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GT-Power Engine Simulation Software, Gamma Technologies, Inc.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Natarajan, J., Lieuwen, T. and Seitzman, J., “Laminar flame speeds of H2/CO mixtures: effect of CO2 dilution, preheat temperature and pressure”, Combustion &amp; Flame, 151: 104-119, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qiao, L. Kim, C.H. Faeth, G.M. “Suppression effects of diluents on laminar premixed hydrogen/oxygen/nitrogen flames”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aung, K. T. Hassan, M. I. Faeth, G. M. “Flame Stretch Interactions of Laminar Premixed Hydrogen/Air Flames at Normal Temperature and Pressure”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., “Internal combustion engines fundamentals”, New York, McGraw-Hill, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
