<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">14</volume>
         <issue-id>i40198602</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44720503</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>MORE EFFICIENT UTILIZATION OF FUEL</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Charles F</given-names>
                  <surname>Kettering</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1919</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>201</fpage>
         <lpage>219</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright, 1920, Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44720503"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>IN general, this article, which was presented to awaken interest and stimulate curiosity in a subject of vital importance to the automotive industry, deals with the fundamentals of combustion of various fuels in internal-combustion engines. The discussion includes broadly (1) The importance of chemical structure in the study of fuels. Such knowledge is necessary to understand refining processes and the reactions taking place during combustion in a gas engine. (2) Boiling points versus specific gravity of fuels. Specific gravity is a term of slight moment; it has nothing to do with what fuel really is or how it performs in service. The distillation curve is the best index of a fuel's suitability (3) Benzol and alcohol as engine fuels. Further proof that chemical structure plays a prominent part in fuel performance (4) The phenomenon called "engine knocking." Theory is proposed that knocking is caused largely by change of fuel structure into secondary or intermediate compounds, the socalled "detonable compounds," during combustion. This theory is based upon the fact that fuels, capable of high compression without any knocking tendency, are compounds which do not decompose at low temperatures and pressures (5) Pressure-volume and pressure-time indicator cards and their interpretation. The cards show genuine preignition, normal combustion and fuel knocks (6) High-compression fuels and engine performance; again showing that certain chemical structures possess high critical temperatures and pressures (7) Some of the specific fuel problems (8) The need of more effective co-operation. On account of the constantly decreasing quality of fuels, investigation and study of the situation become imperative</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


