<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">15</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i20060447</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">20060451</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Machine Translation of Closed Captions</article-title>
          </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Fred</given-names>
                  <surname>Popowich</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Paul</given-names>
                  <surname>McFetridge</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Davide</given-names>
                  <surname>Turcato</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Janine</given-names>
                  <surname>Toole</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
                  <surname>Turcato</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
          </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2000</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>311</fpage>
         <lpage>341</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2001 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/20060451"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>Traditional Machine Translation (MT) systems are designed to translate documents. In this paper we describe an MT system that translates the closed captions that accompany most North American television broadcasts. This domain has two identifying characteristics. First, the captions themselves have properties quite different from the type of textual input that many MT systems have been designed for. This is due to the fact that captions generally represent speech and hence contain many of the phenomena that characterize spoken language. Second, the operational characteristics of the closed-caption domain are also quite distinctive. Unlike most other translation domains, the translated captions are only one of several sources of information that are available to the user. In addition, the user has limited time to comprehend the translation since captions only appear on the screen for a few seconds. In this paper, we look at some of the theoretical and implementational challenges that these characteristics pose for MT. We present a fully automatic large-scale multilingual MT system, ALTo. Our approach is based on Whitelock's Shake and Bake MT paradigm, which relies heavily on lexical resources. The system currently provides wide-coverage translation from English to Spanish. In addition to discussing the design of the system, we also address the evaluation issues that are associated with this domain and report on our current performance.</p>
          </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
              <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
              <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
          </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
        
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d144193e207a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e211" publication-type="other">
ALPAC: 1966, Language and Machines: Computers in Translation and Linguistics, Washington,
DC: National Academy of Sciences, National Research Council.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e221a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e225" publication-type="other">
Arnold, D., L. Balkan, R. L. Humphreys, S. Meijer, and L. Sadler: 1994, Machine Translation: An
Introductory Guide, NCC Blackwell, Manchester.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e235a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e239" publication-type="other">
Arnold, D., L. Sadler, and R. L. Humphreys: 1993, 'Evaluation: An Assessment', Machine
Translation 8, 1-24.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e249a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e253" publication-type="other">
Beaven, J. L.: 1992, 'Shake and Bake Machine Translation', Proceedings of the fifteenth [sic]
International Conference on Computational Linguistics, COLING-92, Nantes, France, pp.
603-609.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e267a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e271" publication-type="other">
Brew, C: 1992, 'Letting the Cat Out of the Bag: Generation for Shake-and-Bake MT', Proceedings of
the fifteenth [sic] International Conference on Computational Linguistics, COLING-92, Nantes,
France, pp. 603-609.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e284a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e288" publication-type="other">
Captionmax: 1993, Suggested Styles and Conventions for Closed Captioning, WGBH Educational
Foundation, Boston.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e298a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e302" publication-type="other">
Carpenter, B.: 1992, The Logic of Typed Feature Structures with Applications to Unification Gram-
mars, Logic Programs, and Constraint Resolution, Cambridge University Press, Cambridge.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e312a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e316" publication-type="other">
Carpenter, B. and G. Penn: 1994, ALE. The Attribute Logic Engine User's Guide. Version 2.0, Tech-
nical report, Laboratory for Computational Linguistics, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh,
PA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e329a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e333" publication-type="other">
Church, K. W.: 1988, 'A Stochastic Parts Program and Noun Phrase Parser for Unrestricted Text',
Second Conference on Applied Natural Language Processing, Austin, TX, pp. 136-143.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e343a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e347" publication-type="other">
Church, K. W. and E. H. Hovy: 1993, 'Good Applications for Crummy Machine Translation',
Machine Translation 8, 239-258.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e358a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e362" publication-type="other">
Ejerhed, F.: 1996, 'Finite State Segmentation of Discourse into Clauses', Proceedings of the ECAI-96
Workshop Extended Finite State Models of Language, Budapest, Hungary.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e372a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e376" publication-type="other">
Gazdar, C, F. Klein, C. K. Pullum, and I. Sag: 1985, Generalized Phrase Structure Grammar,
Blackwell, Oxford.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e386a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e390" publication-type="other">
Hornby, A., A. Cowie, and A. Gimson: 1987, The Oxford Advanced Learners Dictionary of Current
English, Oxford University Press, Oxford.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e400a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e404" publication-type="other">
Hutchins, W. and H. L. Somers: 1992, An Introduction to Machine Translation, Academic Press,
London.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e414a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e418" publication-type="other">
Kishner, J. M. and R. W. Gibbs, Jr: 1996, 'How "Just" Gets Its Meanings: Polysemy and Context in
Psychological Semantics', Language and Speech 39, 19-36.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e428a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e432" publication-type="other">
Minnis, S.: 1993, 'Constructive Machine Translation Evaluation', Machine Translation 8, 67-75.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e440a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e444" publication-type="other">
Mitchell, T. M., R. M. Keller, and S. T. Kedar-Cabelli: 1993, 'Explanation-Based Generalization: A
Unifying View', in B. G. Buchanan and D. C. Wilkins (eds), Readings in Knowledge Acquisition
and Learning: Automating the Construction and Improvement of Expert Systems, Kaufmann, San
Mateo, CA, pp. 539-555.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e460a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e464" publication-type="other">
Nagao, M.: 1989, Machine Translation. How Far Can It Go? Oxford University Press, Oxford.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e471a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e475" publication-type="other">
Nagao, M., J. Tsujii, and J. Nakamura: 1986, 'Machine Translation from Japanese to English',
Proceedings of the IEEE 74, 993-1012.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e485a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e489" publication-type="other">
Nunberg, C, I. A. Sag, and T. Wasow: 1994, 'Idioms', Language 70, 491-538.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e496a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e500" publication-type="other">
Nyberg, E. and T. Mitamura: 1997, 'A Real-Time MT System for Translating Broadcast Captions',
MT Summit VI, Machine Translation Past Present Future, San Diego, CA, pp. 51-57.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e510a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e514" publication-type="other">
Popowich, F.: 1996, 'A Chart Generator for Shake and Bake Machine Translation', in C. McCalla
(ed.), Advances in Artificial Intelligence - 11th Biennial Conference of the Canadian Society for
Computational Studies of Intelligence, Springer, Berlin, pp. 97-108.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e528a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e532" publication-type="other">
Popowich, F., D. Turcato, O. Laurens, P. McFetridge, J. D. Nicholson, P. McGivern, M. Corzo-Pena,
L. Pidruchney, and S. MacDonald: 1997, 'A Lexicalist Approach to the Translation of Colloquial
Text', Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Theoretical and Methodological Issues
in Machine Translation, Santa Fe, New Mexico, pp. 76-86.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e548a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e552" publication-type="other">
Toole, J., F. Popowich, D. Nicholson, D. Turcato, and P. McFetridge: 1999, 'Explanation-Based
Learning for Machine Translation', Proceedings of the 8th International Conference on Theoret-
ical and Methodological Issues in Machine Translation (TMI99), Chester, U.K., pp. 161-171.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e565a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e569" publication-type="other">
Toole, J., D. Turcato, F. Popowich, D. Fass, and P. McFetridge: 1998 'Time-Constrained Machine
Translation', in D. Farwell, L. Gerber and E. Hovy (eds), Machine Translation and the In-
formation Soup: Third Conference of the Association for Machine Translation in the Americas
AMTA-98, Springer, Berlin, pp. 103-112.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e585a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e589" publication-type="other">
Traum, D. and N. Habash: 2000, 'Generation from Lexical Conceptual Structures', Proceedings of
the Third Workshop on lnterlinguas and Interlingual Approaches, Seattle, Washington.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e599a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e603" publication-type="other">
Turcato, D.: 1998, 'Automatically Creating Bilingual Lexicons for Machine Translation from Bi-
lingual Text', 36th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and 17th
International Conference on Computational Linguistics COLING-ACL'98, Montreal, Quebec,
Canada, pp. 1299-1306.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e619a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e623" publication-type="other">
Turcato, D., O. Laurens, P. McFetridge, and F. Popowich: 1997, 'Inflectional Information in Trans-
fer for Lexicalist MT', International Conference: Proceedings Recent Advances in Natural
Language Processing, Tzigov Chark, Bulgaria, pp. 98-103.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e637a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e641" publication-type="other">
Turcato, D., P. McFetridge, F. Popowich, and J. Toole: 1999a, 'A Bootstrap Approach to Auto-
matically Generating Lexical Transfer Rules', Proceedings of MT Summit VII, Singapore, pp.
404-411.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e654a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e658" publication-type="other">
Turcato, D., P. McFetridge, F. Popowich, and J. Toole: 1999b, 'A Unified Example-Based and
Lexicalist Approach to Machine Translation', Proceedings of the 8th International Conference
on Theoretical and Methodological Issues in Machine Translation (TMI99), Chester, U.K., pp.
33-43.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e674a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e678" publication-type="other">
Turcato, D., F. Popowich, P. McFetridge, and O. Laurens: 1998, 'Reuse of Linguistic Resources in
MT', Proceedings of the First International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation
(LREC-98), Granada, Spain, pp. 1227-1233.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e691a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e695" publication-type="other">
Turcato, D., F. Popowich, P. McFetridge, and J. Toole: 2000a, 'Creating High-Quality, Large-Scale
Bilingual Knowledge Bases Using Minimal Resources', LREC 2000 Second International Con-
ference on Language Resources and Evaluations, Workshop Proceedings: Developing Language
Resources for Minority Languages: Reusability and Strategic Priorities, Athens, Greece, pp.
92-99.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e714a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e718" publication-type="other">
Turcato, D., F. Popowich, P. M. D. Nicholson, and J. Toole: 2000b, 'Pre-Processing Closed Captions
for Machine Translation', Proceedings of the Third Workshop on lnterlinguas and Interlingual
Approaches, Seattle, Washington.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e731a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e735" publication-type="other">
Varela, F. C: 1997, 'Translating Non-Verbal Information in Dubbing', in F. Poyatos (ed.), Nonverbal
Communication and Translation, John Benjamins, Amsterdam, pp. 315-326.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d144193e746a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d144193e750" publication-type="other">
Whitelock, P.: 1994, 'Shake and Bake Translation', in C. Rupp, M. Rosner, and R. Johnson (eds),
Constraints, Language and Computation, Academic Press, London, pp. 339-359.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      </back>
</article>
