<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26794464</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Non-Standard Responses to Taxation: Tax Salience and Tax Morale</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Attending to Inattention</article-title>
            <subtitle>Identiacation of Deadweight Loss under Non-Salient Taxes</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Brusco</surname>
                  <given-names>Giacomo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Glass</surname>
                  <given-names>Benjamin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">110</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26794387</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>52</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26794464"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Taxes create deadweight loss by distorting consumer choice, so to the extent that consumers perceive taxes to be lower than they really are, deadweight loss declines. Deadweight loss is a convex function of perceived taxes, so its aggregate magnitude depends not only on the average tax misperception, but also on its heterogeneity among consumers. Aggregate data cannot reveal this heterogeneity, yet one can infer lower and upper bounds on deadweight loss relying solely on properties of aggregate demand. Sufficiently rich individual-level data permit identiacation of deadweight loss even with heterogeneous tax misperceptions. Under strong assumptions on the joint distribution of tax salience and preferences, survey data illustrate that tax salience heterogeneity can yield deadweight loss twice as large as one would calculate under the assumption of a homogeneous perceived price. Relaxing these assumptions, even slightly, yields much more destructive results: the unconstrained upper bound of deadweight loss is more than fifty times larger than the lower bound one would compute assuming homogeneous perceptions of price.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Rudolf Beran and Peter Hall. Estimating coeacient distributions in random coeacient regressions. The annals of Statistics, pages 1970{1984, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Rudolf Beran, Andrey Feuerverger, Peter Hall, et al. On nonparametric estimation of intercept and slope distributions in random coeacient regression. The Annals of Statistics, 24(6):2569{2592, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Raj Chetty, Adam Looney, and Kory Kroft. Salience and taxation. NBER Working Paper N. 13330, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Raj Chetty, Adam Looney, and Kory Kroft. Salience and taxation: Theory and evidence.The American Economic Review, 99(4):1145{1177, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Emmanuel Farhi and Xavier Gabaix. Optimal taxation with behavioral agents. NBERWorking Paper N. 21525, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Amy Finkelstein. Ez-tax: Tax salience and tax rates. Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Jeremy T Fox. A note on nonparametric identiacation of distributions of random coeacients in multinomial choice models. NBER Working Paper No. 23621, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Xavier Gabaix. A sparsity-based model of bounded rationality. Quarterly Journal of Economics, 129(4):1661 1710, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Kelly Sims Gallagher and Erich Muehlegger. Giving green to get green? incentives and consumer adoption of hybrid vehicle technology. Journal of Environmental Economics and Management, 61(1):1{15, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Jacob Goldin. Optimal tax salience. Journal of Public Economics, 131:115{123, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Jacob Goldin and Tatiana Homono . Smoke gets in your eyes: cigarette tax salience and regressivity. American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 5(1), 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Stefan Hoderlein, Jussi Klemel&#x7f;a, and Enno Mammen. Analyzing the random coeacient model nonparametrically. Econometric Theory, 26(3):804{837, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Harvey S Rosen. Tax illusion and the labor supply of married women. The Review of Economics and Statistics, pages 167{172, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Dmitry Taubinsky and Alex Rees-Jones. Attention variation and welfare: theory and evidence from a tax salience experiment. forthcoming at Review of Economic Studies, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Consumer’s decision under limited attention in Gabaix’s model. The solid line represents the consumer’s real budget constraint. For any chosen point c<sup>s</sup> on a convex indifference curve, one can always find a supporting hyperplane, represented by the dotted line, that rationalizes the point as a budget line. Source for image: Gabaix (2014)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Welfare effects from the imposition of a non-salient tax.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>The consumer in (a) is worse off than in (b), although she is subject to a lower tax</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Compensating variation and Tax Revenue for each type in each scenario. Total deadweight loss is the weighted average of compensating variation in excess of tax revenue.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>A graphical illustration of Lemma 2. As long as demand is weakly decreasing, dwl(p′) cannot be smaller than dwl(p) minus (plus) the orange rectangle.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Pre-slide for figure 6</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Pre-slide for figure 7</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>A graphical illustration of Theorem 1. When one picks p̂<sup>s</sup> as to make the change in demand equal for the consumer in (a) and in (b), the decrease in dwl for the consumer in (a) (orange) must be at least as large as the increase in dwl for the consumer in (b) (green).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>A graphical illustration of Theorem 2. The watershed price p̂<sup>s</sup> is picked to make the change in demand equal for the consumer in (a) and in (b). As long as we are dealing with weakly decreasing demand functions, the increase in deadweight loss for (a) is at least as big as the green box, while the decrease in deadweight loss for (b) is at most as big as the orange box. By assigning a perceived price of p̄ + m̄τ to the consumer in (a) and p̄ to the consumer in (b), we have increased aggregate deadweight loss holding aggregate demand constant.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Estimated upper bound depending on the econometrician’s choice of m̄. Error bars are based on the 5<sup>th</sup> and 95<sup>th</sup> percentiles of 10,000 bootstrap replications.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Estimating m̂ with several sets of controls, following the speciacations in Chetty et al. (2009) in the context of a linear model.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Estimating m̂ following the strategy of CLK (2009) in the context of a linear model. As in CLK, we use nominal excise tax rate divided by the average price of a case of beer from 1970 to 2003 as an IV for excise tax to eliminate tax-rate variation coming from inflation erosion. Next, we run the same regression in 3-year differences. Next, we run it only for states where food is exempt from sales-tax, to address concerns about whether consumers react differently to changes in the two taxes only because sales taxes apply to a broad set of goods. Finally, the last column addresses the concern that beer taxes may induce substition with other alcoholic products, biasing the coefficient on excise tax relative to the one on sales tax. It shows that beer excise taxes have no discernable effect on the share of ethanol consumed from beer.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Estimating m̂ based on the intensive response of cigarette consumption to sales taxes (not included in sticker price) and excise taxes (included in the sticker price). The specifications are a linearized version of the specifications in Goldin and Homonoff (2013).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>We report regression results directly from Table 1 of Rosen (1976).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
