<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285095</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Dynamic Downsizing Gasoline Demonstrator</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Bassett</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>MAHLE Powertrain Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hall</surname>
                  <given-names>Jonathan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>MAHLE Powertrain Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Cains</surname>
                  <given-names>Tony</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>MAHLE Powertrain Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Underwood</surname>
                  <given-names>Mark</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>MAHLE Powertrain Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Wall</surname>
                  <given-names>Richard</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Aeristech Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>June 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285080</issue-id>
         <fpage>884</fpage>
         <lpage>891</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285095"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Gasoline engine downsizing is already established as a technology for reducing vehicle CO₂ emissions. Further benefits are possible through more aggressive downsizing, however, the tradeoff between the CO₂ reduction achieved and vehicle drivability limits the level of engine downsizing currently adopted by vehicle manufacturers. This paper will present the latest results achieved from a very heavily downsized engine, and resulting demonstrator vehicle, featuring eSupercharging in combination with a conventional turbocharger.</p>
            <p>The original 1.2 litre, 3-cylinder, MAHLE downsizing engine has been re-configured to enable a specific power output in excess of 160 kW/litre. Of key importance is a cost effective, efficient and flexible boosting system. The Aeristech eSupercharger, operating at 48 V, enables the transient response and low speed torque to be more than recovered, enabling both very high specific output and specific torque characteristic with excellent transient response and drive-ability characteristics, clearly demonstrating eSupercharging as a key technology for enabling further engine downsizing.</p>
            <p>The resulting heavily downsized engine has been installed into a demonstrator vehicle that also features an advanced 48 V lead-carbon battery pack and a 48 V belt-driven integrated starter generator (BISG). The battery and BISG have been selected to enable the continuous high-output (6 kW) operation of the eSupercharger to support prolonged operation of the engine at low speed and high-torque output.</p>
            <p>The fuel consumption of the resulting demonstrator vehicle has been analysed over a number of drive-cycles and the benefits of the downsized engine in conjunction with the complete mild-hybrid system have been assessed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Monitoring of CO2 emissions from passenger cars: Summary data for 2014”, European Environmental Agency http://www.eea.europa.eu/dataand- maps/data/co2-cars-emission-8 (last accessed 15th March 2016).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zacharof, N., Tietge, U. and Mock, P., “CO2 emissions from new passenger cars in the EU: Car manufacturers’ performance in 2014”, International Council on Clean Transportation (ICCT) Berlin 2015. http://www.theicct.org/sites/default/files/publications/ICCTbriefing_EUCO2_201507.pdf (last accessed 2nd September 2016)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mock, P., German, J., Bandivadekar, A., Riemersma, I., Ligterink, N. and Lambrecht, U., “From laboratory to road: A comparison of official and ‘real-world’ fuel consumption and CO2 values for cars in Europe and the United States”, International Council on Clean Transportation (ICCT), Berlin 2013. http://www.theicct.org/sites/default/files/publications/ICCT_LabToRoad_20130527.pdf (last accessed 2nd September 2016)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Report of the Working Party on Pollution and Energy (GRPE) on its 65th session, ECE/TRANS/WP.29/GRPE/65, Geneva 2013. http://www.unece.org/fileadmin/DAM/trans/doc/2013/wp29grpe/ECE-TRANSWP29- GRPE-65e.pdf (last accessed 2nd September 2016)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reducing CO2 emissions from passenger cars, European Commission: http://ec.europa.eu/clima/policies/transport/vehicles/cars/index_en.htm (last accessed 2nd September 2016)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fraser, N., Blaxill, H., Lumsden, G., and Bassett, M., “Challenges for Increased Efficiency through Gasoline Engine Downsizing,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):991–1008, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1053.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bandel, W., Fraidl, G., Kapus, P., Sikinger, H. , “The Turbocharged GDI Engine: Boosted Synergies for High Fuel Economy Plus Ultra-low Emission,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1266, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atkins, M. and Koch, C., “A Well-to-Wheel Comparison of Several Powertrain Technologies,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0081, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0081.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hancock, D., Fraser, N., Jeremy, M., Sykes, R. , “A New 3 Cylinder 1.2l Advanced Downsizing Technology Demonstrator Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0611, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0611.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lumsden, G., OudeNijeweme, D., Fraser, N., and Blaxill, H., “Development of a Turbocharged Direct Injection Downsizing Demonstrator Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1420–1432, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1503.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Korte, V., Rueckauf J., Harms K, Miersch J., Brandt M. Muenz S. and Rauscher M., “MAHLE-Bosch Demonstrator Vehicle for Advanced Downsizing”, 19th Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technology, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aeristech’s 48 V 10 kW eSupercharger datasheet: http://www.aeristech. co.uk/wp-content/uploads/A-Sample-2-English.pdf (last accessed 2nd September 2016)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graf, F., Deinhard, S. and Brockerhoff, P., “AES - An Approach to an Integrated 12 V/48 V Energy Storage Solution”, 24th Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technology, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hubert, A. and Bloore, P., “Benefits of a Switched-Reluctance E-Motor for Mild Hybrid 48 V Applications”, 24th Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technology, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baker D., “NAWA Engine Benchmarking Report”, MAHLE Powertrain internal report No. NAWA0102252RD. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gottschalk, W., Lezius, U., and Mathusall, L., “Investigations on the Potential of a Variable Miller Cycle for SI Knock Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1122, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mahr, B., Taylor, J. and Bassett, M., “Kraftstoffverbrauchsvorteile im realen Fahrbetrieb durch Abgasrückführung bei modernen Downsizing- Motoren”, 7. MTZ-Fachtagung, Der Antrieb von morgen, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fraidl, G., Kapus, P., Melde, H., Loesch, S., Schoeffmann, W., Sorger, H., Weissback, J. and Wolkerstorfer, J., “Variable Compression Ratio - in a Technology Competition?”, 37th International Vienna Motor Symposium, Vienna 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">VW Golf GTi published CO2 figures: http://www.volkswagen.co.uk/new/golf-gti-vii/which-model/engines/overview (last accessed 2nd September 2016)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
