<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">15</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000382</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40007080</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Janus-III Translation System: Speech-to-Speech Translation in Multiple Domains</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Lori</given-names>
                  <surname>Levin</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alon</given-names>
                  <surname>Lavie</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Monika</given-names>
                  <surname>Woszczyna</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Donna</given-names>
                  <surname>Gates</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Marsal</given-names>
                  <surname>Gavaldà</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Detlef</given-names>
                  <surname>Koll</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alex</given-names>
                  <surname>Waibel</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2000</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>3</fpage>
         <lpage>25</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2001 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40007080"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>The Janus-III system translates spoken languages in limited domains. The current research focus is on expanding beyond tasks involving a single limited semantic domain to significantly broader and richer domains. To achieve this goal, The MT components of our system have been engineered to build and manipulate multi-domain parse lattices that are based on modular grammars for multiple semantic domains. This approach yields solutions to several problems including multidomain disambiguation, segmentation of spoken utterances into sentence units, modularity of system design, and re-use of earlier systems with incompatible output.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>JRTk</kwd>
            <kwd>multi-domain</kwd>
            <kwd>robust parsing</kwd>
            <kwd>semantic grammars</kwd>
            <kwd>SOUP</kwd>
            <kwd>speech translation</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d1194262e255a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e259" publication-type="other">
Black, Alan W., Paul Taylor and Richard Caley: 1999, The Festival Speech Synthesis System: System
Documentation, Human Communciation Research Centre, University of Edinburgh, Scotland;
avaliable at http: //www. cstr.ed.ac.uk/projects/festival/manual. 17th June 1999.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e272a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e276" publication-type="other">
Danieli, Morena and Elisabetta Gerbino: 1995, 'Metrics for Evaluating Dialogue Strategies in a
Spoken Language System', Proceedings of the 1995 AAAI Spring Symposium on Empirical
Methods in Discourse Interpretation and Generation, Stanford, California, pp. 34-39.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e289a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e293" publication-type="other">
Dorr, Bonnie J.: 1994. 'Machine Translation Divergences: A Formal Description and Proposed
Solution', Computational Linguistics 20, 597-633.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e303a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e307" publication-type="other">
Frederking, Robert and Sergei Nirenberg: 1994, 'Three Heads are Better than One', 4th Conference
on Applied Natural Language Processing, Stuttgart, Germany, pp. 95-100.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e318a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e322" publication-type="other">
Frederking, Robert, Alexander Rudnicky and Christopher Hogan: 1997, 'Interactive Speech Trans-
lation in the DIPLOMAT Project', Spoken Language Translation: Proceedings of a Workshop
Sponsored by the Association for Computational Linguistics and by the European Network in
Language and Speech (ELSNET), Madrid, Spain, pp. 61-66.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e338a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e342" publication-type="other">
Frederking, Robert, Alexander Rudnicky, Christopher Hogan and Kevin Lenzo: 2000, 'Interactive
Speech Translation in the Diplomat Project', this volume.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e352a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e356" publication-type="other">
Gates, Donna, Alon Lavie, Lori Levin, Marsal Gavaldà, Monika Woszczyna and Puming Zhan: 1997,
'End-to-End Evaluation in JANUS: a Speech-to-Speech Translation System', in E. Maier, M.
Mast and S. Luperfoy (eds), Dialogue Processing in Spoken Language Systems, Berlin, Springer
Verlag, pp. 195-206.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e372a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e376" publication-type="other">
Gavaldà, Marsal: 2000, 'A Parser for Real-world Spontaneous Speech', IWPT 2000: Sixth Inter-
national Workshop on Parsing Technologies, Trento, Italy. Paper available (28 Feb 2001) at
http: //www.cs.emu.edu/~marsal/papers/iwpt2000.html.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e389a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e393" publication-type="other">
Lavie, Alon, Lori Levin, Yan Qu, Alex Waibel, Donna Gates, Marsal Gavalda, Laura Mayfield and
Maite Taboada: 1996, 'Dialogue Processing in a Conversational Speech Translation System',
Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Spoken Language Processing (ICSLP-96),
Philadelphia, PA, pp. 554-557.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e409a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e413" publication-type="other">
Levin, Lori, Donna Gates, Alon Lavie and Alex Waibel: 1998, 'An Interlingua Based on Domain
Actions for Machine Translation of Task-Oriented Dialogues', Proceedings of the International
Conference on Spoken Language Processing (ICSLP'98), Sydney, Australia, pp. 1 155-1 158.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e427a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e431" publication-type="other">
Levin, Lori, Oren Glickman, Yan Qu, Donna Gates, Alon Lavie, Carolyn P. Rosé, Carol Van Ess-
Dykema and Alex Waibel: 1995, 'Using Context in Machine Translation of Spoken Language',
Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference on Theoretical and Methodological Issues in
Machine Translation, TMI95, Leuven, Belgium, pp. 173-187.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e447a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e451" publication-type="other">
Levin, Lori and Sergei Nirenburg: 1994, 'The Correct Place of Lexical Semantics in Interlingual
MT', COLING 94: The 15th International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Kyoto,
Japan, pp. 349-355.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e464a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e468" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, Sergei (ed.): 1995, The Pangloss Mark III Machine Translation System, Joint Technical
Report CMU-CMT-95-145, Computing Research Laboratory (New Mexico State University, Las
Cruces, NM), Center for Machine Translation (Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA),
Information Sciences Institute (University of Southern California, Marina del Rey, CA).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e484a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e488" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, Sergei, Jaime Carbonell, Masaru Tomita and Kenneth Goodman: 1992, Machine Trans-
lation: A Knowledge-Based Approach. San Mateo, California: Morgan Kaufmann.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e498a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e502" publication-type="other">
Qu, Yan, Barbara Di Eugenio, Alon Lavie, Lori Levin and Carolyn P. Rosé: 1997, 'Minimizing
Cumulative Error in Discourse Context', in E. Maier, M. Mast and S. Luperfoy (eds), Dialogue
Processing in Spoken Language Systems, Berlin, Springer Verlag, pp. 171-182.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e515a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e519" publication-type="other">
Qu, Yan, Carolyn P. Rosé and Barbara Di Eugenio: 1996, 'Using Discourse Predictions for Ambigu-
ity Resolution', COLING-96: The 16th International Conference on Computational Linguistics,
Copenhagen, Denmark, 359-363.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e533a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e537" publication-type="other">
Rosé, Carolyn Penstein, Barbara Di Eugenio, Lori S. Levin and Carol Van Ess-Dykema: 1995, 'Dis-
course Processing of Dialogues with Multiple Threads', 33 rd Annual Meeting of the Association
for Computational Linguistics, Cambridge, Massachusetts, pp. 31-38.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e550a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e554" publication-type="other">
Ruland, Tobias, C. J. Rupp, Jörg Spilker, Hans Weber and Karsten L. Worm: 1998, Making the Most
of Multiplicity: A Multi-Parser Multi-Strategy Architecture for the Robust Processing of Spoken
Language, also Proceedings of the International Conference on Spoken Language Processing
(ICSLP'98), Sydney, Australia, pp. 1167-1170.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e570a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e574" publication-type="other">
Thomas, Kavita: 1999, 'Designing a Task-Based Evaluation Methodology for a Spoken Machine
Translation System', 37th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics,
College Park, Maryland, pp. 569-572.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e587a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e591" publication-type="other">
Tomita, Masaru: 1986, Efficient Parsing for Natural Language, Boston, MA: Kluwer.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e598a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e602" publication-type="other">
Tomita, Masaru and Eric H. Nyberg: 1988, Generation Kit and Transformation Kit, Version
3.2: User's Manual, Technical Report CMU-CMT-88-MEMO, Carnegie Mellon University,
Pittsburgh, PA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e615a1310">
               
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e621" publication-type="other">
Walker, Marilyn, D. Litman, C. Kamm and A. Abella: 1997, 'PARADISE: A Framework for Eval-
uating Spoken Dialogue Agents', 35th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational
Linguistics and 8th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational
Linguistics, Madrid, Spain, pp. 271-280.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e638a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e642" publication-type="other">
Ward, Wayne: 1990, 'The CMU Air Travel Information Service: Understanding Spontaneous
Speech', DARPA Workshop on Speech and Natural Language Processing, Hidden Valley, PA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e652a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e656" publication-type="other">
Woszczyna, Monika: 1998, Fast Speaker Independent Large Vocabulary Continuous Speech Recog-
nition, Ph.D. thesis, Fakultat fur Informatik, Universität Karlsruhe, Germany.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e666a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e670" publication-type="other">
Woszczyna, Monika, N. Aoki-Waibel, Finn Dag Buø, Noah B. Coccaro, K. Horiguchi, Thomas
Kemp, Alon Lavie, Arthur McNair, Thomas S. Polzin, Ivica Rogina, C. P. Rosé, Tanja Schultz,
B. Suhm, M. Tomita and Alex Waibel: 1994, 'Janus 93: Towards Spontaneous Speech Transla-
tion', Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing
(ICASSP'94), Adelaide, Australia, Vol. 1, pp. 345-348.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1194262e689a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1194262e693" publication-type="other">
Woszczyna, Monika, N. Coccaro, A. Eisele, A. Lavie, A. McNair, T. Polzin, I. Rogina, C. P. Rosé, T.
Sloboda, M. Tomita, J. Tsutsumi, N. Aoki-Waibel, A. Waibel and W. Ward: 1993, 'Recent Ad-
vances in JANUS: a Speech Translation System', Eurospeech: Proceedings of the 3rd European
Conference on Speech, Communication and Technology, Berlin, Germany, pp. 1295-1298.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
