<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">26</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</issue>
         <issue-id>i24464762</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24464769</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Indexing Executive Compensation Contracts</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ingolf</given-names>
                  <surname>Dittmann</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ernst</given-names>
                  <surname>Maug</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Oliver G.</given-names>
                  <surname>Spalt</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>3182</fpage>
         <lpage>3224</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24464769"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We analyze the efficiency of indexing executive pay by calibrating the standard compensation model to a large sample of U.S. CEOs. The benefits from indexing the strike price of options are small, and fully indexing all options would increase compensation costs by 50% for most firms. Indexing has several effects with overall ambiguous outcome; the quantitatively most important effect is to reduce incentives, because indexed options pay off when CEOs' marginal utility is low. The results also hold if CEOs can extract rents and extend to the case of indexing shares. Our findings may justify the common practice of "pay-for-luck."</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1e238a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e245" publication-type="other">
Murphy (1999) reports that only one out of 1,000 firms in his sample had an indexed option plan. See Meulbroek
(2002) for the case of one company that used indexed options. Other forms to use indexation for limiting
windfalls from strong stock market performance are also rare. For example, Bettis et al. (2010) find that only 35
of the 983 firm-years in their sample use the stock market index or the stock performance of industry peers for
performance-vesting conditions (see their Table 2, Panel D). Jenter and Kanaan (forthcoming) show that CEO
turnover becomes more likely after poor market or industry performance, which is inconsistent with the notion
that firms shield CEOs' human capital from market risk. We comment in Section 2 on the difference between
indexing and relative performance evaluation; there is some evidence that the latter does occur in practice.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e274a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e281" publication-type="other">
Bebchuk and Fried (2004) sparked a controversy on the efficiency properties of a range of compensation
arrangements, which has yielded numerous surveys and policy proposals. See, e.g., Core and Guay (2010),
Edmans and Gabaix (2009), and Weisbach (2007) for surveys.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e294a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e301" publication-type="other">
See Rappaport and Nodine (1999), Johnson and Tian (2000), Hall and Murphy (2000, 2002), and Bebchuk and
Fried (2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e311a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e318" publication-type="other">
There is a fourth effect, which is empirically of minor importance and therefore not emphasized here. It implies
that indexed options retain some exposure to market risk.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e329a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e336" publication-type="other">
See the belief in "lower costs" in the opening quotes as an example for a focus on the first effect and Murphy
(2002) as a statement of the third effect.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e346a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e353" publication-type="other">
See, e.g., Lambert et al. ( 1991 ), Hall and Murphy (2000,2002), Himmelberg and Hubbard (2000), Hall and Knox
(2004), and Oyer and Schaefer (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e363a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e370" publication-type="other">
We still require additivity in the utility function. See, e.g., Edmans et al. (2009) for a model that uses a
multiplicative modeling approach.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e380a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e387" publication-type="other">
For the incentive compatibility constraint, we assume that the first-order approach is satisfied. A sufficient
condition is that the optimization problem is globally concave, and this is the case if the cost function C(e)
is sufficiently convex and the production function Po(e) is sufficiently concave. Dittmann and Maug (2007)
numerically check whether the optimal contract induces the CEO to choose less effort than the observed contract.
We do not follow their approach here, because our main result is that the improvement of the optimal contract
over the observed contract is only marginal, so that we do not suggest that firms should switch to the optimal
contract.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e413a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e420" publication-type="other">
Compared with the setup of Johnson and Tian (2000), we ignore the possibility of deviations from the security
market line here. In their notation, we set a=0.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e430a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e437" publication-type="other">
See also the technical document by Dittmann et al. (2011 ), which explains the technical aspects of their calibration
algorithm in more detail.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e448a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e455" publication-type="other">
Note that for the case of risk neutrality where V(Wj)=Wj, UP PS reduces to the more familiar pay-for-
performance sensitivity, which in our case is equal tows+n&lt;?(l — \Jr)N(di)+nQ}JrN(d^ndx); N(d\ ) and N(d*"dx)
denote the delta of conventional options and indexed options, respectively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e468a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e475" publication-type="other">
We use similar steps to Dittmann and Maug (2007) and Dittmann et al. (2010) here. Note that this step effectively
substitutes out the production function P(e) and the cost function C(e) and permits us to proceed without
specifying their functional forms. As a consequence, we can only analyze the structure of the contract and not
the overall level of pay, which is given from the observed contract.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e491a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e498" publication-type="other">
There is no closed-form solution of the CEO's portfolio problem, and we would therefore have to work with a
nested optimization problem where the firm first chooses the optimal contract and the CEO then adjusts her private
portfolio accordingly. Also, the firm would have to anticipate the CEO's actions, so that the inner optimization
problem would have to be solved at every point where the outer optimization problem is evaluated. It is unlikely
that such a model can be solved in a reasonable amount of time with today's computing power.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e517a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e524" publication-type="other">
We take into account the fact that most CEOs exercise their stock options before maturity by multiplying the
maturities of the individual option grants by 0.7 before calculating the representative option (see Huddart and
Lang 1996 and Carpenter 1998). In these calculations, we use the stock-return volatility from ExecuComp and,
for the risk-free rate, the U.S. Government bond yield with five-year maturity from January 2006. Data on risk-
free rates were obtained from the Federal Reserve Board's website. For CEOs who do not have any options, we
set T=1 (10-year maturity multiplied by 0.7) as this is the typical maturity for newly granted options.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e547a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e554" publication-type="other">
Different strands of the literature use different values of relative risk aversion, and there is no consensus on this
subject. Ait-Sahalia and Lo (2000) survey the research on this topic, which supports values between 0 and 55.
The macroeconomic literature typically uses higher values (see Campbell et al. 1997, chapter 8, for a survey and
discussion). The compensation literature often uses lower values. For example, Murphy (1999) uses 1, 2, and
3, and Hall and Murphy (2002) use 2 and 3. Dittmann et al. (2010) calibrate a loss-aversion model and show
that it fits compensation data well. The degree of relative risk aversion implied by their analysis varies between
0.2 and 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e580a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e587" publication-type="other">
Consider an indexed option with a strike price of 8 on stock with a current price of 10 when the index value
equals 100. Doubling the index value to 200 implies that the strike price and the stock price both double to 20
and 16, respectively. (Assume beta is 1.) Then the payoff of the indexed option doubles from 2 to 4.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e601a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e608" publication-type="other">
The CEO's wealth function W(Pj) is not everywhere differentiable, but we could approximate it with a
differentiable function that is arbitrarily close to W{Pj) and everywhere differentiable. See Ross (2004) for
a similar exposition strategy.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e621a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e628" publication-type="other">
More precisely, W'/W represents the percentage change in pay relative to a dollar change in firm value.
Conventional measures of pay-for-performance sensitivity refer to the dollar (percentage) change in compensation
compared with the dollar (percentage) change in firm value. See Edmans et al. (2009) for a detailed discussion
of different measures of incentives.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e644a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e651" publication-type="other">
An effect related to this one has been noted before by Gjesdal (1982) and Arnott and Stiglitz (1988), who show
that increasing the noise of the performance measure may improve incentives if the first-order condition is convex
in the performance measure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e664a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e671" publication-type="other">
In this special case when y can be neglected, the marginal indirect utility function is convex (concave) only if
the convexity of the wage function is increasing (decreasing).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e681a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e688" publication-type="other">
For these calculations, we convert all options into restricted shares so that the incentive compatibility constraint
remains satisfied.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e698a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e705" publication-type="other">
The utility-adjusted delta takes into account the valuation of states by the CEO as opposed to the valuation by
the market. The concept has also been used by Hall and Murphy (2002) and Dittmann and Maug (2007). Note
that the utility-adjusted delta is related to but different from UPPS, which applies to the whole contract and not
just to the options. For a CEO who has no shares (njts=nNr=Q) the two concepts coincide. An increase in
the strike price has a stronger effect on the utility-adjusted delta compared with the risk-neutral delta because
marginal utility is declining.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e729a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e736" publication-type="other">
See the epigraph quote from Alfred Rappaport.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e743a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e750" publication-type="other">
Meulbroek (2001) also observes that indexed options do not do what they promise, because they do not remove
all market exposure, and she suggests an alternative security that is similar to options on indexed stock. However,
she does not observe that this effect is relatively minor compared with the other disadvantages of indexed options.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e763a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e770" publication-type="other">
Hall and Murphy (2000,2002) also focus on the probability of options finishing in the money to analyze variations
in the strike price.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e780a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e787" publication-type="other">
Bertrand and Mullainathan (2001) argue that the use of relative performance evaluation is correlated with the
quality of corporate governance. We still drop the participation constraint for all CEOs in our sample and not
just for the CEOs in firms with poor corporate governance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e800a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e807" publication-type="other">
Our analytic tools cannot determine optimal levels of indexation for stock and options independently, because
indexing stock and indexing options are very close substitutes. There are many combinations of the degrees of
indexation for stock and options that are approximately equivalent with respect to the objective function we
maximize.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e823a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e830" publication-type="other">
In unreported results we also examine indexation of restricted stock in an all-share contract that does not contain
any options. Dittmann and Maug (2007) show that this contract is optimal for almost all CEOs in the CRRA-
lognormal model if options are restricted to be non-negative. We find results that are qualitatively very similar.
In fact, savings from indexation are even lower (i.e., more negative) for the all-share contract.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e847a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e854" publication-type="other">
Dittmann and Maug (2007) show that the results of Hemmer et al. (1999) obtain with a value of relative risk
aversion of 0.5, as Hemmer et al. (1999) propose, but that their claim is not robust to choosing higher levels of
risk aversion. The loss-aversion model of Dittmann et al. (2010) implies that the risk premium paid to the CEO
is consistent with levels of relative risk aversion that are generally lower than one. The model of Dittmann and
Yu (2011) can potentially accommodate higher risk premiums by assuming that the benefits from risk taking are
very large, but also obtains its best fit if relative risk aversion is only 0.5.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e877a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e884" publication-type="other">
It might also be possible to justify our effort assumption by assuming that the marginal benefit of the CEO's
effort for the firm is sufficiently high, relying on a similar argument as Edmans and Gabaix (2011).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1e903a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e907" publication-type="other">
Aggarwal, R. K., and A. A. Samwick. 1999. Executive compensation, strategic competition, and relative
performance evaluation: Theory and evidence. Journal of Finance 54(6): 1999-2043.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e917a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e921" publication-type="other">
Ait-Sahalia, Y., and A. W. Lo. 2000. Non-parametric risk management and implied risk aversion. Journal of
Econometrics 94:9-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e931a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e935" publication-type="other">
Antle, R., and A. Smith. 1986. An empirical investigation of the relative performance evaluation of corporate
executives. Journal of Accounting Research 24(1): 1-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e945a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e949" publication-type="other">
Arnott, R., and J. E. Stiglitz. 1988. Randomization with asymmetric information. RAND Journal of Economics
19(3):344—62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e960a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e964" publication-type="other">
Bebchuk, L. A., and J. M. Fried. 2004. Pay without performance: The unfulfilled promise of executive
compensation. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e974a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e978" publication-type="other">
Bertrand, M., and S. Mullainathan. 2001. Are CEOs rewarded for luck? The ones without principals are.
Quarterly Journal of Economics 116(3):901—32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e988a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e992" publication-type="other">
Bettis, J. C., J. Bizjak, J. L. Coles, and S. L. Kalpathy. 2010. Stock and option grants with performance-based
vesting provisions. Review of Financial Studies 23(10):3849-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1002a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1006" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., A. W. Lo, and A. C. MacKinlay. 1997. The econometrics of financial markets. Princeton, NJ:
Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1016a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1020" publication-type="other">
Carpenter, J. N. 1998. The exercise and valuation of executive stock options. Journal of Financial Economics
48(2): 127-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1030a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1034" publication-type="other">
Chaigneau, P. 2012. On the value of improved informativeness. Working Paper, HEC Montreal.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1042a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1046" publication-type="other">
Core, J. E., and W. R. Guay. 2002. Estimating the value of stock option portfolios and their sensitivities to price
and volatility. Journal of Accounting Research 40(3):613-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1056a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1060" publication-type="other">
Core, J. E., and W. R. Guay. 2010. Is CEO pay too high and are incentives too low? A wealth-based contracting
framework. Academy of Management Perspectives 24(1):5—19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1070a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1074" publication-type="other">
Diamond, D. W., and R. E. Verrecchia. 1982. Optimal managerial contracts and equilibrium security prices.
Journal of Finance 37(2):275-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1084a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1088" publication-type="other">
Dittmann, I., and E. Maug. 2007. Lower salaries and no options? On the optimal structure of executive pay.
Journal of Finance 62(1):303—43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1098a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1102" publication-type="other">
Dittmann, I., E. Maug, and O. G Spalt. 2010. Sticks or carrots? Optimal CEO compensation when managers are
loss averse. Journal of Finance 65(6):2015-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1112a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1116" publication-type="other">
Dittmann, I., and K.-C. Yu. 2011. Providing effort and risk-taking incentives: The optimal compensation structure
for CEOs. Working Paper, Erasmus University Rotterdam.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1127a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1131" publication-type="other">
Dittmann, I., D. Zhang, E. G Maug, and O. G Spalt. 2011. Note on the calibration of executive compensation
models. Working Paper, Erasmus University Rotterdam.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1141a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1145" publication-type="other">
Dye, R. A. 1992. Relative performance evaluation and project selection. Journal of Accounting Research
30(l):27-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1155a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1159" publication-type="other">
Edmans, A., and X. Gabaix. 2009. Is CEO pay really inefficient? A survey of new optimal contracting theories.
European Financial Management 15(3):486-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1169a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1173" publication-type="other">
Edmans, A., and X. Gabaix. 2011. Tractability in incentive contracting. Review of Financial Studies
24(9):2865-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1183a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1187" publication-type="other">
Edmans, A., X. Gabaix, and A. Landier. 2009. A multiplicative model of optimal CEO incentives in market
equilibrium. Review of Financial Studies 22( 12):4881—917.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1197a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1201" publication-type="other">
Faulkender, M. W., and J. Yang. 2010. Inside the black box: The role and composition of compensation peer
groups. Journal of Financial Economics 96(2):257-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1212a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1216" publication-type="other">
Garvey, G, and T. Milbourn. 2003. Incentive compensation when executives can hedge the market: Evidence of
relative performance evaluation in the cross section. Journal of Finance 58(4): 1557-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1226a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1230" publication-type="other">
Gjesdal, F. 1982. Information and incentives: The agency information problem. The Review of Economic Studies
49(3):373-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1240a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1244" publication-type="other">
Gopalan, R., T. T. Milbourn, and F. Song. 2010. Strategic flexibility and the optimality of pay for sector
performance. Review of Financial Studies 23(5):2060-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1254a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1258" publication-type="other">
Göx, R. 2008. Tax incentives for inefficient executive pay and reward for luck. Review of Accounting Studies
13(4):452-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1268a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1272" publication-type="other">
Grossman, S. J., and O. D. Hart. 1983. An analysis of the principal-agent problem. Econometrica 51(1):
7-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1282a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1286" publication-type="other">
Hall, B. J., and T. A. Knox. 2004. Underwater options and the dynamics of executive pay-to-performance
sensitivities. Journal of Accounting Research 42(2):365-412.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1297a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1301" publication-type="other">
Hall, B. J., and K. J. Murphy. 2000. Optimal exercise prices for executive stock options. American Economic
Review 90(2):209-14.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1311a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1315" publication-type="other">
Hall, B. J., and K. J. Murphy. 2002. Stock options for undiversified executives. Journal of Accounting and
Economics 33(2):3-42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1325a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1329" publication-type="other">
Hemmer, T., O. Kim, and R. E. Verrecchia. 1999. Introducing convexity into optimal compensation contracts.
Journal of Accounting and Economics 28(3): 307-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1339a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1343" publication-type="other">
Himmelberg, C. R, and R. G Hubbard. 2000. Incentive pay and the market for CEOs: An analysis of pay-for-
performance sensitivity. Working Paper, Columbia University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1353a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1357" publication-type="other">
Holmstrom, B. 1979. Moral hazard and observability. Bell Journal of Economics 10:74-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1364a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1368" publication-type="other">
Holmstrom, B. 1982. Moral hazard in teams. Bell Journal of Economics 13:324-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1376a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1380" publication-type="other">
Huddart, S., and M. Lang. 1996. Employee stock option exercises an empirical analysis. Journal of Accounting
and Economics 21(1):5—43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1390a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1394" publication-type="other">
Jenter, D., and F. Kanaan. Forthcoming. CEO turnover and relative performance evaluation. Journal of Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1401a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1405" publication-type="other">
Jin, L. 2002. CEO compensation, diversification, and incentives. Journal of Financial Economics 66(1):
29-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1415a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1419" publication-type="other">
Johnson, S. A., and Y. S. Tian. 2000. Indexed executive stock options. Journal of Financial Economics
57(l):35-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1429a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1433" publication-type="other">
Lambert, R. A., D. F. Larcker, and R. Verrecchia. 1991. Portfolio considerations in valuing executive
compensation. Journal of Accounting Research 29(1): 129-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1443a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1447" publication-type="other">
Maug, E. 2000. The relative performance puzzle. Schmalenbach Business Review 52(1):3—24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1455a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1459" publication-type="other">
Meulbroek, L. K. 2001. Designing an option plan that rewards relative performance: Indexed options revisited.
Working Paper 02-022, Harvard Business School.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1469a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1473" publication-type="other">
Meulbroek, L. K. 2002. Compensation at level 3 communications. Harvard Business School Case 9-202-084.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1480a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1484" publication-type="other">
Murphy, K. J. 1999. Executive compensation. In Handbook of labor economics. Eds. O. Ashenfelter and
D. Card, 2485-563. Amsterdam: North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1494a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1498" publication-type="other">
Murphy, K. J. 2002. Explaining executive compensation: Managerial power vs. the perceived cost of stock
options. University of Chicago Law Review 69:847-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1508a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1512" publication-type="other">
Oyer, P., and S. Schaefer. 2005. Why do some firms give stock options to all employees? An empirical examination
of alternative theories. Journal of Financial Economics 76(1):99—132.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1522a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1526" publication-type="other">
Rappaport, A. 1999. Stock options that don't reward laggards. Wall Street Journal, March 30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1534a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1538" publication-type="other">
Rappaport, A., and T. H. Nodine. 1999. New thinking on how to link executive pay with performance. Harvard
Business Review 77(2):91-101.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1548a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1552" publication-type="other">
Ross, S. A. 2004. Compensation, incentives, and the duality of risk aversion and riskiness. Journal of Finance
59(l):207-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1562a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1566" publication-type="other">
Weisbach, M. S. 2007. Optimal executive compensation versus managerial power: A review of Lucian Bebchuk
and Jesse Fried's Pay without performance: The unfulfilled promise of executive compensation. Journal of
Economic Literature 45(2):419-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


