<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466844</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466847</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investor Attention and Stock Market Volatility</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
                  <surname>Andrei</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
                  <surname>Hasler</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>33</fpage>
         <lpage>72</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466847"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We investigate, in a theoretical framework, the joint role played by investors' attention to news and learning uncertainty in determining asset prices. The model provides two main predictions. First, stock return variance and risk premia increase with both attention and uncertainty. Second, this increasing relationship is quadratic. We empirically test these two predictions, and we show that the data lend support to the increasing relationship. The evidence for a quadratic relationship is mixed. Overall, our study shows theoretically and empirically that both attention and uncertainty are key determinants of asset prices.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1624272e208a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e215" publication-type="other">
The high volatility of the market price of risk is puzzling for asset-pricing models. It is rationalized with
nonstandard preferences (e.g., Campbell and Cochrane 1999, Barberis, Huang, and Santos 2001) or with
intermittent portfolio rebalancing (Chien, Cole, and Lustig 2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e228a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e235" publication-type="other">
See also Peng and Xiong (2006), Mondria (2010), Van Nieuwerburgh and Veldkamp (2010), and Mondria
and Quintana-Domeque (2013) for other studies on limited information-processing capacity and their financial
consequences. On the empirical front, several papers provide evidence of time-varying attention. Lustig and
Verdelhan (2012) compute the number of Google Insight searches for the word "recession" and observe huge
spikes in the search volume in December 2007 and January 2008. Vlastakis and Markellos (2012), Dimpfl and
Jank (2011), and Kita and Wang (2012) find support of countercyclical attention to news.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e258a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e265" publication-type="other">
Other representative papers are Dothan and Feldman (1986), Detemple (1986), Gennotte (1986), Timmermann
(1993), David (1997), Veronesi (1999), Veronesi (2000), Brennan and Xia (2001), Xia (2001), Scheinkman and
Xiong (2003), Dumas, Kurshev, and Uppal (2009), and Ai (2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e278a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e285" publication-type="other">
Consistent with their theoretical model, Van Nieuwerburgh and Veldkamp (2006) show that analyst forecast
errors on the level of nominal GDP are countercyclical. In contrast, we estimate our model on real GDP growth
rates and corresponding analyst forecasts and find support for procyclical analyst forecast errors in this case.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e299a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e306" publication-type="other">
To the best of our knowledge, this specification was first adopted by Dumas, Kurshev, and Uppal (2009). The
alternative would be to assume that the investor observes a noisy signal of the fundamental, dst = ftdt + d Z.
In that case, the variance of the noisy signal would be stochastic and would belong to the interval [0, oo).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e319a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e326" publication-type="other">
Other types of attention have been studied. In the rational inattention literature (Kahneman 1973, Sims 2003),
Peng and Xiong (2006), Kacperczyk, Van Nieuwerburgh, and Veldkamp (2009), and Van Nieuwerburgh and
Veldkamp (2010) study attention-allocation problems when information-processing capacity is limited. Duffie
and Sun (1990), Abel, Eberly, and Panageas (2007), and Rossi (2010) study attention to wealth in the sense
that investors optimally choose not to trade in certain periods. Chien, Cole, and Lustig (2012), Bacchetta and
Wincoop (2010), and Duffie (2010) assume that these periods of inattention are fixed and investigate their impact
on asset prices.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e352a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e359" publication-type="other">
Potential foundations of fluctuating attention to news can be found in Detemple and Kihlstrom (1987), Veldkamp
(2006a,2006b), Kacperczyk, Van Nieuwerburgh, and Veldkamp (2009), Bansal and Shaliastovich (2011), and
Andrei and Hasler (2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e372a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e379" publication-type="other">
See Da, Engelberg, and Gao (2011), Vlastakis and Markellos (2012), Dimpfl and Jank (2011), Kita and Wang
(2012), Chauvet, Gabriel, and Lutz (2012), and Schmidt (2013), among others.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e389a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e396" publication-type="other">
See Andersen, Bollerslev, Diebold, and Vega (2003) for evidence of market reaction to announcement surprises in
the foreign exchange market, Flannery and Protopapadakis (2002) for evidence in the stock market, or Fleming
and Remolona (1999) for evidence in the bond market. See also Brown, Hillegeist, and Lo (2009) for direct
evidence that earnings surprises affects investors' trading decisions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e412a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e419" publication-type="other">
Koijen, Rodriguez, and Sbuelz (2009) build a similar performance index in a dynamic asset allocation problem
to allow for momentum and mean reversion in stock returns. In our case, this index is built directly from the
dividend process in order to capture the recent development of the dividend in a parsimonious way.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e433a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e440" publication-type="other">
Time-varying uncertainty can also arise in the presence of non-Gaussian distributions or when fundamentals
follow regime-switching processes. See Detemple (1991), David (1997), Veronesi (1999), and Timmermann
(2001).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e453a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e460" publication-type="other">
Note that the indirect effect is not contemporaneous; because the uncertainty process y has deterministic dynamics
(see Equation (9) and its interpretation), uncertainty decreases only gradually when attention is high. In other
words, because uncertainty is a "dt" process and attention is driven by a Brownian motion, uncertainty is always
"one step behind" (Xia 2001). This lead-lag relation disconnects uncertainty from short-term movements in
attention, and thus sudden spikes in attention can result in states of high attention and high uncertainty.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e479a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e486" publication-type="other">
Note that / is the long-term mean of /; 0 is the long-term mean of 0; and yss = ~^as+-Ja8 (^2
is the long-term posterior variance under the assumption that fa =0.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e496a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e503" publication-type="other">
More precisely, the Google attention index is built based on the following combination of words: "financial news,"
"economic news," "Wall Street Journal," "Financial Times," "CNN Money," "Bloomberg News," "S&amp;P500,"
"U.S. economy," "stock prices," "stock market," "NYSE," "NASDAQ," "DAX," and "FTSE." Using other
similar words in several combinations provides very similar empirical measures of attention.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e519a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e526" publication-type="other">
The half-life is a measure of the speed of mean-reversion, and it is given by ln(2)/X. For the Bansal and Yaron
(2004) calibration, the half-life is roughly 33 months.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e536a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e543" publication-type="other">
A value of to=4.74 for the exponential moving average means that, at a quarterly frequency, the investor applies
a 69% weighting to the most recent output reading. Then the weights decrease as follows: 21%, 6%, 2%, and so
on.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e557a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e564" publication-type="other">
When we split the data in NBER recessions and expansions, the conditional volatilities of forecasts are 1.98%
and 1.43%, respectively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e574a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e581" publication-type="other">
Specifically, we perform Mincer and Zarnowitz (1969) regressions in the two subsamples (recessions and
expansions); i.e., the realized GDP growth rate is regressed on a constant and its corresponding analyst forecast
in both subsamples. The null hypothesis is that the intercept is equal to zero and the slope is equal to one; i.e.,
the forecast error is conditionally unbiased. The test, which is available upon request, shows that the null cannot
be rejected in recession, whereas it is rejected in expansion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e600a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e607" publication-type="other">
This statement holds when investors acquire information continuously.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e614a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e621" publication-type="other">
We note that in Karlsson, Loewenstein, and Seppi (2009) investors collect information about the value of their
portfolios—attention to wealth—whereas our investors collect information on the fundamental—attention to
news. As such, these two views do not exclude each other but simply suggest that attention to news and attention
to wealth might be inversely related.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e637a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e644" publication-type="other">
We emphasize that in our estimation procedure we only use Google attention data to fit the unconditional variance
of attention. All other moment conditions rely on GDP data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e654a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e661" publication-type="other">
Similar decompositions of variance are presented by David (1997), Veronesi (1999, 2000), David and Veronesi
(2013), and Brennan and Xia (2001).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e672a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e679" publication-type="other">
Note that if we had considered an exponential quadratic form for the price-dividend ratio instead of an exponential
affine form, then this statement would be altered because Ij-fl and I^/I would become functions of the state
variables. Nonetheless, we find in separate calculations that an exponential quadratic form yields exactly the
same results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e695a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e702" publication-type="other">
See for example Schwert (1989) and Meie (2008) for empirical evidence of countercyclical volatility.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e709a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e716" publication-type="other">
As an additional test, we regress attention on lagged variance. The slope coefficient obtained is not significant,
and the adjusted /?2 is 0.003. This provides evidence that lagged volatility does not seem to drive attention (at
least at a quarterly frequency).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e729a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e736" publication-type="other">
We thank an anonymous referee for drawing our attention to this. A regression of current uncertainty on lagged
attention (up to three lags) and lagged uncertainty (one lag) provides significant coefficients, thus suggesting that
attention is indeed a strong driver of future uncertainty.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e749a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e756" publication-type="other">
Attention needs to be larger than 0.26 for the increasing quadratic relationship to apply. When attention is lower
than 0.26, variance decreases quadratically with attention.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e766a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e773" publication-type="other">
Regressing 1-quarter-ahead S&amp;P 500 returns on current dividend yields between Q2:1950 and Q4;2012 provides
a positive and significant slope coefficient at the 95% confidence level. Our measure of risk premia is then
obtained by subtracting the 3-month risk-free rates from the fitted values.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e787a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e794" publication-type="other">
The risk premium, attention, and uncertainty are significantly autocorrelated. In addition, attention drives future
uncertainty. Therefore, we include lagged values of the risk premium, attention, and uncertainty in the regressions
to rule out spurious relationships.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624272e807a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624272e814" publication-type="other">
This extension is consistent with evidence provided by Vozlyublennaia (2014), who shows that a change in
return, especially a decline, significantly influences investor attention to securities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1624272e833a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e837" publication-type="other">
Abel, A. 1999. Risk premia and term premia in general equilibrium. Journal of Monetary Economics 43:3-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e844a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e848" publication-type="other">
Abel, A., J. Eberly, and S. Panageas. 2007. Optimal inattention to the stock market. American Economic Review
97:244-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e858a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e862" publication-type="other">
Ai, H. 2010. Information quality and long-run risk: Asset pricing implications. Journal of Finance 65:1333-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e869a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e873" publication-type="other">
Andersen, T. G, T. Bollerslev, F. X. Diebold, and C. Vega. 2003. Micro effects of macro announcements: Real-time
price discovery in foreign exchange. American Economic Review 93:38-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e884a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e888" publication-type="other">
Andrei, D., and M. Hasler. 2014. Optimal asset and attention allocation. Working Paper, UCLA and University
of Toronto.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e898a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e902" publication-type="other">
Bacchetta, P., and E. v. Wincoop. 2010. Infrequent portfolio decisions: A solution to the forward discount puzzle.
American Economic Review 100:870-904.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e912a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e916" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., R. F. Dittmar, and C. T. Lundblad. 2005. Consumption, dividends, and the cross section of equity
returns. Journal of Finance 60:1639-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e926a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e930" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., D. Kiku, I. Shaliastovich, and A. Yaron. 2013. Volatility, the macroeconomy, and asset prices. Journal
of Finance. Advance Access published September 30, 2013.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e940a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e944" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., and I. Shaliastovich. 2011. Learning and asset-price jumps. Review of Financial Studies 24:2738-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e951a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e955" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., and A. Yaron. 2004. Risks for the long run: A potential resolution of asset pricing puzzles. Journal of
Finance 59:1481-509.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e966a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e970" publication-type="other">
Barber, B. M., and T. Odean. 2008. All that glitters: The effect of attention and news on the buying behavior of
individual and institutional investors. Review of Financial Studies 21:785-818.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e980a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e984" publication-type="other">
Barber, B. M., T. Odean, and N. Zhu. 2009. Do retail trades move markets? Review of Financial Studies
22:151-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e994a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e998" publication-type="other">
Barberis, N., M. Huang, and T. Santos. 2001. Prospect theory and asset prices. Quarterly Journal of Economics
116:1-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1008a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1012" publication-type="other">
Barsky, R. B., and J. B. De Long. 1993. Why does the stock market fluctuate? Quarterly Journal of Economics
108:291-311.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1022a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1026" publication-type="other">
Beeler, J., and J. Y. Campbell. 2012. The long-run risks model and aggregate asset prices: An empirical assessment.
Critical Finance Review 1:141-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1036a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1040" publication-type="other">
Benzoni, L., P. Collin-Dufresne, and R. S. Goldstein. 2011. Explaining asset pricing puzzles associated with the
1987 market crash. Journal of Financial Economics 101:552-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1051a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1055" publication-type="other">
Brennan, M. J., and Y. Xia. 2001. Stock price volatility and equity premium. Journal of Monetary Economics
47:249-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1065a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1069" publication-type="other">
Brown, S., S. A. Hillegeist, and K. Lo. 2009. The effect of earnings surprises on information asymmetry. Journal
of Accounting and Economics 47:208-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1079a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1083" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J., and R. Shiller. 1988. The dividend-price ratio and expectations of future dividends and discount
factors. Review of Financial Studies 1:195-228.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1093a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1097" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., and J. H. Cochrane. 1999. By force of habit: A consumption-based explanation of aggregate
stock market behavior. Journal of Political Economy 107:205-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1107a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1111" publication-type="other">
Carlin, B. I., F. A. Longstaff, and K. Matoba. Forthcoming. Disagreement and asset prices. Journal of Financial
Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1121a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1125" publication-type="other">
Chauvet, M., S. Gabriel, and C. Lutz. 2012. Fear an loathing in the housing market: Evidence from search query
data. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1136a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1140" publication-type="other">
Chien, Y., H. Cole, and H. Lustig. 2012. Is the volatility of the market price of risk due to intermittent portfolio
rebalancing? American Economic Review 102:2859-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1150a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1154" publication-type="other">
Colacito, R., and M. M. Croce. 2013. International asset pricing with recursive preferences. The Journal of
Finance 68:2651-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1164a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1168" publication-type="other">
Da, Z., J. Engelberg, and P. Gao. 2011. In search of attention. Journal of Finance 66:1461-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1175a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1179" publication-type="other">
Da, Z., U. G Gurun, and M. Warachka. 2014. Frog in the pan: Continuous information and momentum. Review
of Financial Studies 27:2171-218.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1189a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1193" publication-type="other">
David, A. 1997. Fluctuating confidence in stock markets: Implications for returns and volatility. Journal of
Financial and Quantitative Analysis 32:427-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1203a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1207" publication-type="other">
. 2008. Heterogeneous beliefs, speculation and the equity premium. Journal of Finance 63:41-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1215a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1219" publication-type="other">
David, A., and P. Veronesi. 2013. What ties return volatilities to price valuations and fundamentals? Journal of
Political Economy 121:682-746.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1229a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1233" publication-type="other">
Dellavigna, S., and J. M. Pollet. 2009. Investor inattention and friday earnings announcements. Journal of Finance
64:709-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1243a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1247" publication-type="other">
Detemple, J. 1986. Asset pricing in a production economy with incomplete information. Journal of Finance
41:383-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1257a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1261" publication-type="other">
. 1991. Further results on asset pricing with incomplete information. Journal of Economic Dynamics and
Control 15:425-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1271a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1275" publication-type="other">
Detemple, J., and R. Kihlstrom. 1987. Acquisition d'information dans un modèle intertemporel en temps continu.
L'Actualité économique 63:118-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1285a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1289" publication-type="other">
Dimpfl, T., and S. Jank. 2011. Can internet search queries help to predict stock market volatility? Working Paper,
University of Tübingen.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1300a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1304" publication-type="other">
Dothan, M. U., and D. Feldman. 1986. Equilibrium interest rates and multiperiod bonds in a partially observable
economy. Journal of Finance 41:369-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1314a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1318" publication-type="other">
Drechsler, I., and A. Yaron. 2011. What's vol got to do with it. Review of Financial Studies 24:1 —45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1325a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1329" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D. 2010. Presidential address: Asset price dynamics with slow-moving capital. Journal of Finance
65:1237-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1339a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1343" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., and L. G Epstein. 1992a. Asset pricing with stochastic differential utility. Review of Financial Studies
5:411-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1353a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1357" publication-type="other">
. 1992b. Stochastic differential utility. Econometrica 60:353-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1364a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1368" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., and T.-s. Sun. 1990. Transactions costs and portfolio choice in a discrete-continuous-time setting.
Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control 14:35-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1379a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1383" publication-type="other">
Dumas, B., A. Kurshev, and R. Uppal. 2009. Equilibrium portfolio strategies in the presence of sentiment risk
and excess volatility. Journal of Finance 64:579-629.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1393a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1397" publication-type="other">
Epstein, L. G, and S. E. Zin. 1989. Substitution, risk aversion, and the temporal behavior of consumption and
asset returns: A theoretical framework. Econometrica 57:937-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1407a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1411" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and K. R. French. 1989. Business conditions and expected returns on stocks and bonds. Journal of
Financial Economics 25:23—49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1421a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1425" publication-type="other">
Flannery, M. J., and A. A. Protopapadakis. 2002. Macroeconomic factors do influence aggregate stock returns.
Review of Financial Studies 15:751-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1435a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1439" publication-type="other">
Fleming, M. J., and E. M. Remolona. 1999. Price formation and liquidity in the u.s. treasury market: The response
to public information. Journal of Finance 54:1901-15.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1449a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1453" publication-type="other">
Garcia, D. 2013. Sentiment during recessions. Journal of Finance 68:1267-300.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1461a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1465" publication-type="other">
Gennotte, G 1986. Optimal portfolio choice under incomplete information. Journal of Finance 41:733-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1472a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1476" publication-type="other">
Graham, J. R., and C. R. Harvey. 2013. The equity risk premium in 2013. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1483a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1487" publication-type="other">
Hansen, L. P. 1982. Large sample properties of generalized method of moments estimators. Econometrica
50:1029-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1497a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1501" publication-type="other">
Huang, L., and H. Liu. 2007. Rational inattention and portfolio selection. Journal of Finance 62:1999-2040.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1508a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1512" publication-type="other">
Huberman, G, and T. Regev. 2001. Contagious speculation and a cure for cancer: A nonevent that made stock
prices soar. Journal of Finance 56:387-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1522a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1526" publication-type="other">
Kacperczyk, M., S. Van Nieuwerburgh, and L. Veldkamp. 2009. Rational attention allocation over the business
cycle. NBER Working Paper 15450, National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1537a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1541" publication-type="other">
Kahneman, D. 1973. Attention and effort. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice-Hall.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1548a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1552" publication-type="other">
Karlsson, N., G Loewenstein, and D. Seppi. 2009. The ostrich effect: Selective attention to information. Journal
of Risk and Uncertainty 38:95-115.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1562a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1566" publication-type="other">
Kita, A., and Q. Wang. 2012. Investor attention and FX market volatility. Working Paper, Bangor Business
School.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1576a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1580" publication-type="other">
Koijen, R. S. J., J. C. Rodriguez, and A. Sbuelz. 2009. Momentum and mean reversion in strategic asset allocation.
Management Science 55:1199-213.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1590a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1594" publication-type="other">
Kreps, D. M., and E. L. Porteus. 1978. Temporal resolution of uncertainty and dynamic choice theory.
Econometrica 46:185-200.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1604a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1608" publication-type="other">
Laster, D., P. Bennett, and I. S. Geoum. 1999. Rational bias in macroeconomic forecasts. Quarterly Journal of
Economics 114:293-318.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1619a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1623" publication-type="other">
Liptser, R. S., and A. N. Shiryaev. 2001. Statistics of random processes, II. New York: Springer Verlag.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1630a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1634" publication-type="other">
Lucas, R. E. 1978. Asset prices in an exchange economy. Econometrica 46:1429^45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1641a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1645" publication-type="other">
Lustig, H., and A. Verdelhan. 2012. Business cycle variation in the risk-return trade-off. Journal of Monetary
Economics 59:S35-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1655a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1659" publication-type="other">
Massa, M., and A. Simonov. 2005. Is learning a dimension of risk? Journal of Banking &amp; Finance 29:2605-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1666a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1670" publication-type="other">
Meie, A. 2008. Understanding stock market volatility: A business cycle perspective. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1677a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1681" publication-type="other">
Mincer, J. A., and V. Zarnowitz. 1969. The evaluation of economic forecasts. In Economic forecasts and
expectations: Analysis of forecasting behavior and performance, NBER Chapters, 1-46. Cambridge: National
Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1695a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1699" publication-type="other">
Mondria, J. 2010. Portfolio choice, attention allocation, and price comovement. Journal of Economic Theory
145:1837-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1709a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1713" publication-type="other">
Mondria, J., and C. Quintana-Domeque. 2013. Financial contagion and attention allocation. Economic Journal
123:429-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1723a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1727" publication-type="other">
Ozoguz, A. 2009. Good times or bad times? investors' uncertainty and stock returns. Review of Financial Studies
22:4377-422.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1737a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1741" publication-type="other">
Pastor, L., and P. Veronesi. 2009. Learning in financial markets. Annual Review of Financial Economics 1:361-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1748a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1752" publication-type="other">
Patton, A. J., and A. G Timmermann. 2008. The resolution of macroeconomic uncertainty: Evidence from survey
forecasts. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1762a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1766" publication-type="other">
Peng, L., and W. Xiong. 2006. Investor attention, overconfidence and category learning. Journal of Financial
Economics 80:563-602.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1777a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1781" publication-type="other">
Rossi, A. 2010. Optimal inattention to the stock market, portfolio allocation, and consumption. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1788a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1792" publication-type="other">
Scheinkman, J. A., and W. Xiong. 2003. Overconfidence and speculative bubbles. Journal of Political Economy
111:1183-219.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1802a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1806" publication-type="other">
Schmidt, D. 2013. Investors' attention and stock covariation: Evidence from google sport searches. Working
Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1816a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1820" publication-type="other">
Schwert, G W. 1989. Why does stock market volatility change over time? Journal of Finance 44:1115-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1827a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1831" publication-type="other">
Sims, C. A. 2003. Implications of rational inattention. Journal of Monetary Economics 50:665-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1838a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1842" publication-type="other">
Timmermann, A. 2001. Structural breaks, incomplete information, and stock prices. Journal of Business &amp;
Economic Statistics 19:299-314.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1853a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1857" publication-type="other">
Timmermann, A. G 1993. How learning in financial markets generates excess volatility and predictability in
stock prices. Quarterly Journal of Economics 108:1135-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1867a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1871" publication-type="other">
Van Nieuwerburgh, S., and L. Veldkamp. 2006. Learning asymmetries in real business cycles. Journal of Monetary
Economics 53:753-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1881a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1885" publication-type="other">
. 2009. Information immobility and the home bias puzzle. Journal of Finance 64:1187-215.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1892a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1896" publication-type="other">
. 2010. Information acquisition and under-diversification. Review of Economic Studies 77:779-805.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1903a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1907" publication-type="other">
Veldkamp, L. 2006a. Information markets and the comovement of asset prices. Review of Economic Studies
73:823-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1917a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1921" publication-type="other">
. 2006b. Media frenzies in markets for financial information. American Economic Review 96:577-601.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1929a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1933" publication-type="other">
Veronesi, P. 1999. Stock market overreaction to bad news in good times: A rational expectations equilibrium
model. Review of Financial Studies 12:975-1007.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1943a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1947" publication-type="other">
. 2000. How does information quality affect stock returns? Journal of Finance 55:807-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1954a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1958" publication-type="other">
Vlastakis, N., and R. N. Markellos. 2012. Information demand and stock market volatility. Journal of Banking
&amp; Finance 36:1808-21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1968a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1972" publication-type="other">
Vozlyublennaia, N. 2014. Investor attention, index performance, and return predictability. Journal of Banking &amp;
Finance 41:17-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1982a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e1986" publication-type="other">
Weil, P. 1989. The equity premium puzzle and the risk-free rate puzzle. Journal of Monetary Economics
24:401-21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624272e1996a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624272e2000" publication-type="other">
Xia, Y. 2001. Learning about predictability: The effects of parameter uncertainty on dynamic asset allocation.
Journal of Finance 56:205-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


