<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26649135</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effects of Injector Temperature on Spray Characteristics in Heavy-Duty Diesel Sprays</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Daly</surname>
                  <given-names>Shane R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hagen</surname>
                  <given-names>Chris</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cenker</surname>
                  <given-names>Emre</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pickett</surname>
                  <given-names>Lyle M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Skeen</surname>
                  <given-names>Scott A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">11</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26649117</issue-id>
         <fpage>879</fpage>
         <lpage>892</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26649135"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This work investigates the impact of injector temperature on the characteristics of high-pressure n-dodecane sprays under conditions relevant to heavy-duty diesel engines. Sprays are injected from a pair of single-hole diesel injectors belonging to the family of “Spray C” and “Spray D” Engine Combustion Network (ECN) injectors. Low and high injector temperature conditions are achieved by activating or deactivating a cooling jacket. We quantify spray spreading angle and penetration using high-speed shadowgraphy and long-distance microscopy imaging. We evaluate differences in fuel/air mixture formation at key timings through one-dimensional modeling. Injections from a cooled injector penetrate faster than those from a higher temperature injector, especially for an injector already prone to cavitation (Spray C). When uncooled, Spray C exhibited a time-varying spreading angle at early times during the injection event, which exacerbates the reduction in initial penetration rate relative to the cooled injector. Changes in fuel density alone cannot account for the observed trends, and we show that implementing a transient spreading angle in the model (guided by the time-sequenced images) is an effective solution to match experimental penetration characteristics. Time- and axially resolved radial mixture fractions derived from the model reveal that failure to account for early spreading angle transients and their impact on penetration and mixture formation leads to erroneous mixture fraction distributions at key timings associated with first- and second-stage ignition. Such oversights could lead the community toward incorrect model calibrations.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Pickett, L.M., Manin, J., Genzale, C., Siebers, D. et al., “Relationship between Diesel Fuel Spray Vapor Penetration/Dispersion and Local Fuel Mixture Fraction,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):764-799, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0686.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Pickett, L.M. and Abraham, J., “Computed and Measured Fuel Vapor Distribution in a Diesel Spray,” 20(3):241-250, 2010, doi:10.1615/AtomizSpr.v20.i3.50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Som, S., D'Errico, G., Longman, D., and Lucchini, T., “Comparison and Standardization of Numerical Approaches for the Prediction of Non-Reacting and Reacting Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1263, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Pickett, L.M., Manin, J., Payri, R., Bardi, M. et al., “Transient Rate of Injection Effects on Spray Development,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0001, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24- 0001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Payri, R. et al., “A New Methodology for Correcting the Signal Cumulative Phenomenon on Injection Rate Measurements,” Experimental Techniques 32(1):46-49, 2008, doi:10.1111/j.1747-1567.2007.00188.x.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Payri, R. et al., “Using Spray Momentum Flux Measurements to Understand the Influence of Diesel Nozzle Geometry on Spray Characteristics,” Fuel 84(5):551-561, 2005, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2004.10.009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Knox, B.W., Franze, M.J., and Genzale, C.L., “Diesel Spray Rate-of-Momentum Measurement Uncertainties and Diagnostic Considerations,” Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 138(3):031507-031507-9, 2015, doi:10.1115/1.4031432.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Technical University of Valencia, “Virtual Injection Rate Generator,” http://www.cmt.upv.es/ECN03.aspx, accessed October 2, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Wang, T.C. et al., “Parametric Characterization of High- Pressure Diesel Fuel Injection Systems,” Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 125(2):412-426, 2003, doi:10.1115/1.1498268.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Lai, M.-C., Wang, T., Xie, X., Han, J. et al., “Microscopic Characterization of Diesel Sprays at VCO Nozzle Exit,” SAE Technical Paper 982542, 1998, doi:10.4271/982542.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Heimgartner, C. and Leipertz, A., “Investigation of the Primary Spray Breakup Close to the Nozzle of a Common— Rail High Pressure Diesel Injection System,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1799, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1799.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Blessing, M., Konig, G., Kruger, C., Michels, U. et al., “Analysis of Flow and Cavitation Phenomena in Diesel Injection Nozzles and Its Effects on Spray and Mixture Formation,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1358, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1358.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Payri, R., Salvador, F., Gimeno, J., and de la Morena, J., “Macroscopic Behavior of Diesel Sprays in the Near-Nozzle Field,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):528-536, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0929.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Jung, Y., Manin, J., Skeen, S., and Pickett, L., “Measurement of Liquid and Vapor Penetration of Diesel Sprays with a Variation in Spreading Angle,” SAE Technical Paper 2015- 01-0946, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0946.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Jung, Y., Manin, J., Skeen, S., and Pickett, L., “Assessment of the Ignition and Lift-Off Characteristics of a Diesel Spray with a Transient Spreading Angle,” SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1828, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1828.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c16">O'Connor, J.F., “CFD Predictions of the Effect of Fuel Temperature on Heavy Duty Diesel Engine NOx and Soot Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0842, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0842.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Salvador, F.J. et al., “Fuel Temperature Influence on the Performance of a Last Generation Common-Rail Diesel Ballistic Injector. Part I: Experimental Mass Flow Rate Measurements and Discussion,” Energy Conversion and Management 114:364-375, 2016, doi:10.1016/j. enconman.2016.02.042.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Manin, J. et al., “Boundary Condition and Fuel Composition Effects on Injection Processes of High-Pressure Sprays at the Microscopic Level,” International Journal of Multiphase Flow 83:267-278, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.ijmultiphaseflow.2015.12.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Payri, R. et al., “A New Approach to Compute Temperature in a Liquid-Gas Mixture. Application to Study the Effect of Wall Nozzle Temperature on a Diesel Injector,” International Journal of Heat and Fluid Flow 68:79-86, 2017, doi:10.1016/j. ijheatfluidflow.2016.12.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Musculus, M.P.B. and Kattke, K., “Entrainment Waves in Diesel Jets,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1170-1193, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Siebers, D.L., “Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 980809, 1998, doi:10.4271/980809.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Westlye, F.R., Battistoni, M., Skeen, S., and Manin, J., “Penetration and Combustion Characterization of Cavitating and Non-Cavitating Fuel Injectors under Diesel Engine Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0860, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0860.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Sandia National Laboratories, “Engine Combustion Network,” http://www.ecn.sandia.gov/, accessed October 15, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Meijer, M. et al., “Engine Combustion Network (ECN): Characterization and Comparison of Boundary Conditions for Different Combustion Vessels,” Atomization and Sprays 22(9):777-806, 2012, doi:10.1615/AtomizSpr.2012006083.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Naber, J.D. and Siebers, D.L., “Effects of Gas Density and Vaporization on Penetration and Dispersion of Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 960034, 1996, doi:10.4271/960034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Payri, R. et al., “Hydraulic Characterization of Diesel Engine Single-Hole Injectors,” Fuel 180:357-366, 2016, doi:10.1016/j. fuel.2016.03.083.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Kastengren, A.L. et al., “Engine Combustion Network (ECN): Measurements of Nozzle Geometry and Hydraulic Behavior,” Atom. Sprays 22(12):1011- 1052, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Zhang, Q. and Johari, H., “Effects of Acceleration on Turbulent Jets,” Physics of Fluids 8(8):2185-2195, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Steady-state hydraulic performance for Spray C and D, cooled (90 K) and uncooled (150 K) injections at 150 MPa fuel pressure and atmospheric back-pressure. Sandia National Laboratories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Hydraulic coefficients for Spray C and D for cooled (90 K) and uncooled (150 K) injections, derived from the experimentally obtained hydraulic parameters of this work. Sandia National Laboratories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Measured spray force as a function of time for Spray C (solid) and Spray D (dashed), cooled (CI, cyan) and uncooled (UCI, red) injectors. Inset axes show a close-up view of the ramp-up and ramp-down. Sandia National Laboratories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Measured spray penetration as a function of time for Spray C and Spray D, cooled (CI) and uncooled (UCI) injectors. Shaded regions indicate one standard deviation of 10 repeat studies. Sandia National Laboratories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Injector and vessel conditions considered in the spray formation investigation. Sandia National Laboratories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Overlaid, false-color LDM images of Spray C cooled (CI) and uncooled (UCI) injectors. Uniqueness for CI (cyan) and UCI (red) sprays are highlighted, and overlapping regions are indicated in black. 440 K 22.8 kg/m³ (left panels) and 900 K 22.8 kg/m³ (right panels). Sandia National Laboratories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Average spray radius for Spray C cooled (CI, cyan) and uncooled injector (UCI, red). 440 K 22.8 kg/m³ (left) and 900 K 22.8 kg/m³ (right). Shaded regions indicate one standard deviation of 10 repeat studies. Sandia National Laboratories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Overlaid, false-color shadowgraphy of Spray C cooled (CI) and uncooled (UCI) injectors. Uniqueness for CI (cyan) and UCI (red) sprays are highlighted, and overlay indicated in black. 440 K 22.8 kg/m³ (left) and 900 K 22.8 kg/m³ (right). Image-processed vapor border indicated in 900 K 22.8 kg/m³ conditions. Sandia National Laboratories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Average spray radius for Spray C cooled (CI, solid cyan) and uncooled injector (UCI, solid red) at 440 K, 22.8 kg/m³. Overlaid are radial profiles (dashed) that highlight the upstream spreading angle—as implemented in the 1-D model. Sandia National Laboratories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Measured spray penetration as a function of time for Spray C cooled (CI, shaded cyan) and uncooled (UCI shaded red) injectors, indicated by shaded error bands representing one standard deviation of the 10 repeat studies. Also shown are 1-D modeled penetration profiles: (dotted) using experimentally observed steady-state spray width and (dashed) using altered ROI with transient spray width. Sandia National Laboratories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Spray C, default CMT ROI profile (dashed) compared to that used for 1-D modeling efforts (solid) implementing reduced-slope ramp-up. Inset axis highlights the subtle alteration to the ramp-up. Sandia National Laboratories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>1-D modeled mixture fractions for Spray C at 440 K 22.8 kg/m³, as a result of implementing altered ROI and transient radial profiles (“transient” model, columns 1 and 2); the relative percent difference between the two is shown in column 3. The relative percent difference between modeled results not implementing an altered ROI or transient radial profile (steady-state profile for all times) is shown for comparison in column 4 (“steady-state” model). Percent difference color scale ranges from 0 to 50% (≥50% in white), and mixture fraction from 0 to 0.4. Sandia National Laboratories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
