<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275562</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Nonlinear Input Transformation for EGR and VGT Control in Diesel Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wahlström</surname>
                  <given-names>Johan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Eriksson</surname>
                  <given-names>Lars</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Linköping University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275542</issue-id>
         <fpage>288</fpage>
         <lpage>305</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275562"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In diesel engines with EGR and VGT, the gas flow dynamics has significant nonlinear effects. This is shown by analyzing DC-gains in different operating points showing that these gains have large variations. To handle these nonlinear effects, a nonlinear state dependent input transformation is investigated. This input transformation is achieved through inversion of the models for EGR-flow and turbine flow. It is shown that the input transformation handles the nonlinear effects and decreases the variations in DC-gains substantially. The input transformation is combined with a new control structure that has a pumping work minimization feature and consists of PID controllers and min/max-selectors for coordinated control of EGR-fraction and oxygen/fuel ratio. The EGR flow and the exhaust manifold pressure are chosen as feedback variables in this structure. Further, the set-points for EGR-fraction and oxygen/fuel ratio are transformed to set-points for the feedback variables. In order to handle model errors in this set-point transformation, an integral action on oxygen/fuel ratio is proposed in an outer loop. An experimental validation and comparison with a control structure without input transformation shows that the proposed structure reduces EGR-errors at the expense of increased pumping losses. In addition the comparison shows that the input transformation improves the performance and achieves the same step response for different flow conditions, thus handling the nonlinear effects.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B.. Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals. McGraw-Hill Book Co, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stefanopoulou, A.G., Kolmanovsky, I.V., and Freudenberg, J.S.. Control of variable geometry turbocharged diesel engines for reduced emissions. IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, 8(4), July 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guzzella, L. and Amstutz, A.. Control of diesel engines. IEEE Control Systems Magazine, 18:53-71, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jankovic, M., Jankovic, M., and Kolmanovsky, I.V.. Constructive lyapunov control design for turbocharged diesel engines. IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nieuwstadt, M.J., Kolmanovsky, I.V., Moraal, P.E., Stefanopoulou, A.G., and Jankovic, M.. EGR-VGT control schemes: Experimental comparison for a high-speed diesel engine. IEEE Control Systems Magazine, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rückert, J., Schloßer, A., Rake, H., Kinoo, B., Krüger, M., and Pischinger, S.. Model based boost pressure and exhaust gas recirculation rate control for a diesel engine with variable turbine geometry. In IFAC Workshop: Advances in Automotive Control, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ammann, M., Fekete, N.P., Guzzella, L. and Glattfelder, A.H. “Model-based Control of the VGT and EGR in a Turbocharged Common-Rail Diesel Engine: Theory and Passenger Car Implementation,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0357, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amstutz, A. and Del Re, L.. EGO sensor based robust output control of EGR in diesel engines. IEEE Transactions on Control System Technology, pages 37-48, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chauvin, Jonathan, Corde, Gilles, Petit, Nicolas, and Rouchon, Pierre. Motion planning for experimental airpath control of a diesel homogeneous charge-compression ignition engine. Control Engineering Practice, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jung, Merten, Glover, Keith, and Christen, Urs. Comparison of uncertainty parameterisations for H-infinity robust control of turbocharged diesel engines. Control Engineering Practice, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nieuwstadt, M., Moraal, P.E., Kolmanovsky, I.V., Stefanopoulou, A., Wood, P., and Widdle, M.. Decentralized and multivariable designs for EGR-VGT control of a diesel engine. In IFAC Workshop, Advances in Automotive Control, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rajamani, R.. Control of a variable-geometry turbocharged and wastegated diesel engine. Proceedings of the I MECH E Part D Journal of Automobile Engineering, November 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wahlström, Johan, Eriksson, Lars, and Nielsen, Lars. EGR-VGT control and tuning for pumping work minimization and emission control. IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, 18(4):993-1003, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wahlström, Johan and Eriksson, Lars. Nonlinear EGR and VGT control with integral action for diesel engines. In IFAC Workshop on Engine and Powertrain Control, Simulation and Modeling, Paris, France, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhou, Kemin, Doyle, John C., and Glover, Keith. Robust and optimal control. Prentice-Hall, Inc., Upper Saddle River, NJ, USA, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakayama, S., Fukuma, T., Matsunaga, A., Miyake, T. et al., “A New Dynamic Combustion Control Method Based on Charge Oxygen Concentration for Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3181, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-3181.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wahlström, Johan. Control of EGR and VGT for Emission Control and Pumping Work Minimization in Diesel Engines. PhD thesis, Linköping University, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kolmanovsky, I.V., Stefanopoulou, A.G., Moraal, P.E., and van Nieuwstadt, M.. Issues in modeling and control of intake flow in variable geometry turbocharged engines. In Proceedings of 18th IFIP Conference on System Modeling and Optimization, Detroit, July 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wahlström, J., Eriksson, L., and Nielsen, L., “Controller Tuning based on Transient Selection and Optimization for a Diesel Engine with EGR and VGT,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0985, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jerhammar, Andreas and Höckerdal, Erik. Gas flow observer for a Scania diesel engine with VGT and EGR. Master's thesis, Linköpings Universitet, SE-581 83 Linköping, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Åström, K. J. and Hägglund, T.. PID Controllers: Theory, Design and Tuning. Research Triangle Park, Instrument Society of America, 2nd edition, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
