<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466820</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466856</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Tail Risk and Asset Prices</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Bryan</given-names>
                  <surname>Kelly</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Hao</given-names>
                  <surname>Jiang</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2841</fpage>
         <lpage>2871</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466856"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We propose a new measure of time-varying tail risk that is directly estimable from the cross-section of returns. We exploit firm-level price crashes every month to identify common fluctuations in tail risk among individual stocks. Our tail measure is significantly correlated with tail risk measures extracted from S&amp;P 500 index options and negatively predicts real economic activity. We show that tail risk has strong predictive power for aggregate market returns. Cross-sectionally, stocks with high loadings on past tail risk earn an annual three-factor alpha 5.4% higher than stocks with low tail risk loadings. We explore potential mechanisms giving rise to these asset pricing facts.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d15e248a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e255" publication-type="other">
This allows us to capture common fluctuations in individual firms' tails over time. This procedure avoids having
to accumulate years of tail observations from the aggregate series in order to estimate tail risk, and therefore
avoids using stale observations that carry little information about current tail risk.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e268a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e275" publication-type="other">
Gabaix (2009) provides a summary of aggregation properties for variables with power law tails. In particular,
power law tails are conserved under addition, so that portfolio return tails behave like the tails of stocks in the
portfolio. Further details and derivations are found in Jessen and Mikosch (2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e288a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e295" publication-type="other">
Gourio (2012) presents a theoretical model showing that shocks to aggregate tail risk induce qualitatively similar
business fluctuations as the volatility uncertainty studied by Bloom (2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e305a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e312" publication-type="other">
These long-run risk extensions build on a large body of literature that models extreme events with jump processes,
most notably the widely used affine class of Duffie, Pan, and Singleton (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e323a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e330" publication-type="other">
A seminal paper documenting variation in the power law tail of returns is that of Quintos, Fan, and Phillips
(2001), with additional evidence presented by Galbraith and Zernov (2004), Werner and Upper (2004), and
Wagner (2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e343a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e350" publication-type="other">
The cross-section procedure that we propose has subsequently been adopted as a measure of systemic banking
sector risk by Allen, Bali, and Tang (2012) and liquidity risk by Wu (2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e360a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e367" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Mandelbrot (1963), Fama (1963,1965), Officer (1972), Blattberg and Gonedes (1974), Akgiray
and Booth (1988), Hols and De Vries (1991), Jansen and De Vries (1991), Kearns and Pagan (1997), Gopikrishnan
et al. (1999), and Gabaix et al. (2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e380a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e387" publication-type="other">
This specification is motivated by the Pickands-Balkema-de Haan limit theorem, which states that for a wide
class of heavy-tailed distributions for Rij+i, P(R^t+ &lt;r Rjtt+1 &lt;«/) will converge to a generalized power
law distribution as ut approaches the support boundary of /?/,+ j. This limit result is operationalized by treating
the power law as an exact relationship for threshold exceedences (Embrechts et al. 1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e403a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e410" publication-type="other">
Gabaix and Ibragimov (2011) propose an alternative "rank-1/2" regression approach to estimating k. Our k
estimates and asset pricing test results are nearly identical when we use their estimator in place of kf*'11.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e420a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e427" publication-type="other">
For simplicity, the Hill formula is written as though the cross-sectional «-exceedences are the first Kt elements
of Rt. This is without loss of generality because the elements of Rt are exchangeable from the perspective of the
estimator.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e441a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e448" publication-type="other">
An inappropriately mild threshold will contaminate tail exponent estimates by using data from the center of
the distribution, whose behavior can vary markedly from tail data. A very extreme threshold can result in noisy
estimates resulting from too few data points. Sophisticated methods for threshold selection have been developed
(Dupuis 1999 and Matthys and Beirlant 2000, among others), though these typically require estimation of
additional parameters and can be unstable. In light of this fact, Gabaix et al. (2006) advocate a simple rule that
fixes the «-exceedence probability at 5% for unconditional power law estimation. We follow these authors by
applying a similar simple rule in the dynamic setting. We find very similar empirical results if we use thresholds
ranging from the first to fifth percentile.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e477a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e484" publication-type="other">
These results are very similar to tail estimates based on raw returns.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e491a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e500" publication-type="other">
If sampling error produces too low an estimate of volatility, volatility scaling excessively inflates returns, making
them appear as tail observations when they are not. On the other hand, if a stock experiences a tail event,
this mechanically raises its measured volatility, in which case standardization can overshrink precisely those
observations that are most informative about the tail distribution. We address this empirically by winsorizing
10% of the highest and lowest estimated volatilities to dampen the influence of the noisiest volatility estimates.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e519a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e526" publication-type="other">
The period-wise Hill approach to the dynamic power law in Section 1 naturally accommodates changes in
cross-section size over time.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e536a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e543" publication-type="other">
The incidence of tail events at the firm-level is fairly evenly distributed across firms. In a large homogenous
cross-section we would expect each firm to show up in the tail 5% of the time. Over 99% of all firms experience
at least 1 tail event, 86% of firms show up in the tail more than 1% of the time; and only 8% of firms show up in
the tail more than 15% of the time. In the average month, 44.8% of available firms appear in the cross-sectional
lower tail on at least one day.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e562a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e569" publication-type="other">
Richardson and Smith (1991), Hodrick's (1992), and Boudoukh and Richardson (1993) (among others) have
noted the inferential problems concomitant with overlapping horizon predictive regressions. Ang and Bekaert
(2007) demonstrate in a Monte Carlo study that the standard error correction of Hodrick's (1992) provides
the most conservative test statistics relative to other commonly employed procedures, maintaining appropriate
test size over horizons as long as five years. We also find in our tests that Hodrick's correction produces more
conservative results than do Newey-West (1987) and other methods.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e593a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e600" publication-type="other">
We find that Goyal and Welch (2008) bootstrap standard errors, which are valid under the Stambaugh (1999)
specification, produce even stronger statistical results than those based on the Hodrick correction.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e610a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e617" publication-type="other">
We thank Amit Goyal for providing the data of Goyal and Welch (2008), updated through 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e624a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e631" publication-type="other">
Our estimates for upper tail risk have a correlation of 81 % with lower tail risk, suggesting that tail risk dynamics
are fairly symmetric. However, lower tail risk dominates upper tail risk in bivariate predictive regressions of the
market return.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e644a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e651" publication-type="other">
Due to the short time series for the variance risk premium, out-of-sample forecasts based on options measures
are infeasible and thus omitted.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e661a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e668" publication-type="other">
Estimating tail risk sensitivity using predictive regressions on levels of A., as opposed to contemporaneous
regressions on A's shocks, helps reduce the influence of A's estimation error on the estimates of tail sensitivities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e678a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e685" publication-type="other">
This analysis uses all NYSE/AMEX/NASDAQ stocks with CRSP share codes 10 and 11 and at least 36 months
out of 120 with nonmissing returns. Portfolios are reconstituted each month.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e696a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e703" publication-type="other">
We use data from OptionMetrics and apply data filters that include dropping all observations for which the
bid-ask spread is smaller than the minimum tick size, the bid is zero, open interest is zero, embedded leverage
is in the top or bottom 1% of the distribution, or time value is below 5%. The time value filter controls for the
American exercise feature as discussed in Frazzini and Pedersen (2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e719a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e726" publication-type="other">
In all regressions, tail risk is first standardized to have unit variance for ease of interpreting the estimated
coefficients.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e736a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e743" publication-type="other">
Equity positions can be levered as much as twenty times using out-of-the-money options. To adjust for leverage,
we follow Karakaya (2013) and scale option positions by the elasticity of an option's price with respect to the
underlying price. Because embedded leverage also magnifies risk exposure and expected returns, deleveraged
return magnitudes are more easily compared to our earlier equity portfolio results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e759a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e766" publication-type="other">
This property is employed in economic settings by Gabaix et al. (2006) and Gabaix (2009) among others. Jessen
and Mikosch (2006) provide a detailed analysis of power law aggregation properties.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e776a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e783" publication-type="other">
We also analyze the association between our tail risk measure and realized moments of individual stock returns.
Tail risk has a correlation with the average monthly skewness for all CRSP stocks of -23% (t = —4.7) and a
correlation with average stock-level kurtosis of 25% (t = 2.5).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e796a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e803" publication-type="other">
We only use options with positive open interest when calculating risk neutral skewness and kurtosis and the
smirk slope. Each of these measures is estimated separately for two sets of options with maturities closest to
30 days (one set for the maturity just greater than 30 days, and one set for the maturity just less than 30 days),
then the estimates are linearly interpolated to arrive at a measure with constant 30-day maturity. We estimate the
smirk slope in a regression of OTM put-implied volatility on option moneyness (strike over spot) using options
with Black-Scholes delta greater than -0.5 and one month to maturity. A more negative slope of the smirk means
that OTM puts are especially expensive relative to ATM puts.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e830a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e837" publication-type="other">
This ratio measures the number of new put contracts purchased by non-market-makers relative to new calls
purchases, depending in part on crash risk perceived by investors. We compute monthly averages of daily
put/call ratios from 1996 to 2010 for all option contracts traded on the CBOE.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e850a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e857" publication-type="other">
Due to the quarterly nature of sales data, we are forced to use a substantially smaller number of observations
to estimate the tail risk series. We therefore define the sales growth tail threshold as the 7.5th percentile of the
cross-section distribution each year. Quarterly stock return tails are calculated as an average of the monthly tail
risk series within each calendar quarter.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e873a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e880" publication-type="other">
Because industrial production and employment are only calculated for the manufacturing sector, the VARs in
panels A and B use tail risk estimated from the cross-section of manufacturing firms. The results are nearly
identical when tails are estimated including nonmanufacturing firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e893a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e900" publication-type="other">
Volatility produces a comparatively large effect because of our use of the volatility indicator constructed by
Bloom (2009). It equals one when the peak of HP detrended volatility is more than 1.65 standard deviations
above the mean. A "shock" is defined as a movement of this variable from zero to one and thus represents an
extreme shift in volatility. If instead we use raw stock market volatility in the VAR (to be more closely comparable
to the tail risk measure that we use), the effect of a one-standard-deviation volatility shock is qualitatively similar,
but quantitatively much smaller, producing a decline in IP growth of 0.4% after one year, whereas the effect of
a tail risk shock is effectively identical to that reported in Figure 5.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e926a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e933" publication-type="other">
Investment is available quarterly (and thus was omitted from Bloom's monthly analysis). We estimate a quarterly
trivariate VAR that includes stock market volatility, tail risk, and aggregate investment. Investment is measured
as either quarterly gross private domestic or private nonresidential fixed investment (as in Cochrane 1991,
1996)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d15e958a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e962" publication-type="other">
Akgiray, V., and G G Booth. 1988. The stable-law model of stock returns. Journal of Business and Economic
Statistics 6:51-7.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e972a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e976" publication-type="other">
Allen, L., T. G Bali, and Y. Tang. 2012. Does systemic risk in the financial sector predict future economic
downturns? Review of Financial Studies 25:3000-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e986a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e990" publication-type="other">
Ang, A., and G Bekaert. 2007. Stock return predictability: Is it there? Review of Financial Studies
20:651-707.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1000a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1004" publication-type="other">
Ang, A., J. Chen, and Y. Xing. 2006. Downside risk. Review of Financial Studies 19:1191-239.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1012a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1016" publication-type="other">
Ang, A., R. J. Hodrick, Y. Xing, and X. Zhang. 2006. The cross-section of volatility and expected returns. Journal
of Finance 61:259-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1026a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1030" publication-type="other">
Backus, D., M. Chernov, and I. Martin. 2011. Disasters implied by equity index options. Journal of Finance
66:1969-2012.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1040a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1044" publication-type="other">
Bakshi, G, N. Kapadia, and D. Madan. 2003. Stock return characteristics, skew laws, and the differential pricing
of individual equity options. Review of Financial Studies 16:101-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1054a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1058" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., and A. Yaron. 2004. Risks for the long run: A potential resolution of asset pricing puzzles. Journal of
Finance 59:1481-509.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1068a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1072" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., and I. Shaliastovich. 2010. Confidence risk and asset prices. American Economic Review: Papers
and Proceedings 100:537^41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1082a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1086" publication-type="other">
-.2011. Learning and asset-price jumps. Review of Financial Studies 24:2738-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1094a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1098" publication-type="other">
Barro, R. 2006. Rare disasters and asset markets in the twentieth century. Quarterly Journal of Economics
121:823-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1108a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1112" publication-type="other">
Blattberg, R. C., and N. J. Gonedes. 1974. A comparison of the stable and student distributions as statistical
models for stock prices. Journal of Business 47:244-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1122a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1126" publication-type="other">
Bloom, N. 2009. The impact of uncertainty shocks. Econometrica 77:623-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1133a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1137" publication-type="other">
Bollerslev, T., G Tauchen, and H. Zhou. 2009. Expected stock returns and variance risk premia. Review of
Financial Studies 22:4463-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1147a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1151" publication-type="other">
Bollerslev, T., and V. Todorov. 2011. Tails, fears, and risk premia. Journal of Finance 66:2165-211.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1158a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1162" publication-type="other">
Boudoukh, J., and M. Richardson. 1993. Stock returns and inflation: A long-horizon perspective. American
Economic Review 83:1346-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1173a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1177" publication-type="other">
Brownlees, C., R. Engle, and B. Kelly. 2011. A practical guide to volatility forecasting through calm and storm.
Journal of Risk 14:3-22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1187a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1191" publication-type="other">
Carhart, M. M. 1997. On persistence in mutual fund performance. Journal of Finance 52:57-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1198a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1202" publication-type="other">
Clark, T. E., and M. W. McCracken. 2001. Tests of equal forecast accuracy and encompassing for nested models.
Journal of econometrics 105:85-110.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1212a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1216" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. H. 1991. Production-based asset pricing and the link between stock returns and economic
fluctuations. Journal of Finance 46:209-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1226a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1230" publication-type="other">
. 1996. A cross-sectional test of an investment-based asset pricing model. Journal of Political Economy
104:572-621.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1240a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1244" publication-type="other">
Drechsler, I., and A. Yaron. 2011. What's vol got to do with it? Review of Financial Studies 24:1-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1252a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1256" publication-type="other">
Duffle, D., J. Pan, and K. Singleton. 2000. Transform analysis and asset pricing for affine jump-diffusions.
Econometrica 68:1343-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1266a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1270" publication-type="other">
Dupuis, D. J. 1999. Exceedances over high thresholds: A guide to threshold selection. Extremes 1:251-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1277a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1281" publication-type="other">
Embrechts, P., C. Klppelberg, and T. Mikosch. 1997. Modelling extremal events: for insurance and finance.
Springer.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1291a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1295" publication-type="other">
Eraker, B., and I. Shaliastovich. 2008. An equilibrium guide to designing affine pricing models. Mathematical
Finance 18:519-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1305a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1309" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. 1963. Mandelbrot and the stable Paretian hypothesis. Journal of Business 36:420-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1316a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1320" publication-type="other">
. 1965. The behavior of stock-market prices. Journal of Business 38:34-105.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1328a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1332" publication-type="other">
Fama, E., and K. French. 1993. Common risk factors in the returns on stocks and bonds. Journal of Financial
Economics 33:3-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1342a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1346" publication-type="other">
Frazzini, A., and L. Pedersen. 2012. Embedded leverage. NBER Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1353a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1357" publication-type="other">
Gabaix, X. 2009. Power laws in economics and finance. Annual Review of Economics 1:255-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1364a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1368" publication-type="other">
. 2012. Variable rare disasters: An exactly solved framework for ten puzzles in macro-finance. Quarterly
Journal of Economics 127:645-700.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1378a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1382" publication-type="other">
Gabaix, X., and R. Ibragimov. 2011. Rank-1/2: A simple way to improve the OLS estimation of tail exponents.
Journal of Business and Economic Statistics 29:24-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1392a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1396" publication-type="other">
Gabaix, X., P. Gopikrishnan, V. Plerou, and H. Stanley. 2006. Institutional investors and stock market volatility.
Quarterly Journal of Economics 121:461-504.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1407a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1411" publication-type="other">
Galbraith, J. W., and S. Zernov. 2004. Circuit breakers and the tail index of equity returns. Journal of Financial
Econometrics 2:109-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1421a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1425" publication-type="other">
Gao, G, and Z. Song. 2013. Rare disaster concerns everywhere. Working Paper, Cornell University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1432a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1436" publication-type="other">
Gopikrishnan, P., V. Plerou, L. A. N. Amaral, M. Meyer, and H. E. Stanley. 1999. Scaling of the distribution of
fluctuations of financial market indices. Physical Review 60:5305-16.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1446a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1450" publication-type="other">
Gourio, F. 2012. Disaster risk and business cycles. American Economic Review 102:2734-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1457a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1461" publication-type="other">
Goyal, A., and I. Welch. 2008. A comprehensive look at the empirical performance of equity premium prediction.
Review of Financial Studies 21:1455-508.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1471a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1475" publication-type="other">
Harvey, C. R., and A. Siddique. 2000. Conditional skewness in asset pricing tests. Journal of Finance
55:1263-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1486a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1490" publication-type="other">
Hill, B. 1975. A simple general approach to inference about the tail of a distribution. Annals of Statistics
3:1163-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1500a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1504" publication-type="other">
Hill, J. B. 2010. On tail index estimation for dependent, heterogeneous data. Econometric Theory
26:1398-436.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1514a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1518" publication-type="other">
Hodrick, R. 1992. Dividend yields and expected stock returns: Alternative procedures for inference and
measurement. Review of Financial Studies 5:357-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1528a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1532" publication-type="other">
Hols, M. C. A. B., and C. G De Vries. 1991. The limiting distribution of extremal exchange rate returns. Journal
of Applied Econometrics 6:287-302.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1542a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1546" publication-type="other">
Jansen, D. W., and C. G De Vries. 1991. On the frequency of large stock returns: putting booms and busts into
perspective. Review of Economics and Statistics 73:18-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1556a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1560" publication-type="other">
Jessen, A. H., and T. Mikosch. 2006. Regularly varying functions. Publications De L'Institut Mathmatique,
Nouvelle srie, tome. 80:171-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1571a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1575" publication-type="other">
Karakaya, M. 2013. Expected returns, volatility, and other characteristics in individual equity option markets.
Working Paper, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1585a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1589" publication-type="other">
Kearns, P., and A. Pagan. 1997. Estimating the density tail index for financial time series. Review of Economics
and Statistics 79:171-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1599a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1603" publication-type="other">
Mandelbrot, B. 1963. The variation of certain speculative prices. Journal of business 36:394-^19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1610a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1614" publication-type="other">
Matthys, G, and J. Beirlant. 2000. Adaptive threshold selection in tail index estimation. Extremes and Integrated
Risk Management 37-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1624a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1628" publication-type="other">
Newey, W., and K. West. 1987. A simple, positive semi-definite, heteroskedasticity and autocorrelation consistent
covariance matrix. Econometrica 55:703-08.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1638a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1642" publication-type="other">
Officer, R. R. 1972. The distribution of stock returns. Journal of the American Statistical Association
67:807-12.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1653a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1657" publication-type="other">
Pan, J., and A. Poteshman. 2006. The information in option volume for future stock prices. Review of Financial
Studies 19:871-908.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1667a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1671" publication-type="other">
Pastor, L., and R. Stambaugh. 2003. Liquidity risk and expected stock returns. Journal of Political Economy
111:642-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1681a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1685" publication-type="other">
Quintos, C., Z. Fan, and P. C. B. Philips. 2001. Structural change tests in tail behaviour and the Asian crisis.
Review of Economic Studies 68:633-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1695a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1699" publication-type="other">
Resnick, S., and C. Starica. 1995. Consistency of Hill's estimator for dependent data. Journal of Applied
Probability 32:139-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1709a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1713" publication-type="other">
Richardson, M., and T. Smith. 1991. Tests of financial models in the presence of overlapping observations.
Review of Financial Studies 4:227-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1723a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1727" publication-type="other">
Rietz, T. 1988. The equity risk premium: A solution. Journal of Monetary Economics 22:117-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1735a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1739" publication-type="other">
Rootzen, H., M. R. Leadbetter, and L. Haan. 1998. On the distribution of tail array sums for strongly mixing
stationary sequences. Annals of Applied Probability 8:868-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1749a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1753" publication-type="other">
Stambaugh, R. F. 1999. Predictive regressions. Journal of Financial Economics 54:375-421.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1760a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1764" publication-type="other">
Wächter, J. A. 2013. Can time-varying risk of rare disasters explain aggregate stock market volatility? Journal
of Finance 68:987-1035.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1774a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1778" publication-type="other">
Wagner, N. 2003. Estimating financial risk under time-varying extremal return behavior. OR Spectrum
25:317-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1788a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1792" publication-type="other">
Werner, T., and C. Upper. 2004. Time variation in the tail behavior of Bund future returns. Journal of Futures
Markets 24:387-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1802a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1806" publication-type="other">
Wu, Y. 2013. Asset pricing with extreme liquidity risk. Working Paper, Cornell University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


