<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">jfinance</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j100221</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00221082</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15406261</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25094449</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Which Shorts Are Informed?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ekkehart</given-names>
                  <surname>Boehmer</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Charles M.</given-names>
                  <surname>Jones</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Xiaoyan</given-names>
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date>
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2008</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">63</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i25094447</issue-id>
         <fpage>491</fpage>
         <lpage>527</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2008 The American Finance Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25094449"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>We construct a long daily panel of short sales using proprietary NYSE order data. From 2000 to 2004, shorting accounts for more than 12.9% of NYSE volume, suggesting that shorting constraints are not widespread. As a group, these short sellers are well informed. Heavily shorted stocks underperform lightly shorted stocks by a risk-adjusted average of 1.16% over the following 20 trading days (15.6% annualized). Institutional nonprogram short sales are the most informative; stocks heavily shorted by institutions underperform by 1.43% the next month (19.6% annualized). The results indicate that, on average, short sellers are important contributors to efficient stock prices.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group>
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d10e158a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d10e167" publication-type="other">
Brent, Morse, and Stice (1990)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d10e173" publication-type="other">
Asquith, Pathak, and Ritter (2005)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d10e180" publication-type="other">
Asquith and Meulbroek (1996)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d10e186" publication-type="other">
Desai et al. (2002)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d10e192" publication-type="other">
Lamont and
Stein (2004)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d10e211a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e215" publication-type="other">
Aitken, Michael J., Alex Frino, Michael S. McCorry, and Peter L. Swan, 1998, Short sales are almost
instantaneously bad news: Evidence from the Australian Stock Exchange, Journal of Finance
53, 2205-2223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e228a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e232" publication-type="other">
Ang, Andrew, Robert Hodrick, Yuhang Xing, and Xiaoyan Zhang, 2006, The cross-section of volatil-
ity and expected returns, Journal of Finance 61, 259-299.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e242a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e246" publication-type="other">
Asquith, Paul, and Lisa Meulbroek, 1996, An empirical investigation of short interest, Working
paper, Harvard University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e256a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e260" publication-type="other">
Asquith, Paul, Parag Pathak, and Jay R. Ritter, 2005, Short interest, institutional ownership, and
stock returns, Journal of Financial Economics 78, 243-276.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e271a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e275" publication-type="other">
Barclay, Michael J., and Jerold B. Warner, 1993, Stealth trading and volatility: Which trades move
prices? Journal of Financial Economics 34, 281-305.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e285a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e289" publication-type="other">
Boehmer, Ekkehart, and Eric Kelley, 2007, Institutional investors and the informational efficiency
of prices, Working paper, Texas A&amp;amp;M University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e299a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e303" publication-type="other">
Brennan, Michael J., Tarun Chordia, and Avanidhar Subrahmanyam, 1998, Alternative factor
specifications, security characteristics, and the cross-section of expected stock returns, Journal
of Financial Economics 49, 345-373.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e316a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e320" publication-type="other">
Brent, Averil, Dale Morse, and E. Kay Stice, 1990, Short interest—Explanations and tests, Journal
of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 25, 273-289.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e330a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e334" publication-type="other">
Chakravarty, Sugato, 2001, Stealth-trading: Which traders' trades move stock prices? Journal of
Financial Economics 61, 289-307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e344a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e348" publication-type="other">
Chordia, Tarun, and Avanidhar Subrahmanyam, 2004, Order imbalance and individual stock re-
turns: Theory and evidence, Journal of Financial Economics 72, 485-518.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e359a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e363" publication-type="other">
Christophe, Stephen E., Michael G. Ferri, and James J. Angel, 2004, Short-selling prior to earnings
announcements, Journal of Finance 59, 1845-1876.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e373a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e377" publication-type="other">
Cohen, Lauren, Karl Diether, and Christopher Malloy, 2007, Supply and demand shifts in the
shorting market, Journal of Finance 62, 2061-2096.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e387a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e391" publication-type="other">
D'Avolio, Gene, 2002, The market for borrowing stock, Journal of Financial Economics 66, 271-
306.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e401a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e405" publication-type="other">
Danielsen, Bartley, and Sorin Sorescu, 2001, Why do option introductions depress stock prices? An
empirical study of diminishing short sale constraints, Journal of Financial and Quantitative
Analysis 36, 451-484.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e418a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e422" publication-type="other">
Daske, Holger, Scott A. Richardson, and A. Irem Tuna, 2005, Do short sale transactions precede
bad news events? Working paper, University of Pennsylvania.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e432a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e436" publication-type="other">
Dechow, Patricia, Amy Hutton, Lisa Meulbroek, and Richard G. Sloan, 2001, Short-sellers, funda-
mental analysis, and stock returns, Journal of Financial Economics 61, 77-106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e447a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e451" publication-type="other">
Desai, Hemang, Srinivasan Krishnamurthy, and Kumar Venkataraman, 2006, Do short sellers
target firms with poor earnings quality? Evidence from earnings restatements, Review of Ac-
counting Studies 11, 71-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e464a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e468" publication-type="other">
Desai, Hemang, K. Ramesh, S. Ramu Thiagarajan, and Bala V. Balachandran, 2002, An investiga-
tion of the informational role of short interest in the Nasdaq market, Journal of Finance 57,
2263-2287.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e481a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e485" publication-type="other">
Diamond, Douglas W, and Robert E. Verrechia, 1987, Constraints on short-selling and asset price
adjustment to private information, Journal of Financial Economics 18, 277-311.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e495a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e499" publication-type="other">
Diether, Karl, Kuan-Hui Lee, and Ingrid Werner, 2007, Short-sale strategies and return predictabil-
ity, Review of Financial Studies (forthcoming).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e509a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e513" publication-type="other">
Duffie, Darrell, Nicolae Bogdan Garleanu, and Lasse Heje Pedersen, 2002, Securities lending,
shorting, and pricing, Journal of Financial Economics 66, 307-339.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e523a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e527" publication-type="other">
Fama, Eugene F, and Kenneth R. French, 1993, Common risk factors in the returns on stocks and
bonds, Journal of Financial Economics 33, 3-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e538a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e542" publication-type="other">
Fama, Eugene F, and James MacBeth, 1973, Risk, return and equilibrium: Empirical tests, Journal
of Political Economy 71, 607-636.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e552a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e556" publication-type="other">
Francis, Jennifer, Mohan Venkatachalam, and Yun Zhang, 2005, Do short sellers convey informa-
tion about changes in fundamentals or risk? Working paper, Duke University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e566a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e570" publication-type="other">
Geczy, Christopher C, David K. Musto, and Adam V. Reed, 2002, Stocks are special too: An analysis
of the equity lending market, Journal of Financial Economics 66, 241-269.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e580a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e584" publication-type="other">
Harrison, J. Michael, and David M. Kreps, 1978, Speculative investor behavior in a stock market
with heterogeneous expectations, Quarterly Journal of Economics 92, 323—336.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e594a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e598" publication-type="other">
Hong, Harrison, Jose Scheinkman, and Wei Xiong, 2006, Asset float and speculative bubbles,
Journal of Finance 61, 1073-1117.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e608a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e612" publication-type="other">
Jegadeesh, Narasimhan, and Sheridan Titman, 1993, Returns to buying winners and selling losers:
Implications for stock market efficiency, Journal of Finance 48, 65-91.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e623a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e627" publication-type="other">
Jones, Charles M., 2004, Shorting restrictions, liquidity, and returns, Working paper, Columbia
University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e637a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e641" publication-type="other">
Jones, Charles M., Gautam Kaul, and Marc Lipson, 1994, Transactions, volume and volatility,
Review of Financial Studies 7, 631-651.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e651a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e655" publication-type="other">
Jones, Charles M., and Owen A. Lamont, 2002, Short sale constraints and stock returns, Journal
of Financial Economics 66, 207-239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e665a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e669" publication-type="other">
Jones, Charles M., and Marc L. Lipson, 2004, Are retail orders different? Working paper, Columbia
University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e679a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e683" publication-type="other">
Kaniel, Ron, Gideon Saar, and Sheridan Titman, 2007, Individual investor trading and stock re-
turns, Journal of Finance 63, 273-310.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e693a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e697" publication-type="other">
Lamont, Owen A., and Jeremy C. Stein, 2004, Aggregate short interest and market valuations,
American Economic Review 94, 29-32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e708a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e712" publication-type="other">
Lamont, Owen A., and Richard H. Thaler, 2003, Can the market add and subtract? Mispricing in
tech stock carve-outs, Journal of Political Economy 111, 227-268.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e722a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e726" publication-type="other">
Lee, Charles M. C, and Mark J. Ready, 1991, Inferring trade direction from intraday data, Journal
of Finance 46, 733-746.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e736a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e740" publication-type="other">
Lee, Charles M. C, and Bhaskaran Swaminathan, 2000, Price momentum and trading volume,
Journal of Finance 55, 2017-2069.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e750a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e754" publication-type="other">
Loughran, Tim, and Jay Ritter, 2004, Why has IPO underpricing increased over time? Financial
Management 33, 5-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e764a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e768" publication-type="other">
Miller, Edward M., 1977, Risk, uncertainty, and divergence of opinion, Journal of Finance 32,
1151-1168.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e778a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e782" publication-type="other">
Ofek, Eli, and Matthew Richardson, 2003, DotCom mania: A survey of market efficiency in the
internet sector, Journal of Finance 58, 1113-1138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e793a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e797" publication-type="other">
Ofek, Eli, Matthew Richardson, and Robert F. Whitelaw, 2004, Limited arbitrage and short sales
restrictions: Evidence from the options markets, Journal of Financial Economics 74, 305-342.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d10e807a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d10e811" publication-type="other">
Pan, Jun, and Allen M. Poteshman, 2006, The information in option volume for future stock prices,
Review of Financial Studies 19, 871-908.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
