<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277764</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Numerical Study of the Influence of EGR on In-Cylinder Soot Characteristics in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine using CMC</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Farrace</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniele</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Swiss Federal Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bolla</surname>
                  <given-names>Michele</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Swiss Federal Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wright</surname>
                  <given-names>Yuri M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ETH Zurich/Combustion+FlowSolutions GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Boulouchos</surname>
                  <given-names>Konstantinos</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Swiss Federal Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>May 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277742</issue-id>
         <fpage>256</fpage>
         <lpage>268</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277764"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper presents numerical simulations of in-cylinder soot evolution in the optically accessible heavy-duty diesel engine of Sandia Laboratories performed with the conditional moment closure (CMC) model employing a reduced n-heptane chemical mechanism coupled with a two-equation soot model. The influence of exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) on in-cylinder processes is studied considering different ambient oxygen volume fractions (8 - 21 percent), while maintaining intake pressure and temperature as well as the injection configuration unchanged. This corresponds to EGR rates between 0 and 65 percent.</p>
            <p>Simulation results are first compared with experimental data by means of apparent heat release rate (AHRR) and temporally resolved in-cylinder soot mass, where a quantitative comparison is presented. The model was found to fairly well reproduce ignition delays as well as AHRR traces along the EGR variation with a slight underestimation of the diffusion burn portion. Subsequently, the impact of EGR on the mixture formation, spray characteristics and soot evolution is investigated numerically and governing processes are identified and discussed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tree, D.R. and Svensson K.I., Soot processes in compression ignition engines. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 2007. 33(3): p. 272-309.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akihama, K., Takatori, Y., Inagaki, K., Sasaki, S. et al., “Mechanism of the Smokeless Rich Diesel Combustion by Reducing Temperature,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0655, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., Miles P.C., and Pickett L.M., Conceptual models for partially premixed low-temperature diesel combustion. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 2013. 39(2-3): p. 246-283.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, W.M., Shuai S.J., and Wang J.X., A soot formation embedded reduced reaction mechanism for diesel surrogate fuel. Fuel, 2009. 88(10): p. 1927-1936.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pang, K.M., Ng H.K., and Gan S.Y., Development of an integrated reduced fuel oxidation and soot precursor formation mechanism for CFD simulations of diesel combustion. Fuel, 2011. 90(9): p. 2902- 2914.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, S., Reitz, R., and Musculus, M., “Comparison of the Characteristic Time (CTC), Representative Interactive Flamelet (RTF), and Direct Integration with Detailed Chemistry Combustion Models against Optical Diagnostic Data for Multi-Mode Combustion in a Heavy-Duty DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01- 0055, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0055.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bolla, M., et al., Modeling of soot formation in a heavy-duty diesel engine with conditional moment closure. Fuel, 2014. 117: p. 309- 325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S.L. and Reitz R.D., Investigation of the Roles of Flame Propagation, Turbulent Mixing, and Volumetric Heat Release in Conventional and Low Temperature Diesel Combustion. Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power-Transactions of the Asme, 2011. 133(10).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vishwanathan, G. and Reitz R.D., Development of a Practical Soot Modeling Approach and Its Application to Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion. Combustion Science and Technology, 2010. 182(8): p. 1050-1082.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, Y.X. and Rutland C.J., A mixing controlled direct chemistry (MCDC) model for diesel engine combustion modelling using large eddy simulation. Combustion Theory and Modelling, 2012. 16(3): p. 571-588.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, S., Reitz, R., and Musculus, M., “2-Color Thermometry Experiments and High-Speed Imaging of Multi-Mode Diesel Engine Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3842, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3842.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., Singh S., and Reitz R.D., Gradient effects on two-color soot optical pyrometry in a heavy-duty DI diesel engine. Combustion and Flame, 2008. 153(1-2): p. 216-227.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mastorakos, E., Ignition of turbulent non-premixed flames. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 2009. 35(1): p. 57- 97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bolla, M., Gudmundsson, T., Wright, Y., and Boulouchos, K., “Simulations of Diesel Sprays Using the Conditional Moment Closure Model,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):1249-1261, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1618.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bolla, M., Wright Y.M., and Boulouchos K., Application of a Conditional Moment Closure Combustion model to a large twostroke marine Diesel engine reference experiment. COMODIA, Fukuoka, Japan, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borghesi, G., et al., Modeling evaporation effects in conditional moment closure for spray autoignition. Combustion Theory and Modelling, 2011. 15(5): p. 725-752.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wright, Y.M., et al., Simulations of spray autoignition and flame establishment with two-dimensional CMC. Combustion and Flame, 2005. 143(4): p. 402-419.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wright, Y.M., et al., Experiments and Simulations of n-Heptane Spray Auto-Ignition in a Closed Combustion Chamber at Diesel Engine Conditions. Flow Turbulence and Combustion, 2010. 84(1): p. 49-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bolla, M., et al., Soot Formation Modeling of n-Heptane Sprays Under Diesel Engine Conditions Using the Conditional Moment Closure Approach. Combustion Science and Technology, 2013. 185(5): p. 766-793.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bottone, F., et al., The Numerical Simulation of Diesel Spray Combustion with LES-CMC. Flow Turbulence and Combustion, 2012. 89(4): p. 651-673.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Paola, G., et al., Diesel engine simulations with multidimensional conditional moment closure. Combustion Science and Technology, 2008. 180(5): p. 883-899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wright, Y., Boulouchos, K., De Paola, G., and Mastorakos, E., “Multi-dimensional Conditional Moment Closure Modelling Applied to a Heavy-duty Common-rail Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):714-726, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0717.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrace, D., Bolla, M., Wright, Y., and Boulouchos, K., “Predicting In-Cylinder Soot in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine for Variations in SOI and TDC Temperature Using the Conditional Moment Closure Model,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(3):1580-1593, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoshikawa, T. and Reitz R.D., Effect of Radiation on Diesel Engine Combustion and Heat Transfer. Journal of Thermal Science and Technology, 2009. 4(1): p. 86-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huestis, E., Erickson, P., and Musculus, M., “In-Cylinder and Exhaust Soot in Low-Temperature Combustion Using a Wide- Range of EGR in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4017, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-4017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CD-adapco, Methodology Star-CD Version 4.16. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R. and Diwakar, R., “Effect of Drop Breakup on Fuel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 860469, 1986, doi:10.4271/860469.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bai, C. and Gosman, A., “Development of Methodology for Spray Impingement Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 950283, 1995, doi:10.4271/950283.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klimenko, A.Y. and Bilger R.W., Conditional moment closure for turbulent combustion. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 1999. 25(6): p. 595-687.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, S.L., et al., Effects of strain rate on high-pressure nonpremixed n-heptane autoignition in counterflow. Combustion and Flame, 2004. 137(3): p. 320-339.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pitz, W.J. and Mueller C.J., Recent progress in the development of diesel surrogate fuels. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 2011. 37(3): p. 330-350.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battin-Leclerc, F., Detailed chemical kinetic models for the low-temperature combustion of hydrocarbons with application to gasoline and diesel fuel surrogates. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 2008. 34(4): p. 440-498.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leung, K.M., Lindstedt R.P., and Jones W.P., A Simplified Reaction-Mechanism for Soot Formation in Nonpremixed Flames. Combustion and Flame, 1991. 87(3-4): p. 289-305.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kronenburg, A., Bilger R.W., and Kent J.H., Modeling soot formation in turbulent methane-air jet diffusion flames. Combustion and Flame, 2000. 121(1-2): p. 24-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pitsch, H., Unsteady flamelet modeling of differential diffusion in turbulent jet diffusion flames. Combustion and Flame, 2000. 123(3): p. 358-374.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ma, G., et al., Optimization of soot modeling in turbulent nonpremixed ethylene/air jet flames. Combustion Science and Technology, 2005. 177(8): p. 1567-1602.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bobba, M., Genzale, C., and Musculus, M., “Effect of Ignition Delay on In-Cylinder Soot Characteristics of a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Operating at Low Temperature Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):911-924, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0946.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., “A Conceptual Model of DI Diesel Combustion Based on Laser-Sheet Imaging*,” SAE Technical Paper 970873, 1997, doi:10.4271/970873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
