<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169009</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Rapid Prototyping Energy Management System for a Single Shaft Parallel Hybrid Electric Vehicle Using Hardware-in-the-Loop Simulation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Yang</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Agashe</surname>
                  <given-names>Pushkar</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ge</surname>
                  <given-names>Zicheng</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chen</surname>
                  <given-names>Bo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Michigan Technological Univ.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>July 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169008</issue-id>
         <fpage>241</fpage>
         <lpage>251</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169009"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Energy management is one of the key challenges for the development of Hybrid Electric Vehicle (HEV) due to its complex powertrain structure. Hardware-In-the-Loop (HIL) simulation provides an open software architecture which enables rapid prototyping HEV energy management system. This paper presents the investigation of the energy management system for a single shaft parallel hybrid electric vehicle using dSPACE eDrive HIL system. The parallel hybrid electric vehicle, energy management system, and low-level Electronic Control Unit (ECU) were modeled using dSPACE Automotive Simulation Models and dSPACE blocksets. Vehicle energy management is achieved by a vehicle-level controller called hybrid ECU, which controls vehicle operation mode and torque distribution among Internal Combustion Engine (ICE) and electric motor. The individual powertrain components such as ICE, electric motor, and transmission are controlled by low-level ECUs. To examine the performance of hybrid ECU and low-level ECUs, vehicle mode control, speed tracking, energy distribution, regenerative braking, and engine operating region were investigated in the HIL environment with a hardware electric motor controller consisting of dSPACE MicroAutoBox II and the AC Motor Control Solution. The presented work illustrates that the HIL system is a suitable environment for the rapid prototyping of HEV control strategies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tate, E. D., Harpster, M. O., and Savagian, P. J., “The Electrification of the Automobile: From Conventional Hybrid, to Plug-in Hybrids, to Extended-Range Electric Vehicles,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Electron. Electr. Syst. 1(1):156-166, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0458.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kott, K. and Waeltermann, P., “Embedded Software Tools Enable Hybrid Vehicle Architecture Design and Optimization,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2308, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2308.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagener, A., Kabza, H., Koerner, C., and Seger, P., “Model-based Drivetrain Development and Rapid Prototyping For a Hybrid Electric Car,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3422, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-3422.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsai, G., Wu, Y., Chen, B., and Chuang, H., “Rapid Prototyping ECU of a SI Engine with Fuel Injection and Ignition Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0419, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0419.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fathy, H. K., Filipi, Z. S., Hagena, J., and Stein, J. L., “Review of hardware-in-the-loop simulation and its prospects in the automotive area,” Proc. SPIE 6228, Modeling and Simulation for Military Applications 62280E-62280E, 2006, doi: 10.1117/12.667794.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anakwa, W. K. N., Roca, H. P., Lopez, J., and Malinowski, A., “Environments for rapid implementation of control algorithms and hardware-in-the-loop simulation,” in IECON 02 [Industrial Electronics Society, IEEE 2002 28th Annual Conference]2002 3:2288-2293 vol.3, 2002, doi: 10.1109/iecon.2002.1185329.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagener, A., Schulte, T., Waeltermann, P., and Schuette, H., “Hardware-in-the-Loop Test Systems for Electric Motors in Advanced Powertrain Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0498, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0498.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Köhl, S. and Jegminat, D., “How to Do Hardware-in-the-Loop Simulation Right,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1657, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-1-1657.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ramaswamy, D., McGee, R., Sivashankar, S., Deshpande, A., Allen, J., Rzemien, K., and Stuart, W., “A Case Study in Hardware-In-the-Loop Testing: Development of an ECU for a Hybrid Electric Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0303, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0303.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dhaliwal, A., Nagaraj, S. C., and Ali, S., “Hardware-in-the-Loop Simulation for Hybrid Electric Vehicles - An Overview, Lessons Learned and Solutions Implemented,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0735, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0735.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Semenov, S. G., “Automation of Hardware-in-the-Loop and In-the- Vehicle Testing and Validation for Hybrid Electric Vehicles at Ford,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1448, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1448.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jiang, S., Smith, M. H., Kitchen, J., and Ogawa, A., “Development of an Engine-in-the-loop Vehicle Simulation System in Engine Dynamometer Test Cell,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1039, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1039.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Habeebullah, A., Zheng, Q., and Chung, W., “A Closed-Loop Drivetrain Model for HIL Test Bench,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1139, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1139</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
