<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169095</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Methods for Measuring, Analyzing and Predicting the Dynamic Torque of an Electric Drive Used in an Automotive Drivetrain</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Albers</surname>
                  <given-names>Albert</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IPEK</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fischer</surname>
                  <given-names>Jan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IPEK</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Behrendt</surname>
                  <given-names>Matthias</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>IPEK</aff>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lieske</surname>
                  <given-names>Dirk</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Daimler AG</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>July 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169081</issue-id>
         <fpage>363</fpage>
         <lpage>369</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 Karlsruhe Institute of Technology</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169095"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The driving comfort is an important factor for buying decisions. For the interior noise of battery electric vehicles (BEV) high frequency tonal orders are characteristic. They can for example be caused by the gearbox or the electric drive and strongly influence the perception and rating of the interior noise by the customer.</p>
            <p>In this contribution methods for measuring, analyzing and predicting the excitation by the dynamic torque of the electric drive are presented. The dynamic torque of the electric drive up to 3.5 kHz is measured on a component test bench with the help of high frequency, high precision torque transducer. The analysis of the results for the order of interest shows a good correlation with the acoustic measurements inside the corresponding vehicle. In addition an experimental and numerical modal analysis of the rotor of the electric drive are performed. The torsional resonance modes are put into context of the elevation of the dynamic torque with regard to the frequency. In a further analysis the phase shifts of the torsional excitation of the different rotor segments, caused by the skewing of the stator, are taken into account. The results show a good correlation with the elevation of the dynamic torque as well as the acoustic measurement for the order of interest.</p>
            <p>The measurements, as well as the simulation, are integrated in a validation environment in context of the X-in-the-Loop framework. This enables a consistent and thorough validation of BEV interior noise in virtual as well as physical domain.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Albers, A., Fischer, J., Behrendt, M., and Lieske, D., “Method for measuring and interpreting the transfer path of acoustic phenomena in the drivetrain of a battery electric vehicle,” VDI-Berichte 2187, Friedrichshafen, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fischer, J., Behrendt, M., Lieske, D., and Albers, A., “Measurement and analysis of the interior noise and the transfer path of acoustic phenomena into the driver cabin of a battery electric vehicle,” INTER-NOISE and NOISE-CON Congress and Conference Proceedings 249(7):823-832, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Albers, A., Fischer, J., Landes, D., and Behrendt, M., “Method for Measuring and Analyzing the Transfer Path of Acoustic Phenomena into the Driver Cabin of a Battery Electric Vehicle,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(3):1585-1592, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2071.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Albers, A., Fischer, J., and Lieske, D., “Measurement and Interpretation of the Transfer Path of an Acoustic Phenomenon in the Drivetrain of an Electric Vehicle,” ATZ Worldwide 116(3):48-55, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Albers, A., Fischer, J., Bahrendt, M., and Schwarz, A., “Method for measuring and interpreting the surface velocities induced by torsional vibration in the drivetrain of a battery electric vehicle,” INTER-NOISE and NOISE-CON Congress and Conference Proceedings 247(8):374-383, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Albers, A., Behrendt, M., Fischer, J., and Lieske, D., “Identification and definition of acoustic relevant limit values for electric vehicles,” 14. Internationales Stuttgarter Symposium, Springer: 1339-1354, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Albers, A., Düser, T., and Ott, S., “X-in-the-loop als integrierte Entwicklungsumgebung von komplexen Antriebsystemen,” 8. Tagung Hardware-in-the-loop-Simulation, Haus der Technik, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Albers, A., Behrendt, M., and Ott, S., “Validation - Central Activity to Ensure Individual Mobility,” FISITA 2010, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Albers, A. and Maier, T., “3D-LDV für die experimentelle Modalanalyse und den Abgleich mit komplexen FE-Modellen,” 11. Polytec Anwenderkonferenz, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mayes, R.L. and Gomez, A.J., “Part 4: What'S Shakin', Dude? Effective use of Modal Shakers,” Experimental Techniques 30(4):51-61, 2006, doi:10.1111/j.1747-1567.2006.00063.x.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adhikari, S., “Damping modelling using generalized proportional damping,” Journal of Sound and Vibration 293(1-2):156-170, 2006, doi:10.1016/j.jsv.2005.09.034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhu, Z.Q. and Howe, D., “Influence of design parameters on cogging torque in permanent magnet machines,” IEEE Transactions on Energy Conversion 15(4):407-412, 2000, doi:10.1109/60.900501.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Islam, R., Husain, I., Fardoun, A., and McLaughlin, K., “Permanent- Magnet Synchronous Motor Magnet Designs With Skewing for Torque Ripple and Cogging Torque Reduction,” IEEE Transactions on Industry Applications 45(1):152-160, 2009, doi:10.1109/TIA.2008.2009653.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dai, M., Keyhani, A., and Sebastian, T., “Torque ripple analysis of a PM brushless DC motor using finite element method,” IEEE Transactions on Energy Conversion 19(1): 40-45, 2004, doi:10.1109/TEC.2003.819105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LaRee, J. De and Boules, N., “Torque production in permanent-magnet synchronous motors,” IEEE Transactions on Industry Applications 25(1):107-112, 1989, doi:10.1109/28.18879.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jahns, T.M. and Soong, W.L., “Pulsating torque minimization techniques for permanent magnet AC motor drives-a review,” IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics 43(2):321-330, 1996, doi:10.1109/41.491356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bianchi, N. and Bolognani, S., “Design techniques for reducing the cogging torque in surface-mounted PM motors,” IEEE Transactions on Industry Applications 38(5):1259-1265, 2002, doi:10.1109/TIA.2002.802989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Systèmes Dassault, ed., Abaqus 6.14 Analysis User's Guide, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Systèmes Dassault, ed., Abaqus 6.14 Theory Guide, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dresig, H., “Schwingungen mechanischer Antriebssysteme: Modellbildung, Berechnung, Analyse, Synthese,” 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skogestad, S. and Postlethwaite, I., “Multivariable Feedback Control - Analysis and Design.”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
