<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26562393</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Validation of Crush Energy Calculation Methods for Use in Accident Reconstructions by Finite Element Analysis</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Numata</surname>
                  <given-names>Shusuke</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nagoya University, Japan</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Mizuno</surname>
                  <given-names>Koji</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nagoya University, Japan</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ito</surname>
                  <given-names>Daisuke</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nagoya University, Japan</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Okumura</surname>
                  <given-names>Dai</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nagoya University, Japan</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kinoshita</surname>
                  <given-names>Hisashi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>DENSO Corporation, Japan</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>6</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26562390</issue-id>
         <fpage>133</fpage>
         <lpage>146</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26562393"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The crush energy is a key parameter to determine the delta-V in accident reconstructions. Since an accurate car crush profile can be obtained from 3D scanners, this research aims at validating the methods currently used in calculating crush energy from a crush profile. For this validation, a finite element (FE) car model was analyzed using various types of impact conditions to investigate the theory of energy-based accident reconstruction.</p> 
            <p>Two methods exist to calculate the crush energy: the work based on the barrier force and the work based on force calculated by the vehicle acceleration times the vehicle mass. We show that the crush energy calculated from the barrier force was substantially larger than the internal energy calculated from the FE model. Whereas the crush energy calculated from the vehicle acceleration was comparable to the internal energy of the FE model.</p> 
            <p>In full frontal impact simulations, the energy of approach factor (EAF) has a linear relation with the residual crush, which had been validated in previous experimental studies. In our study using FE analysis, we found that the slope of EAF versus the residual crush was comparable with that of the dynamic crush energy versus the dynamic crush for crashes at 55 km/h. Using this slope and the residual crush from a 55 km/h impact test, the slope and the intercept of the EAF vs. residual crush can be determined using only one crash test. A database of the slopes and the intercepts was made using Japan New Car Assessment Program (JNCAP) tests. In offset impact simulations, the crush energy calculated from the crush profile agreed with the internal energy of the car FE model when at least one front rail was involved. In oblique impacts, the correction factor for crush energy is not necessary within 20 degrees of principal direction of force of the car’s longitudinal axis.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label> 
            <kwd>Crush energy</kwd> 
            <kwd>Delta-V</kwd> 
            <kwd>Accident reconstruction</kwd> 
            <kwd>Finite element analysis</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Emori, R., “Analytical Approach to Automobile Collisions,” SAE Technical Paper 680016, 1968, doi:10.4271/680016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Campbell, K., “Energy Basis for Collision Severity,” SAE Technical Paper 740565, 1974, doi:10.4271/740565.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McHenry, R., “User’s Manual for the Crash Computer Program,” Calspan Report No. ZQ-5708-V-3, Contract No. DOT-HS-5-01124, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prasad, A., “CRASH3 Damage Algorithm Reformulation for Front and Rear Collisions,” SAE Technical Paper 900098, 1990, doi:10.4271/900098</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strother, C., Woolley, R., and James, M., “A Comparison between NHTSA Crash Test Data and CRASH3 Frontal Stiffness Coefficients,” SAE Technical Paper 900101, 1990, doi:10.4271/900101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Struble, D.E., Automotive Accident Reconstruction: Practices and Principles (Boca Raton, FL: CRC Press, 2013).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kerkhoff, J., Husher, S., Varat, M., Busenga, A. et al., “An Investigation into Vehicle Frontal Impact Stiffness, BEV and Repeated Testing for Reconstruction,” SAE Technical Paper 930899, 1993, doi:10.4271/930899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Varat, M., Husher, S., and Kerkhoff, J., “An Analysis of Trends of Vehicle Frontal Impact Stiffness,” SAE Technical Paper 940914, 1994, doi:10.4271/940914.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brach, R.M. and Brach, R.M., “Crush Energy and Planar Impact Mechanics for Accident Reconstruction,” SAE Technical Paper 980025, 1998, doi:10.4271/980025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fonda, A., “Crush Energy Formulations and Single-Event Reconstruction,” SAE Technical Paper 900099, 1990, doi:10.4271/900099.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woolley, R., “Non-Linear Damage Analysis in Accident Reconstruction,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0504, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0504.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hunter, R., Fix, R., Lee, F., and King, D., “Using Force-Displacement Data to Predict the EBS of Car into Barrier Impacts,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-1483, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-1483.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oga, R., Ide, Y., and Ikari, T., “Construction of Energy Absorption Diagram Based on Experimental Data in Japanese New Car Assessment Program,” Review of Automotive Engineering 29:111-113, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gabler, H.C., Hinch, J.A., and Steiner, J., Event Data Recorders: A Decade of Innovation (SAE International, 2008).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marzougui, D., Samaha, R., Cui, C., and Kan, C., “Extended Validation of the Finite Element Model for the 2010 Toyota Yaris Passenger Sedan,” Working Paper, NCAC 2012- W-005, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Organization for Standardization (ISO), “Road Vehicles - Objective Rating Metric for Non-Ambiguous Signals,” ISO/TS 18571, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johanssen, H., Adolph, T., Thomson, R., Edwards, M. et al., “FIMCAR - Frontal Impact and Compatibility Assessment Research: Strategy and First Results for Future Frontal Impact Assessment,” 22nd ESV, Washington, DC, June 13-16, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yonezawa, H., Mizuno, K., Hirasawa, T. et al., “Summary of Activities of the Compatibility Working Group in Japan,” 21st ESV, Stuttgart, Germany, June 15-18, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mizuno, K., Crash Safety of Passenger Vehicles (Nagoya University Press, 2012) (in Japanese).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wood, D., “Structural Rebound Characteristics of the Car Population in Frontal Impacts,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0461, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0461.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tavakoli, M., Valliappan, P., Pranesh, A., and Savage, C., “Estimation of Frontal Crush Stiffness Coefficients for Car-to-Heavy Truck Underride Collisions,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0731, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0731.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bare, C., Peterson, D., Marine, M., and Welsh, K., “Energy Dissipation in High Speed Frontal Collisions,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0770, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0770.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Monk, M. and Guenther, D., “Update of Crash2 Computer Model Damage Tables,” VRTC-SRL-16, DOT HS-806 446, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
