<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">8</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466874</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466881</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Can "High Costs" Justify Weak Demand for the Home Equity Conversion Mortgage?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
                  <surname>Davidoff</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2364</fpage>
         <lpage>2398</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466881"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Home Equity Conversion Mortgages ("HECMs") implicitly bundle nondefaultable credit lines with put options that let borrowers, or their heirs, sell mortgaged homes for the credit line limit when borrowers move or die. The put option's value, net of closing costs, bounds HECM's value to borrowers below. Older homeowners' weak demand is commonly attributed to HECM's "high costs," and the government prices insurance intending to avoid subsidy. However, simulations indicate put value has often exceeded closing costs, even ignoring other embedded options and using backward-looking expectations near the recent price-cycle peak. These results make weak demand more puzzling.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d623298e169a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e176" publication-type="other">
See Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (2012) for participation-rate calculations. The small private reverse
mortgage market has essentially disappeared since the late 2000s housing finance crisis.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e186a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e193" publication-type="other">
Venti and Wise (2001) among others document the importance of home equity in retiree portfolios. Bayer and
Harper (2000) presents survey evidence that most retirees are strongly averse to moving out of their homes.
Building on the theoretical foundation in Artie and Varaiya (1978), Mayer and Simons (1994) estimate that a
very large number of retired homeowners are sufficiently house rich and cash poor that a reverse mortgage would
provide significant benefits. Market potential in other countries has been explored by Deng and Ma (2013) and
Mitchell and Piggott (2005), among others.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e216a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e223" publication-type="other">
Fewer than 20% of U.S. homeowners over age 75 in the 2007-2010 American Community Survey owe any
mortgage debt. Tabulations of Health and Retirement Study (HRS/AHEAD) data show that among individuals
between 65 and 70 years old who owned a home with no mortgage debt in 1998 or 2000, and who owned a home
in 2010, fewer than 9% owed any mortgage debt in 2010; among those 75 to 80, fewer than 7% owed mortgage
debt in 2010.4</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e242a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e249" publication-type="other">
Author's calculations using unweighted RAND-contributed HRS panel data: "H*AMORT" from RAND and
core interview questions H056 "Home Equity Credit." The latter measure may include HECM loans, the former
is not meant to.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e263a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e270" publication-type="other">
Shiller and Weiss (2000) and Miceli and Sirmans (1994) note maintenance may decline when the put option is
likely to terminate in the money, and Capone, Chang, and Cushman (2010) find evidence that HECM borrowers
do less maintenance than other homeowners do. Davidoff and Welke (2006) find that HECM terminations are
highly procyclical, which likely augments net put-option value, holding mean terminations constant.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e286a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e293" publication-type="other">
See Shan (2011), Haurin and others (2014), and Davidoff and Wetzel (2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e300a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e307" publication-type="other">
Otherwise, both the choice of how much to consume and how to finance each level of consumption would have
to be chosen in each period along every stochastic path.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e317a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e324" publication-type="other">
There are other differences in modeling that may affect put-option value. First, NT's parameterization of utility
appears to generate large response of home sales to anticipated price volatility and expected price declines. If
potential borrowers sell their homes upon news that price declines are imminent, then the put option has little
value, because it does not have enough time to come into the money. Second, unlike this article, NT consider the
option of waiting to use HECM (and spend closing costs) until more information concerning liquidity demand
and available proceeds from HECM is revealed. NT may overstate the benefit of waiting by assuming the need
to dispose of financial assets at closing. The benefit of waiting may also be attenuated in reality by HECM's
discounts to insurance premiums for refinance, which both NT and this article ignore. A third difference, NT's
explicit modeling of bequest and precautionary motives, would likely increase put-option value to borrowers.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e356a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e363" publication-type="other">
Thus a HECM on a high-end home may have very little put-option value.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e370a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e377" publication-type="other">
HECM regulations are laid out in a handbook and a series of "mortgagee letters" (http://portal.hud.gov/hudportal/
HUD?src=/program_offices/housing/sfh/hecm/hecmml).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e388a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e395" publication-type="other">
Eligible homeowners can use HECM if their spouse is under 62, but that spouse must be dropped from title. The
loan is then due upon death or exit from the home of the older spouse. Such terminations have been problematic
and FHA policy is adapting.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e408a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e415" publication-type="other">
Per Redfoot, Scholen, and Brown (2007). Preexisting debt must be subordinated to HECM to stay in place.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e422a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e429" publication-type="other">
Origination fees are capped at 2%, and reimbursable lender costs average roughly $3,400 according to Canadian
Mortgage and Housing Corporation (2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e439a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e446" publication-type="other">
The simulations below ignore servicing fees, which may be charged either as a flat amount (up to $35 per month
on lines of credit) or as interest charges. Servicing fees charged via interest would not reduce put-option value,
but both types diminish line-of-credit value.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e459a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e466" publication-type="other">
Per Mortgagee Letter 2008-38, "If the mortgage is due and payable and the borrower (or estate) will not be
retaining ownership of the property, the property may be sold for at least the lesser of the unpaid mortgage
balance or 95% of appraised value."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e479a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e486" publication-type="other">
Whether heirs can retain the home by paying off the appraised value, as opposed to the loan amount, is an area
of current controversy. Mortgagee letters suggest that heirs could presumably pay the appraised value to cancel
the debt, have the servicer sell the home, and bid for the home.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e500a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e507" publication-type="other">
The fact that borrowers, who must go through credit counseling, apparently do not ask counselors about short-
sale consequences may be evidence that they do not have strategic use of limited liability in mind. For potential
borrowers with low incomes, available nonmortgage credit is likely to be minimal, so that both the opportunity
cost of any damage to credit and the probability that credit damage would affect entry into a nursing home are
likely quite small. Borrowers may live in a nursing facility for at least 12 months before the lender can accelerate
the debt, and Jones (2002) finds that over 80% of nursing-home stays are shorter than 12 months.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e530a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e537" publication-type="other">
See Davidoff and Welke (2006). Assuming expected price growth is less than the loan interest rate, remaining
in the home when the put option is in the money increases expected put option value. Empirically, many of
the excess terminations that have occurred when home values have grown faster than credit lines have been
(relatively underpriced) refinances into larger HECMs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e553a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e560" publication-type="other">
Required repairs that the homeowner would otherwise not do, and deviations of homeowners' insurance from fair
pricing are costs of HECM to risk-neutral borrowers relative to no HECM loan. The requirement that borrowers
pay property taxes is likely not a cost of HECM absent mortgage debt. Borrowers would presumably have
difficulty avoiding property taxes long enough for the tax lien to exceed property value.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e576a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e583" publication-type="other">
This truncation reduces put-option value somewhat because expected put value is convex in age, but there is
little data on termination probabilities past 97, and it may strain credulity to model borrowers at advanced ages
cashing in on option value just before termination.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e596a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e603" publication-type="other">
In reality, Case-Shiller local home-price index futures are not liquid even at short horizons; Real Estate Investment
Trusts (REITs) or home builder shares might approximate the underlying collateral but would introduce stock
market risk. A portfolio of hedging position offsetting the puts value at each possible T would themselves only
be offset by a realized put at one T. Without (a) or (b), trades in a price index and bonds might be able to hedge
the expectation of put value across termination dates without risk, but not the realization.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e622a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e629" publication-type="other">
Borrowers who discount between loan closing and expected termination at a greater rate than the loan interest
rate would benefit from borrowing against the credit line. Section 3 discusses a case in which patient borrowers
might value the put option alone less than impatient borrowers do.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e643a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e650" publication-type="other">
Based on online tabulations from IPUMS USA.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e657a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e664" publication-type="other">
With 8(t,z)=r(t,z)+s credit use does not affect HECM's NPV to the borrower.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e671a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e678" publication-type="other">
HRS exit rates a// over 2-year periods are converted to annual rates. For two missing values I use fitted values
from a regression with a dummy for marital status and a quadratic in age. The coefficient on gender in such a
regression is indistinguishable from zero.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e691a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e698" publication-type="other">
The 2 million cutoff is motivated by the facts that Vermont and West Virginia featured some obvious outlying
FHFA home-price data early in the time series, and West Virginia had just under 2 million residents as of 1980.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e708a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e715" publication-type="other">
rt is the sum of 4 quarters for 4-quarter differences. Imposing a 2% mean riskless rate reduces the volatility of
k in Monte Carlo simulations because long sequences of dates contain almost all observations of r, particularly
over the 1983-2002 period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e728a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e735" publication-type="other">
The published version of that article has a shorter panel. With far fewer observations per period than U.S. states,
we expect short-run differences to be overstated because of noise.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e746a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e753" publication-type="other">
That methodology assumes away market-level volatility. Peng (2015) suggests that the magnitude of individual
property deviations from market index growth may, in fact, not vary with time. I find in untabulated simulations
that fixing the standard deviation at the exit probability-weighted mean yields almost identical results to those
presented, not surprisingly in light of the exit rates plotted in Figure 2.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e769a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e776" publication-type="other">
See Glaeser, Gyourko, and Saiz (2008); Davidoff (2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e783a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e790" publication-type="other">
Sinai and Souleles (2005) and Sinai and Souleles (2013) provide evidence consistent with hedging demand on
the part of younger households (although weaker demand among older households). Standard models of bequests
echoed in NT, such as De Nardi, French, and Jones (2010), do not have home prices in the bequest function.
Heirs' housing consumption is also likely hedged through uninsured labor income. Shiller (1993) and Caplin and
others (1997) suggest that there should be strong demand for short positions in prices among homeowners.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e809a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e816" publication-type="other">
The relationships between nursing home expenditures and longevity (Webb, 2009) and the marginal utility of
wealth themselves are not well understood. Consumption externalities (Finkelstein, Luttmer, and Notowidigdo,
2013) and Medicaid (Brown and Finkelstein, 2007) cloud the relationship between marginal utility and nursing
home expenditures. If long-term care is a very high marginal utility state of the world, then absence of demand for
long-term care insurance is difficult to rationalize (Lockwood, 2013, Koijen, Van Nieuwerburgh, and Yogo, 2014).
Home equity illiquidity may rationalize both absence of demand for annuities and long-term care insurance, so
whether these products would be more commonly held with a HECM in place is difficult to know (Davidoff,
2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e845a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e852" publication-type="other">
Brown and others (2008) and Chalmers and Reuter (2012) find that framing and lagged stock market returns
affect demand for annuities in ways that appear inconsistent with rational valuation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e862a1310">
            <label>34</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e869" publication-type="other">
This project was inspired by a discussion with an Arizona mortgage broker who confessed difficulty explaining to
prospective borrowers that they could use HECM as a put option that would not adversely affect heirs' bequests.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e880a1310">
            <label>35</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e887" publication-type="other">
Quantifying the effect on value is difficult because there does not appear to be an off-the-shelf estimate of
the fraction of deaths that come without warning. Heirs have an incentive to alert parents to put value near
termination.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623298e900a1310">
            <label>35</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623298e907" publication-type="other">
Most older homeowners express a desire to avoid selling and moving out of their homes, per Bayer and Harper
(2000), and there are institutional barriers to taking on home-equity debt in retirement (see Shan (2011) and NT).
However, these alternatives may be particularly attractive to those otherwise likeliest to use HECM. Among
those for whom HECM offers a favorably priced put, selling is a more plausible substitute for the put option for
those anticipating short-run price declines, rather than stable but weak price appreciation. Coile and Davidoff
(2013) find that while home sales among older owners were procyclical during the home-price boom and bust,
there was not a quantitatively large jump in home sales among older homeowners in the Sand States.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d623298e942a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e946" publication-type="other">
Artie, R., and P. Varaiya. 1978. Life cycle consumption and homeownership. Journal of Economic Theory
18:38-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e956a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e960" publication-type="other">
Bayer, A., and L. Harper. 2000. Fixing to stay: a national survey of housing and home modification issues.
Research Report, AARP.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e970a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e974" publication-type="other">
Brown, J., and A. Finkelstein. 2007. Why is the market for long-term care insurance so small? Journal of Public
Economics 91:1967-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e984a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e988" publication-type="other">
Brown, J., J. Kling, S. Mullainathan, and M. Wrobel. 2008. Why don't people insure late-life consumption? A
framing explanation of the under-annuitization puzzle. American Economic Review 98:304-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e999a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1003" publication-type="other">
Burnside, C., M. Eichenbaum, and S. Rebelo. 2011. Understanding booms and busts in housing markets.
Discussion Papers 8232, CEPR.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1013a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1017" publication-type="other">
Calhoun, C. 1996. OFHEO house price indices: HPI technical description. Manuscript, Office of Federal Housing
Enterprise Oversight.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1027a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1031" publication-type="other">
Canadian Mortgage and Housing Corporation. 2012. Reverse mortgages. Technical Report, CMHC.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1038a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1042" publication-type="other">
Caplin, A., S. Chan, C. Freeman, and J. Tracy. 1997. Housing Partnerships: A new approach to markets at a
crossroads. Cambridge: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1052a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1056" publication-type="other">
Capone, C., K. Chang, and C. Cushman. 2010. Identification of home maintenance risk in reverse mortgages: An
empirical examination of home price appreciation among HECM borrowers. Working Paper, U.S. Department
of Housing and Urban Development.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1069a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1073" publication-type="other">
Case, K., and R. Shiller. 1989. The efficiency of the market for single-family homes. The American Economic
Review 79:125-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1084a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1088" publication-type="other">
Chalmers, J., and J. Reuter. 2012. How do retirees value life annuities? Evidence from public employees. Review
of Financial Studies 25:2601-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1098a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1102" publication-type="other">
Chinloy, P., and I. Megbolugbe. 1994. Reverse mortgages: Contracting and crossover risk. Journal of the American
Real Estate and Urban Economics Association 22:367-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1112a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1116" publication-type="other">
Coile, C., and T. Davidoff. 2013. House prices, mobility, and mortgage debt among the elderly: Evidence from
the 2000s. Working Paper, University of British Columbia and Wellesley College.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1126a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1130" publication-type="other">
Consumer Financial Protection Bureau. 2012. Reverse mortgages. Report to Congress, U.S. Government.
Davidoff, T. 2009. Housing, health, and annuities. Journal of Risk and Insurance 76:31-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1140a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1144" publication-type="other">
. 2014. Reverse mortgage demographics and collateral performance. Working Paper, University of British
Columbia.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1154a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1158" publication-type="other">
. 2013. Supply elasticity and the housing cycle of the 2000s. Real Estate Economics 41:793-813.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1166a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1170" publication-type="other">
Davidoff, T., J. Brown, and P. Diamond. 2005. Annuities and individual welfare. American Economic Review
95:1573-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1180a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1184" publication-type="other">
Davidoff, T., and G Welke. 2006. Selection and moral hazard in the reverse mortgage market. Working Paper,
UC Berkeley.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1194a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1198" publication-type="other">
Davidoff, T., and J. Wetzel. 2013. Do reverse mortgage borrowers use credit ruthlessly? Working Paper, Sauder
School of Business, University of British Columbia.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1208a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1212" publication-type="other">
Davis, M., and F. Ortalo-Magne. 2011. Househould expenditures, wages, rents. Review of Economic Dynamics
14:248-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1222a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1226" publication-type="other">
De Nardi, M., E. French, and J. Jones. 2010. Why do the elderly save? The role of medical expenses. Journal of
Political Economy 118:39—75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1236a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1240" publication-type="other">
Deng, Y., and S. Ma. 2013. Evaluation of reverse mortgage programs in Korea. Seoul Journal of Business
19:137-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1251a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1255" publication-type="other">
Eichholtz, P. 1997. A long run house price index: The Herengracht Index, 1628-1973. Real Estate Economics
25:175-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1265a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1269" publication-type="other">
Favara, G, and Z. Song. 2014. House price dynamics with dispersed information. Journal of Economic Theory
149:350-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1279a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1283" publication-type="other">
Finkelstein, A., E. Luttmer, and M. Notowidigdo. 2013. What good is wealth without health? The effect
of health on the marginal utility of consumption. Journal of the European Economic Association 11:
221-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1296a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1300" publication-type="other">
Glaeser, E., J. Gyourko, and A. Saiz. 2008. Housing supply and housing bubbles. Journal of Urban Economics
64:198-217.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1310a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1314" publication-type="other">
Greenhalgh-Stanley, N. 2012. Medicaid and the housing and asset decisions of the elderly: Evidence from estate
recovery programs. Journal of Urban Economics 72:210-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1324a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1328" publication-type="other">
Haurin, D., C. Ma, S. Moulton, M. Schmeiser, J. Seligman, and W. Shi. 2014. Spatial variation in reverse
mortgages usage: House price dynamics and consumer selection. The Journal of Real Estate Finance and
Economics : 1—26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1342a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1346" publication-type="other">
Integrated Financial Engineering, Inc. 2012. Actuarial review of the Federal Housing Administration Mutual
Mortgage Insurance Fund HECM loans for fiscal year 2012. Working Paper, For U.S. Department of Housing
and Urban Development.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1359a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1363" publication-type="other">
Jones, A. 2002. The national nursing home survey: 1999 summary. National Center for Health Statistics: Vital
Health Stat 13:1-110.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1373a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1377" publication-type="other">
Koijen, R., S. Van Nieuwerburgh, and M. Yogo. 2014. Health and mortality delta: Assessing the welfare cost of
household insurance choice. Discussion Paper 05/2011-050, Netspar.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1387a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1391" publication-type="other">
Laibson, D., A. Repetto, and J. Tobacman. 2003. A debt puzzle. In Knowledge, information, and expectations
in modern economics: In honor of Edmund S. Phelps, ed. P. Aghion, R. Frydman, J. Stiglitz, and M. Woodford,
Princeton: Princeton University Press. 228-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1404a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1408" publication-type="other">
Lockwood, L. 2013. Bequest motives and the choice to self-insure late-life risks. Working Paper, Northwestern
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1418a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1422" publication-type="other">
Lusardi, A., O. Mitchell, and V. Curto. 2009. Financial literacy and financial sophistication among older
Americans. Working Paper 15469, NBER.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1433a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1437" publication-type="other">
Mayer, C., and K. Simons. 1994. Reverse mortgages and the liquidity of housing wealth. Journal of the American
Real Estate and Urban Economics Association 22:235-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1447a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1451" publication-type="other">
Miceli, T., and C. Sirmans. 1994. Reverse mortgage and borrower maintenance risk. Journal of the American
Real Estate and Urban Economics Association 22:257-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1461a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1465" publication-type="other">
Mitchell, O., and J. Piggott. 2005. Unlocking housing equity in Japan. Journal of the Japanese and International
Economies 18:466-505.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1475a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1479" publication-type="other">
Mitchell, O. J. Poterba, M. Warshawsky, and J. Brown. 1999. New evidence on the money's worth of individual
annuities. The American Economic Review 89:1299-318.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1489a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1493" publication-type="other">
Moulton, S., D. Haurin, and W. Shi. 2014. An analysis of default risk in the Home Equity Conversion Mortgage
(HECM) program. Working Paper, Ohio State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1503a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1507" publication-type="other">
Nakajima, M., and I. Telyukova. 2013. Reverse mortgage loans: A quantitative analysis. Working Paper,
University of California, San Diego.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1518a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1522" publication-type="other">
Nathanson, C., and E. Zwick. 2013. Arrested development: Theory and evidence of supply-side speculation.
Working Paper, Harvard.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1532a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1536" publication-type="other">
Peng, L. 2015. The risk and return of commercial real estate: A property level analysis. Journal of Real Estate
Finance and Economics forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1546a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1550" publication-type="other">
Redfoot, D., K. Scholen, and S. Brown. 2007. Reverse mortgages: Niche product or mainstream solution? Report
on the 2006 AARP National Survey of Reverse Mortgage Shoppers. Report 2007-22, AARP.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1560a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1564" publication-type="other">
Shan, H. 2011. Reversing the trend: The recent expansion of the reverse mortgage market. Real Estate Economics
39:743-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1574a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1578" publication-type="other">
Sheiner, L., and D. Weil. 1992. The housing wealth of the aged. Working Paper 4115, NBER.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1585a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1589" publication-type="other">
Sheshinski, E. 2010. Refundable annuities (annuity options). Journal of Public Economic Theory 12:7-21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1597a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1601" publication-type="other">
Shiller, R. 1993. Macro Markets. Oxford: Clarendon Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1608a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1612" publication-type="other">
Shiller, R., and A. Weiss. 2000. Moral hazard in home equity conversion. Real Estate Economics 28:1-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1619a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1623" publication-type="other">
Sinai, T., and N. Souleles. 2013. Can owning a home hedge the risk of moving? American Economic Journal -
Economic Policy 5:282-312.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1633a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1637" publication-type="other">
. 2005. Owner occupied housing as insurance against rent risk. Quarterly Journal of Economics 120:
763-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1647a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1651" publication-type="other">
Skinner, J. 1996. Is housing wealth a sideshow? In Advances in the economics of aging, ed. D. Wise, Chicago:
NBER and University of Chicago Press. 241-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1661a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1665" publication-type="other">
Stone, J. 2008. Medicaid coverage for long-term care: Eligibility, asset transfers, and estate recovery. Report
RL33593, Congressional Research Service.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1676a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1680" publication-type="other">
Szymanoski, E. 1994. Risk and the Home Equity Conversion Mortgage. Journal of the American Real Estate
and Urban Economics Association 22:347-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1690a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1694" publication-type="other">
Turra, C., and O. Mitchell. 2004. The impact of health status and out-of-pocket medical expenditures on annuity
valuation. Working Paper, Pension Research Council. WP 2004-2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1704a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1708" publication-type="other">
Venti, S., and D. Wise. 2001. Aging and housing equity: Another look. NBER Working Paper 8608.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1715a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1719" publication-type="other">
Webb, D., 2009. Long-term care insurance, annuities and asymmetric information: The case for bundling
contracts. Journal of Risk and Insurance 76:53-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623298e1729a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623298e1733" publication-type="other">
Yaari, M., 1965. Uncertain lifetime, life insurance, and the theory of the consumer. Review of Economic Studies
32:137-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


