<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">98</volume>
         <issue-id>i40187968</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44472262</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A New Investigation Tool for the Dynamics of 4WD and 4WS Cars</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>R.</given-names>
                  <surname>Filderman</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>H.</given-names>
                  <surname>Focqueur</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1989</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>131</fpage>
         <lpage>139</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1990 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44472262"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>VALEO's Road Simulation Test Bench has a number of features which make it a unique tool for the investigation of vehicle dynamic behavior, more particularly in relation with 4WD and 4WS concepts. Both these concepts rely on the road contact properties of tyres for improving vehicle handling characteristics. The Road Simulation Test Rig is a unique means of measuring wheel contact forces on the ground, which is not otherwise possible on the road; it is based on the combination of : - four large diameter rollers, one for each vehicle wheel, which are each fitted with load sensors for the measurement of longitudinal, lateral and vertical forces - a unique restraint mechanism for preventing forward or rearward movements of the vehicle, leaving entire freedom, within limits, for all other movements: lateral and vertical translations, pitch, roll and yaw around the vehicle center of gravity. On this rig, the roller width enables expressway lane change maneuvers to be carried out, and large radius curves at high speed can be simulated. The rig and vehicle can both be easily instrumented to monitor other important parameters, with the added convenience of an indoor facility and easy connection to a mainframe computer. Several actual test results with 4WD and 4WS cars will be presented.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


