<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275560</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>High-Efficiency and Low-NOx Hydrogen Combustion by High Pressure Direct Injection</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tanno</surname>
                  <given-names>Shiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Motor Corporation</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ito</surname>
                  <given-names>Yasushi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Motor Corporation</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Michikawauchi</surname>
                  <given-names>Ryo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Motor Corporation</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nakamura</surname>
                  <given-names>Mikio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Motor Corporation</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tomita</surname>
                  <given-names>Hirokuni</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nippon Soken, Inc</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275542</issue-id>
         <fpage>259</fpage>
         <lpage>268</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275560"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Hydrogen can be produced from various renewable energy sources, therefore it is predicted that hydrogen could play a greater role in meeting society's energy needs in the mid- to long-term. Conventional hydrogen engines have some disadvantages: higher cooling loss results in low thermal efficiency and abnormal combustion (backfire, pre-ignition, higher burning velocity) limits high load operation. Direct injection is an effective solution to overcome these disadvantages, but combustion methods that enable both high efficiency and low NOx have yet to be studied in enough detail.</p>
            <p>In this research, high-efficiency and low-NOx hydrogen combustion was investigated using a prototype high-pressure hydrogen injector (maximum 30 MPa). Experiments were carried out with a 2.2-liter 4-cylinder diesel engine equipped with a centrally mounted hydrogen injector, a toroidal shape combustion chamber, and a spark plug in the glow plug position. Furthermore this engine was modified to allow the supply of hydrogen to a single cylinder. By controlling both injection and spark timing, homogeneous and stratified combustion was studied. In addition, diffusive combustion used in combination with SI (i.e., spark assisted diffusive combustion) was investigated.</p>
            <p>Result shows that stratified and diffusive combustion by high pressure direct injection greatly improves indicated thermal efficiency by approximately 3% compared with conventional homogeneous combustion. This advancement is derived from three reasons. 1) Stratified and diffusive combustion improves trade-off between cooling loss and degree of constant volume. 2) Pressure recovery effect by injection close to TDC has a large advantage on thermal efficiency. 3) EGR is effective when it is combined with stratified and diffusive combustion.</p>
            <p>Furthermore by suppressing jet penetration to reduce more cooling loss, a good indicated thermal efficiency for a small engine of 52% was achieved. Phenomenon was confirmed by CFD and visualization of in-cylinder combustion.</p>
            <p>In addition, some valuable knowledge was derived that dehumidifying EGR increases specific heat ratio of the working gas, and improves thermal efficiency while reducing NOx.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Furuhama, S., “Dictionary of Automotive Engineering: New Energy Automobiles, Chapter 3 Hydrogen Vehicles”, Sankaido, 154-228.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Verhelst, S., De Landtsheere, J., De Smet, F., Billiouw, C. et al., “Effects of Supercharging, EGR and Variable Valve Timing on Power and Emissions of Hydrogen Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):647-656, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-1033.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shioji, M., Komatsu, Y., Ishikura, W., Mohammadi, A., “Strategies for a Higher-Performance Direct-Injection Hydrogen Engine”, Transactions of Society of Automotive Engineers of Japan, Vol. 39, No. 2, 231-236, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rottengruber, H., Wiebicke, U., Woschni, G., Zeilinger, K., “Hydrogen Diesel Engine with Direct Injection, High Power Density and Low Exhaust Gas Emissions Part3: Engine Testing and Calculations”, MTZ, Vol.61, No.2, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wimmer, A., Wallner, T., Ringler, J., and Gerbig, F., “H2- Direct Injection - A Highly Promising Combustion Concept,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0108, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-0108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Welch, A., Mumford, D., Munshi, S., Holbery, J. et al., “Challenges in Developing Hydrogen Direct Injection Technology for Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2379, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-2379.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eichlseder, H., Peter, G., Falk, G., Klaus, H., “Advanced combustion concepts and development methods for hydrogen IC engines”, Proceedings of the FISITA 2008 World Automotive Congress (paper no. F2008-06-103), 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eichlseder, H., Spuller, C., Heindl, R., Gerbig, F., Heller, K., “Concepts for Diesel -Like Hydrogen Combustion”, MTZ, Vol.71, No.1, 60-66, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vogel, C., “Hydrogen Diesel Engine with Direct Injection, High Power Density and Low Exhaust Gas Emissions Part1: Concept”, MTZ, Vol.60, No.10, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akagawa, H., “Development of Hydrogen Injection Clean Engine”, Proceedings of the 15th World Hydrogen Energy Conference, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shudo, T., Cheng, W.K., Kuninaga, T., and Hasegawa, T., “Reduction of Cooling Loss in Hydrogen Combustion by Direct Injection Stratified Charge,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3094, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3094.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Demuynck, J., Raes, N., Zuliani, M., De Paepe, M., Sierens, R., Verhelst, S., “Local Heat Flux measurements in a hydrogen and methane spark ignition engine with a thermopile sensor”, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, Vol.34, No.24, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wallner, T., Ciatti, S., Bihari, B., Stockhausen, W., Boyer, B., “Endoscopic Investigations in a Hydrogen Internal Combustion Engine”, 1st International Symposium on Hydrogen Internal Combustion Engines, Graz, Austria, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">White, C.M., “OH* Chemiluminescence Measurements in a Direct Injection Hydrogen-fuelled Internal Combustion Engine”, International Journal of Engine Research, Vol. 8 No.2, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
