<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26794455</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Offshore Tax Evasion</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Transparency and Tax Evasion</article-title>
            <subtitle>Evidence from the Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act (FATCA)</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>De Simone</surname>
                  <given-names>Lisa</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lester</surname>
                  <given-names>Rebecca</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Markle</surname>
                  <given-names>Kevin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">110</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26794387</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>49</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26794455"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We examine how increased reporting requirements for U.S. individuals with offshore assets affect the location of hidden investment assets. Specifically, we study the Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act (FATCA). FATCA requires foreign financial institutions to provide information to the U.S. government regarding U.S. account holders for the purpose of reducing offshore tax evasion. Using annual country-level data on investments in U.S. securities by foreign account holders from 2006 to 2015, we document a significant decrease in foreign portfolio investment to the U.S. from tax haven countries after signing on to FATCA, consistent with a decrease in “round-tripping” investment activity attributable to U.S. investors’ offshore tax evasion activities. However, we also find weak evidence of an increase in the amount of investment out of tax haven countries that did not agree to exchange information. These results suggest that some U.S. investors with hidden offshore assets moved assets to other countries that provide secrecy, thus enabling these investors to continue to evade U.S. tax liabilities. Our study contributes to both the academic literature on tax evasion as well as the analysis of similar yet controversial regulation being contemplated by numerous countries around the world.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Allingham, Michael G., and Agnar Sandmo. 1972. “Income Tax Evasion: A Theoretical Analysis.” Journal of Public Economics 1 (3–4): 323–38. doi:10.1016/0047-2727(72)90010-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Alm, James, John Deskins, and Michael McKee. 2009. “Do Individuals Comply on Income Not Reported by Their Employer?” Public Finance Review 37 (2): 120–41. doi:10.1177/1091142108322878.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Alstadsaeter, Annette, Niels Johannesen, and Gabriel Zucman. 2017. “Tax Evasion and Inequality.” Working Paper, May. http://www.nielsjohannesen.net/wpcontent/uploads/AJZ2017.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bacchetta, Philippe, and María Paz Espinosa. 1995. “Information Sharing and Tax Competition among Governments.” Journal of International Economics 39 (1): 103–21. doi:10.1016/0022-1996(94)01356-W.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Becker, Gary S. 1974. “A Theory of Social Interactions.” Journal of Political Economy 82 (6): 1063–93. doi:10.1086/260265.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Bertaut, Carol C., and Ralph W. Tryon. 2007. “Monthly Estimates of U.S. Cross-Border Securities Positions.” SSRN Scholarly Paper ID 1066802. Rochester, NY: Social Science Research Network. https://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=1066802.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Blum, Cynthia. 2003. “Sharing Bank Deposit Information with Other Countries: Should Tax Compliance or Privacy Claims Prevail.” Florida Tax Review 6: 579–648.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Caruana-Galizia, Paul, and Matthew Caruana-Galizia. 2016. “Offshore Financial Activity and Tax Policy: Evidence from a Leaked Data Set&lt;a href=‘#fn1’&gt;*&lt;/A&gt;.” Journal of Public Policy 36 (3): 457–88. doi:10.1017/S0143814X16000027.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Christensen, Hans B., Luzi Hail, and Christian Leuz. 2016. “Capital-Market Effects of Securities Regulation: Prior Conditions, Implementation, and Enforcement.” The Review of Financial Studies 29 (11): 2885–2924. doi:10.1093/rfs/hhw055.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Christians, Allison. 2012. “Putting the Reign Back in Sovereign Symposium: Tax Advice for the Second Obama Administration.” Pepperdine Law Review 40: 1373–1414.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Coder, Jeremiah. 2011. “IRS Wants New Foreign Payment Scheme to Be Simple, Official Says.”Tax Notes.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Coder, Jeremiah. 2012. “Treasury Releases FATCA Model II Agreement.” Tax Notes, November 19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">De Simone, Lisa, Kenneth J. Klassen, and Jeri K. Seidman. 2016. “Unprofitable Affiliates and Income Shifting Behavior.” The Accounting Review Forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Deloitte. 2017. “FATCA IGA Global Summary.” Deloitte Development LLC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Desai, Mihir A, and Dhammika Dharmapala. 2010. “Dividend Taxes and International Portfolio Choice.” The Review of Economics and Statistics 93 (1): 266–84. doi:10.1162/REST_a_00073.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Dharmapala, Dhammika. 2016. “Cross-Border Tax Evasion under a Unilateral FATCA Regime.”Journal of Public Economics 141 (September): 29–37. doi:10.1016/j.jpubeco.2016.07.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Drucker, Jesse. 2010. “Google 2.4% Rate Shows How $60 Billion Lost to Tax Loopholes.”Bloomberg. October 21. http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2010-10-21/google-2-4-rateshows- how-60-billion-u-s-revenue-lost-to-tax-loopholes.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Dyreng, Scott D., Michelle Hanlon, Edward L. Maydew, and Jacob R. Thornock. 2017.“Changes in Corporate Effective Tax Rates Over the Past 25 Years.” Journal of Financial Economics. Accessed April 24. doi:10.1016/j.jfineco.2017.04.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Dyreng, Scott D., and Bradley P. Lindsey. 2009. “Using Financial Accounting Data to Examine the Effect of Foreign Operations Located in Tax Havens and Other Countries on U.S.Multinational Firms’ Tax Rates.” Journal of Accounting Research 47 (5): 1283–1316. doi:10.1111/j.1475-679X.2009.00346.x.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Everson, Mark. 2006. “Written Testimony of Commissioner of Internal Revenue Mark Everson Before Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs’ Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations Hearing on Offshore Abuses: The Enablers, the Tools and Offshore Secrecy.” Tax Analysts.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">“Financial Secrecy Index.” 2015. Tax Justice Network. http://www.financialsecrecyindex.com/introduction/fsi-2015-results.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">French, Kenneth R., and James M. Poterba. 1991. “Investor Diversification and International Equity Markets.” Working Paper 3609. National Bureau of Economic Research. doi:10.3386/w3609.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Granwell, Alan. 2009. “Be Careful In Designing International Tax Reform Measures.” Tax Analysts.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Hanlon, Michelle, Edward L. Maydew, and Jacob R. Thornock. 2015. “Taking the Long Way Home: U.S. Tax Evasion and Offshore Investments in U.S. Equity and Debt Markets.”The Journal of Finance 70 (1): 257–87. doi:10.1111/jofi.12120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Harvey, J. Richard (Dick) Jr. 2012. “Offshore Accounts: Insider’s Summary of FATCA and Its Potential Future Norman J. Shachoy Symposium: U.S. Taxation of Offshore Activity and Regulation of Executive Compensation: Taxation of Offshore Accounts.” Villanova Law Review 57: 471–98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Huizinga, Harry, and Gaëtan Nicodème. 2004. “Are International Deposits Tax-Driven.” Journal of Public Economics, OTPR, 88 (6): 1093–1118. doi:10.1016/S0047-2727(03)00058-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Johannesen, Niels. 2014. “Tax Evasion and Swiss Bank Deposits.” Journal of Public Economics 111 (March): 46–62. doi:10.1016/j.jpubeco.2013.12.003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Johannesen, Niels, Patrick Langetieg, Daniel Reck, Max Risch, and Joel Slemrod. 2017. “Taxing Hidden Wealth: The Consequences of U.S. Enforcement Initiatives on Evasive Foreign Accounts.” Working Paper - University of Michigan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Johannesen, Niels, and Gabriel Zucman. 2014. “The End of Bank Secrecy?” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy 6 (1): 65–91. doi:10.1257/pol.6.1.65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Jopson, Barney. 2014. “Biggest Tax Inverters ‘have $21bn Offshore.’” Financial Times, September 7. http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c122f9e6-3566-11e4-a2c2-00144feabdc0.html?ft_site=falcon#axzz4fBk5r9Rw.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Kaplow, Louis. 1990. “Optimal Taxation with Costly Enforcement and Evasion.” Journal of Public Economics 43 (2): 221–36. doi:10.1016/0047-2727(90)90031-C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Kleinbard, Edward D. 2014. “‘Competitiveness’ Has Nothing to Do With It.” Tax Notes 144(1055). http://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=2476453.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Klepper, Steven, and Daniel Nagin. 1989. “The Anatomy of Tax Evasion.” Journal of Law, Economics &amp; Organization 5: 1–24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Kleven, Henrik Jacobsen, Martin B. Knudsen, Claus Thustrup Kreiner, Søren Pedersen, and Emmanuel Saez. 2011. “Unwilling or Unable to Cheat? Evidence From a Tax Audit Experiment in Denmark.” Econometrica 79 (3): 651–92. doi:10.3982/ecta9113.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Laffie, Lesli S. 2003. “Amnesty for Offshore Tax Evasion: April 15 Is the Last Chance to Avoid Certain Penalties.” Journal of Accountancy 195 (4): 86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Langenmayr, Dominika. 2015. “Voluntary Disclosure of Evaded Taxes — Increasing Revenue, or Increasing Incentives to Evade?” Journal of Public Economics. doi:10.1016/j.jpubeco.2015.08.007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">McMahon, Emily. 2012. “Remarks by Acting Assistant Secretary Emily McMahon at the NYState Bar Association Annual Meeting.” January 24. https://www.treasury.gov/presscenter/press-releases/Pages/tg1399.aspx.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Michel, Scott, and H. David Rosenbloom. 2011. “FATCA and Foreign Bank Accounts: Has the U.S. Overreached?” Tax Notes International, May 30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Omartian, Jim. 2016. “Tax Information Exchange and Offshore Entities: Evidence from the Panama Papers.” SSRN Scholarly Paper ID 2836635. Rochester, NY: Social Science Research Network. https://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=2836635.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Omartian, Jim. 2017. “Tax Information Exchange and Offshore Entities: Evidence from the Panama Papers.” SSRN Scholarly Paper ID 2836635. Rochester, NY: Social Science Research Network. https://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=2836635.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Parillo, Kristen. 2010. “IRS, Treasury Aim for Release of FATCA Guidance in Stages, Official Says.” Tax Notes.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Parillo, Kristen. 2012. “Nonfinancial Institutions May Be Unaware of FATCA Obligations, Practitioner Says.” Tax Notes.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Parillo, Kristen. 2013. “Practitioners Describe Top FATCA Operational Challenges Facing Asset Managers.” Tax Notes.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Sandmo, Agnar. 2005. “The Theory of Tax Evasion: A Retrospective View.” National Tax Journal 58 (4): 643–63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Sapirie, Marie. 2010. “Taxpayer Comments Crucial to FATCA Implementation, IRS Officials Say.” Tax Notes, September 15.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Sapirie, Marie. 2014. “Year in Review: Steady Progress in OVDP and FATCA.” Tax Notes.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Sapirie, Marie, Jeremiah Coder, and Kristen Parillo. 2012. “Treasury Releases FATCA Regs, Statement of Info Exchange.” Tax Notes, February 13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Sapirie, Marie, and Stephanie Johnston. 2013. “Solving the Expatriation Enigma.” Tax Notes.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Schreiber, Sally. 2013. “IRS Issues Annual Whistleblower Report to Congress.” Journal of Accountancy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Sheppard, Lee. 2005. “Offshore Investments: Don’t Ask, Don’t Tell.” Tax Notes.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Sheppard, Lee A. 2009. “Tax Schemes Are Proliferating, Official Tells NYU Conference.” Tax Notes.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Slemrod, Joel. 2007. “Cheating Ourselves: The Economics of Tax Evasion.” The Journal of Economic Perspectives 21 (1): 25–48. doi:10.1257/089533007780095529.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Slemrod, Joel, Marsha Blumenthal, and Charles Christian. 2001. “Taxpayer Response to an Increased Probability of Audit: Evidence from a Controlled Experiment in Minnesota.”Journal of Public Economics 79 (3): 455–83. doi:10.1016/S0047-2727(99)00107-3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Tesar, Linda L., and Ingrid M. Werner. 1995. “Home Bias and High Turnover.” Journal of International Money and Finance 14 (4): 467–92. doi:10.1016/0261-5606(95)00023-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Thomas, Charles P., Francis E. Warnock, and Jon Wongswan. 2006. “The Performance of International Equity Portfolios.” Working Paper 12346. National Bureau of Economic Research. doi:10.3386/w12346.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">TIGTA. 2009. “A Combination of Legislative Actions and Increased IRS Capability and Capacity Are Required to Reduce the Multi-Billion Dollar U.S. International Tax Gap.”Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">TIGTA. 2012. “The Tax Gap - Tax Gap Estimates for Tax Years 2008-2010.” https://www.irs.gov/uac/the-tax-gap.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Velarde, Andrew. 2016. “Still No IRS Plans to Terminate OVDP Yet.” Tax Notes.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Wheater, Jennifer. 2012. “FATCA and Funds - Where Are We Now.” Business Law International 13: 143–62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Zucman, Gabriel. 2013a. “The Missing Wealth of Nations: Are Europe and The U.S. Net Debtors or Net Creditors? Data Appendix.” Paris School of Economics. http://gabrielzucman. eu/files/Zucman2013DataAppendix.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Zucman, Gabriel. 2013b. “The Missing Wealth of Nations: Are Europe and the U.S. Net Debtors or Net Creditors?*.” The Quarterly Journal of Economics 128 (3): 1321–64. doi:10.1093/qje/qjt012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix A</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Reconciliation of Sample to Hanlon et al. (2015)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1 -</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Sample Composition and Descriptive Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Correlations of Key Variables</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>U.S. Inbound Foreign Portfolio Investment</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>U.S. Inbound Foreign Portfolio Investment by Haven Country</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>U.S. Inbound Foreign Portfolio Investment: Falsification Tests</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Worldwide Foreign Portfolio Investment</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Level of Hidden Assets</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
