<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24910169</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PROFESSIONAL FEATURES</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Organizing Your Data Closet:</article-title>
            <subtitle>Using Latent Class Analysis with Survey Data</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Moten</surname>
                  <given-names>Cardy</given-names>
                  <suffix>III</suffix>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>MAJ Cardy Moten III is an active duty army logistics officer in the functional area FA 49 Operations Research/Systems Analyst (ORSA). He is currently serving as a combat analyst for the TRADOC Analysis Center—Monterey (TRAC-MTRY). He holds an MS in operations research from the Naval Postgraduate School and a bachelor’s degree in personal finance from Liberty University. His previous assignments included multiple combat rotations to Iraq and Afghanistan supporting the 160th Special Operations Aviation Regiment (Airborne) and the 4th Brigade, 101st Airborne Division (Air Assault).</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Smith</surname>
                  <given-names>Christopher M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>LTC Christopher M. Smith is an active duty army operations research/systems analyst officer and currently the director of the TRADOC Analysis Center—Monterey (TRAC-MTRY). He completed this work as part of his dissertation work at the University of Virginia in the Department of Systems and Information Engineering. He has taught in the Department of Mathematical Sciences at West Point and served overseas in a combat tour as an artilleryman during Operation Iraqi Freedom 1. He has a master’s degree in operations research from the University of Texas, Austin, a master’s degree in engineering management from the Missouri University of Science and Technology, and an undergraduate degree in systems engineering from West Point. His current research focuses on applying systems engineering methodologies to the problems of the intelligence community.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>March 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>49</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e24910156</issue-id>
         <fpage>24</fpage>
         <lpage>29</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24910169"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Army Resiliency Directorate. 2013. The United States Army’s Ready and Resilient Campaign. Retrieved February 12, www.army. mil/e2/c/downloads/285588.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Army Resiliency Directorate. 2015. About CSF2. Retrieved from Comprehensive Soldier and Family Fitness, http://csf2.army. mil/about.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dean, N., and Raftery, A. E. 2010. Latent Class Analysis Variable Selection, Annals of the Institute of Statistical Mathematics, Vol 62, No 1, 11–35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kirkwood, C. W. 1997. Strategic Decision Making. Wadsworth Publishing Company.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Linzer, D. A., and Lewis, J. B. 2011. poLCA: An R Package for Polytomous Variable Latent Class Analysis, Journal of Statistical Software, Vol 42, No 10, 1–29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oberski, D. L. 2015. Mixture Models: Latent Profile and Latent Class Analysis. Modern Statistical Methods for HCI, R. Judy, and M. Kaptein, eds. Springer International Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Picard, F. 2007. An Introduction to Mixture Models. Statisticsfor Systems Biology, Research Report.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R Core Team. 2014. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing [Computer Software Manual]. Vienna, Austria. Retrieved from http://www.R-project.org.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Subtil, A., Rosario de Oliveira, M., and Goncalves, L. 2012. Conditional Dependence Diagnostic in the Latent Class Model: A Simulation Study, Statistics and Probability Letters, Vol 82, 1407–1412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Templin, J., and Henson, R. A. 2010. Diagnostic Measurement: Theory, Methods, and Applications. Guilford Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Uebersax, J. S. 2009. A Practical Guide to Conditional Dependence in Latent Class Models. Retrieved from Latent Structure Analysis, http://john-uebersax.com/stat/condep.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vermunt, J. K., and Magidson, J. 2004. Latent Class Analysis. The Sage Encyclopedia of Social Science Research Methods.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
