<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">jeducfina</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000843</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Journal of Education Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>University of Illinois Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00989495</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19446470</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">41</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i24459283</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24459300</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Do Tax Revolt Provisions Influence Tuition and Fee Levels? Evidence from the States using Recent Panel Data</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Gabriel R.</given-names>
                  <surname>Serna</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>48</fpage>
         <lpage>82</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015 Board of Directors of the Journal of Education Finance, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24459300"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Previous research has shown that Tax Revolt Provisions (TRPs) aimed at limiting state government revenues and/or expenditures, negatively impact public higher education funding. This analysis explores the influence of these same types of policies on average in-state undergraduate tuition and fees at public four-year colleges and universities. Employing a data set spanning 13 years and using an econometric estimator appropriate for finite samples with time-invariant variables related to unit-effects, the findings indicate that TRPs matter, but not equally. Tax and Expenditure Limitations, regardless of provision type, share no discernible relationship with tuition and fees. Conversely, Supermajority requirements are associated with higher levels of tuition and fees by approximately 5.5% to 6.6%. The findings suggest that as policy-makers and researchers seek out the drivers of rising tuition and fees, it would be prudent to take into consideration both the role played by traditionally considered variables and that played by state fiscal policy as well.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d338066e178a1310">
            <label>*</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e185" publication-type="other">
This paper was previously presented at the 2013 National Education Finance Conference, the 2013
annual meeting of the Association for the Study of Higher Education, and the Education Innovation
Institute.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e198a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e205" publication-type="other">
For the purposes of this analysis tuition and fees are measured as the average listed in-state price
at state-supported four-year institutions of higher education that covers the student portion of the ex-
penses of providing a public university undergraduate education as well as mandatory fees, not includ-
ing room and board and other elective fees.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e221a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e228" publication-type="other">
"Price-sensitive students" are those students who tend to be more sensitive to changes in listed
tuition and fee levels because they are from low income families (Gwartney et al. 2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e238a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e245" publication-type="other">
Please note that the Carnegie Foundations definition only includes baccalaureate degree granting
institutions for which at least 10% of the degrees offered are designated as bachelors degrees.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e256a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e263" publication-type="other">
Although these authors find interdependence by modeling the relationship simultaneously, I sug-
gest that instead of being a case of simultaneity this may be better understood as sequential games with
incomplete information and thus their results may suggest sub-optimal Nash Equilibria (see Achen
(2000) for examples of this as applied to national budgets).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e279a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e286" publication-type="other">
This is not to suggest that institutions can increase tuition and fees indefinitely. Instead, the goal
is to highlight the role played by tuition and fees in university revenue structure and how institutions,
even when limited by state policy or policy makers, can often times still raise tuition and fees to make
up budgetary gaps that arise.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e302a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e309" publication-type="other">
To be clear, the TELs under investigation here are those that have been adopted at the state, not
municipal, level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e319a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e326" publication-type="other">
After a basic examination of the data, it does appear that in states with SMRs the citizen ideology
score is slightly but statistically significantly more conservative (r= -.1454, p=.0001) but this finding is
merely descriptive not causal.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e339a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e346" publication-type="other">
In this instance the term "collective choices" does not imply that all voters or legislators choose
these types of provisions. Rather, the term here is related to notions of decision-making and political
behavior in constitutional democracies.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e359a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e366" publication-type="other">
The definition per NCES is "A postsecondary institution that offers programs of at least 4 years
duration or one that offers programs at or above the baccalaureate level" (see http://nces.ed.gov/ipeds/
glossary/?charindex=F )</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e380a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e387" publication-type="other">
Please see Richard Fording's website https://rcfording.wordpress.com/state-ideology-data for a
full explanation of the differences between ADA/COPE and nominate data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e397a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e404" publication-type="other">
Although called regions, the actual nomenclature for these nine areas is "Census Division" as op-
posed to the four "Census Regions." (see http://www2.census.gov/geo/pdfs/maps-data/maps/reference/
us_regdiv.pdf)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e417a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e424" publication-type="other">
The FEVD estimator has recently come under scrutiny from some scholars (see Political Analy-
sis 19(2), 2011). However, after careful consideration of the original article, the articles critical of the
method, and the rebuttal articles, I am confident that the method is both valid and appropriate based on
the goals of the current study. Additionally, while some might not consider this a reasonable solution for
the problem of time-invariant regressors, recent studies suggest that though flawed in some instances,
the estimators usefulness is still evident if the finite sample properties of the estimator can be met, if
important theoretical variables are time-invariant, and the inclusion of fixed-effects is vital (Zhu, 2013)
all of which is the case for the current study.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e453a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e460" publication-type="other">
The null hypothesis for this test is that the FE and RE models are both consistent and efficient.
The rejection of the null means that there are systematic differences between the models and that the FE
model is more reasonable and hence, preferred (see Cameron and Trivedi, 2005,2010 for more details).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e473a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e480" publication-type="other">
In the formal explanation of the FEVD model, the unexplained part of u is denoted as h.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e487a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e494" publication-type="other">
The author did consider employing a Lagged Dependent Variable (LDV). However, the reason for
not employing a LDV is that the inclusion of such a control in the model did not improve its fit dramati-
cally (.950 to .970) so as to support such an inclusion as another control for possible endogeneity or
autocorrelation, especially when the data are heavily trended (Achen, 2000). In other words, it is likely
that in this instance the cure would be worse than the disease.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d338066e514a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d338066e521" publication-type="other">
These parameter coefficients are calculated using Wooldridge (2013, p. 100).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>Works Cited</title>
        <ref id="d338066e537a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e541" publication-type="other">
Abrams, B., and W. Dougan. "The Effects of Constitutional Restraints on Governmental Spend-
ing." Public Choice 49, no. 2 (1986): 101-116.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e551a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e555" publication-type="other">
Achen, C. "Why Lagged Dependent Variables can Suppress the Explanatory Power of Other In-
dependent Variables." Prepared for the Political Science Methodology Section of the American
Political Science Association. Los Angeles, 2000. 1-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e568a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e572" publication-type="other">
Archibald, R., and D. Feldman. "State Higher Education Spending and the Tax Revolt." The Journal
of Higher Education 77, no. 4 (2006): 618-643.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e582a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e586" publication-type="other">
—. "Explaining Increases in Higher Education Costs." The Journal of Higher Education 79, no. 3
(2008): 268-295.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e597a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e601" publication-type="other">
—. Why Does College Cost so Much? New York: Oxford University Press, 2011.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e608a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e612" publication-type="other">
Bails, D„ and M. Tieslau. "The Impact of Fiscal Constitutions on State and Local Expenditures."
Cato Journal 20, no. 2 (2000): 255-277.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e622a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e626" publication-type="other">
Barr, M., and G. McClellan. Budgeting and Financial Management in Higher Education. 3. San
Francisco, California: Jossey-Bass, 2011.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e636a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e640" publication-type="other">
Baum, S., L. Lapovsky, and J. Ma. Tuition Discounting: Institutional Aid Patterns at Public and Pri-
vate Colleges and Universities, 2001-01 to 2008-09. New York: College Board, 2010.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e650a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e654" publication-type="other">
Beck, N. "Of Fixed-Effects and Time-Invariant Variables." Political Analysis 19, no. 2 (2011): 119-
122.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e664a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e668" publication-type="other">
Bergstrom, T., and R. Goodman. "Private Demands for Public Goods." American Economic Review
63, no. 2 (1973): 280-296.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e679a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e683" publication-type="other">
Berry, W., E. Rinquist, R. Fording, and R. Hanson. "Measuring Citizen and Government Ideol-
ogy in the American States, 1960-1993, Revised 1960-2008 Citizen Ideology Series." American
Journal of Political Science 42 (1998): 327.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e696a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e700" publication-type="other">
Besley, T., and A. Case. "Political Institutions and Policy Choices: Evidence from the United States."
Journal of Economic Literature 4 (2003): 7-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e710a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e714" publication-type="other">
Borcherding, T., and R. Deacon. "The Demand for the Services of Non-Federal Government."
American Economic Review 62, no. 4 (1972): 891-901.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e724a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e728" publication-type="other">
Bowen, W., M. Chingos, and M. McPherson. Crossing the Finish Line: Completing College at Amer-
ica's Public Universities. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press, 2009.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e738a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e742" publication-type="other">
Bradbury, J., and J. Johnson. "Do Supermajority Rules Limit or Enhance Majority Tyranny? Evi-
dence from the U.S." Public Choice 127, no. 3/4 (2006): 437-449.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e752a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e756" publication-type="other">
Buchanan, J., and G. Tullock. "The Calculus of Consent: Logical Foundations of Constitutional
Democracy." In The Selected Works of Gordon Tullock: Volume 2, edited by C. Rowley. India-
napolis, IN: Liberty Fund Inc., 1962, 2004.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e770a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e774" publication-type="other">
Callan, P. Coping with Recession: Public Policy, Economic Downturns and Higher Education. San
Jose, CA: The National Center for Public Policy and Higher Education: National Center Report
#02-2, 2002.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e787a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e791" publication-type="other">
—. "Reframing Access and Opportunity: Public Policy Dimensions." In The States and Higher Edu-
cation Policy: Affordability, Access, and Accountability, by D. Heller, 87-105. Baltimore, MD:
The Johns Hopkins University Press, 2011.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e804a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e808" publication-type="other">
Cameron, A.C., and P. Trivedi. Microeconometrics: Methods and Applications. New York, NY:
Cambridge University Press, 2005.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e818a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e822" publication-type="other">
—. Microeconometrics Using Stata. College Station, TX: Stata Press, 2010.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e829a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e833" publication-type="other">
Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching. Classification Descriptions. 2010. http://
classifications.carnegiefoundation.org/descriptions/basic.php (accessed April 15, 2011).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e843a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e847" publication-type="other">
Courant, P., E. Grämlich, and D. Rubinfeld. "Why Voters Support Tax Limitation Amendments:
The Michigan Case." National Tax Journal 33, no. 1 (1980): 1-20.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e858a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e862" publication-type="other">
Cruce, T., and N. Hillman. "Preparing for the Silver Tsunami: The Demand for Higher Education
Among Older Adults." Research in Higher Education 53 (2012): 593-613.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e872a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e876" publication-type="other">
Dar, L. "The Political Dynamics of Higher Education Policy." The Journal of Higher Education 83,
no. 6 (2012): 769-794.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e886a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e890" publication-type="other">
Delaney, J. "The Role of State Policy in Promoting College Affordability." The Annals of the Ameri-
can Academy of Political and Social Sciences 655 (2014): 56-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e900a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e904" publication-type="other">
Delaney, J., and W. Doyle. "State spending on higher education: Testing the balance wheel over
tim e!' Journal of Education Finance 36, no. 4 (2011): 343-368.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e914a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e918" publication-type="other">
Doyle, W. "The Politics of Public College Tuition and State Financial Aid." The Journal of Higher
Education 83, no. 5 (2012): 617-647.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e928a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e932" publication-type="other">
Goldstein, Larry. A Guide to College and University Budgeting: Foundations for Institutional Ef-
fectiveness. 4th. Washington, D.C.: National Association of College and University Budget Of-
ficers, 2012.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e946a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e950" publication-type="other">
Griswold, C., and G. Marine. "Political Influences on State Policy: Higher Tuition, Higher-Aid,
and the Real World." The Review of Higher Education 19, no. 4 (1996): 361-389.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e960a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e964" publication-type="other">
Grizzle, C. "For Better or for Worse: Reassessing the Impact of Tax and Expenditure Limitations
on State Expenditure." Journal of Public Budgeting, Accounting and Financial Management 23,
no. 1 (2011): 26-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e977a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e981" publication-type="other">
Gwartney, J., R. Stroup, R. Sobel, and D. MacPherson. Economics: Private and Public Choice. 12.
Mason, OH: Southwestern: Cenage Learning, 2009.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e991a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e995" publication-type="other">
Hauptman, A. "Reforming the Ways in Which States Finance Higher Education." In The States and
Public Higher Education Policy, edited by Donald Heller. Baltimore, MD: The Johns Hopkins
University Press, 2011.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1008a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1012" publication-type="other">
Hearn, J„ C. Griswold, and G. Marine. "Region, Resources, and Reason: A Contextual Analysis
of State Tuition and Student Aid Policies." Research in Higher Education 37 (1996): 241-278.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1022a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1026" publication-type="other">
Hearn, J., and J. Holdsworth. "Federal Student Aid: The Shift from Grants to Loans." In Public
Funding of Higher Education: Changing Contexts and New Rationales, edited by Edward St. John
and Michael Parsons. Baltimore, MD: The Johns Hopkins University Press, 2004.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1040a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1044" publication-type="other">
Heinemann, F., S. Osterloh, and A. Kalb. "Sovereign risk premia: The link between fiscal rules and
stability culture." Journal of International Money and Finance 41 (2014): 110-127.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1054a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1058" publication-type="other">
Heller, D. "The Effects of Tuition and State Financial Aid on Public College Enrollment." The Re-
view of Higher Education 23, no. 1 (1999): 65-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1068a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1072" publication-type="other">
—. "State Support of Higher Education: Past, Present, and Future." In Privatization and Public Uni-
versities, edited by D. Priest and E. St. John. Bloomington, IN: Indiana University Press, 2006.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1082a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1086" publication-type="other">
—. "Introduction: Affordability, Access and Accountability in Twenty-first Century Public Higher
Education." In The States and Public Higher Education Policy: Affordability, Access, and Account-
ability, edited by Donald Heller. Baltimore, MD: The Johns Hopkins University Press, 2011a.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1099a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1103" publication-type="other">
—. "Trends in the Affordability of Public Colleges and Universities: The Contradiction of Increas-
ing Prices and Increasing Enrollment." In The States and Public Higher Education Policy: Afford-
ability, Access, and Accountability, edited by Donald Heller. Baltimore, MD: The Johns Hopkins
University Press, 201 lb.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1119a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1123" publication-type="other">
Hossler, D„ J. Lund, J. Ramin, S. Westfall, and S. Irish. "State Funding for Higher Education: The
Sisyphean Task." The Journal of Higher Education 68 (1997): 160-190.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1134a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1138" publication-type="other">
Hovey, H.A. State Spending for Higher Education in the Next Decade: The Battle to Sustain Current
Support. San Jose, CA: The National Center for Public Policy and Higher Education; NCR-
99-3,1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1151a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1155" publication-type="other">
Johnstone, D.B., and P.N. Marcucci. Financing Higher Education Worldwide: Who Pays? Who
Should Pay? Baltimore, MD: The Johns Hopkins University Press, 2010.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1165a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1169" publication-type="other">
Jordan, M., and K. Hoffman. "The Revenue Impacts of State Legislative Supermajority Voting
Requirements." Midsouth Political Science Review 10 (2009): 1-16.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1179a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1183" publication-type="other">
Joyce, P., and D. Mullins. "The Changing Fiscal Structure of the State and Local Public Sector: The
Impact of Tax and Expenditure Limitations." Public Administration Review 51, no. 3 (1991):
240-253.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1196a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1200" publication-type="other">
Kane, T., P. Orszag, and D. Gunter. State Fiscal Constraints and Higher Education Spending: The
Role of Medicaid and the Business Cylce. Washington D.C.: The Urban-Brookings Tax Policy
Center; Discussion Paper No.ll, 2003.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1213a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1217" publication-type="other">
Kim, M., and J. Ko. "The Impact of State Control Policies on College Tuition Increase." Educational
Policy, Online First (2014): 1-24. DOI: 10.1177/0895904813518100</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1228a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1232" publication-type="other">
King-Meadows, T, and D. Lowery. "The Impact of the Tax Revolt Era State Fiscal Caps: A Research
Update." Public Budgeting and Finance 16, no. 1 (1996): 102-112.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1242a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1246" publication-type="other">
Knight, B. "Supermajority Voting Requirements for Tax Increases: Evidence from the States." Jour-
nal of Public Economics 76 (2000): 41-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1256a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1260" publication-type="other">
Knott, J., and A. A. Payne. "The Impact of State Governance Structures on Management and Per-
formance of Public Organizations: A Study of Higher Education Institutions." Journal of Policy
Analysis and Management 23, no. 1 (2004): 13-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1273a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1277" publication-type="other">
Koshal, R„ and M. Koshal. "State Appropriation and Higher Education Tuition: What is the Rela-
tionship?" Education Economics 8, no. 1 (2000): 81-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1287a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1291" publication-type="other">
Kousser, T., J. McCubbins, and E. Moule. "For Whom the TEL Tolls: Can State Tax and Expen-
diture Limits Effectively Reduce Spending?" State Politics and Policy Quarterly 8, no. 4 (2008):
331-361.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1304a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1308" publication-type="other">
Kousser, T., M. McCubbins, and K. Rozga. "When Does the Ballot Box Limit the Budget?" In Fiscal
Challenges: An Interdisciplinary Approach to Budget Policy, edited by E. Garrett, E. Graddy and
H. Jackson. New York, NY: Cambridge University Press, 2009.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1322a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1326" publication-type="other">
Ladd, H., and J. Boatright-Wilson. "Why Voters Support Tax Limitations: Evidence from Massa-
chusetts' Proposition 2 1/2." National Tax Journal 35, no. 2 (1982): 121-148.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1336a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1340" publication-type="other">
Lenth, C. The Tuition Dilemma: State Policies and Practicies in Pricing Public Higher Education.
Denver, CO: State Higher Education Executive Officers Association, 1993.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1350a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1354" publication-type="other">
Lowry, R. "Governmental Structure, Trustee Selection, and Public University Prices and Spending:
Multiple Means to Similar Ends." Journal of Political Science 45, no. 4 (2001a): 845-861.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1364a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1368" publication-type="other">
—. "The Effects of State Political Interests and Campus Outputs on Public University Revenues."
Economics of Education Review 20 (2001b): 105—119.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1378a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1382" publication-type="other">
—. "The Political Economy of Public Universities in the United States: A Review Essay." State Poli-
tics and Policy Quarterly 7, no. 3 (2007): 303-324.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1392a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1396" publication-type="other">
Martin, R., and A. Gillen. "Measuring College Affordability." Social Science Research Network.
January 2011a. http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1734914 (accessed April
5,2011a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1410a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1414" publication-type="other">
—. How College Pricing Undermines Financial Aid. Washington, D.C. : Center for College Afford-
ability, 2011b.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1424a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1428" publication-type="other">
McLendon, M.K., J.C. Hearn, and R. Deaton. "Called to Account: Analyzing the Origins and
Spread of State Performance-Accountability Policies for Higher Education." Educational Evalu-
ation and Policy Analysis 28, no. 1 (2006): 1-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1441a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1445" publication-type="other">
McLendon, M., J. Hearn, and C. Mokher. "Partisans, Professionals, and Power: The Role of Po-
litical Factors in State Higher Education Funding." The Journal of Higher Education 80, no. 6
(2009): 686-713.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1458a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1462" publication-type="other">
McLendon, M.K., D.E. Heller, and S.P. Young. "State Postsecondary Policy Innovation: Politics,
Competition, and the Interstate Migration of Policy Ideas." The Journal of Higher Education 76,
no. 4 (2005): 363-400.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1475a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1479" publication-type="other">
McPherson, M., and M. Schapiro. The Student Aid Game: Meeting Need and Rewarding Talent in
American Higher Education. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press, 1998.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1489a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1493" publication-type="other">
Moody, M. "Do State Debt Policies and Oversight Impact How Much Public Universities Bor-
row?" Municipal Finance Journal 28, no. 3 (2007): 1-17.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1504a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1508" publication-type="other">
—. "State Debt Policies and the Credit Ratings of Public Universities." Public Finance Review 36,
no. 3 (2008): 287-307.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1518a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1522" publication-type="other">
Mullins, D„ and P. Joyce. "Tax and Expenditure Limitations and State and Local Fiscal Structure:
An Empirical Assessment." Public Budgeting and Finance 16, no. 1 (1996): 75-101.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1532a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1536" publication-type="other">
Mullins, D., and B. Wallin. "Tax and Expenditure Limitations: Introduction and Overview." Public
Budgeting and Finance 24, no. 4 (2004): 2-15.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1546a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1550" publication-type="other">
Musso, J. A., E. Graddy, and J. Grizard. "Budgetary Arrangements in the 50 States." In Fiscal Chal-
lenges: An Interdisciplinary Approach to Budget Policy, edited by E. Garrett, E. Graddy and H.
Jackson. New York, NY: Cambridge University Press, 2009.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1563a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1567" publication-type="other">
Neill, C. "Tuition Fees and the Demand for University Places." Economics of Education Review 28
(2009): 561-570.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1577a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1581" publication-type="other">
New, M. "US State Tax and Expenditure Limitations: A Comparative Political Analysis." State Poli-
tics and Policy Quarterly 10, no. 1 (2010): 25-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1592a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1596" publication-type="other">
Paulsen, M. "College tuition: Demand and supply determinants from 1960 to 1986." The Review of
Higher Education 14, no. 3 (1991): 339-358.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1606a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1610" publication-type="other">
Perna, L. "Toward a more complete understanding of the role of financial aid in promoting college
enrollment: The importance of context." Higher Education: Handbook of Theory and Research
25 (2010): 129-179.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1623a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1627" publication-type="other">
Pluemper, T., and V. Troeger. "Efficient Estimation of Time-Invariant and Rarely Changing Vari-
ables in Finite Sample Panel Analyses with Unit Fixed-Effects." Political Analysis 15 (2007):
124-139.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1640a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1644" publication-type="other">
—. "Fixed-Effects Vector Decomposition: Properties, Reliability, and Instruments." Political Anal-
ysis 19 (2011): 147-164.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1654a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1658" publication-type="other">
Poterba, J. "State Responses to Fiscal Crises: The Effects of Budgetary Institutions and Politics." The
Journal of Political Economy 102, no. 4 (1994): 799-821.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1668a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1672" publication-type="other">
Poterba, J„ and K. Rueben. State Fiscal Institutions and the U.S. Municipal Bond Market; NBER
Working Paper No. 6237. Cambridge, MA.: National Bureau of Economic Research, 1997.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1683a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1687" publication-type="other">
—. Fiscal Rules and State Borrowing Costs: Evidence from California and Other States. San Fran-
cisco: Public Policy Institute of California, 1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1697a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1701" publication-type="other">
—. "Fiscal News, State Budget Rules, and Tax-Exempt Bond Yields." Journal of Urban Economics
50 (2001): 537-562.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1711a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1715" publication-type="other">
Rizzo, M. "State preferences for higher education spending: A panel data analysis, 1977-2001." In
What's Happening to Public Higher Education?, by R. Ehrenberg. Westport, CT: Praeger, 2006.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1725a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1729" publication-type="other">
Rizzo, M, and R. Ehrenberg. "Resident and Nonresident Tuition and Enrollment at Flagship State
Universities." In College Choices: The Economics of Where to Go, When to Go, and How to Pay
For It, edited by Caroline Hoxby, 303-354. Chicago, IL: University of Chicago Press, 2004.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1742a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1746" publication-type="other">
Rose, S. "Institutions and Fiscal Sustainability." National Tax Journal 63, no. 4 (2010): 807-838.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1753a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1757" publication-type="other">
Rusk, J., and L. Leslie. "The Setting of Tuition in Public Higher Education." The Journal of Higher
Education 49, no. 6 (1978): 531-547.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1768a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1772" publication-type="other">
Serna, G. "Understanding the Effects of State Oversight and Fiscal Policy on University Revenues:
Considerations for Financial Planning." Planning for Higher Education 41, no. 2 (2013): 93-108.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1782a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1786" publication-type="other">
Serna, G., and G. Harris. "Higher Education Expenditures and State Balanced Budget Require-
ments: Is There a Relationship?" Journal of Education Finance 39, no. 3 (2014): 175-202.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1796a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1800" publication-type="other">
Shadbegian, R. "Do Tax and Expenditure Limitations Affect the Size and Growth of State Govern-
ment?" Contemporary Economic Policy 14, no. 1 (1996): 22-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1810a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1814" publication-type="other">
Shin, J., and S. Milton. "Rethinking Tuition Effects on Enrollment in Public Four-Year Colleges
and Universities." The Review of Higher Education 29, no. 2 (2006): 213-237.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1824a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1828" publication-type="other">
Skidmore, M. "Tax and Expenditure Limitations and the Fiscal Relationships between State and
Local Governments." Public Choice 99, no. 1-2 (1999): 77-102.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1838a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1842" publication-type="other">
Tandberg, D. "Politics, interest groups, and state funding of public higher education." Research in
Higher Education 15, no. 5 (2010): 416-450.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1853a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1857" publication-type="other">
—. "The conditioning role of state higher education governance structures." The Tournai of Higher
Education 84, no. 4 (2013): 506-543.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1867a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1871" publication-type="other">
Thelin, J. "Higher Education and the Public Trough." In Public Funding of Higher Education:
Changing Contexts and New Rationales, edited by Edward St. John and Michael Parsons. Balti-
more, MC: The Johns Hopkins University Press, 2004.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1884a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1888" publication-type="other">
Torna, E. "Boards of Trustees, Agency Problems, and University Output." Public Choice 67, no. 1
(1990): 1-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1898a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1902" publication-type="other">
Toutkoushian, R. "Weathering the storm: Generating Revenues for Higher Education During a
Recession." In Maximizing Revenue for Higher Education, edited by F.K. Alexander and R. Eh-
renberg, 27-40. San Franciso, CA: Jossey-Bass, 2003.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1915a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1919" publication-type="other">
Toutkoushian, R., and P. Hollis. "Using Panel Data to Examine Legislative Demand for Higher
Education." Education Economics 6, no. 2 (1998): 141-157.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1929a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1933" publication-type="other">
Waisanen, B. State Tax and Expenditure Limitations—2008. 2011. http://www.ncsl.org/IssuesRe-
search/BudgetTax/StateTaxandExpenditureLimits2008/tabid/12633/Default.aspx (accessed
January 27, 2011).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1947a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1951" publication-type="other">
Weerts, D., and J. Ronca. "Examining Differences in State Support for Higher Education: A Com-
parative Study of State Appropriations for Research I Universities." The Journal of Higher Educa-
tion 77, no. 6 (2006): 935-967.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1964a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1968" publication-type="other">
—. Determinants of State Appropriations for Higher Education from 1985-2005: An Organizational
Theory Analysis. Madison, WI: Working Paper Series WP013: Wisconsin Center for the Ad-
vancement of Postsecondary Education, 2008.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1981a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e1985" publication-type="other">
Winston, G. Toward a Theory of Tuition: Prices, Peer Wages, and Competition in Higher Education
. Discussion Paper No. 65 Williamstown, MA: Williams Project on the Economics of Higher
Education, 2003.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e1998a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e2002" publication-type="other">
Wooldridge, J. Econometric Analysis of Cross Section and Panel Data. 2nd. Cambridge, MA: The
MIT Press, 2010.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e2012a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e2016" publication-type="other">
—. Introductory Econometrics: A Modern Approach. 5th. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage
Learning, 2013.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e2026a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e2030" publication-type="other">
Zhu, L. "Panel Data Analysis in Public Administration: Substantive and Statistical Considerations."
Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory 23, no. 2 (2013): 395-428.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d338066e2041a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d338066e2045" publication-type="other">
Zumeta, William. "State Higher Education Financing: Demand Imperatives Meet Structural, Cy-
clical, and Political Constraints." In Public Funding of Higher Education: Changing Contexts and
New Rationales, edited by Edward St. John and Michael Parsons. Baltimore, Maryland: The
John Hopkins University Press, 2004.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


