<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">104</volume>
         <issue-id>i40192731</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44612254</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Vibrating Rotation Sensors</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>B.</given-names>
                  <surname>Johnson</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1995</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>925</fpage>
         <lpage>931</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1996 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44612254"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>British Aerospace Systems and Equipment (BASE) has developed new solid state rotation sensors the Vibrating Structure Gyroscope (VSG) and the 2010. The VSG has been extensively tested in automotive trials in Europe and the Far East, the results of have been published. The VSG has proved to be and robust. The VSG senses rate using a piezo-electric ceramic which is excited into a cos (20) vibration pattern. The of vibration pattern lags behind the shell when the is rotated. This enables rotation to be sensed. The electronics excites the shell into resonance, stabilise the pattern direction with respect to the shell, and a DC signal proportional to rotation rate. VSG 2010 was developed as a continuation of the Vibrating Structure Gyroscope family of products. The aim to design a product that would improve the performance over temperature whilst retaining the inherent levels of reliability and robustness. VSG 2010 extends range of solid state sensors which BASE produces. Both the VSG 2010 gyroscope and the VSG sense through the use of resonating circular structures. The improvement in performance of the VSG 2010 arise the replacement of the ceramic cup with a meialic structure. The VSG 2010 has been designed from the to be suitable for high volume production. The paper will outline the basic principles of rotation using resonating structures and their design. It will consider the applications for which this new product is and will also present data which illustrates the of the instrument.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d218e224a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d218e228" publication-type="other">
G H Bryan, "On the beat in the vibration of a revolving
cylinder on bell", proceedings of the Cambridge
Philosophical Society 1880; 7, pp 101-111.
British Aerospace US Patent No:-0461761</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


