<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000451</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40008411</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Verb Semantics for English-Chinese Translation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Martha</given-names>
                  <surname>Palmer</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Zhibiao</given-names>
                  <surname>Wu</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1995</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>59</fpage>
         <lpage>92</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1995 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40008411"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>A common practice in operational Machine Translation (MT) and Natural Language Processing (NLP) systems is to assume that a verb has a fixed number of senses and rely on a pre-compiled lexicon to achieve large coverage. This paper demonstrates that this assumption is too weak to cope with the similar problems of lexical divergences between languages and unexpected uses of words that give rise to cases outside of the pre-compiled lexicon coverage. We first examine the lexical divergences between English verbs and Chinese verbs. We then focus on a specific lexical selection problem-translating English "change-of-state" verbs into Chinese verb compounds. We show that an accurate translation depends not only on information about the participants, but also on contextual information. Therefore, selectional restrictions on verb arguments lack the necessary power for accurate lexical selection. Second, we examine verb representation theories and practices in MT systems and show that under the fixed sense assumption, the existing representation schemes are not adequate for handling these lexical divergences and extending existing verb senses to unexpected usages. We then propose a method of verb representation based on conceptual lattices which allows the similarities among different verbs in different languages to be quantitatively measured. A prototype system UNICON implements this theory and performs more accurate MT lexical selection for our chosen set of verbs. An additional lexical module for UNICON is also provided that handles sense extension.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>verb semantics</kwd>
            <kwd>lexical divergences</kwd>
            <kwd>lexical organization</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d908438e220a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e224" publication-type="other">
Church, K. 1991. Some Statistical Opportunities in Speech and Language. In Pro-
ceedings of 23rd Symposium on the Interface, Computing Science and Statistics,
Seattle, Washington, April.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e237a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e241" publication-type="other">
Dong, Z.D. 1987. Language, Translation, Machine Translation. In Proceedings of
International Forum on Today's Translation, Hong Kong.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e251a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e255" publication-type="other">
Dong, Z.D. 1994. A Categorization System of Chinese Movement Concepts. In
Proceedings of International Conference on Chinese Computing, Singapore.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e265a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e269" publication-type="other">
Dorr, B.J. 1993. Machine Translation: A View from the Lexicon. MIT Press,
Cambridge, Masssachusetts.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e280a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e284" publication-type="other">
Egedi, D. 1991. Learning Through Metaphor. In D. Nerin-Aime, editor, Knowledge
Modeling and Expertise Transfer. ISO Press, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e294a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e298" publication-type="other">
Feng, Z. and X. Zhou, editors. 1989. New Chinese Multi-Purpose Dictionary.
International Culture Publisher.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e308a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e312" publication-type="other">
Grishman, R. and J. Sterling. 1989. Preference Semantics for Message Understand-
ing. In Proceedings of the DARPA Speech and Natural Language Workshop, Cape
Cod, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e325a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e329" publication-type="other">
Henne, H. 1977. A handbook on Chinese Language Structure. Columbia University
Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e339a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e343" publication-type="other">
Hobbs, J. 1986. Overview of the TACITUS Project. Computational Linguistics,
12(3).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e353a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e357" publication-type="other">
Jackendoff, R. 1990. Semantic Structures. MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e365a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e369" publication-type="other">
Kurohashi, S. and M. Nagao. 1992. Dynamic Programming Method for Analyzing
Conjunctive Structures in Japanese. In Proceedings of the 14th International
Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING-92), Nantes, France.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e382a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e386" publication-type="other">
Langacker, R.W. 1988. An Overview of Cognitive Grammar. In B. Rudzka-Ostyn,
editor, Topics in Cognitive Grammar. John Benjamins Publishing Company, Am-
sterdam/Philadelphia.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e399a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e403" publication-type="other">
Levin, B. 1987. Approaches to Lexical Semantic representation. In B. Levin,
editor, Readings for Lexical Semantics. Northwestern University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e413a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e417" publication-type="other">
Levin, B. 1993. English Verb Classes and Alternations: A Preliminary Investiga-
tion. University of Chicago Press, Chicago.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e427a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e431" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, S., J. Carbonell, M. Tomita, and K. Goodman. 1992. Machine Trans-
lation: A Knowledge-Based Approach. Morgan Kaufmann Publishers.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e441a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e445" publication-type="other">
Onyshkevich, B. and S. Nirenburg. 1995. A Lexicon for Knowledge-Based MT.
Machine Translation, 10(1-2).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e456a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e460" publication-type="other">
P. Resnik. 1993. Selection and Information: A Class-Based Approach to Lexical
Relationships. Ph.D. thesis, Department of Information and Computer Science,
University of Pennsylvania.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e473a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e477" publication-type="other">
Palmer, M. 1990. Customizing Verb Definitions for Specific Semantic Domains.
Machine Translation, 5(30).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e487a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e491" publication-type="other">
Palmer, M. and A. Polguère. 1995. A Preliminary Lexical and Conceptual Anal-
ysis of BREAK: a Computational Perspective. In P. Saint-Dizier and E. Viegas,
editors, Computational Lexical Semantics. Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e504a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e508" publication-type="other">
Procter, P. 1978. Longman Dictionary of Contemporary English. Longman, Lon-
don.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e518a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e522" publication-type="other">
Pustejovsky, J. 1991. The generative lexicon. Computational Linguistics, 17(4).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e529a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e533" publication-type="other">
Wilks, Y. 1986. An intelligent analyzer and understander of English. In B.J.
Grosz, K. Sparck-Jones, and B.L. Webber, editors, Readings in Natural Language
Processing. Morgan Kaufmann.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e547a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e551" publication-type="other">
Wu, D. 1991. On Serial verb Construction. Ph.D. thesis, Department of Informa-
tion and Computer Science, University of Maryland.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e561a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e565" publication-type="other">
Wu, Z. 1994. Verb Semantics and Lexical Selection. Ph.D. thesis, Department of
Information System and Computer Science, National University of Singapore.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e575a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e579" publication-type="other">
Wu, Z. and M. Palmer. 1994. Verb Semantics and Lexical Selection. In Proceedings
of ACL94, New Mexico State University, USA, May.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e589a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e593" publication-type="other">
Y.R.Chao. 1968. A Grammar of Spoken Chinese. University of California Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e600a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e604" publication-type="other">
Yuan, C., C. Huang, Y. Peng, and Z. Guo. 1994. Construction and Application of
the Chinese Morpheme Database. In Proceedings of International Conference on
Chinese Computing, Singapore.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908438e617a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908438e621" publication-type="other">
Zernik, U. 1987. The Self-Extending Phrasal Lexicon. Computational Linguistics,
13(3-4).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
