<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">natitaxjour</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50005631</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>National Tax Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00280283</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19447477</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26349699</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>UNMASKING LOCAL FISCAL RESPONSES TO FEDERAL TAX DEDUCTIBILITY</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
                  <surname>Coyne</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">70</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i26349696</issue-id>
         <fpage>223</fpage>
         <lpage>255</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2017 National Tax Association-Tax Institute of America</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26349699"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper analyzes how changes to the deductibility of state and local taxes under the federal personal income tax affect local fiscal outcomes. This paper is the first to study the impact of changing tax prices on local fiscal outcomes while allowing for local heterogeneity in tax incentives at the county level. Exploiting variation at the county level yields a more elastic relationship between tax price and local spending than using coarser units of observation. Simulations suggest that limiting the deduction for state and local taxes would not disproportionately hurt resource-poor areas, making such limits potentially progressive policy options.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1101e217a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e224" publication-type="other">
Earlier papers (e.g., Hettich and Winer, 1984; Noto and Zimmerman, 1984; Inman, 1985) claim that a
subnational government's choice of revenue sources does not depend on the jurisdiction's tax price.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e234a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e241" publication-type="other">
Epple and Zelenitz (1981) discuss the implications of competition among jurisdictions in a Tiebout model.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e248a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e255" publication-type="other">
I do not claim that the county level is the optimal level to perform the analysis, but it may be the best
possible option given current data limitations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e265a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e272" publication-type="other">
The overall rate of itemization widely varies over my sample, starting at more than 40 percent, falling to
less than 30 percent following the Tax Reform Act of 1986, and fluctuating between 31 and 35 percent
since 2003.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e286a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e293" publication-type="other">
I find a first-stage F-statistic on fdtp' of well over 16, suggesting that the instrument is indeed relevant.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e300a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e307" publication-type="other">
There is a possibility that the response to the deductibility of sales taxes post-2003 is attenuated due to the
fact that the deductibility status was passed as a temporary provision that needed to be renewed every two
years. However, this potential attenuation would only affect a handful of states (those who do not have an
income tax) in two years (2004 and 2005) of my sample.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e323a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e330" publication-type="other">
The state-level analysis includes only federal aid, while the local analysis includes both state aid and federal
aid.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e340a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e347" publication-type="other">
The U.S. Census Bureau (2006) explains that any discrepancy between revenue and expenditure cannot
be construed as a surplus or deficit due to these data intentionally excluding some accounting measures,
such as future pension fund liability or revenue streams. The data provided by the Census program is not
intended to be viewed as standard accounting reports.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e363a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e370" publication-type="other">
Decisions about revenues and expenditures happen at the beginning of the fiscal year, which actually oc-
curs in the previous calendar year. As such the fiscal data is matched to the economic and demographic
information of the prioryear, yielding a period of analysis from 1979-2005.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e383a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e390" publication-type="other">
Although the fiscal data end in 2005,1 use the 2008-2012 five-year ACS to allow for a similar 10-year
interpolation of populations for 2001-2005 as I use for non-Census years in earlier decades.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e401a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e408" publication-type="other">
Previous papers in other contexts have done such an assignment using only population data, but incorporat-
ing income data improves the matching process,</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e418a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e425" publication-type="other">
The procedure to create the data is described in more detail in the Online Appendix, which is available on
the author's website.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e435a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e442" publication-type="other">
Categorical variables, such as marriage, homeownership, and number of dependents are held constant,
while age groups are allowed to change linearly over time. The unemployment rate for each county is
available from 1990-2005, and earlier years are estimated based on the actual state unemployment rate
and the degree to which the county rate changes with the state rate in later years.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e458a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e465" publication-type="other">
See Feenberg and Coutts (1993) for an overview of the TAXSIM program.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e472a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e479" publication-type="other">
The data available from IPUMS does not provide enough information to allow for the estimation of other
types of deductions, including medical expenses and charitable contributions. These variables were im-
puted using the average for each state-AGI decile available from the 1RS public use flies for the years of
analysis.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e495a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e502" publication-type="other">
It is possible that the decision to locate in a particular area is driven by the local fiscal environment, so
there could be some reverse causality regarding families with children and the elderly sorting to areas with
certain revenue mixes and expenditure patterns.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e516a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e523" publication-type="other">
Counties from Alaska and Hawaii are omitted from analysis due to both states' unique fiscal characteristics
and natures as states and to be consistent with past analyses.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e533a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e540" publication-type="other">
There are six other independent city-counties in Virginia that actually appear in city-level data, and hence
are not dropped.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e550a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e557" publication-type="other">
Due to data limitations, this group may also include some taxes that are not deductible collected by county
governments. However, this amount should be small relative to property, general sales, and income taxes
collected at the county level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e570a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e577" publication-type="other">
While this elasticity may seem high, it is important to note that this is measured at the average tax price,
which does not necessarily correspond to any individual S tax incentive. It also refers to the elasticity of
deductible taxes used to finance local public spending, not the local public goods and services themselves.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e590a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e597" publication-type="other">
In some specifications, a rise in tax price is correlated with a fall in non-deductible revenues for states with
no income tax, which may reflect the relatively fewer fiscal instruments available to those states.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e607a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e614" publication-type="other">
The largest federal matching grant program is Medicaid, which is run through state governments and thus
should not directly impact the local results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e625a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e632" publication-type="other">
When aggregating state and local combined revenues to the state level, I find that a larger share of high
AGI earners leads to more use of deductible taxes, similar to past findings.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e642a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e649" publication-type="other">
If, however, I aggregate local revenues to the state level, then I find a significant and negative coefficient
on share of population 65 and older, qualitatively similar to Heim and Abbas (2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e659a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e666" publication-type="other">
Full results of these robustness tests can be found in the Online Appendix on the author's website.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e673a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e680" publication-type="other">
The coefficient estimates are mostly insignificant, but this is largely due to the choice to cluster standard
errors by state. If classical standard errors are used, such as those reported in Metcalf (2011), then the
coefficient estimates for tax price presented in Panel Ε of Table 4 become significant in Columns 1, 3,4,
and 6.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e696a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e703" publication-type="other">
California has a somewhat unique situation in terms of property tax rates in that local governments have
no control over those rates since Proposition 13 was passed in 1978.1 run the same regressions as above
omitting all California counties. The results move in the direction we would expect, with coefficients on
tax price increasing in magnitude.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1101e719a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1101e726" publication-type="other">
Because revenue centralization is measured as a ratio of state revenue to state and local combined revenue,
this also makes the interpretation of the estimated coefficients much clearer, as it removes the dependent
variable (a state's current state and local revenue collections) from the right-hand side of the equation.
The test yields a large first-stage F-statistic, signaling a highly-relevant instrument.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d1101e751a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e755" publication-type="other">
Burman, Leonard Ε., Christopher Geissler, and Eric J. Toder, 2008. "How Big Are Total Indi-
vidual Income Tax Expenditures, and Who Benefits from Them?" American Economic Review
98 (2), 79-83.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e768a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e772" publication-type="other">
Case, Anne C., Harvey S. Rosen, and James R. Hines, 1993. "Budget Spillovers and Fiscal Policy
Interdependence." Journal of Public Economics 52 (3), 285-307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e782a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e786" publication-type="other">
Congressional Budget Office, 2008. The Deductibility of State and Local Taxes. Congressional
Budget Office, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e796a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e800" publication-type="other">
Congressional Research Service, 2012. Tax Expenditures: Compendium of Background Material
on Individual Provisions. U.S. Government Printing Office, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e811a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e815" publication-type="other">
Courant, Paul N., and Edward M. Gramlich, 1990. "The Impact of the Tax Reform Act of 1986
on State and Local Fiscal Behavior." In Slemrod, Joel (ed.), Do Taxes Matter? The Economic
Effect of Tax Reform, 243-275. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e828a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e832" publication-type="other">
DiPasquale, Denise, and Edward L. Glaeser, 1999. "Incentives and Social Capital: Are Home-
owners Better Citizens?" Journal of Urban Economics 45 (2), 354-384.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e842a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e846" publication-type="other">
Epple, Dennis, and Allan Zelenitz, 1981. "The Implications of Competition among Jurisdictions:
Does Tiebout Need Politics?" Journal of Political Economy 89 (6), 1197-1217.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e856a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e860" publication-type="other">
Feenberg, Daniel, and Elisabeth Coutts, 1993. "An Introduction to the TAXSIM Model." Journal
of Policy Analysis and Management 12 (1), 189-194.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e870a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e874" publication-type="other">
Feldstein, Martin, and Amy Taylor, 1976. "The Income Tax and Charitable Contributions."
Econometrica 44 (6), 1201-1222.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e884a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e888" publication-type="other">
Feldstein, Martin S., and Gilbert E. Metcalf, 1987. "The Effect of Federal Tax Deductibility on
State and Local Taxes and Spending." Journal of Political Economy 95 (4), 710-736.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e899a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e903" publication-type="other">
Glaeser, Edward L., and Jesse M. Shapiro, 2003. "The Benefits of the Home Mortgage Interest
Deduction." Tax Policy and the Economy 17,37-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e913a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e917" publication-type="other">
Heim, Bradley, and Yulianti Abbas, 2015. "Does Federal Deductibility Affect State and Local
Revenue Sources?" National Tax Journal 68 (1), 33-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e927a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e931" publication-type="other">
Henchman, Joseph, and Jason Sapia, 2011. "Local Income Taxes: City- and County-level In-
come and Wage Taxes Continue to Wane." Tax Foundation Fiscal Fact, No. 280, https://files.
taxfoundation.org/legacy/docs/ff280.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e944a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e948" publication-type="other">
Hettich, Walter, and Stanley Winer, 1984. "A Positive Model ofTax Structure." Journal of Public
Economics 24, 67-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e958a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e962" publication-type="other">
Holtz-Eakin, Douglas, and Harvey Rosen, 1988. "Tax Deductibility and Municipal Budget Struc-
ture." In Rosen, Harvey S. (ed.), Fiscal Federalism: Quantitative Studies, 107-136. University
of Chicago Press, Chicago, IL.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e975a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e979" publication-type="other">
Holtz-Eakin, Douglas, and Harvey Rosen, 1990. "Federal Deductibility and Local Property Tax
Rates." Journal of Urban Economics 27 (3), 269-284.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e990a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e994" publication-type="other">
Inman, Robert P, 1985. "Does Deductibility Influence Local Taxation?" NBER Working Paper
No. 1714. National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e1004a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e1008" publication-type="other">
Isen, Adam, 2014. "Do Local Government Fiscal Spillovers Exist? Evidence from Counties,
Municipalities, and School Districts." Journal of Public Economics 110, 57-73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e1018a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e1022" publication-type="other">
Ladd, Helen F., 1984. "Federal Aid to State and Local Governments." In Mills, Gregory B., and
John L. Palmer (eds. ), Federal Budget Policy in the 1980s. The Urban Institute, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e1032a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e1036" publication-type="other">
Leuven, Edwin, and Hessel Oosterbeek, 2004. "Evaluating the Effect of Tax Deductions on
Training." Journal of Labor Economics 22 (2), 461-488.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e1046a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e1050" publication-type="other">
Metcalf, Gilbert E., 2011. "Assessing the Federal Deduction for State and Local Tax Payments."
National Tax Journal 64 (2, part 2), 565-590.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e1060a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e1064" publication-type="other">
Noto, Nonna, and Dennis Zimmerman, 1984. "Limiting State-Local Tax Deductibility: Effects
Among the States." National Tax Journal 37 (4), 539-550.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e1075a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e1079" publication-type="other">
Poterba, James, and Todd Sinai, 2008. "Tax Expenditures for Owner-Occupied Housing: Deduc-
tions for Property Taxes and Mortgage Interest and the Exclusion of Imputed Rental Income."
American Economic Review: Papers and Proceedings 98 (2), 84-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e1092a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e1096" publication-type="other">
Poterba, James M., 2011. "Introduction: Economic Analysis of Tax Expenditures.''/Vahona/ Tax
Journal 64 (2, part 2), 451-457.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e1106a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e1110" publication-type="other">
Rueben, Kim, 2005. "The Impact of Repealing State and Local Tax Deductibility." State Tax
Notes (August 15).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e1120a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e1124" publication-type="other">
Ruggles, Steven, J. Trent Alexander, Katie Genadek, Ronald Goeken, Matthew B. Schroeder, and
Matthew Sobek, 2010. Integrated Public Use Microdata Series: Version 5.0 [machine-readable
database], Minnesota Population Center, Minneapolis, MN.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e1137a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e1141" publication-type="other">
Saez, Emmanuel, 2004. "The Optimal Treatment of Tax Expenditures. " Journal of Public Eco-
nomics 88 (12), 2657-2684.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e1151a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e1155" publication-type="other">
The Tax Foundation, 2012. Property Taxes on Owner-Occupied Housing. The Tax Foundation,
Washington, DC, http://taxfoundation.org/sites/taxfoundation.org/files/docs/proptaxlO_income_0.
pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1101e1169a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1101e1173" publication-type="other">
U.S. Census Bureau, 2006. Government Finance and Employment Classification Manual. U.S.
Census Bureau, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
