<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26272329</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Influence of Residual Gas NO Content on Knock Onset of Iso-Octane, PRF, TRF and ULG Mixtures in SI Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Roberts</surname>
                  <given-names>P.J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sheppard</surname>
                  <given-names>C.G.W.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Leeds</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>December 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26272316</issue-id>
         <fpage>2028</fpage>
         <lpage>2043</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26272329"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Reported in the current paper is a study of the effects of Nitric Oxide (NO) within a simulated Exhaust Gas Residual (sEGR) on Spark Ignition (SI) engine end gas autoignition.</p>
            <p>A modified version of the single cylinder Leeds University Ported Optical Engine Version 2 (LUPOE-2) engine was designed to completely eliminate retained residual gas and so allow unambiguous definition of the composition of the incylinder charge.</p>
            <p>The engine was alternately operated on stoichiometric mixtures of iso-octane, two Primary Reference Fuels (PRF), a Toluene Reference Fuel (TRF), and a commercially available Unleaded Gasoline (ULG) and air. These mixtures were diluted with sEGR (products of the complete stoichiometric combustion of the given fuel/air mixture) in mass fractions ranging from 0-15%; with and without 5000ppm NO (0.52% by mass) within that sEGR.</p>
            <p>For those fuels exhibiting little or no Negative Temperature Coefficient (NTC) behaviour, NO addition to the sEGR resulted in increased rate of reaction in the end gas and advanced autoignition and thus knock onset.</p>
            <p>Conversely, autoignition (and thus knock onset) was suppressed with the addition of NO for fuels exhibiting strong NTC characteristics if the cycle unburned pressure/temperature history spent a significant period of time to autoignition in the NTC regime.</p>
            <p>Ideas relating to the effects of residual gas NO concentration on autoignition, and thus knock onset are subsequently discussed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konig, G. and Sheppard, C., “End Gas Autoignition and Knock in a Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 902135, 1990, doi: 10.4271/902135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burluka, A., Liu, K., Sheppard, C., Smallbone, A. et al., “The Influence of Simulated Residual and NO Concentrations on Knock Onset for PRFs and Gasolines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2998, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-2998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smallbone, A. “Fuel and residual effects on knock onset in spark ignition engines,” Ph.D Thesis, University of Leeds, England, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prabhu, S., Li, H., Miller, D., and Cernansky, N., “The Effect of Nitric Oxide on Autoignition of a Primary Reference Fuel Blend in a Motored Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 932757, 1993, doi:10.4271/932757.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J., Leppard, W., Najt, P., and Dryer, F., “The Interaction Between Nitric Oxide and Hydrocarbon Oxidation Chemistry in a Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 972889, 1997, doi:10.4271/972889.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stenlåås, O., Gogan, A., Egnell, R., Sundén, B. et al., “The Influence of Nitric Oxide on the Occurrence of Autoignition in the End Gas of Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2699, 2002, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-2699.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Risberg, P., Johansson, D., Andrae, J., Kalghatgi, G. et al., “The Influence of NO on the Combustion Phasing in an HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0416, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0416.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roberts, P, “Fuel and residual effects in spark ignition and homogeneous charge compression ignition engines,” Ph.D Thesis, University of Leeds, England, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hattrell, T, “A computational and experimental study of spark ignition engine combustion,” Ph.D Thesis, University of Leeds, England, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw- Hill, New York, United States of America, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Griffiths, J.F., and Barnard, J.A., Flame and Combustion, Blackie Academic and Professional, London, England, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fieweger, K., Blumenthal, R., and Adomeit, G., “Self-ignition of S.I. engine model fuels: A shock tube investigation at high pressure,” Combustion &amp; Flame, Volume 109, Pages 599-619, 1997, DOI:10.1016/S0010-2180(97)00049-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Halstead, M.P., Kirsch, L.J., and Quinn, C.P., “The autoignition of hydrocarbon fuels at high temperatures and pressures - Fitting of a mathematical model,” Combustion &amp; Flame, Volume 30, Pages 45-60, 1977, DOI:10.1016/0010-2180(77)90050-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schreiber, M., Sadat Sakak, A., and Lingens, A., “A reduced thermokinetic model for the autoignition of fuels with variable octane ratings,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, Volume 25, Pages 933-940, 1994, DOI:10.1016/S0082-0784(06)80729-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davidson, D.F., Gauthier, B.M., and Hanson, R.K., “Shock tube ignition measurements of iso-octane/air and toluene/air at high pressures,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, Volume 30, Pages 1175-1182, 2005, DOI:10.1016/j.proci.2004.08.004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">His-Ping, S.S., Vanderover, J and Oehlschlaeger, M.A., “A shock tube study of iso-octane ignition at elevated pressures: The influence of diluent gases,” Combustion &amp; Flame, Volume 155, Pages 739-755, 2008, DOI:10.1016/10.1016/j.combustflame.2008.06.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ciezki, H.K., and Adomeit, G., “Shock-tube investigation of selfignition of n-heptane-air mixtures under engine relevant conditions,” Combustion &amp; Flame, Volume 93, Pages 421-433, 1993, DOI: 10.1016/0010-2180(93)90142-P.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Minetti, R., Carlier, M., Ribaucour, M., Therssen, E., and Sochet, L.R., “A rapid compression machine investigation of oxidation and autoignition of n-heptane: Measurements and modelling,” Combustion &amp; Flame, Volume 102, Pages 298-309, 1995, DOI: 10.1016/0010-2180(94)00236-L.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bromly, J.H., Barnes, F.J., Mandyczewsky, R., Edwards, T.J., and Haynes, B.S., “An experimental investigation of the mutually sensitised oxidation of nitric oxide and n-butane,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, Volume 24, Pages 899-907, 1992, DOI:10.1016/S0082-0784(06)80107-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Westbrook, C., Pitz, W., and Leppard, W., “The Autoignition Chemistry of Paraffinic Fuels and Pro-Knock and Anti-Knock Additives: A Detailed Chemical Kinetic Study,” SAE Technical Paper 912314, 1991, doi:10.4271/912314.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Callahan, C.V., Held, T.J., Dryer, F.L., Minetti, R., Ribaucour, M., Sochet, L.R., Faravelli, T. Gaffuri, P., and Ranzi, E., “Experimental data and kinetic modelling of primary reference fuel mixtures,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, Volume 26, Pages 739-746, 1996, DOI: 10.1016/S0082-0784(96)80282-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herzler, J., Fikri, M., Hitzbleck, Starke, R., Schulz, C., Roth, P., and Kalghatgi, G.T., “Shock-tube study of the autoignition of n-heptane/toluene/air mixtures at intermediate temperatures and high pressures,” Combustion &amp; Flame, Volume 149, Pages 25-31, 2007, DOI:10.1016/j.combustflame.2006.12.015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Håkansson, A., Strömberg, K., Pedersen, J., and Olsson, J.O., “Combustion of gasolines in premixed laminar flames European certified and California phase 2 reformulated gasoline,” Chemosphere, Volume 44, Pages 1243-1252, 2001, DOI:10.1016/S0045-6535(00)00481-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Silke, E., Pitz, W., Westbrook, C., Sjöberg, M. et al., “Understanding the Chemical Effects of Increased Boost Pressure under HCCI Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):12-25, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-0019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lemaire, O., Ribaucour, M., Carlier, M., and Minetti, R., “The production of benzene in the low-temperature oxidation of cyclohexane, cyclohexene and cyclo-1,3-diene,”. Combustion &amp; Flame, Volume 127, Pages 1971-1980, 2001, DOI:10.1016/S0010-2180(01)00301-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mandilas, C, “Laminar and turbulent burning characteristics of hydrocarbon fuels”. Ph.D Thesis, University of Leeds, England, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
