<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">quarbankrevi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016167</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Quarterly Banking Review / רבעון לבנקאות</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>אגוד הבנקים בישראל</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">05571480</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">ג'</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">11</issue>
         <issue-id>i24010132</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24011969</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Trading in Bills from the Banking Viewpoint / הסחר בשטרות מהבחינה הבנקאית</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>א.</given-names>
                  <surname>שמעוני</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>E.</given-names>
                  <surname>Shimoni</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>1963</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>42</fpage>
         <lpage>47</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24011969"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This article deals largely with an analysis of the relationship between parties to transactions involving bill-brokerage. In Mr. Shimoni's view the legal validity of some of these transactions is faulty, and in many cases contrary to banking ethics. Sometimes clients have been led to believe that they hold time deposits rather than that they have acquired bills. Mr. Shimoni maintains that the 'investor' in bills must be furnished with full particulars of the deal. He mentions two main types of bill-brokerage business. First, that in which the bank is purely a go-between, the second, that in which the bank sells clients' bills from its own bill-portfolio. In the first case, the moment the bank becomes a party to the transaction and not merely an intermediary, the transaction constitutes in his view the acceptance of a deposit and the making of an advance. He points out that in law, part of a bill is not negotiable. Banks cannot therefore sell parts of bills. Furthermore, he maintains that as the general public cannot be expected, when purchasing bills, to assess their value, it is desirable that deals should to be made in negotiable instruments only, which should also carry the bank's guarantee. When there is a lack of identity between the sum loaned and the bill bought, or between the date on which the bill is due to be paid and the date on which the investible funds are repayable, or when there is no clear link between the buyer and seller, the deal would not be considered as a bill-brokerage transaction. Likewise, the sale of bills from the bank's portfolio without furnishing details of the bills sold is in fact a transaction equivalent to receiveing a deposit and granting an advance. (which is therefore subject to the "liquidity" regulations). A bill purchased from a bank's portfolio is of course already secured by the bank's endorsement. It is suggested that in the case where a transaction does not carry the bank's guarantee, this fact should be made explicitly clear in the relevant documents. Banks should issue guarantees only to an extent compatible with their paid up capital, and it should bear some reasonable relationship to the volume of their business. There have already been cases of bankruptcies in which firms were able to continue with their business despite their losses, owing to finance obtained by them via the bill market. Up till now the banks have borne the losses, but a position may be reached, when the unfortunate investor may have to suffer the loss, in the event of bills acquired by him do not carry a bank's guarantee.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>heb</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>[הערות שוליים]</title>
        <ref id="d22e119a1310">
            <label>*</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e126" publication-type="other">
) מר א. שמעוני הוא המפקח על ד.בנקים בבנק ישראל.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


