<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422536</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effects of Injection Timing on Fluid Flow Characteristics of Partially Premixed Combustion Based on High-Speed Particle Image Velocimetry</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Najafabadi</surname>
                  <given-names>Mohammad Izadi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Eindhoven University Of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Tanov</surname>
                  <given-names>Slavey</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lund University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Wang</surname>
                  <given-names>Hua</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Dantec Dynamics A/S</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Somers</surname>
                  <given-names>Bart</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Eindhoven University Of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Johansson</surname>
                  <given-names>Bengt</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>King Abdullah University of Science and Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Dam</surname>
                  <given-names>Nico</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Eindhoven University Of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>October 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422530</issue-id>
         <fpage>1443</fpage>
         <lpage>1453</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422536"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Partially Premixed Combustion (PPC) is a promising combustion concept ,based on judicious tuning of the charge stratification, to meet the increasing demands of emission legislation and to improve fuel efficiency. Longer ignition delays of PPC in comparison with conventional diesel combustion provide better fuel/air mixture which decreases soot and NOₓ emissions. Moreover, a proper injection timing and strategy for PPC can improve the combustion stability as a result of a higher level of fuel stratification in comparison with the Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) concept. Injection timing is the major parameter with which to affect the level of fuel and combustion stratification and to control the combustion phasing and the heat release behavior. The scope of the present study is to investigate the fluid flow characteristics of PPC at different injection timings. To this end, high-speed Particle Image Velocimetry (PIV) is implemented in a light-duty optical engine to measure fluid flow characteristics, including the flow fields, mean velocity and cycle-resolved turbulence, inside the piston bowl as well as the squish region with a temporal resolution of 1 crank angle degree at 800 rpm. Two injectors, having 5 and 7 holes, were compared to see their effects on fluid flow and heat release behavior for different injection timings. Reactive and non-reactive measurements were performed to distinguish injection-driven and combustion-driven turbulence. Formation of vortices and higher turbulence levels enhance the air/fuel interaction, changing the level of fuel stratification and combustion duration. Results demonstrate clearly how turbulence level correlates with heat release behavior, and provide a quantitative dataset for validation of numerical simulations.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Johansson, B., and Cannella, W., "Gasoline partially premixed combustion, the future of internal combustion engines?, " Int. J. Engine Res. 12(3):194-208, 2011, doi:10.1177/1468087411402441.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hardy, W. and Reitz, R., "An Experimental Investigation of Partially Premixed Combustion Strategies Using Multiple Injections in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0917, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0917.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noehre, C., Andersson, M., Johansson, B., and Hultqvist, A., "Characterization of Partially Premixed Combustion," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3412, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Izadi Najafabadi, M., Somers, B., and Nuraini, A., "Validation of a Reduced Chemical Mechanism Coupled to CFD Model in a 2-Stroke HCCI Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-0392, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0392.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neely, G., Sasaki, S., and Leet, J., "Experimental Investigation of PCCIDI Combustion on Emissions in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0121, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Risberg, P., and Ångström, H., "Advantages of Fuels with High Resistance to Auto-ignition in Late-injection, Low-temperature, Compression Ignition Combustion," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3385, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3385.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yin, L., Ingesson, G., Shamun, S., Tunestal, P. et al., "Sensitivity Analysis of Partially Premixed Combustion (PPC) for Control Purposes," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-0884, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0884.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., "Operating a Heavy-Duty Direct-Injection Compression-Ignition Engine with Gasoline for Low Emissions," SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1442, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1442.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Z., Tanov, S., Wang, H., Richter, M. et al., "High-Speed Particle Image Velocimetry Measurement of Partially Premixed Combustion (PPC) in a Light Duty Engine for Different Injection Strategies," SAE Technical Paper 2015-24-2454, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-24-2454.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johansson, B., "Influence of the Velocity Near the Spark Plug on Early Flame Development," SAE Technical Paper 930481, 1993, doi:10.4271/930481.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P., Megerle, M., Sick, V., Richards, K. et al., "The Evolution of Flow Structures and Turbulence in a Fired HSDI Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3501, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3501.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P., Megerle, M., Hammer, J., Nagel, Z. et al., "Late-Cycle Turbulence Generation in Swirl-Supported, Direct-Injection Diesel Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0891, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0891.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P.C., Collin, R., Hildingsson, L., Hultqvist, A., Andersson, Ö., “Combined measurements of flow structure, partially oxidized fuel, and soot in a high-speed, direct-injection diesel engine,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 31(2):2963-2970, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2006.07.231</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P.C., Hildingsson, L., Hultqvist, A., “The influence of fuel injection and heat release on bulk flow structures in a direct-injection, swirl-supported diesel engine”, Exp. Fluids 43(2-3): 273, 2007, doi:10.1007/s00348-007-0281-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zegers, R.P.C., Luijten, C.C.M., Dam, N. J., De Goey, L.P.H., "Pre- and post-injection flow characterization in a heavy-duty diesel engine using high-speed PIV, " Exp. Fluids 53(3):731-746, 2012, doi:10.1007/s00348-012-1323-3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.dantecdynamics.com/particle-image-velocimetry</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanov, S., Wang, Z., Wang, H., Richter, M. et al., "Effects of Injection Strategies on Fluid Flow and Turbulence in Partially Premixed Combustion (PPC) in a Light Duty Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2015-24-2455, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-24-2455.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Izadi Najafabadi, M., Dam, N., Somers, B., and Johansson, B., "Ignition Sensitivity Study of Partially Premixed Combustion by Using Shadowgraphy and OH* Chemiluminescence Methods," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0761, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0761.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, H.; Tanov, S.; Izadi Najafabadi, M.; Wang, Z.; Johansson, B., "Time-resolved in-cylinder PIV measurement in a light duty optical engine under PPC conditions," Lisbon 2016 International Symposium on the Application of Laser and Imaging Techniques to Fluid Mechanics, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanov, S., Johansson, B., Izadi Najafabadi, M., Wang, H., "Analyzing Of In-Cylinder Flow Structures And Cyclic Variations Of Partially Premix Combustion In A Light Duty Engine," FISITA 2016 World Automotive Congress, F2016-ESYF-005, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G. and Fieger, J., “Determination of Local Heat Transfer Coefficients at the Piston of a High Speed Diesel Engine by Evaluation of Measured Temperature Distribution,” SAE Technical Paper 790834, 1979, doi:10.4271/790834.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gatowski, J., Balles, E., Chun, K., Nelson, F. et al., "Heat Release Analysis of Engine Pressure Data," SAE Technical Paper 841359, 1984, doi:10.4271/841359.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles P C, “Turbulent flow structure in direct-injection, swirl-supported diesel engines” in Flow and combustion in reciprocating engines, ed. Arcoumanis C. and Kamimoto T., Springer Berlin, Heidelberg Germany (2009).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tabaczynski Rodney J., "Turbulence and turbulent combustion in sparkignition engines," Prog. Energy Combust. Sci. 2(3): 143-165, 2003, doi:10.1016/0360-1285(76)90010-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
