<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">52</volume>
         <issue-id>i40187875</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44468117</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>MOBILIZED RESEARCH: Progress Report of Coordinating Research Council Shows Rapid Wartime Growth</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>C. B.</given-names>
                  <surname>VEAL</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1944</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>162</fpage>
         <lpage>168</lpage>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44468117"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>BORN during the aftermath of World War 1, the nation's outstanding cooperative petroleum research organization has again enlisted in the service of the Army, Navy, and Government civilian agencies. Although both the type and the urgency of war time problems are unlike those of peace, the mechanism of the Coordinating Research Council, supported equally by the Society of Automotive Engineers and the American Petroleum Institute, has been geared to the task of solving the new problems with unprecedented speed. More than 150 technical working groups, scores of the world's finest petroleum laboratories, and the research facilities of the Government have been coordinated on problems requested of the CRC by the Armed Services. Intensive coordinated research in fuels and lubricants is demanded by the strenuous use of combat airplanes, military vehicles, and war vessels, wartime shipment and storage of fuels and lubricants and, shortages of certain critical petroleum products. Because of the urgency of the problems, high-speed technical education has been required to acquaint novices with the intricacies of testing procedures and laboratory techniques. This invigorated program, besides performing tasks of immediate necessity, is calculated to strengthen the organization so that it will be able to continue to serve the automotive and petroleum industries and the American public in the post-war era.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


