<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437546</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Alcohol Taxes, Tax Revenues and the Single European Market</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>IAN</given-names>
                  <surname>CRAWFORD</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>ZOË</given-names>
                  <surname>SMITH</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>SARAH</given-names>
                  <surname>TANNER</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>1999</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">20</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437500</issue-id>
         <fpage>287</fpage>
         <lpage>304</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 1999</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437546"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper addresses the issue of whether tax revenue from alcohol lost through cross-border shopping could be recouped by cutting excise duties. This in turn depends on the elasticity of demand for alcohol. We use data from the Family Expenditure Survey 1978–96 to estimate own- and cross-price elasticities of demand for beer, wine and spirits before and after completion of the Single Market. We find no evidence of a significant change in elasticities after the Single Market. The tax rates on beer and wine are currently below their revenue-maximising rates, implying that a cut in the duty rate on beer or wine would lead to a decrease in indirect tax revenue from alcohol. We cannot reject that the current tax rate on spirits is at the revenue-maximising rate, implying that further increases in the duty on spirits are likely to cause indirect tax revenue to fall.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d43e232a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e239" publication-type="other">
Differences in pre-tax prices would also create an incentive for cross-border shopping.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e246a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e253" publication-type="other">
HM Customs and Excise, 1998a. These estimates assume that 70-80 per cent of cross-border shopping is a
substitute for domestically purchased alcohol.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e263a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e270" publication-type="other">
HM Customs and Excise, 1998b.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e277a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e284" publication-type="other">
The FES is an annual, random, cross-sectional survey of around 7,000 households per year.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e292a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e299" publication-type="other">
Foreign purchases are not recorded in the FES. Note that we cannot take account of the fact that some
domestically purchased alcohol may have been initially purchased in France and then illegally resold. For this
reason, our analysis is concerned only with the impact of legitimate cross-border shopping.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e312a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e319" publication-type="other">
There is evidence that total spending on alcohol is under-reported in the Family Expenditure Survey. However,
the fact that the level of under-reporting is consistent over time allows us to make reasonable inferences about
changes in behaviour over time from changes in the data (see Tanner ( 1998)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e332a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e339" publication-type="other">
At the 5 per cent significance level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e346a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e353" publication-type="other">
Calculated using standard prices in HM Customs and Excise (1998b).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e360a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e367" publication-type="other">
Ramsey (1927) showed that to raise revenue with the minimum welfare loss, in the absence of lump-sum
taxes, goods with the lowest compensated elasticities should be taxed the most as a proportion of price
(assuming no cross-price effects). In this case, beer should be taxed the most heavily of the three types of
alcohol, not the least, since demand for beer is less elastic than demand for wine or spirits, as our later
empirical results show.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e386a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e393" publication-type="other">
Gorman, 1976.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e401a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e408" publication-type="other">
The level of total expenditure is treated as endogenous and we estimate the model by instrumental variables
using total household income and total household income squared as instruments. The standard errors reported
with the results reflect this.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e421a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e428" publication-type="other">
Expenditure on beer, wine and spirits in the UK as a proportion of non-durable expenditure. Note that we are
unable to address the issue of quality change in response to price changes with these data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e438a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e445" publication-type="other">
Symmetry is slightly more complicated than usual in this model because of the way in which the dummy
variable indicating whether or not each household was observed during the period of the Single Market
multiplies the prices. This means that, for a household observed before the Single Market, the price terms are
y (because dm = U). But for a household observed after the completion of the Single Market, the price
terms are y + o (because dm = 1 ). The symmetry restriction requires that the price terms for both types of
household are symmetric: for pre-Single-Market households, this means y = y; for households observed
during the Single Market, it means that y + o -y +o.for which o = o is sufficient if y =y.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e471a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e478" publication-type="other">
The parameter a is fixed to be In min{x) (which is 0.288 in our sample) and the estimation is an iterative
process which is treated as converged once the maximum absolute change in the parameter vectors becomes
less than half of one per cent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e491a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e498" publication-type="other">
The elasticities and their standard errors are calculated at mean budget shares.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e505a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e512" publication-type="other">
Note that we are not looking at whether the elasticities for households with given characteristics have
changed after the Single Market. We are merely testing whether the elasticity has changed taking into account
that households may have different characteristics before and after the Single Market since it is this that matters
for revenue.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e529a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e536" publication-type="other">
To calculate dR / 3r at 1999 tax rates, we update prices and total non-durable spending to March 1999 using
RPi sub-indices and recalculate elasticities. Figures from the National Accounts are used for average spending
on beer, wine, spirits and total non-durables.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d43e558a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e562" publication-type="other">
Banks, J., Blundell, R. and Lewbel, A. (1997), 'Quadratic Engel curves and consumer demand'
Review of Economics and Statistics, vol. 79, pp. 527-39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e572a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e576" publication-type="other">
Crawford, I. and Tanner, S. (1995), 'Bringing it all back home: alcohol taxation and cross-border
shopping', Fiscal Studies, vol. 16, no. 2, pp. 94-1 14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e586a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e590" publication-type="other">
Gorman, W. M. (1976), 'Tricks with utility functions', in M. Artis and R. Nobay (eds), Essays in
Econometric Analysis, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e600a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e604" publication-type="other">
HM Customs and Excise (1998a), Report of the Alcohol and Tobacco Fraud Review, London:
HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e615a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e619" publication-type="other">
— (1998b), Annual Report, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e626a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e630" publication-type="other">
Ramsey, F. P. (1927), 'A contribution to the theory of indirect taxation'. Economic Journal, vol.
37, pp. 47-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e640a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e644" publication-type="other">
Tanner, S. (1998), 'How much do consumers spend? Comparing the FES and National Accounts',
in J. Banks and P. Johnson (eds), How Reliable is the Family Expenditure Survey? Trends in
Incomes and Expenditures over Time, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
