<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308485</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Dynamic Performance of a Metal V-belt CVT during Rapid Shift-ratio Conditions for Control Applications</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bhate</surname>
                  <given-names>Rohan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Srivastava</surname>
                  <given-names>Nilabh</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Motorsports and Automotive Research Centre, University of North Carolina at Charlotte</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>1499</fpage>
         <lpage>1507</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308485"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper presents a detailed continuous one-dimensional transient-dynamic model of a metal V-belt continuously variable transmission (CVT) for control applications. The simulation model developed captures the power transmission characteristics and inertial dynamics of a metal pushing V-belt CVT. The torque transmitting mechanism of a metal V-belt CVT under the conditions of high load torque, constant driven pulley axial force and a constant driver pulley input torque was studied. The results discuss the performance of a metal V-belt CVT system model under transient and steady state operating conditions. The model proposed in this work expounds a relationship between the transmission ratio change and pulley actuation force, which will serve as a powerful tool for the development of fast and reliable CVT controllers to meet the objectives of reduced losses, higher torque capacity, higher vehicle fuel economy and better acceleration performance.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Asayama, H. et al., Mechanism of metal pushing belt, JSAE Review 16(1995) 137-143</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kobayashi, D. et al., A study of the torque capacity of metal pushing V-belt for CVTs, SAE Paper 980822, SAE Transmission and Driveline Systems Symposium, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Srivastava, N. et al., On the operating regime of metal pushing V-belt CVT under steady state microslip conditions, 2004 SAE International Continuously Variable and Hybrid Transmission Congress, Paper No. 2004-34-2851 (04-CVT-11), San Francisco, September 23-25, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carbone, G. et al., Theoretical Model of Metal V-Belt Drives During Ratio Changing Speed, ASME J. Mech. Des., 2000, 123(1), pp. 111-117.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carbone, G. et al., The influence of Pulley Deformations on the Shifting Mechanism of Metal Belt CVT, ASME J. Mech. Des., 2005, 127, pp. 103- 113.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fujii, T. et al., A Study of a Metal Pushing V-Belt Type CVT-Part 2: Compression Force Between Metal Blocks and Ring Tension, SAE Transactions (1993), Paper No. 930667</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kitagawa, T. et al., A Study on a metal pushing VBelt Type CVT (Part 4: Forces act on Metal Blocks when the Speed Ratio is changing), SAE Transactions (1995), Paper No. 950671</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Srivastava, N. et al., Transient dynamics of a metal V-belt CVT: effects of pulley flexibility and friction characteristic, ASME Journal of Computational and Nonlinear Dynamics 2 (1) (2007) 86-97</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Srivastava, N. et al., Transient dynamics of a metal V-belt CVT: effects of band pack slip and friction characteristic, Mechanism and Machine Theory 43 (4) (2008) 459-479</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Micklem, J.D. et al., Modeling of the steel pushing Vbelt continuously variable transmission, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part C: Journal of Mechanical Engineering Science 208 (1) (1994) 13-27</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wicke, V. et al., The characterization of drivability of CVT powertrains during acceleration transients, VDI Berichte, Vol. 1709, 2002, pp. 311-325</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bhate, R. et al., Transient Dynamic Model of a metal V-belt CVT for ratio shift control applications, IMECE2008-66440</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pfiffner, R. et al., Fuel-optimal control of CVT powertrains, Control Engineering Practice 11 (2003) 329–336</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Srivastava, N. et al., Using Genetic Algorithms to Identify Initial Operating Conditions for a Transient CVT Model, 2004 ASME IMECE2004-61999, November 13-19, Anaheim, CA</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
