<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">jeducfina</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000843</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Journal of Education Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>University of Illinois Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00989495</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19446470</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">36</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i23018100</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23018117</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Differences Across States in Higher Education Finance Policy</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>John J.</given-names>
                  <surname>Cheslock</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Rodney P.</given-names>
                  <surname>Hughes</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2011</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>369</fpage>
         <lpage>393</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2010 Board of Trustees of the University of Illinois Manufactured in the United States of America</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23018117"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>In the United States, public higher education finance policy is primarily decided at the state level, and policies can vary dramatically across state lines. Data was used from 1989—1990 and 2008—2009 to describe these differences and how they have changed over time. Numerous aspects of each state's higher education system were examined—average four-year tuition and fees, average two-year tuition and fees, the share of each state's public enrollment that is located at two-year institutions, total state grant aid, total need-based state grant aid, and total non-need-based state grant aid. The findings reveal substantial variation across states, but these differences across states fell over time for most measures. The relationships between variables also changed. For example, the positive relationship between a state's tuition level and its financial aid offerings declined during the period. Our analyses produce insight into national trends in tuition and grant aid by examining the contribution of individual states to these trends. National figures have been heavily influenced by the decisions of a few large states with atypical finance policies and by the shifting of population away from high-tuition northern industrial states and towards low-tuition Sun Belt states.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d29e162a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e169" publication-type="other">
Bowen (1980)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e175" publication-type="other">
Ehrenberg (2000)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d29e191a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e195" publication-type="other">
Archibald, R. B., and Feldman, D. H. 2008. Explaining increases in higher education costs. The
Journal of Higher Education 79 (3): 268-295.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e205a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e209" publication-type="other">
Baum, S., and Ma, J. 2009. Trends in college pricing. The College Board. http://www.trends-
collegeboard.com/college_pricing/pdf/2009_Trends_College_Pricing.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e219a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e223" publication-type="other">
Bowen, H. R. 1980. The costs of higher education: How much do colleges and universities spend per
student and how much should they spend? San Francisco, CA: Jossey-Bass Publishers.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e233a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e237" publication-type="other">
Burd, S. 2003. Congressional plan to penalize colleges for tuition increases is criticized. Chronicle
of Higher Education. October 3.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e248a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e252" publication-type="other">
---. 2004. Plan to punish big increases in tuition is dropped. Chronicle of Higher Education. March
12.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e262a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e266" publication-type="other">
Cheslock, J. J., and Gianneschi, M. 2008. Replacing state appropriations with alternative revenue
sources: The case of voluntary support. The Journal of Higher Education 79 (2): 208-229.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e276a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e280" publication-type="other">
Cornwell, C., Mustard, D. B„ and Sridhar, D. B. 2006. The enrollment effects of merit-based
financial aid: Evidence from Georgia's HOPE program. Journal of Labor Economics 24 (4):
761-786.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e293a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e297" publication-type="other">
Commonfund Institute. 2009. Higher education price index, http://www.commonfund.org/
InvestorResources/Publications/Brochures/CF_HEPI_2009.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e307a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e311" publication-type="other">
Curs, B., and Dar, L. 2010. Does state financial aid affect institutional aid? An analysis of the role of
state policy on postsecondary institutional pricing strategies. Paper prepared for the Western
Economics Association Conference, Portland, OR.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e324a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e328" publication-type="other">
Doyle, W. R. 2006. Adoption of merit-based student grant programs: An event history analysis.
Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis 28 (3): 259-285.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e339a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e343" publication-type="other">
---. 2011. The politics of public college tuition and student financial aid. Forthcoming, The Journal
of Higher Education, http://www.vanderbilt.edu/lpo/doyle/tuitpolitics.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e353a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e357" publication-type="other">
Doyle, W. R., Delaney, J. A., and Naughton, B. A. 2009. Does institutional aid compensate for or
comply with state policy? Research in Higher Education 50(5): 502-523.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e367a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e371" publication-type="other">
Dynarski, S. 2000. Hope for whom? Financial aid for the middle class and its impact on college
attendance. National Tax Journal 53 (3): 629-662.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e381a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e385" publication-type="other">
Ehrenberg, R. G. 2000. Tuition rising: Why college costs so much. Cambridge, MA: Harvard
University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e395a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e399" publication-type="other">
Goldin, C., and Katz, L. F. 1999. The shaping of higher education: The formative years in the
United States, 1890 to 1940. Journal of Economic Perspectives 13 (1): 37-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e409a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e413" publication-type="other">
Griswold, C. P., and Marine, G. M. 1996. Political influences on state policy: Higher-tuition,
higher-aid, and the real world. Review of Higher Education, 19 (4), 361-389.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e424a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e428" publication-type="other">
Hauptman, A. M. 2001. Reforming the ways in which states finance higher education. In D. Heller
(Ed.), The states and public higher education policy: Affordability, access, and accountability.
64-80. Baltimore, MD: Johns Hopkins University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e441a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e445" publication-type="other">
Hearn, J. C., Griswold, C. P., and Marine, G. M. 1996. Region, resources, and reason: A contextual
analysis of state tuition and student aid policies. Research in Higher Education 37 (3): 241-278.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e455a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e459" publication-type="other">
Hearn, J. G, and Longanecker, D. 1985. Enrollment effects of alternative postsecondary pricing
policies. The Journal of Higher Education 56 (5): 485-508.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e469a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e473" publication-type="other">
Heller, D. E. 1997. Student price response in higher education: An update to Leslie and Brinkman.
The Journal of Higher Education 68 (6): 624-659.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e483a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e487" publication-type="other">
---. 1999. The effects of tuition and state financial aid on public college enrollment. The Review of
Higher Education 23 (1): 65-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e497a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e501" publication-type="other">
---. 2002. The policy shift in state financial aid programs. In J. Smart (Ed.), Higher education:
Handbook of theory and research, volume XVII. 221-262. Dordrecht, The Netherlands: Kluwer
Academic Publishers.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e515a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e519" publication-type="other">
---. 2006. Merit aid and college access. Madison: Wisconsin Center for the Advancement of
Postsecondary Education, University of Wisconsin.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e529a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e533" publication-type="other">
Hovey, H.A.I 999. State spending for higher education in the next decade: The battle to sustain current
support. Paper prepared for the National Center for Public Policy and Higher Education.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e543a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e547" publication-type="other">
Johnstone, D. B. 1993. The "high tuition-high aid" model of public higher education finance: The case
against. Paper prepared for the 1993 Annual Meeting of the National Association of Systems
Heads.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e560a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e564" publication-type="other">
---. 2004. The economics and politics of cost sharing in higher education: Comparative perspectives.
Economics of Education Review 23(4): 403-410.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e574a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e578" publication-type="other">
Kane, T. J. 1994. College entry by Blacks since 1970: The role of college costs, family background,
and the returns to education. Journal of Political Economy 102 (5): 878-911.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e588a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e592" publication-type="other">
Kane, T. J., Orszag, P. R., and Gunter, D. L. 2003. State fiscal constraints and higher education
spending: The role of Medicaid and the business cycle. Discussion Paper No. 11. The Urban-
Brookings Tax Policy Center. Washington, D. C.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e606a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e610" publication-type="other">
Lenth, C. S. 1993. The tuition dilemma: State policies and practices in pricing public higher education.
State Higher Education Executive Officers. Denver, CO.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e620a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e624" publication-type="other">
Leslie, L. L., and Brinkman, P. T. 1987. Student price response in higher education. The Journal of
Higher Education 58(2): 181-204.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e634a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e638" publication-type="other">
Lowry, R. C. 2001. Governmental structure, trustee selection, and public university prices and
spending: Multiple means to similar ends. American Journal of Political Science 45 (4): 845-
861.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e651a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e655" publication-type="other">
McLendon, M. K, Hearn, J. C., and Hammond, R. G. 1996. Pricing the flagships: The politics of
tuition setting and public research universities. Paper prepared for the Association for the

              Study of Higher Education 21
              
              Annual Conference, Memphis, TN.
            </mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e671a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e675" publication-type="other">
Mumper, M. 2001. The paradox of college prices: Five stories with no clear lesson. In D. Heller
(Ed.), The states and public higher education policy: Affordability, access, and accountability.
39-63. Baltimore, MD: Johns Hopkins University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e688a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e692" publication-type="other">
National Association of State Student Grant and Aid Programs (NASSGAP). 2010. Annual survey
report on state-sponsored student financial aid.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e703a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e707" publication-type="other">
National Center for Education Statistics. Digest of education statistics, http://www.nces.ed.gov/
programs/digest/</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e717a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e721" publication-type="other">
---. The integrated postsecondary education data system (IPEDS). http://www.nces.ed.gov/ipeds</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e728a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e732" publication-type="other">
---. National postsecondary student aid study (NPSAS). http://www.nces.ed.gov/npsas</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e739a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e743" publication-type="other">
National Commission on the Cost of Higher Education. 1998. Straight talk about college costs and
prices. 1-18. Phoenix, AZ: Oryx Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e753a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e757" publication-type="other">
Nicholson-Crotty, J., and Meier, K. J. 2003. Politics, structure, and public policy: The case of higher
education. Educational Policy 17(1): 80-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e767a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e771" publication-type="other">
Paulsen, M. B. 2000. Economic perspectives on rising college tuition: A theoretical and empirical
exploration. In J. Smart (Ed.), Higher education: Handbook of theory and research, volume XV.
39-104. New York: Agathon Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e785a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e789" publication-type="other">
Rusk, J. J., and Leslie, L. L. 1978. The setting of tuition in public higher education. The Journal of
Higher Education 49 (6): 531-547.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e799a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e803" publication-type="other">
St. John, E. P. 1992. Changes in pricing behavior during the 1980s: An analysis of selected case
studies. The Journal of Higher Education 63 (2): 165-187.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e813a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e817" publication-type="other">
Washington Higher Education Coordinating Board. 2010.2009-10 tuition and fee rates: A national
comparison. http://www.hecb.wa.gov/research/issues/documents/TuitionandFees2009-
10Report-Final.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


