<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24908918</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Incorporating Battle Focused Training and Operations Research</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Brown</surname>
                  <given-names>Donald</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Donald E. Brown is Professor and Chair of the Department of Systems and Information Engineering at the University of Virginia. He received the Ph.D. degree in Industrial and Operations Engineering from the University of Michigan, the M.S. and M.Eng. degrees in Operations Research and Industrial Engineering, respectively from the University of California, Berkeley, and the B.S. degree from the US Military Academy, West Point. His research is in statistical learning, data mining, data fusion, and simulation-optimization.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kwinn</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
                  <suffix>Jr</suffix>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>LTC Michael J. Kwinn, Jr is an Academy Professor and is currently the Director of the Operations Research Center of Excellence at the US Military Academy. He holds a BS from the US Military Academy, an MS from the University of Arizona and a Ph.D from the University of Texas at Austin. His research interests are varied and include recruiting marketing analysis, EBO assessment analysis, decision analysis, and combat systems requirements development.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Downes</surname>
                  <given-names>Patrick</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>MAJ Patrick M. Downes is an Instructor in the Department of Systems Engineering at the United States Military Academy. He holds a BS from the US Military Academy and an MS from the University of Virginia. His research interests include combat modeling and agent based modeling.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2004</year>
            <string-date>June 2004</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>37</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e24908911</issue-id>
         <fpage>6</fpage>
         <lpage>9</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24908918"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Federation of American Scientists, “Land Warrior.” http://www.fas.org/man/dod-101/sys/land/land-warrior.htm. 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Department of Military Instruction, United States Military Academy Instructional Memorandum. “Military Science 102, Ground Maneuver Warfare I,” January 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">James Fudge, “Delta Force II Chosen by US Army.” http://www.cdmag.com/articles/027/007/d2_army.html, March 21, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pleban, Robert J., Functional Capabilities of Four Virtual Individual Combatant (VIC) Simulator Technologies: An Independent Assessment. Alexandria, Virginia, U.S. Army Research Institute for the Behavioral and Social Sciences, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Infantry Forces Research Unit, “Measures of Platoon Leader Situation Awareness in Virtual Decision Making Exercises.” http://wwwbenning.army.mil.arifb/Reports/2001/, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mica Endsley, “Theoretical Underpinnings of Situation Awareness: A Critical Review.” In Mica Endsley, Daniel Garland (eds), Situation Awareness Analysis and Measurement. Mahwah, New Jersey: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, Publishers, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marc Green, J. Odom, and J. Yates, Measuring Situation Awareness with the ‘Ideal Observer.’ ERGO/GERO Human Factors Science, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
