<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277543</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Visualization of Partially Premixed Combustion of Gasoline-like Fuel Using High Speed Imaging in a Constant Volume Vessel</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zheng</surname>
                  <given-names>Liang</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Qi</surname>
                  <given-names>Yunliang</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>He</surname>
                  <given-names>Xu</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wang</surname>
                  <given-names>Zhi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Tsinghua University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>1320</fpage>
         <lpage>1329</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277543"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Combustion visualizations were carried out in a constant volume vessel to study the partially premixed combustion of a gasoline-like fuel using high speed imaging. The test fuel (G80H20) is composed by volume 80% commercial gasoline and 20% n-heptane. The effects of ambient gas composition, ambient temperature and injection pressure on G80H20 combustion characteristics were analyzed. Meanwhile, a comparison of the EGR effect on combustion process between G80H20 and diesel was made. Four ambient gas conditions that represent the in-cylinder gas compositions of a heavy duty diesel engine with EGR ratios of 0%, 20%, 40% and 60% were used to simulate EGR conditions. Variables also include two ambient temperature (910K and 870K) and two injection pressure (20MPa and 50MPa) conditions. Results show that the flame luminance of G80H20 decreases, ignition delay increases and ignition position moves downstream from the injector tip with increasing EGR ratio, decreasing ambient temperature and increasing injection pressure. The liquid spray length of G80H20 is much shorter than that of diesel under the same conditions. The flame luminance of G80H20 fuel decreased significantly when ambient oxygen concentration drops from 21% to 16.3% (EGR ratio: 20%). While 11.1% oxygen concentration (EGR ratio: 60%) is needed for diesel fuel to achieve a great drop in flame luminance. This is mainly because a separation of end of injection (EOI) and start of combustion (SOC) is more easily achieved with G80H20, since the ignition delay (2.7∼4.5ms) of G80H20 is longer than that (1.2∼2.3ms) of diesel.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noehre, C., Andersson, M., Johansson, B., and Hultqvist, A., “Characterization of Partially Premixed Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3412, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Zander, C., Johansson, B., Tunestal, P. et al., “An Advanced Internal Combustion Engine Concept for Low Emissions and High Efficiency from Idle to Max Load Using Gasoline Partially Premixed Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2198, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-2198.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kanda, T., Hakozaki, T., Uchimoto, T., Hatano, J. et al., “PCCI Operation with Early Injection of Conventional Diesel Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0378, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0378.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Risberg, P., and Ångström, H., “Advantages of Fuels with High Resistance to Auto-ignition in Late-injection, Lowtemperature, Compression Ignition Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3385, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3385.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Risberg, P., and Ångström, H., “Partially Pre-Mixed Auto-Ignition of Gasoline to Attain Low Smoke and Low NOx at High Load in a Compression Ignition Engine and Comparison with a Diesel Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0006, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Johansson, B., and Tunestal, P., “Partially Premixed Combustion at High Load using Gasoline and Ethanol, a Comparison with Diesel,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0944, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0944.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Johansson, B., Tunestal, P., and Cannella, W., “Effects of Different Type of Gasoline Fuels on Heavy Duty Partially Premixed Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):71-88, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-2668.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hildingsson, L., Johansson, B., Kalghatgi, G., and Harrison, A., “Some Effects of Fuel Autoignition Quality and Volatility in Premixed Compression Ignition Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):440-460, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0607.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Tunestal, P., Johansson, B., and Cannella, W., “Effects of Ethanol and Different Type of Gasoline Fuels on Partially Premixed Combustion from Low to High Load,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0871, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0871.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Operating a Heavy-Duty Direct- Injection Compression-Ignition Engine with Gasoline for Low Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1442, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1442.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra, Y., Loeper, P., Reitz, R., Andrie, M. et al., “Study of High Speed Gasoline Direct Injection Compression Ignition (GDICI) Engine Operation in the LTC Regime,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1412-1430, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weall, A. and Collings, N., “Investigation into Partially Premixed Combustion in a Light-Duty Multi-Cylinder Diesel Engine Fuelled Gasoline and Diesel with a Mixture of,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4058, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-4058.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weall, A. and Collings, N., “Gasoline Fuelled Partially Premixed Compression Ignition in a Light Duty Multi Cylinder Engine: A Study of Low Load and Low Speed Operation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 1574-1586, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1791.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shi, Y. and Reitz, R. D. Optimization of a heavy-duty compressionignition engine fueled with diesel and gasoline-like fuels, Fuel, 2010, doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2010.02.023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A. and Reitz, R., “Computational Optimization of a Heavy- Duty Compression Ignition Engine Fueled with Conventional Gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):338-359, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Hildingsson, L., Harrison, A. and Johansson, B., “Low- NOx, low-smoke operation of a diesel engine using “premixed enough” compression ignition - Effects of fuel autoignition quality, volatility and aromatic content”, presented at THIESEL 2010 Conference on Thermoand Fluid Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines, Spain, Sep. 14-17, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M. and Siebers, D.L., “Soot in Diesel Fuel Jets: Effects of Ambient Temperature, Ambient Density, and Injection Pressure,” Combustion and Flame, 138:114-135, 2004, doi: 10.1016/j.combustflame.2004.04.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chikando, A. and Kinser, J., “Optimizing Image Segmentation Using Color Model Mixtures,” AIPR, pp.230-235, 34th Applied Imagery and Pattern Recognition Workshop (AIPR'05), 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
