<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">16</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830294</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830297</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>L'OFFRE DE MONNAIE ET L'INFLATION AU MAROC / MONEY SUPPLY AND INFLATION IN MOROCCO</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ahmed</given-names>
                  <surname>Zejli</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1992</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>145</fpage>
         <lpage>158</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830297"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Le propos du présent papier est d'examiner la stabilité fonctionelle du multiplicateur monétaire. L'analyse econométrique des différents ratios traduisant le comportement du système bancaires et des agents non bancaires montre que le multiplicateur est expliqué par le taux d'intérêt, le taux de la réserve obligatoire, le taux d'inflation et le niveau de l'activité économique. La simulation du multiplicateur et d'une équation de prix montre que la hausse du taux d'intérêt renforce le pouvoir de création monétaire des banques sans engendrer d'inflation. L'accroissement du taux de la réserve obligatoire sur les dépôts à vue, comme il est récemment décide par les pouvoirs publics s'avère avoir plus d'effet sur l'offre de monnaie que sur l'inflation. L'effet inverse se produit pour le taux de change réel. The paper adresses the functional stability of the money supply multiplier. The econometric analysis of the ratios translating the financial behavior of the banks and non banking agents shows that the multiplier is explained by the interest rate, the bank legal reserve ratio, the anticipated inflation and the level of output. The multiplier and a price equation are simulated to show that the rise of interest rate enhances the money supply power of the banking system without inducing excessive inflation. The use of legal required reserves on the sight deposits as is recently decided by the government, turns out to be more effective on money supply than on inflation. The opposite occurred for the real exchange rate.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>fre</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d50e156a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e160" publication-type="other">
Beenstock M. (1989): «The Determinants of the Money Multiplier in United Kingdom», Journal of Money Credit
and Banking, November.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e170a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e174" publication-type="other">
Militz J. (1976): «A General Model of Stock Determination and a Special Econometric Application To France*.
Working paper I.N.S.E.E.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e184a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e188" publication-type="other">
Niehans J. (1978): «The Theory of Money» Johns Hopkins University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e195a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e199" publication-type="other">
Theil H. (1966): «Applied Economic Forecasting* North-Holland, Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


