<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">7</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466894</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466903</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Do Individual Investors Treat Trading as a Fun and Exciting Gambling Activity? Evidence from Repeated Natural Experiments</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Xiaohui</given-names>
                  <surname>Gao</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Tse-Chun</given-names>
                  <surname>Lin</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2128</fpage>
         <lpage>2166</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466903"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We hypothesize that individual investors treat trading as a fun and exciting gambling activity, implying substitution between this activity and alternative gambling opportunities. To examine this hypothesis, we study the lottery jackpots and the trading of individual investors in Taiwan. When the jackpots exceed 500 million Taiwan dollars, the trading volume decreases between 5.2% and 9.1% among stocks preferred by individual investors and between 6.8% and 8.6% among lottery-like stocks. The decline in individual buy volume is statistically indistinct from the decline in sell volume. Large jackpots are associated with less trading in options with high sensitivity to volatility.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1305484e318a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305484e325" publication-type="other">
We also refer the reader to the discussions in Barber and Odean (2000, Section VI.D), Grinblatt and Kelohaiju
(2001, Introduction), and Statman (2002). The evidence in Li (2012, Table 7) further suggests that gamblers are
more likely to invest in financial securities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305484e338a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305484e345" publication-type="other">
See also the insights offered by the distraction hypothesis of (Hirshleifer, Lim, and Teoh, 2009, Table VI) and
the inattention hypothesis of (DellaVigna and Pollet, 2009, Table V).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305484e355a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305484e362" publication-type="other">
For robustness, we replaced the past trading volume with a polynomial time trend of order five within each year,
and we obtained similar conclusions. Therefore, this comparison has been omitted.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305484e372a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305484e379" publication-type="other">
The Taiwan coincident index is released by the Council for Economic Planning and Development and downloaded
from Bloomberg. It is an economic index made up of seven components: industrial production, machinery
and electrical equipment imports, customs-cleared exports, electric power consumption, manufacturing sales,
nonagricultural employment, and wholesale and retail sales index.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305484e396a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305484e403" publication-type="other">
Histogram evidence (not reported) confirms that while the level of the shares traded is skewed to the right,
the empirical distribution of the log counterpart is closer to normal. Moreover, inspection of the plots of log
variables suggests that the series is stationary. The null hypothesis of a unit root is rejected at 1% confidence
level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305484e419a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305484e428" publication-type="other">
We recognize that when stocks are divided into two groups by return variance, it may still leave room for skewness
to be correlated with variance. To address this issue, we pursue two additional exercises. First, we sort stocks
into quintiles based on variance and then divide stocks within each quintile into three skewness groups. Then
we construct the corresponding trading volume and perform the SUR estimations analogous to Equation (1).
Our results (not reported) confirm the conclusions obtained from Table 6. Second, we perform a one-way sort of
stocks, by their daily residual skewness into three groups (top 30%, middle 40%, and bottom 30%) and generate
the corresponding trading volume series. The residual skewness is obtained from fitting a bivariate time-series
regression using daily data, where the skewness (computed using a three-month trailing window) is the dependent
variable and the corresponding variance along with lagged skewness (to account for serial dependence) are the
independent variables. Our SUR estimation approach reveals that the trading volume declines more prominently
among high residual skewness stocks on large jackpot days.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305484e466a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305484e473" publication-type="other">
If individuals' stock trading data were available and could be matched to their lottery purchase records, it
could deliver a more cogent message about the nature of the substitution effect between stocks and lotteries.
In addition, our analysis raises further questions of interest: What is the demographic profile of individuals
who participate in the lottery? What are their religious beliefs? What are their income profiles? Access to
comprehensive demographic data that contain socioeconomic characteristics would enable us to pursue such
questions using the methods of Korniotis and Kumar (2011) and Kumar, Page, and Spalt (2011). We leave such
scrutiny to a follow-up study.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1305484e508a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e512" publication-type="other">
Baker, M., and J. Wurgler. 2007. Investor sentiment in the stock market. Journal of Economie Perspectives
21:129-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e522a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e526" publication-type="other">
Bakshi, G, C. Cao, and Z. Chen. 1997. Empirical performance of alternative option pricing models. Journal of
Finance 52:2003—49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e536a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e540" publication-type="other">
Bali, T., N. Cakici, and R. Whitelaw. 2011. Maxing out: Stocks as lotteries and the cross-section of expected
returns. Journal of Financial Economies 99:427—46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e550a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e554" publication-type="other">
Barber, B., Y.-T. Lee, Y.-J. Liu, and T. Odean. 2009. Just how much do individual investors lose by trading?
Review of Financial Studies 22:609-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e565a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e569" publication-type="other">
Barber, B., and T. Odean. 2000. Trading is hazardous to your wealth: The common stock investment performance
of individual investors. Journal of Finance 55:773-806.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e579a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e583" publication-type="other">
. 2008. All that glitters: The effect of attention and news on the buying behavior of individual and
institutional investors. Review of Financial Studies 21:785-818.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e593a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e597" publication-type="other">
Barberis, N., and M. Huang. 2008. Stocks as lotteries: The implications of probability weighting for security
prices. American Economic Review 98:2066-100.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e607a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e611" publication-type="other">
Bondarenko, O. 2003. Why are put options so expensive? Unpublished working paper, University of Illinois-
Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e621a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e625" publication-type="other">
Boyer, B., and K. Vorkink. 2014. Stock options as lotteries. The Journal of Finance 69:1485-527.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e632a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e636" publication-type="other">
Chen, J., H. Hong, and J. Stein. 2001. Forecasting crashes: Trading volume, past returns, and conditional skewness
in stock prices. Journal of Financial Economics 61:345-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e647a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e651" publication-type="other">
Chordia, T., R. Roll, and A. Subrahmanyam. 2001. Market liquidity and trading activity. Journal of Finance
56:501-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e661a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e665" publication-type="other">
Clark, T., and K. West. 2007. Approximately normal tests for equal predictive accuracy in nested models. Journal
of Econometrics 138:291-311.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e675a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e679" publication-type="other">
DellaVigna, S., and J. Pollet. 2009. Investor inattention and Friday earnings announcements. Journal of Finance
64:709-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e689a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e693" publication-type="other">
Dorn, A., D. Dom, and R Sengmueller. 2013. Trading as gambling. Unpublished working paper, Drexel
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e703a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e707" publication-type="other">
Dom, D., and P. Sengmueller. 2009. Trading as entertainment. Management Science 55:591-603.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e714a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e718" publication-type="other">
Foucault, T., D. Sraer, and D. Thesmar. 2011. Individual investors and volatility. Journal of Finance 66:
1369-406.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e729a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e733" publication-type="other">
Golec, J., and M. Tamarkin. 1998. Bettors love skewness, not risk, at the horse track. Journal of Political Economy
106:205-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e743a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e747" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P., and A. Metrick. 2001. Institutional investors and equity prices. Quarterly Journal of Economics
116:229-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e757a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e761" publication-type="other">
Green, T., and B.-H. Hwang. 2012. Initial public offerings as lotteries: Skewness preference and first-day returns.
Management Science 58:432—44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e771a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e775" publication-type="other">
Grinblatt, M., and M. Kelohaiju. 2001. What makes investors trade? Journal of Finance 56:589-616.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e782a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e786" publication-type="other">
. 2009. Sensation seeking, overconfidence, and trading activity. Journal of Finance 64:549-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e793a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e797" publication-type="other">
Hansen, L., and R. Hodrick. 1980. Forward exchange rates as optimal predictors of future spot rates: An
econometric analysis. Journal of Political Economy 88:829-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e808a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e812" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, D. 2001. Investor psychology and asset pricing. Journal of Finance 56:1533-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e819a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e823" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, D., S. Lim, and S. Teoh. 2009. Driven to distraction: Extraneous events and underreaction to earnings
news. Journal of Finance 64:2289-325.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e833a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e837" publication-type="other">
Hodrick, R. 1992. Dividend yields and expected stock returns: Alternative procedures for inference and
measurement. Review of Financial Studies 5:141-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e847a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e851" publication-type="other">
Kaniel, R., G Saar, and S. Titman. 2008. Individual investor trading and stock returns. Journal of Finance
63:273-310.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e861a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e865" publication-type="other">
Komiotis, G, and A. Kumar. 2011. Do behavioral biases adversely affect the macro-economy? Review of
Financial Studies 24:1513-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e875a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e879" publication-type="other">
Kumar, A. 2009. Who gambles in the stock market? Journal of Finance 64:1889-933.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e887a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e891" publication-type="other">
Kumar, A., J. Page, and O. Spalt. 2011. Religious Beliefs, Gambling Attitudes, and Financial Market Outcomes.
Journal of Financial Economics 102:671-708.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e901a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e905" publication-type="other">
Li, G 2012. Gamblers as personal finance activists. Unpublished working paper, Board of Governors of the
Federal Reserve System.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e915a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e919" publication-type="other">
Mikeseil, J. 1994. State lottery sales and economic activity. National Tax Journal 47:165-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e926a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e930" publication-type="other">
Newey, W., and K. West. 1987. A Simple, Positive Semi-Definite, Heteroskedasticity and Autocorrelation
Consistent Covariance Matrix. Econometrica 55:703-8.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e940a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e944" publication-type="other">
. 1994. Automatic Lag Selection in Covariance Matrix Estimation. Review of Economic Studies 61:
631-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e954a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e958" publication-type="other">
Pan, J., and A. Poteshman. 2006. The Information in option volume for future stock prices. Review of Financial
Studies 19:871-908.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e969a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e973" publication-type="other">
Rigobon, R., and T. Stoker. 2009. "Bias from censored regressors. Journal of Business and Economic Statistics
27:340-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305484e983a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305484e987" publication-type="other">
Statman, M. 2002. Lottery players/stock traders. Financial Analysts Journal 58:14-21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


