<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275503</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Performance Characteristics of an Production Oriented Air Hybrid Powertrain</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lee</surname>
                  <given-names>Cho-Yu</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhao</surname>
                  <given-names>Huz</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ma</surname>
                  <given-names>Tom</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Brunel University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>609</fpage>
         <lpage>619</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275503"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In a previous paper [1], the authors have proposed a cost effective air hybrid concept based on a proprietary intake system and cam profile switching (CPS) system [2]. It was shown through engine simulations that the pneumatic hybrid operation could be achieved with about 15% regenerative efficiency. The proposed air hybrid operation can be achieved with proven technologies and engine components and hence it represents a cost-effective, reliable and quick deployable solution for low carbon vehicles.</p>
            <p>In this work, a four-cylinder 2 litre diesel engine has been modelled to operate on refined air hybrid engine configurations and the braking and motoring performance of each configuration have been studied.</p>
            <p>Both air hybrid systems can be constructed with production technologies and incur minimum changes to the existing engine design. The regenerative engine braking and staring capability is realised through the employment of innovative proprietary intake system and production cam profile switching (CPS) devices. The 1st hybrid engine configuration is shown to be capable of producing compressed air to 15 bar during its compression mode operation. Both hybrid systems will allow the engine to be cranked by the compressed air at moderate pressure without using an additional starter or dedicated valves in the cylinder head. Therefore, the proposed air hybrid engine systems can be considered as a very cost-effective regenerative hybrid powertrain and can be implemented in vehicles using existing production technologies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, C.-Y., Zhao, H., and Ma, T., “Analysis of a Cost Effective Air Hybrid Concept,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1111, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ma T.., Zhao H., “Method of operating an internal combustion Engine” Europe Patent No. 1747351; U.S. Patent No. 7,380,525.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tai, C. and Tsao, T.-C., “Using Camless Valvetrain for Air Hybrid Optimization,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0038, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The University of California, “UCLA Study Suggests Air Hybrid Car Could Improve Fuel Efficiency”, obtained from http://www.newsroom.ucla.edu/page.asp?id=4420, last visited March 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kang, H., Tai, C., Smith, E., Wang, X. et al., “Demonstration of Air-Power-Assist (APA) Engine Technology for Clean Combustion and Direct Energy Recovery in Heavy Duty Application,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1197, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Trajkovic, S., Tunestål, P., and Johansson, B., “Investigation of Different Valve Geometries and Valve Timing Strategies and their Effect on Regenerative Efficiency for a Pneumatic Hybrid with Variable Valve Actuation,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):1206-1223, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dönitz, C., Vasile, I., Onder, C., and Guzzella, L., “Realizing a Concept for High Efficiency and Excellent Driveability: The Downsized and Supercharged Hybrid Pneumatic Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1326, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schechter, M.M., “New Cycles for Automobile Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0623, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schechter, M.M., “Regenerative Compression Braking - A Low Cost Alternative to Electric Hybrids,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1025, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner, J.W.G., Bassett, M.D., Pearson, R.J., Pitcher, G. et al., “New Operating Strategies Afforded by Fully Variable Valve Trains,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1386, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner J., Pearson, R. and Kenchington, S. A., “Concepts for Improved Fuel Economy from Gasoline Engines”, International Journal of Engine Research, vol.6, no.2, pp. 137-157, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
