<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278151</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of Integrated Modular Motor Drive for Traction Applications</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Choi</surname>
                  <given-names>Gilsu</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Wisconsin - Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Xu</surname>
                  <given-names>Zhuxian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Tennessee - Knoxville</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Ming</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Tennessee - Knoxville</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gupta</surname>
                  <given-names>Shiv</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Wisconsin - Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jahns</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Wisconsin - Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wang</surname>
                  <given-names>Fred</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Tennessee and ORNL</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Duffie</surname>
                  <given-names>Neil A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Wisconsin - Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Marlino</surname>
                  <given-names>Laura</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Oak Ridge National Laboratory</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>286</fpage>
         <lpage>300</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278151"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper introduces a promising approach for developing an integrated traction motor drive based on the Integrated Modular Motor Drive (IMMD) concept. The IMMD concept strives to meet aggressive power density and performance targets by modularizing both the machine and power electronics and then integrating them into a single combined machine-plus-drive structure. Physical integration of the power electronics inside the machine makes it highly desirable to increase the power electronics operating temperature including higher power semiconductor junction temperatures and improved device packaging.</p>
            <p>Recent progress towards implementing the IMMD concept in an integrated traction motor drive is summarized in this paper. Several candidate permanent magnet (PM) machine configurations with different numbers of phases between 3 and 6 are analyzed to compare their performance characteristics and key application features. A 6-phase, 10-pole PM machine topology has been selected as the most promising configuration for meeting the major requirements in the areas of power density, efficiency, and module count. A parallel investigation of fault-tolerant distributed control configurations for the IMMD traction drive has led to selection of a heterarchical controller configuration that requires each phase module to be equipped with its own independent microcontroller operating as a peer with all of the other phase module controllers.</p>
            <p>The potential of silicon (Si) insulated gate bipolar transistors (IGBTs) operating at junction temperatures up to 200°C has been evaluated using a hardware testbed in terms of device losses and thermal issues. Based on these study results, a 10 kW phase-leg package design using Si IGBTs has been investigated including die selection, material selection, layout design, parasitic extraction and thermal characterization. Thermal performance characterization has been conducted for different packaging structures, operating conditions and coolant selections. The proposed packaging design and cooling approach can maintain the Si IGBT junction temperature below 200°C with an ambient temperature of 150°C.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown, N. R., Jahns, T. M., and Lorenz, R. D., “Power Converter Design for an Integrated Modular Motor Drive,” in Rec. of 2007 IEEE Industry Applications Society Annual Meeting (IAS'07), pp. 1322-1328, New Orleans, Sept. 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sykora, B. J., Jahns, T. M., and Lorenz, R. D., “Development of a Demonstrator Model of an Integrated Modular Motor Drive,” in Proc. 2008 NSF-CPES Annual Conference, Blacksburg, VA, April 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buttay, C., Planson, D., Allard, B., Bergogne, D., Bevilacqua, P., Joubert, C., Lazar, M., Martin, C., Morel, H., Tournier, D., and Raynaud, C., “State of the Art of High Temperature Power Electronics,” presented at Microtherm 2009, pp. 1-10, Lodz: Poland, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ning, P., Lai, R., Wang, F., Ngo, K.D.T., Immanuel, V.D., and Karimi, K.J., “SiC Wirebond Multichip Phase-leg Module Packaging Design and Testing for Harsh Environment,” IEEE Transactions on Power Electronics, 25(1):16-23, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, H., Wang, F., Huang, A. Q., and Tipton, C. W., “Investigation of Power MOSFETs for High Temperature Operation,” in Rec. of 2005 IEEE Industry Applications Society Annual Meeting (IAS'05), Vol. 1: 388-392, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schlapbach, U., Rahimo, M., von Arx, C., Mukhitdinov, A., and Linder, S., “1200V IGBTs Operating at 200°C? An Investigation on the Potentials and the Design Constraints,” presented at ISPSD 2007, Jeju, South Korea, May 27-31, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EL-Refaie, A. M., “High Speed Operation of PM Machines,” PhD thesis, Dept. of Electrical and Computer Eng., University of Wisconsin - Madison, USA, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jack, A. G., Mecrow, B. C., Dickinson, P. G., Stephenson, D., Burdess, J. S., Fawcett, N., and Evans, J. T., “Permanent Magnet Machines with Powdered Iron Cores and Pressed Windings,” IEEE Trans. Industry Applications, 36(4): 1077-1084, July/August 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dilts, D. M. et al., “The Evolution of Control Architectures for Automated Manufacturing Systems,” J. Manufacturing Syst., 10(1):79-93, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sheng, W. W., and Colino, R. P., “Power Electronic Modules: Design and Manufacture,” CRC press: Boca Raton, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamadal, J., Simizu, T., Kawaguchi, M., Nakamural, M., Kikuchi, M., and Thal, E., “The Latest High Performance and High Reliability IGBT Technology in New Packages with Conventional Pin Layout,” presented at PCIM 2003, Nuremberg, Germany, May 20-22, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burress, T. A., Coomer, C. L., Campbell, S. L., Wereszczak, A. A., Cunningham, J. P., Marlino, L. D., Seiber, L. E., and Lin, H. T., “Evaluation of the 2008 Lexus LS 600H Hybrid Synergy Drive System,” UT-Battelle, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, Tennessee, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Narumanchi, S., Mihalic, M., Kelly, K., and Eesley, G., “Thermal Interface Materials for Power Electronics Applications,” presented at ITHERM 2008, Orlando, USA, May 28-31, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prasher, R., “Thermal Interface Materials: Historical Perspective, Status, and Future Directions,” Proceedings of the IEEE, 94(8):1571-1586, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
