<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26272317</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Influence of In-Cylinder Flows on Emissions and Heat Transfer from Methane-Diesel Dual Fuel Combustion</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Königsson</surname>
                  <given-names>Fredrik</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>AVL Sweden</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dembinski</surname>
                  <given-names>Henrik</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Scania CV</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Angstrom</surname>
                  <given-names>Hans-Erik</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Royal Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>December 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26272316</issue-id>
         <fpage>1877</fpage>
         <lpage>1887</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International and Copyright © 2013 KSAE</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26272317"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In order for premixed methane diesel dual fuel engines to meet current and future legislation, the emissions of unburned hydrocarbons must be reduced while high efficiency and high methane utilization is maintained.</p>
            <p>This paper presents an experimental investigation into the effects of in cylinder air motion, swirl and tumble, on the emissions, heat transfer and combustion characteristics of dual fuel combustion at different air excess ratios. Measurements have been carried out on a single cylinder engine equipped with a fully variable valve train, Lotus AVT. By applying different valve lift profiles for the intake valves, the swirl was varied between 0.5 and 6.5 at BDC and the tumble between 0.5 and 4 at BDC. A commercial 1D engine simulation tool was used to calculate swirl number and tumble for the different valve profiles. Input data for the simulation software was generated using a steady-state flow rig with honeycomb torque measurements. To measure heat transfer, thermocouples were fitted in the cylinder head and heat exchangers on the coolant circuit and the engine oil.</p>
            <p>The study shows that swirl has a strong effect on the heat transfer; increasing the swirl from 0.5 to 6.5 increases the heat transfer to the coolant by 50%. With regards to emissions; swirl has the effect of increasing oxidation of hydrocarbons returning from crevices. For this reason a 20% reduction of hydrocarbon emissions can be achieved by increasing the swirl from 0.4 to 3. At high λ of 1.9, combustion is very sensitive to mixing between the gas and the air. The mixing is affected by the turbulence generated over the intake valves. A difference in engine out HC emissions by a factor of two can be achieved by varying the valve lift curve and hence varying the turbulence generated during the intake event. The timing of the gas injection can also improve mixing and achieve similar results. Compared to SI, dual fuel combustion is relatively insensitive to tumble.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karim, G., Liu, Z., and Jones, W., “Exhaust Emissions from Dual Fuel Engines at Light Load,” SAE Technical Paper 932822, 1993, doi: 10.4271/932822.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guliaeff, A., Wanninger, K., Klose, F., Maletz, G. et al., “Development of a Sulfur Tolerant PGM Based Zeolite Catalyst for Methane Oxidation and Low Temperature Hydrocarbon Trapping,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0531, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0531.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Königsson, F., Stalhammar, P., and Angstrom, H., “Characterization and Potential of Dual Fuel Combustion in a Modern Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-2223, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-2223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dembinski, H. and Ångström, H., “An Experimental Study of the Influence of Variable In-Cylinder Flow, Caused by Active Valve Train, on Combustion and Emissions in a Diesel Engine at Low Lambda Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1830, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1830.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wheeler, J., Polovina, D., Ramanathan, S., Roth, K. et al., “Increasing EGR Tolerance using High Tumble in a Modern GTDI Engine for Improved Low-Speed Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1123, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1123.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amer, A. and Reddy, T., “Multidimensional Optimization of In- Cylinder Tumble Motion for the New Chrysler Hemi,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1732, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1732.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergin, M., Reitz, R., Oh, S., Miles, P. et al., “Fuel Injection and Mean Swirl Effects on Combustion and Soot Formation in Heavy Duty Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0912, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0912.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dembinski, H. and Angstrom, H., “Swirl and Injection Pressure Impact on After-Oxidation in Diesel Combustion, Examined with Simultaneous Combustion Image Velocimetry and Two Colour Optical Method,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0913, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0913.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Antila, E., Imperato, M., Kaario, O., and Larmi, M., “Effect of Intake Channel Design to Cylinder Charge and Initial Swirl,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0624, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0624.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">(2013) Lotus Cars. [Online]. http://www.lotuscars.com/engineering/en/avt-standard-package</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schwoerer, J., Kumar, K., Ruggiero, B., and Swanbon, B., “Lost-Motion VVA Systems for Enabling Next Generation Diesel Engine Efficiency and After-Treatment Optimization,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1189, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deng, J. and Stobart, R., “BSFC Investigation Using Variable Valve Timing in a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1525, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1525.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thien G., “Entwicklungsarbeiten an Ventilkanälen von Viertakt- Dieselmotoren”, ÖIZ, vol. 9, 1965.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T., Rackmil, C., Keribar, R., and Jennings, M., “Model for Heat Transfer and Combustion In Spark Ignited Engines and its Comparison with Experiments,” SAE Technical Paper 880198, 1988, doi: 10.4271/880198.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Uzkan, T., Borgnakke, C., and Morel, T., “Characterization of Flow Produced by a High-Swirl Inlet Port,” SAE Technical Paper 830266, 1983, doi:10.4271/830266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T. and Keribar, R., “A Model for Predicting Spatially and Time Resolved Convective Heat Transfer in Bowl-in-Piston Combustion Chambers,” SAE Technical Paper 850204, 1985, doi:10.4271/850204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Königsson, F., Kuyper, J., Stalhammar, P., and Angstrom, H., “The Influence of Crevices on Hydrocarbon Emissions from a Diesel- Methane Dual Fuel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):751-765, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0848.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Min, K., Cheng, W., and Heywood, J., “The Effects of Crevices on the Engine-Out Hydrocarbon Emissions in SI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 940306, 1994, doi:10.4271/940306.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
