<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>CALICO</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i24146599</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24147812</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>USING SYSTÈME-D IN A CLASSROOM ENVIRONMENT</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>JACK L.</given-names>
                  <surname>BURSTON</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>1991</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>51</fpage>
         <lpage>57</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24147812"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Using Système-D in a Classroom Environment The purpose of this paper is to provide an evaluation of the effectiveness of Système-D, a composition resource tool, in a first-year university level advanced language classroom environment. Incorporating a simple text editor, a small bidirectional French-English dictionary, a lexicon of thematically related vocabulary and phrases, and elementary grammar notes, Système-D has great potential to enhance basic writing skills. Unfortunately, on their own, few students show themselves willing or able to profit from what Système-D has to offer. Maximum exploitation of the program requires its integration into the curriculum and the classroom. When used as a vehicle for directed text manipulation exercises, in combination with peer group teaching, Système-D can lead to welcome improvements in grammatical accuracy. The active involvement of the instructor in the process, however, is crucial to its success. Complete control of Système- D's functions and a thorough knowledge of the contents of its data bases are a sine qua non for the selection of topics, preparation of exercise texts, and provision of supplementary pedagogical materials.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d2676236e107a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2676236e111" publication-type="other">
Barson, John. 1989. Review of Système-D. CALICO Journal Vol 6 No 3, pp 70-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2676236e118a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2676236e122" publication-type="other">
Burston, Jack L, Bernadette Dejean de la BÉtie, Alastair Hurst and Monique Mon-
ville-Burston. 1988. Student Contributions to the Development of Computer-Aided
Language Learning Programs. Australian Review of Applied Linguistics Vol 11 No
1 pp 158-175.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2676236e138a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2676236e142" publication-type="other">
Church, Dan M. 1988. On the Use of Sticks and Carrots. CALICO Journal Vol 6 No
1 pp 37-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2676236e152a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2676236e156" publication-type="other">
Garrett, Nina. 1988. Review of Système-D. Foreign Language Annals, April pp 161-
165.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2676236e167a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2676236e171" publication-type="other">
Jones, Ann and Tim O'Shea. 1982. Barriers to the Use of Computer Assisted
Learning. British Journal of Educational Technology, Vol 3 No 13 pp 207-217.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2676236e181a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2676236e185" publication-type="other">
Pederson, Kathleen M. 1989. Review of Système-D. French Review (April) pp 913-
915.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2676236e195a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2676236e199" publication-type="other">
Scott, Virginia M. 1990. Task Oriented Creative Writing with Système-D. CALICO
Journal Vol 7 No 3 pp 58-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2676236e209a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2676236e213" publication-type="other">
Wyatt, David H. 1988. The Logo Syndrome. CALICO Journal Vol 5 No 4, pp 76-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


