<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422596</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Flow Noise Predictions for Single Cylinder Engine-Mounted Muffler Using a Lattice Boltzmann Based Method</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Mann</surname>
                  <given-names>Adrien</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Exa Corporation</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Nair</surname>
                  <given-names>Raj</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Exa Corporation</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Gill</surname>
                  <given-names>Jaspreet Singh</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Exa Corporation</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Birschbach</surname>
                  <given-names>Brett</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Briggs &amp; Stratton Corp</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Crowley</surname>
                  <given-names>Patrick</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Briggs &amp; Stratton Corp</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>October 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422530</issue-id>
         <fpage>2067</fpage>
         <lpage>2076</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422596"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Exhaust systems including mufflers are commonly mounted on engines to reduce the firing cycle noise originating from the combustion process. However, mufflers also produce flow-induced self-noise, originating from the complex flow path throughout the muffler. As an engine prototype is not available in the early stages of a development program, it is challenging to assess the acoustic performance of the full system when only experiment is available. It is also difficult to pinpoint the design features of a muffler generating noise, as a portion of the noise is generated internally.</p>
            <p>Numerical approaches are a possible alternative. However, capturing non-linear dissipation mechanisms and thermal fluctuations of exhaust flows is challenging, while necessary to accurately predict flow noise. Transient and compressible Computational Fluid Dynamics and Computational AeroAcoustics (CFD/CAA) Lattice-Boltzmann based Methods (LBM) have previously been successfully applied to quantify the flow noise generated by mufflers mounted on an experimental cold flow test bench.</p>
            <p>In this paper, the accuracy of the method for self-noise predictions of a muffler mounted on a single cylinder engine is demonstrated comparing results with experimental noise measurements obtained in a hemi-anechoic room. The inlet boundary condition of the muffler is calculated using a 1-D system modeling tool, providing oscillating transient temperature and mass flow rate. Measured temperature on the surface of the muffler is prescribed in the simulation on the geometry walls. After validation of the results, the simulation data is further post-processed to identify flow-induced noise sources in the system and propose design changes to reduce self-noise. This study confirms that this numerical approach can be used in a production process to quantify and reduce flow noise in mufflers.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T., Silvestri, J., Goerg, K., and Jebasinski, R., "Modeling of Engine Exhaust Acoustics," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1665, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-1665.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shaohua, Z., Guodong, J., Tianfeng, X. “Design and analysis method for internal combustion engine mufflers based on GT-Power software” [J]. Automobile Technology 7, 7-10, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mann, A., Kim, M., Neuhierl, B., Perot, F. et al., "Exhaust and Muffler Aeroacoustics Predictions using Lattice Boltzmann Method," SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 8(3):1009-1017, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-2314.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mann, A., Kim, M., Pan, S., Neuhierl, B., Perot, F. and Ocampo, J., 2016 “Towards engine-mounted exhaust and muffler aeroacoustics predictions using a Lattice Boltzmann based method” [M], FISITA World Congress 2016, F2016-NVHG-027.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rana, D., Regin, F., and Makana, M., "Analysis of Flow Induced Noise in a Passenger Car Exhaust System - An Experimental and Numerical Approach," SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1528, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1528.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rose, T., Krüger, J. and Neuhierl, B., 2014, “Strömungsakustische Simulation von Abgasanlagen” [M], Magdeburger Symposium für Motor- und Aggregate-Akustik</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neuhierl, B., “Simulation of Flow-Induced Noise in Exhaust Silencers” [M], Internoise 2016</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Powell, R., Hendriana, D., Gutzeit, B., Golsch, K. et al., "Direct Aeroacoustic Simulation of Flow Impingement Noise in an Exhaust Opening," SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 4(2):961-969, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1517.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Frisch, U., Hasslacher, B. and Pomeau, Y., 1986, “Lattice-gas Automata for the Navier-Stokes Equations”, Phys. Rev. Lett., Vol. 56, pp.1505-1508.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H., Chen, S., and Matthaeus, W., “Recovery of the Navier-Stokes equations using a lattice-gas Boltzmann method”, Phys. Rev. A 45, 5339-5342 (1992).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H., Teixeira, C. and Molvig, K., “Digital physics approach to computational fluid dynamics: Some basic theoretical features” [J], Intl. J. Mod. Phys. C 9 (8), 675 (1997).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H., Teixeira, C. and Molvig, K., “Realization of Fluid Boundary Conditions via Discrete Boltzmann Dynamics” [J], Intl J. Mod. Phys. C, Vol. 9 (8), pp. 1281-1292, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thantanapally, C., Singh, S., Succi, S., and Ansumali, S., “Quasiequilibrium lattice Boltzmann models with tunable Prandtl number for incompressible hydrodynamics” [J], International Journal of Modern Physics C 24 (12), 1340004 (2013).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H., “Volumetric Formulation of the Lattice Boltzmann Method for Fluid Dynamics: Basic Concept” [J], Phys. Rev. E, Vol. 58, pp. 3955-3963, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shan, X. and Chen, H., “A general multiple-relaxation-time Boltzmann collision model” [J], International Journal of Modern Physics C 18, 635 (2007).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H., Goldhirsh, I. and Orszag, S., “Discrete rotational symmetry, moment isotropy, and higher order lattice Boltzmann models" [J], J. Sci. Computing, submitted (August. 2007).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bhatnagar, P., Gross, E. and Krook, M., 1954, “A model for collision processes in gases. I. small amplitude processes in charged and neutral one-component system” [J], Pys. Rev., vol.94, pp.511-525, 1954.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chapman, S. and Cowling, T., “The Mathematical Theory of Non-Uniform Gases” [J], Cambridge University Press, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yakhot, V., “Extended Boltzmann Kinetic Equation for Turbulent Flows” [J], Science, Vol. 301, pp. 633-636, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shan, X. and Chen, H., 1993, “Lattice Boltzmann model for simulating flows with multiple phases and components” [J], Phys. Rev. E, 47, 1815-1819.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, Y., Shock, R., Zhang, R., and Chen, H., 2004, “Numerical Study of Flow Past an Impulsively Started Cylinder by Lattice Boltzmann Method” [J], J. Fluid Mech., Vol. 519, pp. 273-300.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H., Kandasamy, S., Orszag, S., Shock, R., Succi, S. and Yakhot, V., “Extended Boltzmann Kinetic Equation for Turbulent Flows” [J], Science, Vol. 301, pp. 633-636, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H., Orszag, S., Staroselsky, I. and Succi, S., 2004, “Expanded Analogy between Boltzmann Kinetic Theory of Fluid and Turbulence” [J], J. Fluid Mech., Vol. 519, pp. 307-314.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, R., Fan, H., and Chen, H. "A lattice Boltzmann approach for solving scalar transport equations."[J], Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society A: Mathematical, Physical and Engineering Sciences, 369(1944), 2264-2273, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaylard, A., "CFD Simulation of Side Glass Surface Noise Spectra for a Bluff SUV," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0137, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0137.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oettle, N., Meskine, M., Senthooran, S., Bissell, A. et al., "A Computational Approach to Assess Buffeting and Broadband Noise Generated by a Vehicle Sunroof," SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 8(1):196-204, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1532.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pérot, F., Meskine, M., Vergne, S., “HVAC noise predictions using a Lattice Boltzmann Method” [M], 19th AIAA/CEAS Aeroacoustics conference, May 2013, Berlin, Germany, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aissaoui, A., Tupake, R., Bijwe, V., Meskine, M. et al., "Flow-Induced Noise Optimization of SUV HVAC System using a Lattice Boltzmann Method," SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 8(3):1053-1062, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-2323.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laffite, A., Pérot, F., “Investigation of the Noise Generated by Cylinder Flows Using a Direct Lattice-Boltzmann Approach” [M], AIAA 2009-3268, 13th AIAA/CEAS aeroacoustics conference, Miami, Florida, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brès, G.A., Pérot, F., Freed, D., “Properties of the Lattice-Boltzmann Method for Acoustics” [M], AIAA 2009-3395, 13th AIAA/CEAS aeroacoustics conference, Miami, Florida, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keating, A., Dethioux, P., Satti, R., Noelting, S., Louis, J., Van de Ven, T. and Vieito, R., 2009, “Computational Aeroacoustics Validation and Analysis of a Nose Landing Gear” [M], AIAA 2009-3154, 13th AIAA/CEAS aeroacoustics conference, Miami, FL.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mann, A., Pérot, F., Kim, M.S., Casalino, D., Fares, E., 2012, “Advanced Noise Control Fan Direct Aeroacoustics Predictions using a Lattice-Boltzmann Method” [M], AIAA paper 2012-2287, 16th AIAA/CEAS aeroacoustics conference, Colorado Springs, June 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Balasubramanian, G., Mutnuri, L., Sugiyama, Z., Senthooran, S. et al., "A Computational Process for Early Stage Assessment of Automotive Buffeting and Wind Noise," SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 6(2):1231-1238, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1929.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Powell, A. 1964 “Theory of vortex sound” [J] Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 36(1), pp. 177-195</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mann, A., Pérot, F., Meskine, M., Kim, M.-S., 2015, “Designing quieter HVAC systems coupling LBM and flow-induced noise source identification methods” [M], 10th FKFS-Conference, Progress in Vehicle Aerodynamics and Thermal Management</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Senthooran, S., Powell, R., Choi, E.S., Cyr, S., 2015, “Computational prediction of interior noise for design variations on a simplified vehicle” [M], Internoise 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, M.-S., Pérot, F., Mann, A., Choi, E.-S., Cho, M.-H., Kim, J.-H., 2016, “Automotive engine cooling fan noise prediction using a Lattice Boltzmann based Mathod” [M], FISITA World Congress 2016, F2016-NVHG-024</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ffowcs Williams, J. E. and Hawkings, D. L., “Sound Generated by Turbulence and Surfaces in Arbitrary Motion,” [J] Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society, Vol. A264, No. 1151, 1969, pp. 321-342.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pérot , F., Freed, D., Mann, A., "Acoustic absorption of porous materials using LBM" [M], 19th AIAA/CEAS Aeroacoustics Conference, Aeroacoustics Conferences, AIAA 2013-2070.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun, C., Pérot, F., Zhang, R., Lew, P. T., Mann, A., Gupta, V., Freed, D. M., Staroselsky, I., Chen, H., 2015. “Lattice Boltzmann formulation for flows with acoustic porous media;” [J] Comptes Rendus Mécanique 343:10-11, 533-544.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
