<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830638</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830640</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>FOREIGN CAPITAL INFLOWS AND DOMESTIC SAVINGS IN THE PHILIPPINES / L'AFFLUX DE CAPITAUX ÉTRANGERS ET L'ÉPARGNE INTÉRIEURE AUX PHILIPPINES</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Maria Claret M.</given-names>
                  <surname>Mapalad</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1998</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>5</fpage>
         <lpage>25</lpage>
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830640"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper is an empirical analysis of the relation between foreign capital inflows and domestic savings. Existing studies which attempted to establish whether the nature of such relation is one of complementarity or substitutability leave the debate unsettled. Some attempts to explain the lack of consensus on the issue criticized these studies themselves for having methodological weaknesses. This paper proposes a model of domestic savings which attempts to correct for the shortcomings of earlier studies, namely, (1) the lack of attempt to correctly specify the domestic and foreign savings functions (the latter is usually assumed exogenous); (2) the possibility of inappropriately aggregating different forms of foreign capital inflows; and (3) the use of cross-country, cross-section data which assumes similarity in the domestic savings behavior of different countries. The model so constructed is applied using two-stage-least squares and annual Philippine data for the period 1952-1993. The findings suggest that foreign capital inflows do not have a significant direct impact, positive or negative, on domestic savings. This result holds regardless of whether foreign capital inflows are expressed as an aggregate measure or disaggregated into direct investment, portfolio investment, loans, and aid and grants. Higher and sustained economic growth is still the most effective way to increase domestic savings in the Philippines. In this regard, the model highlights the importance of maintaining macroeconomic stability through policies which aim at moderating domestic credit expansion and inflation and maintaining low (but presumably, positive) real interest rates. Cette étude est une analyse empirique de la relation entre l'afflux de capitaux étrangers et l'épargne intérieure. Les études jusqu'ici menées dans le but d'établir s'il s'agit d'une relation de complementarité ou de remplacement ont laissé la question ouverte et les tentatives d'expliquer le manque de consensus à ce sujet en ont souligné les faiblesses au point de vue méthodologique. Cette étude propose un modèle d'épargne intérieure qui essaie de corriger les points faibles des autres études, à savoir (1) le fait qu'ils n'aient pas essayé de spécifier correctement les fonctions épargne intérieure et étrangère (cette dernière étant normalement prise comme exogène), (2) la possibilité qu'ils aient aggrégé de façon impropre des formes différente d'afflux de capitaux étrangers et (3) l'utilisation de données relatives à plusieurs pays et à plusieurs couches de population, ce qui suppose une attitude égale ou semblable en matière d'épargne dans tous les pays et les couches concernés. Le modèle ainsi construit a été appliqué en utilisant des données annuelles et obtenues par la méthode des doubles moindres carrés relatives aux Philippines pour la période 1952-1993. Les résultats de l'étude suggèrent que l'afflux de capitaux étrangers n'a pas d'influence directe, positive ou négative, sur l'épargne intérieure. Cela vaut soit que l'affux de capitaux étrangers soit exprimé comme aggregat, soit qu'il soit désaggregé en investissement direct, investissement de portefeuille, prêts et aide et dons. Aux Philippines, le moyen le plus efficace pour augmenter l'épargne intérieure reste encore une croissance économique plus rapide et soutenue: À ce propos, le modèle fait ressortir l'importance du maintien de la stabilité macroéconomique par l'adoption de politiques visant à contrôler l'expansion du crédit intérieur et l'inflation et à garder les taux d'intérêts bas (mais probablement positifs).</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d43e135a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e142" publication-type="other">
Mapalad and Liverakos (1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e149a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e156" publication-type="other">
Fry (1993), pp. 25-30 and 41-45.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e163a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e170" publication-type="other">
Boyce (1990)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e176" publication-type="other">
Fry (1993)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e183a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e190" publication-type="other">
Fry (1993), pp. 18-21.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e198a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e205" publication-type="other">
Tanhueco (1994)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e212a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e219" publication-type="other">
Okuda (1990)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e225" publication-type="other">
Tanhueco (1994)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e232a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e239" publication-type="other">
Tanhueco (1994)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e245" publication-type="other">
Burkner (1980)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e251" publication-type="other">
Okuda (1990)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e258" publication-type="other">
Lim (1996)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e265a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e272" publication-type="other">
Burkner (1980)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e278" publication-type="other">
Lim (1996)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d43e294a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e298" publication-type="other">
Bowles Paul, "Foreign Aid and Domestic Savings in Less Developed Countries: Some Test for Causality", World
Development, Vol. 15, No. 6, 1987, pp. 789-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e308a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e312" publication-type="other">
Boyce James, "The Revolving Door? External Debt and Capital Flight: A Philippine Case Study", World Develop-
ment, Vol.20, No. 3, 1992, pp. 335-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e322a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e326" publication-type="other">
Burkner Hans-Paul, "Savings Mobilization Through Financial Development: A Study of Saving in the Philippines",
The Philippine Economic Journal Vol. 19, Nos. 3 &amp; 4,1980, pp. 451-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e336a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e340" publication-type="other">
Cuthbertson Keith, Stephen G. Hall and Mark P. Taylor, Applied Econometric Techniques, Harvester Wheatsheaf,
London, 1992.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e351a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e355" publication-type="other">
Dohner R. and P. Intal, Jr., "The Marcos Legacy; Economic Policy and Foreign Debt in the Philippines", in Sachs
and Collins (ed.) Developing Country Debt and Economic Performance, Vol.3, The University of Chicago
Press, Chicago, Illinois, 1989.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e368a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e372" publication-type="other">
Fabella Raul V., "Investment and the Allocation of Resources under Macroeconomic Instability", in Fabella and
Sakai (ed.), Resource Mobilization and Resource Use in the Philippines, Institute of Developing
Economies, Tokyo, 1994.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e385a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e389" publication-type="other">
Fry Maxwell J, Money, Interest, and Banking in Economic Development, Second Ed., Johns Hopkins University
Press, Baltimore and London, 1995.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e399a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e403" publication-type="other">
_, "Foreign Direct Investment in Southeast Asia: Differential Impacts", ISEAS Current Economic Affairs Series,
Institute of Southeast Asian Studies, 1993.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e413a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e417" publication-type="other">
Griffin Keith B., 'The Effect of Aid and Other Resource Transfers on Savings and Growth in Less Developed
Countries: A Comment", Economic Journal Vo\. 83, No. 331, 1973, pp. 863-6.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e427a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e431" publication-type="other">
_, "Foreign Capital, Domestic Savings and Economic Development", Bulletin Vol. 32, No. 2,1970, pp. 99-112.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e439a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e443" publication-type="other">
_and John L. Enos, "Foreign Assistance: Objectives and Consequences", Economic Development and
Cultural ChangeMol 18, No. 3, 1970, pp. 313-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e453a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e457" publication-type="other">
_and Ricardo Ffrench-Davis, "El Capital Extranjero y el Desarrollo", Revista Economia Vol. 3, No. 1 1964, pp.
11-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e467a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e471" publication-type="other">
International Monetary Fund, Balance of Payments Yearbook, Washington, D.C., various issues.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e478a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e482" publication-type="other">
_, International Financial Statistics Yearbook, Washington, D.C., 1972 and 1995.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e489a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e493" publication-type="other">
Islam Azizul, "Mobilization of Domestic Financial Resources for Development: The Asian Experience", Research
and Information System for the Non-Aligned and Other Developing Countries Occasional Paper No. 49,
.. New Delhi, 1996.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e506a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e510" publication-type="other">
Lim Joseph Y., "The Effects of Monetary Policy on Savings and Investments", in Fabella and ito (ed.), Financial
Sector Issues in the Philippines, Institute of Developing Economies, Tokyo, 1996.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e521a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e525" publication-type="other">
Mapalad Maria Claret M., "The Causal Relation Between Foreign and Domestic Savings in Four Southeast Asian
Economies", School of Economics Discussion Paper No. 9609, University of the Philippines, Diliman,
Quezon City, 1996.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e538a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e542" publication-type="other">
_and Petros K. Liverakos, "The Negative Correlation between Foreign and Domestic Savings", Philippine
Review of Business and Economics, Vol. 35, No. 1,1997, pp. 38-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e552a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e556" publication-type="other">
Mason Andrew, "An Extension of the Life-Cycle Model and Its Application to Population Growth and Aggregate
Saving", East-West Center, Honolulu, 1981.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e566a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e570" publication-type="other">
Morriset Jacques, "The Impact of Foreign Capital Inflows on Domestic Savings Reexamined: The Case of
Argentina", World Development Vol. 17, No. 11,1989, pp. 1709-15.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e580a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e584" publication-type="other">
Okuda Hidenobu, "Financial Factors in Economic Development: A Study of the Financial Liberalization Policy in the
Philippines", The Developing Economies Vol. 28, No. 3,1990, pp. 240-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e594a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e598" publication-type="other">
Papanek Gustav F., "A Reply to Dr. Griffin and Professor Newlyn", Economic Journal'Vol. 83, No. 331,1973, pp.
870-4.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e609a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e613" publication-type="other">
_, "The Effect of Aid and Other Resource Transfers on Savings and Growth in Less Developed Countries",
Economic Journal Vo\. 82, No. 327, 1973, pp. 934-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e623a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e627" publication-type="other">
Rahman Md. Anisur, "Foreign Capital and Domestic Savings: A Test of Haavelmo's Hypothesis with Cross-Country
Data", Review of Economics and Statistics Vol. 50, No. 1,1968, pp. 137-8.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e637a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e641" publication-type="other">
Rana Pradumma B. and J. Malcolm Dowling, Jr., "The Impact of Foreign Capital on Growth: Evidences from Asian
Developing Countries", The Developing Economies Vol. 26, No. 1,1989, pp. 3-11.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e651a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e655" publication-type="other">
Snyder Donald, "Foreign Aid and Domestic Savings: A Spurious Correlation?", Economic Development and Cultural
Change Vol. 39, No. 1, 1990, pp. 175-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e665a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e669" publication-type="other">
Tanhueco Honorina B., "Determinants of Savings and Investment in the Philippines", in Fabella and Sakai (ed.),
Resource Mobilization and Resource Use in the Philippines, Institute of Developing Economies, Tokyo,
1994.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e682a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e686" publication-type="other">
Vos Rob, "Savings, Investment and Foreign Capital Flows: Have Capital Markets Become More Integrated?",
Journal of Development Studies Vol. 24, No. 3,1988, pp. 310-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e697a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e701" publication-type="other">
Weisskopf Thomas E., "The Impact of Foreign Capital Inflow on Domestic Savings in Underdeveloped Countries",
Journal of International Economics Vol. 2, No. 1,1972, pp. 25-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e711a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e715" publication-type="other">
White Howard, "The Macroeconomic Impact of Development Aid: A Critical Review," Journal of Development
Studies Vol. 28, No. 2, 1992a, pp. 163-240.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e725a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e729" publication-type="other">
_, "What Do We Know about Aid's Macroeconomic Impact? An Overview of the Aid Effectiveness Debate",
Journal of International Development, Vol. 4, No. 2,1992b, pp. 121-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e739a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e743" publication-type="other">
The World Bank, World Debt Tables, Vol. 2, Washington, D.C Various issues.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


