<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830132</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830134</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>SAVINGS AND LOANS COOPERATIVES IN RURAL AREAS OF DEVELOPING COUNTRIES: RECENT PERFORMANCE AND POTENTIAL / L'ÉPARGNE ET LES COOPÉRATIVES DE PRÊTS DANS LES ZONES RURALES DES PAYS EN VOIE DE DÉVELOPPEMENT: LES RÉCENTES EXPÉRIENCES ET LES POTENTIALITÉS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Carlos E.</given-names>
                  <surname>Cuevas</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1988</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>5</fpage>
         <lpage>17</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830134"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper relies upon data from four case studies to analyze some of the main indicators of credit-union performance and draw implications about their potential as an institutional basis for the development of rural financial systems. The cases reviewed are Cameroon, Rwanda and Togo in Africa and Honduras in Latin America. The growth rates of credit-union savings and loans outstanding are compared against the growth of quasi-money and private sector credit in the economy. The findings indicate that cooperative savings grow in general faster than quasi-money in the economy, thus increasing the relative importance of credit unions in the country's monetary system. This trend is even more visible when comparing the lending performance of credit unions with the growth of private sector credit. The results presented suggest that cooperative organizations can be a dynamic form of financial institution, and are likely to substantially increase access to financial services in rural areas of low income countries. Cet article se base sur des données tirées de quatre études de cas pour analyser, sur la base des indicateurs plus appropriés, les résultats des unions de crédit et pour tirer des conclusions sur leur capacité de développer les systèmes financiers ruraux. Les pays considérés dans l'article sont le Cameroun, le Rwanda et le Togo en Afrique et l'Honduras en Amérique latine. Les taux de croissance de l'épargne et des prêts des unions de crédit sont comparés avec l'augmentation de la monnaie (quasi-monnaie) et du crédit du secteur privé dans l'économie. Les données indiquent qu'en général, l'épargne coopérative croît à un taux plus élevé que la quasi-monnaie: de cette façon, l'importance relative des unions de crédit dans le système monétaire du pays se trouve renforcée. La tendance mentionnée est encore plus visible si on compare les résultats des prêts des unions de crédit avec la croissance du crédit du secteur privé. Les résultats présentés suggèrent que les organisations coopératives peuvent être une forme dynamique d'institutions financières et très probablement faciliteront l'accès aux services financiers dans les zones rurales des pays à faible revenu.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d36e172a1310">
            <label>*</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e179" publication-type="other">
"Viabilidade Economica e Insergao no Meio Rural das Cooperativas Agncolas Por-
tuguesas" Lisbon, Portugal, July 3-4, 1987.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e189a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e196" publication-type="other">
Bureau d'Orientation des Banques Populaires du Rwanda, Rapport Annuel, 1984.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e203a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e210" publication-type="other">
Mahon (1986).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e217a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e224" publication-type="other">
Poyo (1985)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e230" publication-type="other">
Poyo (1987).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d36e246a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e250" publication-type="other">
Bureau d'Orientation des Banques Populaires du Rwanda, Rapport AnnueI 1984.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e257a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e261" publication-type="other">
DeLancey, Virginia, "Report on The Base-line Data Survey for the CamCCUL/WOCCU/USAID Development
Project in Cameroon". World Council of Credit Unions, July 1983.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e271a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e275" publication-type="other">
FUCEC-Togo, "Development of the Togo Credit Union Association, Progress Report No. 14", March 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e282a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e286" publication-type="other">
Gadway, John F., "The Cameroon Credit Union Development Project. 1986 Baseline Data Survey". World Council
of Credit Unions, March 1986.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e297a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e301" publication-type="other">
International Monetary Fund, International Financial Statistics, various issues.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e308a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e312" publication-type="other">
Mahon, Dean, "Two Case Studies: Cameroon and Togo". World Reporter, World Council of Credit Unions,
September 1986.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e322a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e326" publication-type="other">
Poyo, Jeffrey, "Development without Dependency: Financial Repression and Deposit Mobilization among the
Rural Credit Unions in Honduras". Unpublished Ph.D. Dissertation, Syracuse University, September 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e336a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e340" publication-type="other">
Poyo, Jeffrey, "Represion y Liberalizacion Financiera en las Cooperativas de Ahorro y Credito en la Republica
Dominicana". Programa de Finanzas Agricolas Ohio State University y Programa de Banca y Finanzas
INCAE, 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e353a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e357" publication-type="other">
World Council of Credit Unions, Statistical Report 1986.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


