<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">finamana</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j100419</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Financial Management</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Financial Management Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00463892</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">1755053X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">3665941</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Topics in Real Options and Applications</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Real Options and Game-Theoretic Approach to Corporate Investment Strategy under Competition</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>Han T. J. Smit</string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>L. A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Ankum</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date>
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>1993</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i284589</issue-id>
         <fpage>241</fpage>
         <lpage>250</lpage>
         <page-range>241-250</page-range>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1993 Financial Management Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/3665941"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>An investment strategy encompasses a sequence of tactical investment projects, of which several may yield a low return when considered in isolation. Some low-return investment projects can actually be seen as the first links in a chain of subsequent investment decisions. The value of these projects does not derive so much from their expected cash inflows but rather from the option to invest in a follow-up project for future commercial exploitation. For example, an R&amp;D project, the development of a new technology, or entry into a new geographical market may create future investment opportunities. In strategy, these projects are often compared with options for future company growth. Standard forecasting of the expected cash inflows implicitly assumes investing in the follow-up project, or does not take properly into account the value of flexibility to reject the follow-up project if events turn out to be unfavorable. Application of option theory can be used as an analytical tool to evaluate such flexible projects and to support the overall investment strategy. We here consider the timing of the follow-up project analogous to the timing of the exercise of a call option on a dividend-paying stock. In this investment strategy, decisions involving the creation of capacity may be postponed so that management can decide not to invest if market demand turns out to be unfavorable. On the other hand, deferral also has disadvantages since during the postponement period the firm misses the net operating cash inflows. However, the call option analogy must be seen in the context of market structure. Emerging competition or rivalry may create an incentive to invest early, as postponement of the follow-up project may result in project value erosion. This is particularly so if early investment would preempt competitive entry. This paper casts the real options approach for project timing in a microeconomic framework to analyze aspects of competition. Using game-theoretic principles, we propose various investment tactics in an oligopolistic market. Simple numerical examples illustrate solving the timing problem under competition. Given the complexity of real-world problems, we provide a prototype approach for investment timing that practitioners can adjust to their particular application. We use the expected economic rents or excess profits for forecasting the operating cash inflows. Barriers to entry or a distinct competitive advantage over existing competitors (e.g., economies of scale and scope, absolute cost advantages, or product differentiation) are the real source of economic rents. The firm therefore needs to identify those markets in which it has a temporary or permanent competitive advantage, and concentrate investment in these areas. Understanding potential barriers to entry helps identify these markets and potential value-creating investment opportunities. One strategy, for example, will be directed towards increasing capacity because of economies of scale, or broadening when economies of scope are important in the market. An investment opportunity under perfect competition is like a "public good" of the whole industry. Expected economic rents attract new entrants to the market, so new entrants will diminish returns until expected and required returns are equal. Absence of a structural competitive advantage may thus result in a tendency to invest early to preclude this erosion of value. An investment opportunity in a monopoly is exclusive, so during the postponement period there is no expected loss in value due to competition. Compared to perfect competition, there is a stronger tendency under monopoly to postpone follow-up projects with relatively low net present values. On the other hand, an exclusive project with large present value creates a tendency to invest early. Oligopoly is between these extremes in that the timing of a project will be influenced by the behavior of individual competitors. Where firms in the industry have asymmetric market power, early investment could preempt entry. The investment tactic in the follow-up project will be influenced by the value of the project in relation to market uncertainty and the threat of preemption. We use game-theoretic principles combined with option theory for setting an investment strategy and, based on the reaction of competitors, we propose various investment tactics.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d176e163a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e170" publication-type="journal">
M.J. Brennan and E.S. Schwartz, "Evaluating Natural Resource
Investments," Journal of Business (April 1985), pp. 135-157.<object-id pub-id-type="jstor">10.2307/2352967</object-id>
               <fpage>135</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d176e186a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e193" publication-type="journal">
J.C. Cox, S.A. Ross, and M. Rubinstein, "Option Pricing: A Simpli-
fied Approach," Journal of Financial Economics (September 1979),
pp. 229-263.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Cox</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <issue>September</issue>
               <fpage>229</fpage>
               <source>Journal of Financial Economics</source>
               <year>1979</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d176e228a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e235" publication-type="journal">
W.K. Hall, "Survival Strategies in a Hostile Environment," Harvard
Business Review (September-October 1980), pp. 75-85.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Hall</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <issue>September</issue>
               <fpage>75</fpage>
               <source>Harvard Business Review</source>
               <year>1980</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d176e267a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e274" publication-type="journal">
A.G.Z. Kemna and T.F.C. Vorst, "Options and Optimal Investment
Timing," Finance and Investment State of the Art, 1987, pp. 107-123.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kemna</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <fpage>107</fpage>
               <source>Finance and Investment State of the Art</source>
               <year>1987</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d176e304a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e311" publication-type="journal">
W.C. Kester, "Today's Options for Tomorrow's Growth," Harvard
Business Review (March-April 1984), pp. 153-160.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kester</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <issue>March</issue>
               <fpage>153</fpage>
               <source>Harvard Business Review</source>
               <year>1984</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d176e343a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e350" publication-type="journal">
S. Majd and R. Pindyck, "Time to Build, Option Value, and Invest-
ment Decisions," Journal of Financial Economics (March 1987), pp.
7-27.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Majd</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <issue>March</issue>
               <fpage>7</fpage>
               <source>Journal of Financial Economics</source>
               <year>1987</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d176e385a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e392" publication-type="book">
S. Mason and R.C. Merton, "The Role of Contingent Claims Analy-
sis in Corporate Finance," in Recent Advances in Corporate Finance,
E.I. Altman and M. Subrahmanyan (eds.), Homewood, IL, R.D.
Irwin, 1985.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Mason</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <comment content-type="section">The Role of Contingent Claims Analysis in Corporate Finance</comment>
               <source>Recent Advances in Corporate Finance</source>
               <year>1985</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d176e427a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e434" publication-type="journal">
R.L. McDonald and D.R. Siegel, "The Value of Waiting to Invest,"
Quarterly Journal of Economics (November 1986), pp. 707-727.<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/1884175</object-id>
               <fpage>707</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d176e450a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e457" publication-type="journal">
S.C. Myers, "Finance Theory and Financial Strategy," Midland
Corporate Finance Journal (Spring 1987), pp. 6-13.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Myers</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <issue>Spring</issue>
               <fpage>6</fpage>
               <source>Midland Corporate Finance Journal</source>
               <year>1987</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d176e489a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e496" publication-type="journal">
S.C. Myers and S. Majd, "Abandonment Value and Project Life,"
Advances in Futures and Options Research, 1990, pp. 1-21.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Myers</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <fpage>1</fpage>
               <source>Advances in Futures and Options Research</source>
               <year>1990</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d176e526a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e533" publication-type="book">
A.C. Shapiro, Modern Corporate Finance, Macmillan Publishing
Company, 1991.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Shapiro</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <source>Modern Corporate Finance</source>
               <year>1991</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d176e558a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e565" publication-type="other">
L. Trigeorgis, "Valuing Real Investment Opportunities: An Options
Approach to Strategic Capital Budgeting," Unpublished Doctoral
Dissertation, Harvard University, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d176e578a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e585" publication-type="journal">
L. Trigeorgis, "Anticipated Competitive Entry and Early Preemptive
Investment in Deferrable Projects," Journal of Economics and Busi-
ness (May 1991), pp. 143-156.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Trigeorgis</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <issue>May</issue>
               <fpage>143</fpage>
               <source>Journal of Economics and Business</source>
               <year>1991</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d176e620a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d176e627" publication-type="book">
J. Tirole, The Theory oflndustrial Organization, MIT Press, 1990.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Tirole</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <source>The Theory oflndustrial Organization</source>
               <year>1990</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
