<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284949</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Internal Combustion Engine - Automatic Transmission Matching for Next Generation Power Transfer Technology Development in Automotive Applications</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Robinette</surname>
                  <given-names>Darrell</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Singh</surname>
                  <given-names>Tejinder</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>General Motors Co.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>September 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284904</issue-id>
         <fpage>1863</fpage>
         <lpage>1880</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284949"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Development of the next generation internal combustion engines and automatic transmissions for automotive applications is a mandatory powertrain engineering activity required now and in the coming years to meet forthcoming global emissions regulations. This paper details a preliminary investigation into possible synergies for fuel consumption reduction considering emerging automotive technologies integrated into the next generation combustion engine and automatic transmission architectures. A range of hypothetical gasoline engines were created and paired with a generalized set of step gear automatic transmissions designed to meet the performance requirements of high volume longitudinal full size truck application. These designs were then run through a design of experiments orthogonal array for prediction of fuel consumption on the WLTP test schedule and stand still acceleration to 100 kph. Results from the design of experiments agrees with previous investigations with regards to required transmission gearing selection even with profoundly different engine brake specific fuel consumption maps. New automatic transmission concepts were then developed with the objective to alter the paradigm for step gear automatic transmissions. A number of unique automatic transmission concepts are discussed at length for longitudinal applications, including architecture and functionality, that match the performance attributes of the next generation gasoline engines. These designs represent a reduction in fuel consumption from current 6 speed planetary technology at a minimum of 2% while maintaining equivalent or better acceleration characteristics.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Environmental Protection Agency, “Computer Simulation of Light-Duty Vehicle Technologies for Greenhouse Gas Emission Reduction in the 2020-2025 Timeframe,” EPA-420-R-11-020, Dec. 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greiner, J. and Grumbach, M., "Automatic Transmission Systems Beyond 2020 - Challenges and Competition," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1273, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1273.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greiner, J., Grumbach, M., Dick, A., and Sasse, C., "Advancement in NVH- and Fuel-Saving Transmission and Driveline Technologies," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1087, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1087.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lemazurier, L., Shidore, N., Kim, N., Moawad, A. et al., "Impact of Advanced Engine and Powertrain Technologies on Engine Operation and Fuel Consumption for Future Vehicles," SAE Technical Paper 2015- 01-0978, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0978.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robinette, D., "A DFSS Approach to Determine Automatic Transmission Gearing Content for Powertrain-Vehicle System Integration," SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 7(3):1138-1154, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014- 01-1774.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robinette, D. and Wehrwein, D., "Automatic Transmission Gear Ratio Optimization and Monte Carlo Simulation of Fuel Consumption with Parasitic Loss Uncertainty," SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 8(1):45-62, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1145.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fischer, R., Ellinger R., Kapus, P., Erjawetz, K., et. al., “7/8/9/XXSpeeds or is 4 Enough?,” Panel Presentation at 7th International CTI Symposium, May 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walzer, P., "Future Power Plants For Cars," SAE Technical Paper 2001- 01-3192, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3192.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lecointe, B. and Monnier, G., "Downsizing a Gasoline Engine Using Turbocharging with Direct Injection," SAE Technical Paper 2003-01- 0542, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0542.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bandel, W., Fraidl, G., Kapus, P., Sikinger, H. et al., "The Turbocharged GDI Engine: Boosted Synergies for High Fuel Economy Plus Ultra-low Emission," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1266, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coltman, D., Turner, J., Curtis, R., Blake, D. et al., "Project Sabre: A Close-Spaced Direct Injection 3-Cylinder Engine with Synergistic Technologies to Achieve Low CO2 Output," SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):129-146, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kirwan, J., Shost, M., Roth, G., and Zizelman, J., "3-Cylinder Turbocharged Gasoline Direct Injection: A High Value Solution for Low CO2 and NOx Emissions," SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):355-371, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0590.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W., Fraser, N., Parsons, P., and Toulson, E., "A Turbulent Jet Ignition Pre-Chamber Combustion System for Large Fuel Economy Improvements in a Modern Vehicle Powertrain," SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):20-37, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1457.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stanton, D., "Systematic Development of Highly Efficient and Clean Engines to Meet Future Commercial Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Regulations," SAE Int. J. Engines 6(3):1395-1480, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2421.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shahed, S. and Bauer, K., "Parametric Studies of the Impact of Turbocharging on Gasoline Engine Downsizing," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1347-1358, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1472.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lavoie, G., Ortiz-Soto, E., Babajimopoulos, A., Martz, B., and Assanis, D., “Thermodynamic Sweet Spot for High-Efficiency, Dilute, Boosted Gasoline Engines,” International Journal of Engine Research June 2013 14: 260-278, doi:10.1177/1468087412455372.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T., "Review of Vehicular Emissions Trends," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(3):1152-1167, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Al-Hasan, N., Beer, J., Ehrhard, J., Lorenz, T. et al., "Charging Technologies for CO2 Optimization by Millerization," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1250, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1250.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malliaris, A., Withjack, E., and Gould, H., "Simulated Sensitivities of Auto Fuel Economy, Performance and Emissions," SAE Technical Paper 760157, 1976, doi:10.4271/760157.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kluger, M. and Greenbaum, J., "Automatic Transmission Efficiency Characteristics and Gearbox Torque Loss Data Regression Techniques," SAE Technical Paper 930907, 1993, doi:10.4271/930907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Phlips, P., "Analytic Engine and Transmission Models for Vehicle Fuel Consumption Estimation," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 8(2):423-440, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robinette, D., Gibson, G., Szpara, D., and Tehansky, E., "Performance Characterization of Automatic Transmission Upshifts with Reduced Shift Times," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(3):1359-1373, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015- 01-1086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baglione, M., Duty, M., and Pannone, G., "Vehicle System Energy Analysis Methodology and Tool for Determining Vehicle Subsystem Energy Supply and Demand," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0398, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0398.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Le Guen, D., Weck, T., Balihe, A., and Verbeke, B., "Definition of Gearshift Pattern: Innovative Optimization Procedures Using System Simulation," SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):412-431, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011- 01-0395.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schneider, E., Muller, J., Leesch, M. and Resch, R., “Nine-Speed Hybrid Dual Clutch Transmission for High Performance Front-Transverse Powertrains,” ATZ, Vol. 72, pp. 26-30, June 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hellenbroich, G.., Ruschhaupt, J., Duidam C., “Compact Seven- and Ten-Speed Dual Clutch Transmissions,” ATZ, Vol. 5, pp. 38-42, May 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rieger, W., Recker, P., and Grumpoltsberger, G., “Double Clutch Transmission,” US Patent Application, US20100257961 A1, October 14, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rieger, W., Recker, P., and Grumpoltsberger, G., “Double Clutch Transmission,” US Patent, US8365625 B2, February. 5, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mellet, E. W., Ross, C. S., and Wittkopp, S. H., “Dual Clutch Multi- Speed Transmission,” U.S. Patent, US8733194 B2, May 27, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robinette, D., "Performance Characterization of a Triple Input Clutch, Layshaft Automatic Transmission Using Energy Analysis," SAE Int. J. Engines 6(4):1984-1994, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-9042.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
