<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465699</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465702</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Corporate Investment and Stock Market Listing: A Puzzle?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
                  <surname>Asker</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Joan</given-names>
                  <surname>Farre-Mensa</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alexander</given-names>
                  <surname>Ljungqvist</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>342</fpage>
         <lpage>390</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465702"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We investigate whether short-termism distorts the investment decisions of stock market-listed firms. To do so, we compare the investment behavior of observably similar public and private firms, using a new data source on private U.S. firms and assuming for identification that closely held private firms are subject to fewer short-termist pressures. Our results show that compared with private firms, public firms invest substantially less and are less responsive to changes in investment opportunities, especially in industries in which stock prices are most sensitive to earnings news. These findings are consistent with the notion that short-termist pressures distort investment decisions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d5010610e312a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e321" publication-type="other">
Writing in the Harvard Business Review, Barton and Wiseman (2014), global managing director at McKinsey &amp;
Co. and CEO of the Canada Pension Plan Investment Board, respectively, argue that "the ongoing short-termism
in the business world is undermining corporate investment, holding back economic growth." The Kay Review of
U.K. Equity Markets and Long-Term Decision-Making, published in 2012, echoes this sentiment, while similar
points have been made in The Economist ("The profits prophet," October 5, 2013) and the Financial Times
("Corporate investment: A mysterious divergence," July 24, 2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e344a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e351" publication-type="other">
Most studies of investment dynamics use firm-level data from Compustat and so focus on public firms. The
exceptions are studies that use plant-level data from the Census of Manufactures (Caballero et al. 1995; Cooper
and Haltiwanger 2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e364a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e371" publication-type="other">
The denominators in these estimates are from the National Income and Product Accounts
(http://www.bea.gov/national) and the Statistics of U.S. Businesses (http://www.census.gov/econ/susb).
The numerators use CRSP-Compustat data for U.S. firms listed on the NYSE, AMEX, or Nasdaq. Sales data are
from 2007, the most recent year for which they are available.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e387a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e394" publication-type="other">
Another paper that, like us, focuses on the extensive margin is Baghai (2012), who shows that public firms in
the food retail industry respond to short-term performance pressures by increasing prices relative to their private
competitors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e408a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e415" publication-type="other">
This figure does not include the self-employed (source: http://www.census.gov/econ/susb).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e422a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e429" publication-type="other">
In Brau and Fawcett's (2006) survey of large private firms, only 10.5% of firms had considered going public.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e436a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e443" publication-type="other">
The firms in S age works are either standalone companies or the parent companies of groups of privately held
firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e453a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e460" publication-type="other">
Commercial users of the Sageworks database only have access to data aggregated by industry and region. This
alleviates potential disclosure concerns on the part of the private firms. Only a few academic researchers, ourselves
included, have had confidential access to an anonymized version of the underlying firm-by-firm data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e473a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e480" publication-type="other">
Sageworks is free of survivorship bias. If a firm goes public, dies, or switches to an accounting firm that does
not cooperate with Sageworks, its time series will end, but all of its historical data remains in the database.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e490a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e497" publication-type="other">
Our results are robust to using finer industry classifications and to imposing tighter calipers on the maximum
size difference.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e508a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e515" publication-type="other">
As Smith and Todd (2005) point out, matching with replacement involves a trade-off between bias and efficiency.
Bias is reduced as higher quality matches are generated, but efficiency is reduced as fewer distinct observations
are used.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e528a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e535" publication-type="other">
The change in noncurrent assets captures investment in both fixed and intangible assets. Another form of
investment, R&amp;D, is usually expensed and so does not affect intangibles. We cannot model investment in R&amp;D
as Sageworks does not break out R&amp;D spending. We will report evidence showing it is highly unlikely that our
results are driven by this data limitation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e551a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e558" publication-type="other">
The purpose of matching is not to eliminate all observable differences between public and private firms but
to make firms comparable along the dimensions thought to affect the outcome variable of interest (here:
investment). Overmatching on dimensions unrelated to the outcome variable of interest results in samples that are
unrepresentative of their respective populations. In other words, we can make matched firms arbitrarily similar to
each other on arbitrarily many dimensions, but as we do so, the firms that end up in the matched sample become
ever less representative of their respective groups. See Heckman, LaLonde, and Smith (1999) for an exhaustive
discussion of this point.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e584a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e591" publication-type="other">
Contrast this with the fact that the average (median) public-firm CEO in our sample owns a mere 3.1% (0.66%)
of his firm's equity, and the average (median) public firm has 35,550 (1,210) shareholders.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e601a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e608" publication-type="other">
Sageworks does not report R&amp;D data, so we cannot test for differences in R&amp;D spending. Moreover, Sageworks
firms are anonymous, so we cannot obtain information about their patenting activity. However, Bernstein's
(Forthcoming) results suggest that including innovation is unlikely to close the investment gap between public
and private firms: he finds that going public leaves a firm's scale of innovation unchanged (as measured by the
number of patents), while reducing the novelty of its innovations (as measured by patent citations).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e627a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e634" publication-type="other">
To match on other variables besides industry and size, we construct a propensity score based on size and additional
matching variables. We then adapt the matching algorithm described in Section 2.2 as follows: for each public
firm, we find the private firm with the closest propensity score that operates in the same four-digit NAICS
industry, imposing a 0.05 caliper.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e651a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e658" publication-type="other">
All measures of investment, along with all other continuous variables used in the paper, are winsorized 0.5% in
each tail to reduce the impact of outliers. Results are robust to alternative cutoffs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e668a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e675" publication-type="other">
The variable Z/A is ROA. Prior work shows that standard proxies for investment opportunities are not,
as neoclassical theory predicts, a sufficient statistic for investment and that ROA correlates positively with
investment. The latter is often interpreted as a sign of financing constraints (Fazzari, Hubbard, and Petersen
1988), though some disagree (Kaplan, and Zingales 1997). While we are agnostic about the debate surrounding
its interpretation, we follow the literature by conditioning on ROA.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e694a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e701" publication-type="other">
Recall that all firms in Sageworks are unlisted and all firms in Compustat are listed. Thus, when comparing
differences in investment levels between public and private firms, we cannot include firm fixed effects.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e711a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e718" publication-type="other">
Recall that all firms in Sageworks are unlisted and all firms in Compustat are listed. Thus, our fixed effects
specifications cannot include a public-firm indicator, though we can let the effect of investment opportunities or
ROA vary by listing status.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e731a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e738" publication-type="other">
Not surprisingly, the public firms that end up in our matched sample are small by public-firm standards: 71.3%
come from decile 10, 12.4% from decile 9, and 16.3% from the remaining eight deciles.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e748a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e755" publication-type="other">
See Grullon, Hund, and Weston (2013) for related evidence that the investment behavior of the largest public
firms differs markedly from that of smaller public firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e766a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e773" publication-type="other">
However, the evidence in Figure 7 runs counter to this concern. It shows that investment sensitivity is highest
among the largest public firms, which are arguably least likely to be financially constrained.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e783a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e790" publication-type="other">
Farre-Mensa and Ljungqvist (2014) show that the top quartile by size of Sageworks private firms are not
financially constrained. Because 96% of the private firms in our matched sample come from this quartile, it
is unlikely that our results are driven by differences in financial constraints.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e803a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e810" publication-type="other">
This test limits private firms to C Corps, as other legal forms are not subject to corporate taxes in most states.
The Internet Appendix exploits this fact as an indirect validity test of our tax identification strategy. If corporate
tax changes capture changes in firms' investment opportunities rather than, say, reflecting changes in a state's
economic environment, they should have no effect on the investment behavior of non-C Corps. This is precisely
what we find; see Column 4 in Table IA. 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e829a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e836" publication-type="other">
The manager may care about the current stock price because he intends to sell some of his stockholdings (as
suggested by Stein 1989 and confirmed empirically by Bhojraj et al. 2009) or because he fears losing his job in the
event of a hostile takeover (Shleifer and Vishny 1990; Stein 1988). Another possibility is that some shareholders
may incentivize the manager to pursue short-termist actions that increase the firm's stock price in the short term
(albeit at the expense of long-run fundamental value) in the hope of selling the stock in the future to potentially
overoptimistic investors (see Bolton, Scheinkman, and Xiong 2006 for such a model).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e859a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e866" publication-type="other">
While CAPEX is not expensed, it does depress earnings by increasing depreciation. Graham, Harvey, and
Rajgopal (2005) report survey evidence that managers avoid missing earnings-per-share (EPS) targets by cutting
CAPEX to reduce "depreciation charges to earnings." Almeida, Fos, and Kronlund (2013) emphasize that, in
addition to increasing the numerator in EPS by reducing depreciation, cutting CAPEX frees up cash for share
repurchases, which can reduce the denominator in EPS.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e885a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e892" publication-type="other">
Following our approach, Gilje and Taillard (2013) show that natural gas producers have a below-median ERC,
which in turn could explain why the public firms in their sample appear not to invest myopically.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e903a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e910" publication-type="other">
Another agency problem that might distort the investment decisions of public firms is empire building. However,
if this were a prevalent distortion among public firms, they would invest more than private ones, the opposite of
what we find in Tables 2 and 3. An alternative hypothesis that might a priori explain why public and private firms
invest differently is the possibility that private firms are financially constrained. However, recall from Section
3.2.2 that we found no support for the notion that private firms'-higher investment and investment sensitivity
are the result of financial constraints. Other channels that may explain the observed differences in investment
behavior between public and private firms include the idea that public firms are weighed down by rules and
regulations designed to protect minority shareholders or that private firms are capital inefficient or inexperienced
at making investment decisions. None of these alternative channels seems to predict our Table 7 findings.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e942a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e949" publication-type="other">
According to Chemmanur, Krishnan, and Nandy (2011), the median VC-backed firm is around two years old
when it first receives VC funding.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e959a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e966" publication-type="other">
VC supply varies considerably over time: the correlation between a state's VC supply in 1985 (the year when
VC supply is measured for the median firm in our sample) and 2002 (our first panel year) is only 0.24.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e976a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e983" publication-type="other">
Because VC supply does not vary within-firm, Equation (2) is estimated with industry fixed effects instead of
firm fixed effects.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d5010610e993a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1000" publication-type="other">
Note that owing to the presence of interaction effects in Column 3, the public-firm indicator is not informative:
it captures the mean difference in investment levels for public and private firms with zero sales growth and zero
ROA.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d5010610e1022a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1026" publication-type="other">
Acemoglu, D., S. Johnson, and J. Robinson. 2009. The colonial origins of comparative development: An empirical
investigation. American Economic Review 91:1369-401.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1036a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1040" publication-type="other">
Almeida, H., V. Fos, and M. Kronlund. 2013. The real effects of share repurchases. Working Paper, University
of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1050a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1054" publication-type="other">
Angrist, J., and J.-S. Pischke. 2008. Mostly harmless econometrics: An empiricist's companion. Princeton:
Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1064a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1068" publication-type="other">
Arellano, M., and S. Bond. 1991. Some tests of specification for panel data: Monte Carlo evidence and an
application to employment equations. Review of Economic Studies 58:277-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1079a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1083" publication-type="other">
Baber, W., P. Fairfield, and J. Haggard. 1991. The effect of concern about reported income on discretionary
spending decisions: The case of research and development. Accounting Review 66:818-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1093a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1097" publication-type="other">
Baghai, R. 2012. Equity ownership and product prices. Working Paper, Stockholm School of Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1104a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1108" publication-type="other">
Ball, R., and P. Brown. 1968. An empirical evaluation of accounting income numbers. Journal of Accounting
Research 6:159-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1118a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1122" publication-type="other">
Barton, D., and M. Wiseman. 2014. Focusing capital on the long term. Harvard Business Review (January-
February):48-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1132a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1136" publication-type="other">
Bartov, E., D. Givoloy, and C. Hayn. 2002. The rewards to meeting or beating earnings expectations. Journal of
Accounting and Economics 33:173-204.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1146a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1150" publication-type="other">
Beaver, W. 1968. The information content of annual earnings announcements. Journal of Accounting Research
6:67-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1161a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1165" publication-type="other">
Bernstein, S. Forthcoming. Does going public affect innovation? Journal of Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1172a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1176" publication-type="other">
Bertrand, M., and S. Mullainathan. 2003. Enjoying the quiet life? Corporate governance and managerial
preferences. Journal of Political Economy 111:1043-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1186a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1190" publication-type="other">
Bharath, S., A. Dittmar, and J. Sivadasan. 2014. Do going private transactions affect plant productivity? Review
of Financial Studies 27:1929-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1200a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1204" publication-type="other">
Bhide, A. 1993. The hidden cost of stock market liquidity. Journal of Financial Economics 34:34-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1211a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1215" publication-type="other">
Bhojraj, S., P. Hribar, M. Picconi, and J. Mclnnis. 2009. Making sense of cents: An examination of firms that
marginally miss or beat analyst forecasts. Journal of Finance 64:2361-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1225a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1229" publication-type="other">
Bloom, N., S. Bond, and J. van Reenen. 2007. Uncertainty and investment dynamics. Review of Economic Studies
74:391-415.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1240a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1244" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R., and S. Bond. 1998. Initial conditions and moment restrictions in dynamic panel data models. Journal
of Econometrics 87:115-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1254a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1258" publication-type="other">
Bolton, P., J. Scheinkman, and W. Xiong. 2006. Executive compensation and short-termist behavior in speculative
markets. Review of Economic Studies 73:577-610.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1268a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1272" publication-type="other">
Bond, S., and J. van Reenen. 2007. Microeconometric models of investment and employment. In Handbook of
econometrics, vol. 6. Eds. J. Heckman, and E. Learner. Amsterdam: Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1282a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1286" publication-type="other">
Brau, J., and S. Fawcett. 2006. Initial public offerings: An analysis of theory and practice. Journal of Finance
59:399-436.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1296a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1300" publication-type="other">
Brav, O. 2009. Access to capital, capital structure, and the funding of the firm. Journal of Finance 64:263-308.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1307a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1311" publication-type="other">
Brown, J., S. Fazzari, and B. Petersen. 2009. Financing innovation and growth: Cash flow, external equity, and
the 1990s R&amp;D boom. Journal of Finance 64:151-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1322a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1326" publication-type="other">
Bushee, B. 1998. The influence of institutional investors on myopic R&amp;D investment behavior. Accounting
Review 73:305-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1336a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1340" publication-type="other">
. 2001. Do institutional investors prefer near-term earnings over long-run value? Contemporary
Accounting Research 18:207-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1350a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1354" publication-type="other">
Caballero, R., E. Engel, J. Haltiwanger, M. Woodford, and R. Hall. 1995. Plant-level adjustment and aggregate
investment dynamics. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 26:1-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1364a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1368" publication-type="other">
Campello, M., and J. Graham. 2013. Do stock prices influence corporate decisions? Evidence from the technology
bubble. Journal of Financial Economics 107:89-110.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1378a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1382" publication-type="other">
Chemmanur, T., K. Krishnan, and D. Nandy. 2011. How does venture capital financing improve efficiency in
private firms? A look beneath the surface. Review of Financial Studies 24:4037-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1392a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1396" publication-type="other">
Cooper, R., and J. Haltiwanger. 2006. On the nature of capital adjustment costs. Review of Economic Studies
73:611-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1407a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1411" publication-type="other">
Cummins, J., K. Hassett, and G Hubbard. 1994. A reconsideration of investment behavior using tax reforms as
natural experiments. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 25:1-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1421a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1425" publication-type="other">
Cummins, J., K. Hassett, and S. Oliner. 2006. Investment behavior, observable expectations, and internal funds.
American Economic Review 96:796-810.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1435a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1439" publication-type="other">
DeAngelo, H., L. DeAngelo, and R. Stulz. 2006. Dividend policy and the earned/contributed capital mix: A test
of the lifecycle theory. Journal of Financial Economics 81:227-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1449a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1453" publication-type="other">
Dechow, P., and R. Sloan. 1991. Executive incentives and the horizon problem: An empirical investigation.
Journal of Accounting and Economics 14:51-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1463a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1467" publication-type="other">
Easton, P., and M. Zmijewski. 1989. Cross-sectional variation in the stock market response to accounting earnings
announcements. Journal of Accounting and Economics 11:117-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1477a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1481" publication-type="other">
Edgerton, J. 2012. Agency problems in public firms: Evidence from corporate jets in leveraged buyouts. Journal
of Finance 67:2187-214.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1492a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1496" publication-type="other">
Edmans, A, V. Fang, and K. Lewellen. 2014. Equity vesting and managerial myopia. Working Paper, London
Business School.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1506a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1510" publication-type="other">
Fama, E., and K. French. 1997. Industry costs of equity. Journal of Financial Economics 43:153-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1517a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1521" publication-type="other">
Fang, V., X. Tian, and S. Tice. 2014. Does stock liquidity enhance or impede firm innovation? Journal of Finance
69:2085-125.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1531a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1535" publication-type="other">
Farre-Mensa, J., and A. Ljungqvist. 2014. Do measures of financial constraints measure financial constraints?
Working Paper, Harvard Business School.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1545a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1549" publication-type="other">
Fazzari, S. G Hubbard, and B. Petersen. 1988. Financing constraints and corporate investment. Brookings Papers
on Economic Activity 19:141-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1559a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1563" publication-type="other">
Gala, V., and B. Julio. 2011. Convergence in corporate investment. Working Paper, London Business School.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1571a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1575" publication-type="other">
Gao, H., J. Harford, and K. Li. 2013. Determinants of corporate cash policy: A comparison of private and public
firms. Journal of Financial Economics 109:623-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1585a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1589" publication-type="other">
Gao, H., and K. Li. 2014. Large shareholders and CEO performance-based pay: New evidence from privately-
held firms. Working Paper, University of British Columbia.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1599a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1603" publication-type="other">
Gilje, E., and J. Taillard. 2013. Do private firms invest differently than public firms? Taking cues from the natural
gas industry. Working Paper, Boston College.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1613a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1617" publication-type="other">
Glaeser, E., S. Kerr, and W. Kerr. Forthcoming. Entrepreneurship and urban growth: An empirical assessment
with historical mines. Review of Economics and Statistics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1627a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1631" publication-type="other">
Graham, J., C. Harvey, and S. Rajgopal. 2005. The economic implications of corporate financial reporting.
Journal of Accounting and Economics 40:3-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1641a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1645" publication-type="other">
Grenadier, S., and N. Wang. 2005. Investment timing, agency, and information. Journal of Financial Economics
75:493-533.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1656a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1660" publication-type="other">
Grullon, G, J. Hund, and J. Weston. 2013. A granular analysis of corporate investment. Working Paper, Rice
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1670a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1674" publication-type="other">
Hayashi, F. 1982. Tobin's Q and average Q: A neoclassical interpretation. Econometrica 50:213-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1681a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1685" publication-type="other">
Heckman, J., H. Ichimura, and P. Todd. 1998. Matching as an econometric evaluation estimator. Review of
Economic Studies 65:261-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1695a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1699" publication-type="other">
Heckman, J., R. LaLonde, and J. Smith. 1999. The economics and econometrics of active labor market programs.
In Handbook of labor economics, vol. 3. Eds. O. Ashenfelter and D. Card. Amsterdam: Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1709a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1713" publication-type="other">
Heider, F., and A. Ljungqvist. Forthcoming. As certain as debt and taxes: Estimating the tax sensitivity of leverage
from exogenous state tax changes. Journal of Financial Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1723a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1727" publication-type="other">
Holmström, B. 1982. Managerial incentive problems: A dynamic perspective, in: Essays in Economics and
Management in Honor of Lars Wahlbeck. Helsinki: Swedish School of Economics. Reprinted in Review of
Economic Studies 66 (1999): 169-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1741a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1745" publication-type="other">
Imbens, G, and J. Wooldridge. 2009. Recent developments in the econometrics of program evaluation. Journal
of Economic Literature 47:5-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1755a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1759" publication-type="other">
Jensen, M. 1989. Eclipse of the public corporation. Harvard Business Review (September-October): 61-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1766a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1770" publication-type="other">
Jensen, M., and W. Meckling. 1976. Theory of the firm: Managerial behavior, agency costs and ownership
structure. Journal of Financial Economics 3:305-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1780a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1784" publication-type="other">
John, K., L. Litov, and B. Yeung. 2008. Corporate governance and risk-taking. Journal of Finance 63:1679-728.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1791a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1795" publication-type="other">
Jorgenson, D. 1971. Econometric studies of investment behavior: A survey. Journal of Economic Literature
9:1111—47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1805a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1809" publication-type="other">
Jovanovic, B., and P. Rousseau. 2014. Extensive and intensive investment over the business cycle. Journal of
Political Economy 122:863-908.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1820a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1824" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S., and L. Zingales. 1997. Do financing constraints explain why investment is correlated with cash flow?
Quarterly Journal of Economics 112:169-215.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1834a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1838" publication-type="other">
Ladika, T., and Z. Sautner, 2014, The effect of managerial short-termism on corporate investment. Working
Paper, University of Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1848a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1852" publication-type="other">
Lehn, K., and A. Poulsen. 1989. Free cash flow and stockholder gains in going private transactions. Journal of
Finance 44:771-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1862a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1866" publication-type="other">
Lerner, J. 1995. Venture capitalists and the oversight of private firms. Journal of Finance 50:301-18.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1873a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1877" publication-type="other">
Michaely, R., and M. Roberts. 2012. Corporate dividend policies: Lessons from private firms. Review of Financial
Studies 25:711-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1887a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1891" publication-type="other">
Miller, M., and K. Rock. 1985. Dividend policy under asymmetric information. Journal of Finance 40:1031-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1899a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1903" publication-type="other">
Narayanan, M. 1985. Managerial incentives for short-term results. Journal of Finance 40:1469-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1910a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1914" publication-type="other">
Ozmel, U., D. Robinson, and T. Stuart. 2013. Strategic alliances, venture capital, and exit decisions in early stage
high-tech firms. Journal of Financial Economics 107:655-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1924a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1928" publication-type="other">
Poterba, J., and L. Summers. 1995. A CEO survey of U.S. companies' time horizons and hurdle rates. Sloan
Management Review 37:43-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1938a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1942" publication-type="other">
Rosenbaum, P., and D. Rubin. 1985. Constructing a control group using multivariate matched sampling methods
that incorporate the propensity score. American Statistician 39:33-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1952a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1956" publication-type="other">
Roychowdhury, S. 2006. Earnings management through real activities manipulation. Journal of Accounting and
Economics 42:335-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1966a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1970" publication-type="other">
Saunders, A., and S. Steffen. 2011. The costs of being private: Evidence from the loan market. Review of Financial
Studies 24:4091-122.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1981a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1985" publication-type="other">
Sheen, A. 2009. Do public and private firms behave differently? An examination of investment in the chemical
industry. Working Paper, UCLA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e1995a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e1999" publication-type="other">
Shin, H-H., and R. Stulz. 1998. Are internal capital markets efficient? Quarterly Journal of Economics 113:531-
52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e2009a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e2013" publication-type="other">
Shleifer, A., and R. Vishny. 1990. Equilibrium short horizons of investors and firms. American Economic Review
80:148-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e2023a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e2027" publication-type="other">
Smith, J., and P. Todd. 2005. Does matching overcome LaLonde's critique of nonexperimental estimators?
Journal of Econometrics 125:305-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e2037a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e2041" publication-type="other">
Stein, J. 1988. Takeover threats and managerial myopia. Journal of Political Economy 96:61-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e2048a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e2052" publication-type="other">
. 1989. Efficient capital markets, inefficient firms: A model of myopic corporate behavior. Quarterly
Journal of Economics 104:655-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e2063a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e2067" publication-type="other">
. 2003. Agency, information and corporate investment. In Handbook of the economics of finance. Eds. G
Constantinides, M. Harris, and R. Stulz. Amsterdam: Elsevier Science.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e2077a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e2081" publication-type="other">
Thomas, J. 2002. Is lumpy investment relevant for the business cycle? Journal of Political Economy 110:508-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e2088a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e2092" publication-type="other">
Tirole, J. 2001. Corporate governance. Econometrica 69:1-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e2099a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e2103" publication-type="other">
Von Thadden, E.-L. 1995. Long-term contracts, short-term investment, and monitoring. Review of Economic
Studies 62:557-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e2113a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e2117" publication-type="other">
Wooldridge, J. 2010. Econometric analysis of cross section and panel data. Cambridge: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d5010610e2124a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d5010610e2128" publication-type="other">
Wurgler, J. 2000. Financial markets and the allocation of capital. Journal of Financial Economics 58:187-214.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


