<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465710</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465712</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Money Creation and the Shadow Banking System</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Adi</given-names>
                  <surname>Sunderam</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>939</fpage>
         <lpage>977</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465712"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>It is widely argued that shadow banking grew rapidly before the recent financial crisis because of rising demand for "money-like" claims. This paper assesses a key premise of this argument: that investors actually treated short-term debt issued by shadow banks as a money-like claim. I present a model where the financial sector and the central bank jointly respond to demand for money-like claims. The model generates predictions about the prices and quantities of Treasury bills, central bank reserves, and shadow bank debt. These predictions are borne out in the data, suggesting investors did treat shadow bank debt as money-like.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1240255e233a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e240" publication-type="other">
Why might these claims be imperfect substitutes? One answer is that the types of money services they provide
are different. Treasury bills and ABCP provide safety and liquidity, while deposits provide safety, liquidity, and
transaction services (e.g., check writing).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e253a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e260" publication-type="other">
Nagel (2014) argues that the level of short-term interest rates plays an important role in determining this premium
at low frequencies.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e270a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e277" publication-type="other">
In practice, the distinction between traditional commercial banks and shadow banks is somewhat blurred. There
are small commercial banks that only issue deposits, standalone shadow banks, investment vehicles which only
issue ABCP, and large financial institutions, which do both. For simplicity, the banks we model issue both deposits
and ABCP.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e293a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e300" publication-type="other">
There is no distinction in pricing between bonds and equity in the model since we assume households are
risk-neutral.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e311a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e318" publication-type="other">
This assumption simplifies the analysis by eliminating a variable but is not crucial. Similar results would obtain
if we had banks pick the size of their balance sheets as well.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e328a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e335" publication-type="other">
Banks may also choose to hold reserves against their ABCP liabilities. However, these reserves are likely to be
smaller than the reserves held against deposits, because unlike deposits, ABCP is not immediately demandable.
We can think of T as the incremental reserves banks choose to hold against deposit liabilities over and above
reserves held against other liabilities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e351a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e358" publication-type="other">
In practice, the reserve requirement depends on the deposits issued over a prior period. This means that
a shock to the demand for money services creates demand for reserves at two horizons. Payments-driven
precautionary demand for reserves is contemporaneous with the shock to money demand. Demand driven by
reserve requirements follows the shock to money demand with a lag. Reserve-requirement-driven demand can
be incorporated into the model by adding a second period. The first period would be similar to the existing model,
with a random realization of money demand 0. This realization of money demand would drive precautionary
demand for reserves in the first period and reserve-requirement-based demand for reserves in the second
period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e387a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e394" publication-type="other">
The fact that adding reserves forces the bank to forgo productive investment is a product of the assumption that
the bank's balance sheet is fixed in the short run. In a model where banks can adjust the sizes of their balance
sheets, this effect would vanish.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e407a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e414" publication-type="other">
The predictions about open market operations and central bank reserves make the indirect link as direct as
possible. Reserves are at the very heart of the formal money supply.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e424a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e431" publication-type="other">
In the Internet Appendix, we extend the model to allow banks to issue different types of ABCP that deliver
different amount of money services and formally prove this result.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e442a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e449" publication-type="other">
This would be the case, for instance, in the presence of unanticipated shocks to money demand. In the model,
the Federal Reserve can keep the federal funds rate exactly at the target because money demand 0 is known
exactly. In practice, however, 6 may not be perfectly observable. There are both expected and unexpected shocks
to money demand — for instance, Hamilton (1996, 1997) uses Federal Reserve daily errors in forecasting the
supply and demand for reserves to show that the federal funds rate is decreasing in the quantity of reserves
supplied.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e472a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e479" publication-type="other">
Formally, the OIS rate is the fixed rate in a fixed-to-floating interest rate swap. When two counterparties enter
into the swap, one agrees to pay the OIS rate and in return receive the geometric average of the daily overnight
federal funds rate over the term of the contract. Thus, the OIS rate should represent the average of the federal
funds rate over the term of the contraction. There may be a small term premium component as well, but over the
one-month horizon we focus on, this is likely to be negligible.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e498a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e505" publication-type="other">
In the Internet Appendix, we show that we obtain similar results if we use the spread between the federal funds
target rate and Treasury bill yields. The difference between using the target rate and OIS is that OIS correctly
reflects short-term expected changes in the target.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e518a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e525" publication-type="other">
Note that our approach is somewhat different from a standard instrumental variables approach for identifying
supply elasticities. A typical instrument would shift money demand holding other determinants of ABCP
outstanding constant. Here we are essentially dividing money-like claims into private claims (ABCP and deposits)
and government claims (Treasury bills). Any variable that shifts price while holding the private supply curve
fixed (i.e., satisfying the exclusion restriction) is sufficient to identify the private supply elasticity. As argued
above, the change in government supply is such a variable. Changes in Treasury supply essentially shift around
the residual demand for money-like claims that is not met by Treasury bills, while holding the private supply
curve constant.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e554a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e561" publication-type="other">
The Modigliani-Miller theorem implies that the shadow banking system should be indifferent to issuing different
types of ABCP. However, this logic breaks down in the presence of a money premium. If investors are willing
to pay a money premium for money-like claims, above and beyond any risk premia they charge, then by issuing
money-like claims, the banking sector can capture the money premium without bearing any additional risk. This
ability to earn a riskless profit breaks the Modigliani-Miller argument.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e580a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e587" publication-type="other">
The positive relationship for long maturities shows that ABCP issuers not only increase their total issuance in
response to money demand, but they also rotate the composition of their liabilities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e598a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e605" publication-type="other">
An alternative interpretation of the results is that they simply reflect variation in Treasury supply rather than
money demand. It could just be that the Treasury bill yield is low when the supply of Treasury bills is low, and
use of non-Treasury collateral is high when the supply of Treasury bills is low. However, in untabulated results,
we find that the effect remains if we control for the supply of Treasury bills outstanding, though the statistical
significance is sometimes weaker.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e624a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e631" publication-type="other">
An alternative explanation for these results is that the primary dealers are simply engaging in a carry trade, buying
longer-term and riskier securities when short-term yields are low. Note that the table controls for the term spread
and the Baa-Aaa spread. This helps to rule out this alternative. The results cannot be explained by a story where
the dealers simply hold MBS and corporate bonds when the term spread or credit spreads are high.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e647a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e654" publication-type="other">
In many narratives emphasizing the demand for money-like claims, the financial sector itself plays an important
role. For instance, when securities lenders lend out securities to short sellers, they receive cash as collateral in
case the short seller defaults on the loan. They typically invest this cash in money-like claims because it has to be
returned to the short seller immediately whenever the short seller chooses to close the position. Securities lending
grew rapidly in the mid-2000s, when securities lenders held significant quantities of ABCP (Krishnamurthy,
Nagel, and Orlov 2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e677a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e684" publication-type="other">
The evidence is also consistent with the idea that neglected risks played an important role in the boom, as
argued by Gennaioli, Shleifer, and Vishny (2012, Forthcoming). In the model, we assumed the amount of money
services provided by ABCP, olabcp^ did not vary with the quantity of ABCP produced. However, it would be
reasonable to think that a'abcp should decline with the quantity of ABCP produced because, for instance, larger
quantities of ABCP must be backed by riskier assets. To the extent that this is the case, it is partially captured by
the assumption that c" is positive. Assuming that banks face constant benefits and increasing marginal costs of
ABCP production has similar implications to assuming they have decreasing marginal benefits and fixed marginal
costs. Thus, finding a decline in cas Figure 5 suggests, is consistent with the notion that investors began to
think the banking system could produce more and more ABCP without sacrificing asset quality. The key question
under this interpretation is why investor perceptions changed beginning in the 1990s.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240255e719a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240255e726" publication-type="other">
See, for instance, http://www.frbsf.org/education/publications/doctor-econ/2007/august/temporary-reserves-
liquidity-injection.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1240255e745a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e749" publication-type="other">
Baumol, W. 1952. The transactions demand for cash: An inventory theoretic approach. Quarterly Journal of
Economics 66:545-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e759a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e763" publication-type="other">
Bessembinder, H., Maxwell, W., and Venkataraman, K. Forthcoming. Introducing daylight to structured credit
products. Financial Analyst Journal.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e773a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e777" publication-type="other">
Brunnermeier, M. 2009. Deciphering the 2007-08 liquidity and credit crunch. Journal of Economic Perspectives
23:77-100.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e787a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e791" publication-type="other">
Carpenter, S., and Demiralp, S. 2006. The liquidity effect in the federal funds market: Evidence from daily open
market operations. Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking 38(4):900-920.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e802a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e806" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. 1989. The return of the liquidity effect: A study of the short-run relation between money growth
and interest rates. Journal of Business and Economic Statistics 7:75-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e816a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e820" publication-type="other">
Covitz, D., and Downing, C. 2007. Liquidity or credit risk? The determinants of very short-term corporate yield
spreads. Journal of Finance 62:2303-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e830a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e834" publication-type="other">
Covitz, D., Liang, N., and Suarez, G 2013. The evolution of a financial crisis: Collapse of the asset-backed
commercial paper market. Journal of Finance 68:815-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e844a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e848" publication-type="other">
Dang, T., Gorton, G, and Holmstrom, B. 2010. Opacity and the optimality of debt for liquidity provision. Working
Paper, Yale University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e858a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e862" publication-type="other">
Diamond, D., and Dybvig, P. 1983. Bank runs, deposit insurance, and liquidity. Journal of Political Economy
91:401-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e872a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e876" publication-type="other">
Duffee, G 1996. Idiosyncratic variation of Treasury bill yields. Journal of Finance 51:527-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e884a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e888" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., and Choudhry, M. 2011. Debt markets. Mimeo.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e895a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e899" publication-type="other">
Faig, M. 1989. Seasonal fluctuations and the demand for money. Quarterly Journal of Economics 104:
847-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e909a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e913" publication-type="other">
Federal Reserve Board of Governors, 2005. The Federal Reserve system: Purposes and functions.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e920a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e924" publication-type="other">
Feldhiitter, P., and Lando, D. 2008. Decomposing swap spreads. Journal of Financial Economics 88:375-405.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e931a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e935" publication-type="other">
Gennaioli, N., Shleifer, A., and Vishny, R. 2012. Neglected risks, financial innovation, and financial fragility.
Journal of Financial Economics 104:452-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e945a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e949" publication-type="other">
Gennaioli, N., Shleifer, A., and Vishny, R. Forthcoming. A model of shadow banking. Journal of Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e957a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e961" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G, Lewellen, S., and Metrick, A. 2012. The safe asset share. American Economic Review, Papers and
Proceedings 102:101-06.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e971a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e975" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G, and Metrick, A. 2010a. Haircuts. Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis Review 92:507-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e982a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e986" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G, and Metrick, A. 2010b. Regulating the shadow banking system. Brookings Papers on Economic
Activity 41:261—312.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e996a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1000" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G, and Metrick, A. 2011. Securitized banking and the run on repo. Journal of Financial Economics
104:425-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1010a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1014" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G, and Pennacchi, G 1990. Financial intermediaries and liquidity creation. Journal of Finance 45:
49-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1024a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1028" publication-type="other">
Greenwood, R., Hanson, S., and Stein, J. 2013. A comparative-advantage approach to government debt maturity.
Working Paper, Harvard University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1039a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1043" publication-type="other">
Gurkaynak, R., Sack, B., and Wright, J. 2007. The U.S. Treasury yield curve: 1961 to the present. Journal of
Monetary Economics 54:2291-304.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1053a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1057" publication-type="other">
Hamilton, J. 1996. The daily market for federal funds. Journal of Political Economy 104:26-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1064a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1068" publication-type="other">
Hamilton, J. 1997. Measuring the liquidity effect. American Economic Review 87:80-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1075a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1079" publication-type="other">
Hamilton, J. 1997. The supply and demand for Federal Reserve deposits. Discussion Paper, Carnegie-Rochester
Conference on Public Policy.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1089a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1093" publication-type="other">
Ho, T., and Saunders, A. 1984. A micro model of the federal funds market. Journal of Finance 40:977-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1100a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1104" publication-type="other">
Krishnamurthy, A., Nagel, S., and Orlov, D. 2013. Sizing up repo. Working Paper, NBER.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1112a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1116" publication-type="other">
Krishnamurthy, A., and Vissing-Jorgensen, A. 2012. The aggregate demand for Treasury debt. Journal of Political
Economy 120:233-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1126a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1130" publication-type="other">
Krishnamurthy, A., and Vissing-Jorgensen, A. 2013. What drives short-term debt creation? The impact of Treasury
supply. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1140a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1144" publication-type="other">
Nagel, S. 2014. The liquidity premium on near-money assets. Working Paper, University of Michigan.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1151a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1155" publication-type="other">
Poole, W. 1968. Commercial bank reserve management in a stochastic model: Implications for monetary policy.
Journal of Finance 23:769-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1165a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1169" publication-type="other">
Poole, W., and Lieberman, C. 1972. Improving monetary control. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 2:
293-335.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1179a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1183" publication-type="other">
Schwarz, K. 2010. Mind the gap: Disentangling credit and liquidity in risk spreads. Working Paper, University
of Pennsylvania.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1194a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1198" publication-type="other">
Sidrauski, M. 1967. Rational choice and patterns of growth in a monetary economy. American Economic Review
57:534-44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1208a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1212" publication-type="other">
Stein, J. 2012. Monetary policy as financial-stability regulation. Quarterly Journal of Economics 127:57-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1219a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1223" publication-type="other">
Taylor, J.B. 1993. Discretion versus policy rules in practice. Carnegie-Rochester Conference Series on Public
Policy 39:195-214.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1233a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1237" publication-type="other">
Tobin, J. 1956. The interest-elasticity of transactions demand for cash. Review of Economics and Statistics
38:241-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240255e1247a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240255e1251" publication-type="other">
Tobin, J., and Brainard, W. 1963. Financial intermediaries and the effectiveness of monetary controls. American
Economic Review 53:383-400.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


