<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014365</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effect of a Simple Simulation Game on Long-Term Vocabulary Retention</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Franciosi</surname>
                  <given-names>Stephan J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Stephan J. Franciosi is a Doctor of Education in Learning Technology, Master of Arts in Linguistics and Associate Professor of EFL and Applied Linguistics at Osaka University, Graduate School of Language and Culture. Current research focus is on the foreign language learning outcomes of digital games.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Yagi</surname>
                  <given-names>Junichi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Junichi Yagi is a graduate student of linguistics at Osaka University, Graduate School of Language and Culture. Research interests include phonology, conversation analysis, and second language acquisition.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Tomoshige</surname>
                  <given-names>Yuuki</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Yuuki Tomoshige is a graduate student of linguistics at Osaka University, Graduate School of Language and Culture. Research interests include cognitive linguistics and metaphor.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ye</surname>
                  <given-names>Suying</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Suying Ye is a graduate student of linguistics at Osaka University, Graduate School of Language and Culture. Research interests include vocabulary acquisition and foreign language proficiency assessment.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Osaka University, Graduate School of Language and Culture, Osaka, Japan.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>33</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014360</issue-id>
         <fpage>355</fpage>
         <lpage>379</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2016, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014365"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>Recent studies have shown that simulation games may be useful tools for supporting foreign language education. However, much of this research has focused on games using 3D graphic technology, which entail technical requirements that may render them too complex for use in many educational contexts. Accordingly, we wanted to determine if less complex simulation games could also support the acquisition of a foreign language. We conducted a quasi-experiment using whole classes comprising EFL learners at a Japanese university. A treatment group used an online vocabulary learning application (Quizlet) in conjunction with a simple simulation game (3rd World Farmer), and a control group used the vocabulary learning application alone. Although using the simulation game showed no short-term benefit, the treatment group outperformed the control group on a delayed post-test administered 11 weeks after treatment. We conclude that the effect of simulation games can be used in foreign language learning to improve long-term retention of target language vocabulary.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>simulation game</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>vocabulary learning</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>vocabulary retention</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Al-Seghayer, K. (2001). The effect of multimedia annotation modes on L2 vocabulary acquisition: A comparative study. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 5(1), 202–232. Retrieved from http://www.llt.msu.edu/vol5num1/alseghayer/default.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ang, C. S., &amp; Zaphiris, P. (2006). Developing enjoyable second language learning software tools: A computer game paradigm. In P. Zaphiris &amp; G. Zacharia (Eds.), User-centered computer aided language learning (pp. 1–21). IGI Global, Inc. Retrieved from http://www.igiglobal.com/chapter/developing-enjoyable-second-language-learning/30640 http://dx.doi.org/10.4018/978-1-59140-750-8.ch001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arslanyilmaz, A. (2013). Computer-assisted foreign language instruction: Task based vs. form focused: Computer-assisted foreign language instruction. Journal of Computer Assisted Learning, 29(4), 303–318. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jcal.12003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bakar, N. A., &amp; Nosratirad, E. (2013). Sustaining vocabulary acquisition through computer game: A case study. Asian Social Science, 9(5), 235–242. http://dx.doi.org/10.5539/ass.v9n5p235</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ballou, K. (2009). Language learner experiences in an online virtual world. The JALT CALL Journal, 5(2), 61–70. Retrieved from http://journal.jaltcall.org/articles/5_2_Ballou.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bax, S. (2003). CALL—past, present and future. System, 31(1), 13–28. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0346-251X(02)00071-4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bax, S. (2011). Normalization revisited. International Journal of Computer-Assisted Language Learning and Teaching, 1(2), 1–15. http://dx.doi.org/10.4018/ijcallt.2011040101</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berns, A., Gonzalez-Pardo, A., &amp; Camacho, D. (2013). Game-like language learning in 3-D virtual environments. Computers &amp; Education, 60(1), 210–220. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2012.07.001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bonanno, P., &amp; Kommers, P. A. M. (2007). Exploring the influence of gender and gaming competence on attitudes towards using instructional games. British Journal of Educational Technology, 39(1), 97–109. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8535.2007.00732.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown, I., Campbell, A., &amp; Weatherford, Y. (2008). Using DynEd and ALC with low-level university freshmen. Jalt CALL Journal, 4(3), 37–53. Retrieved from http://journal.jaltcall.org/articles/4_3_Brown.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bush, M. D. (2008). Computer-assisted language learning: From vision to reality? CALICO Journal, 25(3), 443–470. Retrieved from http://journals.sfu.ca/CALICO/index.php/calico/article/viewFile/790/651</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, Y.-L. (2014). Virtual reality software usage in an EFL scenario: An empirical study. Journal of Software, 9(2), 374–381. http://dx.doi.org/10.4304/jsw.9.2.374-381</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chiu, Y., Kao, C., &amp; Reynolds, B. L. (2012). The relative effectiveness of digital game-based learning types in English as a foreign language setting: A meta-analysis: Colloquium. British Journal of Educational Technology, 43(4), E104–E107. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8535.2012.01295.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Clark, A., &amp; Jeremy, E. (2010). Gaming research for technology education. Journal of STEM Education: Innovations &amp; Research, 10(1), 25–30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Clark, D. B., Nelson, B. C., Chang, H.-Y., Martinez-Garza, M., Slack, K., &amp; D’Angelo, C. M. (2011). Exploring Newtonian mechanics in a conceptually-integrated digital game: Comparison of learning and affective outcomes for students in Taiwan and the United States. Computers &amp; Education, 57(3), 2178–2195. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2011.05.007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cockburn, C., &amp; Ormrod, S. (1993). Gender and technology in the making. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cohen, J. (1988). Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences (2nd ed.). Hillsdale, NJ: L. Erlbaum Associates.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coleman, D. W. (1990). Computerized simulations and games for language learning: Part 1. Simulation &amp; Gaming, 21(4), 443–444. http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/104687819002100407</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Connolly, T. M., Stansfield, M., &amp; Hainey, T. (2011). An alternate reality game for language learning: ARGuing for multilingual motivation. Computers &amp; Education, 57(1), 1389–1415. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2011.01.009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dickey, M. D. (2006a). Game design and learning: A conjectural analysis of how massively multiple online role-playing games (MMORPGs) foster intrinsic motivation. Educational Technology Research and Development, 55(3), 253–273. http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11423-006-9004-7</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dickey, M. D. (2006b). Game design narrative for learning: Appropriating adventure game design narrative devices and techniques for the design of interactive learning environments. Educational Technology Research and Development, 54(3), 245–263. http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11423-006-8806-y</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Educational Testing Service. (2012). Test and score data summary for TOEFL iBT tests and TOEFL PBT tests: January 2011–December 2011 test data. Princeton, NJ. Retrieved from http://www.ets.org/s/toefl/pdf/94227_unlweb.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ellis, R. (2003). Task-based language learning and teaching. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Franciosi, S. (2011). A comparison of computer game and language-learning task design using flow theory. CALL-EJ, 12(1), 11–25. Retrieved from http://callej.org/journal/12-1/Franciosi_2011.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Franciosi, S. (2014). Educator perceptions of digital game-based learning in the instruction of foreign languages in Japanese higher education (Doctoral dissertation). Pepperdine University, Malibu, CA. Retrieved from ProQuest Dissertations and Theses (UMI No. 3611461).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gass, S. M. (2000). Changing views of language learning. In H. Trappes-Lomax (Ed.), Change and continuity in applied linguistics: Selected papers from the annual meeting of the British Association of Applied Linguistics Edinburgh (pp. 51–67). Edinburgh: British Association of Applied Linguistics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gee, J. P. (2004). Situated Language and Learning: A Critique of Traditional Schooling. New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gee, J. P. (2005). Good video games and good learning. Phi Kappa Phi Forum, 85 (2), 33–37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haratmeh, M. S. (2012). Involvement load and task type in task effectiveness: Two aspects of vocabulary knowledge. International Journal of Academic Research, 4(4), 86–95. http://dx.doi.org/10.7813/2075-4124.2012/4-4/B.13</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ikeda, N. (1999). Language learning strategies with sound-hints in computer-based drill. Journal of Computer Assisted Learning, 15(4), 312–332. Retrieved from http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1046/j.1365-2729.1999.00106.x/abstract http://dx.doi.org/10.1046/j.1365-2729.1999.00106.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inman, C., Wright, V., &amp; Hartman, J. (2010). Use of Second Life in K-12 and higher education: A review of research. Journal of Interactive Online Learning, 9(1), 44–63. Retrieved from http://www.ncolr.org/jiol/issues/pdf/9.1.3.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jahangard, A., &amp; Movassagh, H. (2011). High vs. low load vocabulary learning tasks: A case for intentional learning. BRAIN: Broad Research in Artificial Intelligence &amp; Neuroscience, 2(4), 48–55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, W. L. (2009). A simulation-based approach to training operational cultural competence. Proc. of ModSIM World 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, Y. (2011). The role of task-induced involvement and learner proficiency in L2 vocabulary acquisition. Language Learning, 61(s1), 100–140. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9922.2011.00644.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klimesch, W. (2013). The Structure of Long-Term Memory: A Connectivity Model of Semantic Processing. Abingdon: Psychology Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kron, F. W., Gjerde, C. L., Sen, A., &amp; Fetters, M. D. (2010). Medical student attitudes toward video games and related new media technologies in medical education. BMC Medical Education, 10(1), 50. http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/1472-6920-10-50</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kroneisen, M. &amp; Erdfelder, E. (2011). On the plasticity of the survival processing effect. Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition, 37(6), 1553–1562. http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0024493</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kroneisen, M., Erdfelder, E., &amp; Buchner, A. (2013). The proximate memory mechanism underlying the survival-processing effect: Richness of encoding or interactive imagery? Memory, 21(4), 494–502. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09658211.2012.741603</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kumaravadivelu, B. (2006). TESOL Methods: Changing tracks, challenging trends. TESOL Quarterly, 40(1), 59–81. Retrieved from http://people.ufpr.br/~clarissa/pdfs/ChangeTracksTrends_Kumaravadivelu2006.pdf http://dx.doi.org/10.2307/40264511</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lim, C. P., Nonis, D., &amp; Hedberg, J. (2006). Gaming in a 3D multiuser virtual environment: Engaging students in science lessons. British Journal of Educational Technology, 37(2), 211–231. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8535.2006.00531.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liou, H.-C. (2012). The roles of Second Life in a college computer-assisted language learning (CALL) course in Taiwan, ROC. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 25(4), 365–382. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2011.597766</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Littlewood, W. (2004). The task-based approach: Some questions and suggestions. ELT Journal, 58(4), 319–326. http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/elt/58.4.319</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, T.-Y., &amp; Chu, Y.-L. (2010). Using ubiquitous games in an English listening and speaking course: Impact on learning outcomes and motivation. Computers &amp; Education, 55(2), 630–643. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2010.02.023</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Long, M. H. (1981). Input, interaction and second-language acquisition. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 379 (1 Native Langua), 259–278. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-6632.1981.tb42014.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lopes, M. C., Fialho, F. A. P., Cunha, C. J. C. A., &amp; Niveiros, S. I. (2013). Business games for leadership development: A systematic review. Simulation &amp; Gaming, 44(4), 523–543. http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1046878112471509</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lynch-Sauer, J., VandenBosch, T. M., Kron, F., Gjerde, C. L., Arato, N., Sen, A., &amp; Fetters, M. D. (2011). Nursing students’ attitudes toward video games and related new media technologies. Journal of Nursing Education, 50(9), 513–523. http://dx.doi.org/10.3928/01484834-20110531-04</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Macedonia, M., &amp; Klimesch, W. (2014). Long-term effects of gestures on memory for foreign language words trained in the classroom. Mind, Brain, and Education, 8(2), 74–88. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/mbe.12047</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McDonough, S. K. (2001). Way beyond drill and practice: Foreign language lab activities in support of constructivist learning. International Journal of Instructional Media, 28(1), 75–81. Retrieved from http://cadre11.wikispaces.com/file/view/Way+Beyond+Drill+and+Practice.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McVeigh, B. J. (2002). Japanese Higher Education as Myth. Armonk, NY: M. E. Sharpe. Miller, M., &amp; Hegelheimer, V. (2006). The SIMs meet ESL incorporating authentic computer simulation games into the language classroom. Interactive Technology and Smart Education, 3(4), 311–328. http://dx.doi.org/10.1108/17415650680000070</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mills, V., Smith, R., &amp; Swain, K. (2003). An examination of the effectiveness of simulation games as a means of enhancing intercultural awareness. Australian Journal of Psychology, 55, 53–54. Retrieved from http://dspace.dsto.defence.gov.au/dspace/handle/1947/2598</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Milton, J., Jonsen, S., Hirst, S., &amp; Lindenburn, S. (2012). Foreign language vocabulary development through activities in an online 3D environment. The Language Learning Journal, 40(1), 99–112. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09571736.2012.658229</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Min, H.-T. (2008). EFL Vocabulary acquisition and retention: Reading plus vocabulary enhancement activities and narrow reading. Language Learning, 58(1), 73–115. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9922.2007.00435.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ming, Y., Ruan, Q., &amp; Gao, G. (2013). A Mandarin edutainment system integrated virtual learning environments. Speech Communication, 55(1), 71–83. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.specom.2012.06.007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mishra, P., &amp; Koehler, M. J. (2006). Technological pedagogical content knowledge: A framework for teacher knowledge. Teachers College Record, 108(6), 1017–1054. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9620.2006.00684.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nunn, R. (2006). Designing holistic units for task-based teaching. Asian EFL Journal, 8(3), 69–93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Orvis, K. A., Horn, D. B., &amp; Belanich, J. (2009). An examination of the role individual differences play in videogame-based training. Military Psychology, 21(4), 461–481. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/08995600903206412</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oxford, R. (2006). Task-based language teaching and learning: An overview. Asian EFL Journal, 8(3), 94–121. Retrieved from http://www.idemployee.id.tue.nl/g.w.m.rauterberg/amme/oxford-2006.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peterson, M. (2009). Computerized games and simulations in computer-assisted language learning: A meta-analysis of research. Simulation &amp; Gaming, 41(1), 72–93. http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1046878109355684</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peterson, M. (2012). EFL learner collaborative interaction in Second Life. ReCALL, 24(1), 20–39. http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0958344011000279</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ranalli, J. (2008). Learning English with The Sims: Exploiting authentic computer simulation games for L2 learning. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 21(5), 441–455. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09588220802447859</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rapeepisarn, K., Wong, K. W., Fung, C. C., &amp; Khine, M. S. (2008). The relationship between game genres, learning techniques and learning styles in educational computer games. In Z. Pan, Z. Zhang, A. El Rhalibi, W. Woo, &amp; Y. Li (Eds.), Technologies for e-learning and digital entertainment (pp. 497–508). Berlin: Springer. http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-697 36-7_53</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reinders, H., &amp; Wattana, S. (2011). Learn English or die: The effects of digital games on interaction and willingness to communicate in a foreign language. Digital Culture &amp; Education, 3(1), 3–29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rodriguez, M., &amp; Sadoski, M. (2000). Effects of rote, context, keyword, and context/keyword methods on retention of vocabulary in EFL classrooms. Languge Learning, 50(2), 385–413. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/0023-8333.00121</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Röer, J. P., Bell, R., &amp; Buchner, A. (2013). Is the survival-processing memory advantage due to richness of encoding? Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition, 39(4), 1294–1302. http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0031214</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roubstova, O. V. (2010). Competition in the role-play game as an effective technology for teaching adolescents with a foreign language as an example. Psychological Science &amp; Education, 5, 37–42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ryu, D. (2013). Play to learn, learn to play: Language learning through gaming culture. ReCALL, 25(2), 286–301. http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0958344013000050</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sadoski, M. (2005). A dual coding view of vocabulary learning. Reading &amp; Writing Quarterly, 21(3), 221–238. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10573560590949359</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schell, J. (2008). The Art of Game Design: A Book of Lenses. Amsterdam: Elsevier; Morgan Kaufmann.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skehan, P., Xiaoyue, B., Qian, L., &amp; Wang, Z. (2012). The task is not enough: Processing approaches to task-based performance. Language Teaching Research, 16(2), 170–187. http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1362168811428414</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Suh, S., Kim, S. W., &amp; Kim, N. J. (2010). Effectiveness of MMORPG-based instruction in elementary English education in Korea. Journal of Computer Assisted Learning, 26(5), 370–378. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2729.2010.00353.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref71">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taheri, M. (2014). The effect of using language games on vocabulary retention of Iranian elementary EFL learners. Journal of Language Teaching and Research, 5(3), 544–549. http://dx.doi.org/10.4304/jltr.5.3.544-549</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref72">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takashima, A., Bakker, I., van Hell, J. G., Janzen, G., &amp; McQueen, J. M. (2014). Richness of information about novel words influences how episodic and semantic memory networks interact during lexicalization. NeuroImage, 84, 265–278. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2013.08.023</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref73">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tao, Y.-H., Cheng, C.-J., &amp; Sun, S.-Y. (2009). What influences college students to continue using business simulation games? The Taiwan experience. Computers &amp; Education, 53(3), 929–939. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2009.05.009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref74">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taylor, K. C., &amp; Chyung, S. Y. (Yonnie). (2008). Would you adopt Second Life as a training and development tool? Performance Improvement, 47(8), 17–25. http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pfi.20019</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref75">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thompson, D., Baranowski, T., Buday, R., Baranowski, J., Thompson, V., Jago, R., &amp; Griffith, M. J. (2008). Serious video games for health: How behavioral science guided the development of a serious video game. Simulation &amp; Gaming, 41(4), 587–606. http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1046878108328087</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref76">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, F., &amp; Shao, E. (2012). Using Second Life to assist EFL teaching: We do not have to sign in to the program. TechTrends, 56(4), 15–18. http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11528-012-0582-4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref77">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wilson, K., Bedwell, W., Lazzara, E. H., Salas, E., Burke, C. S., Estock, J. L., &amp; Conkey, C. (2009). Relationships between game attributes and learning outcomes review and research proposal. Simulation &amp; Gaming, 40(2), 217–266. http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1046878108321866</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref78">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, H. (2013). Pedagogical challenges of spoken English learning in the Second Life virtual world: A case study. British Journal of Educational Technology, 44(2), 243–254. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8535.2012.01312.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>

