<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">26</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i23322391</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23323229</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Jane: an advanced freely available hierarchical machine translation toolkit</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
                  <surname>Vilar</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
                  <surname>Stein</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Matthias</given-names>
                  <surname>Huck</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Hermann</given-names>
                  <surname>Ney</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2012</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>197</fpage>
         <lpage>216</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Springer Science+Business Media B.V. 2012</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23323229"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>In this article we will describe the design and implementation of Jane, an efficient hierarchical phrase-based (HPB) toolkit developed at RWTH Aachen University. The system has been used by RWTH at several international evaluation campaigns, including the WMT and NIST evaluations, and is now freely available for non-commercial application. We will go through the main features of Jane, which include, among others, support for different search strategies, different language model formats, support for syntax-based enhancements to the HPB machine translation paradigm, string-to-dependency translation, extended lexicon models, different methods for minimum-error-rate training and distributed operation on a computer cluster. Special attention has been paid to the efficiency of the decoder, clean code and quality assurance through unit and regression testing. Results on current machine translation tasks are reported, which show that the system is able to obtain state-of-the-art performance.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d630687e246a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d630687e253" publication-type="other">
http://www.itl.nist.gov/iadymig/tests/mt/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d630687e260a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d630687e267" publication-type="other">
http://www.statmt.org/wmtll/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d630687e274a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d630687e281" publication-type="other">
http://www.quaero.org/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d630687e288a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d630687e295" publication-type="other">
http://matrix.statmt.org/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d630687e311a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e315" publication-type="other">
Birch A, Blunsom P, Osborne M (2009) A quantitative analysis of reordering phenomena. In: Proceedings
of the fourth workshop on statistical machine translation, Athens, pp 197-205</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e325a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e329" publication-type="other">
Blunsom P, Cohn T, Osborne M (2008) A discriminative latent variable model for statistical machine trans-
lation. In: ACL-08: HLT, 46th annual meeting of the association for computational linguistics: human
language technologies, proceedings of the conference, Columbus, pp 200-208</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e342a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e346" publication-type="other">
Brown PF, Delia Pietra SA, Delia Pietra VJ, Mercer RL (1993) The mathematics of statistical machine
translation: parameter estimation. Comput Linguist 19(2):263-311</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e356a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e360" publication-type="other">
Byrd RH, Lu P. Nocedal J, Zhu C (1995) A limited memory algorithm for bound constrained optimization.
SIAM J Sei Comput 16(5): 1190-1208</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e371a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e375" publication-type="other">
Card OS (1986) Speaker for the dead. Tor Books, New York</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e382a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e386" publication-type="other">
Chappelier JC, Rajman M (1998) A generalized CYK algorithm for parsing stochastic CFG. In: Proceedings
of the first workshop on tabulation in parsing and deduction, Paris, pp 133-137</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e396a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e400" publication-type="other">
Chiang D (2005) A hierarchical phrase-based model for statistical machine translation. In: ACL-05: 43rd
annua] meeting of the association for computational linguistics, Ann Arbor, pp 263-270</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e410a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e414" publication-type="other">
Chiang D, Knight K, Wang W (2009) 11,001 new features for statistical machine translation. In: Proceed-
ings of human language technologies: the 2009 annual conference of the North American chapter of
the association for computational linguistics, Boulder, pp 218-226</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e427a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e431" publication-type="other">
Cmejrek M, Zhou B, Xiang B (2009) Enriching SCFG rules directly from efficient bilingual chart parsing.
In: Proceedings of the international workshop on spoken language translation, Tokyo, pp 136-143</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e441a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e445" publication-type="other">
Hasan S, Ney H (2009) Comparison of extended lexicon models in search and rescoring for SMT. In:
Joint conference of the 47th annual meeting of the association for computational linguistics and the
4th international joint conference on natural language processing of the asian federation of natural
language processing, Boulder, pp 17-20</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e462a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e466" publication-type="other">
Hasan S, Ganitkevitch J, Ney H, Andres-Ferrer J (2008) Triplet lexicon models for statistical machine
translation. In: EMNLP 2008: Proceedings of the 2008 conference on empirical methods in natural
language processing, Honolulu, pp 372-381</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e479a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e483" publication-type="other">
Heger C, Wuebker J, Huck M, Leusch G, Mansour S, Stein D, Ney H (2010) The RWTH Aachen machine
translation system for WMT 2010. In: Proceedings of the joint 5th workshop on statistical machine
translation and metricsMATR, Uppsala, pp 93-97</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e496a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e500" publication-type="other">
Huang L, Chiang D (2007) Forest rescoring: Faster decoding with integrated language models. In: Pro-
ceedings of the 2007 joint conference on empirical methods in natural language processing and com-
putational natural language learning, Prague, pp 144-151</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e513a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e517" publication-type="other">
Huck M, Ratajczak M, Lehnen P. Ney H (2010) A comparison of various types of extended lexicon mod-
els for statistical machine translation. In: AMTA 2010: proceedings of the ninth conference of the
association for machine translation in the Americas, Denver</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e530a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e534" publication-type="other">
Johnson H, Martin J, Foster G, Kuhn R (2007) Improving translation quality by discarding most of the
phrasetable. In: Proceedings of the 2007 joint conference on empirical methods in natural language
processing and computational natural language learning, Prague, pp 967-975</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e547a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e551" publication-type="other">
Koehn P (2010) Statistical machine translation. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e559a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e563" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Haddow B, Williams P, Hoang H (2010) More linguistic annotation for statistical machine trans-
lation. In: ACL 2010: Joint 5th workshop on statistical machine translation and metricsMATR, pro-
ceedings of the workshop, Uppsala, pp 121-126</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e576a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e580" publication-type="other">
Leusch G, Ney H (2009) Edit distances with block movements and error rate confidence estimates. Mach
Transí 23:129-140</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e590a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e594" publication-type="other">
Li Z, Callison-Burch C, Dyer C, Khudanpur S, Schwartz L, Thornton W, Weese J, Zaidan O (2009) Joshua:
an open source toolkit for parsing-based machine translation. In: EACL 2009: 4th workshop on sta-
tistical machine translation, proceedings of the workshop, Athens, pp 135-139</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e607a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e611" publication-type="other">
Mauser A, Hasan S, Ney H (2009) Extending statistical machine translation with discriminative and trigger-
based lexicon models. In: EMNLP 2009: proceedings of the 2009 conference on empirical methods
in natural language processing, Singapore, pp 210-218</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e624a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e628" publication-type="other">
Och FJ (2003) Minimum error rate training for statistical machine translation. In: 41st annual meeting of
the association for computational linguistics, proceedings of the conference, Sapporo, pp 160-167</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e638a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e642" publication-type="other">
Schwartz L (2010) Reproducible results in parsing-based machine translation: the JHU shared task sub-
mission. In: ACL 2010: joint Fifth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation and MetricsMATR,
proceedings of the workshop, Uppsala, pp 177-182</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e656a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e660" publication-type="other">
Shen L, Xu J, Weischedel R (2008) A new string-to-dependency machine translation algorithm with a
target dependency language model. In: ACL-08: HLT, 46th annual meeting of the association for
computational linguistics: human language technologies, proceedings of the conference, Columbus,
pp 577-585</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e676a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e680" publication-type="other">
Stolcke A (2002) SRILM—an extensible language modeling toolkit. In: Proceedings of the 7th international
conference on spoken language processing, vol 3. Denver, pp 901-904</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e690a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e694" publication-type="other">
Talbot D, Osborne M (2007) Smoothed Bloom filter language models: tera-scale LMs on the cheap. In:
EMNLP-CoNLL 2007: proceedings of the 2007 joint conference on empirical methods in natural
language processing and computational natural language learning, Prague, pp 468-476</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e707a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e711" publication-type="other">
Venugopal A, Zollmann A, Smith N, Vogel S (2009) Preference grammars: Softening syntactic constraints
to improve statistical machine translation. In: Human language technologies: the 2009 annual confer-
ence of the North American chapter of the association for computational linguistics, proceedings of
the conference, Boulder, pp 236-244</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e727a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e731" publication-type="other">
Vilar D, Ney H (2009) On LM heuristics for the cube growing algorithm. In: EAMT-2009: proceed-
ings of the 13th annual conference of the European association for machine translation, Barcelona,
pp 242-249</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e744a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e748" publication-type="other">
Vilar D, Ney H (2011) Cardinality pruning and language model heuristics for hierarchical phrase-based
translation. Mach Transí 1-38. doi:10.1007/s 10590-011-9119-4</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e759a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e763" publication-type="other">
Vilar D, Stein D, Ney H (2008) Analysing soft syntax features and heuristics for hierarchical phrase based
machine translation. In: IWSLT 2008: proceedings of the international workshop on spoken language
translation, Waikiki, pp 190-197</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e776a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e780" publication-type="other">
Vilar D, Stein D, Huck M, Ney H (2010a) Jane: open source hierarchical translation, extended with reor-
dering and lexicon models. In: ACL 2010: joint 5th workshop on statistical machine translation and
metricsMATR, proceedings of the workshop, Uppsala, pp 262-270</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e793a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e797" publication-type="other">
Vilar D, Stein D, Peitz S, Ney H (2010b) If I only had a parser: Poor man's syntax for hierarchical machine
translation. In: Proceedings of the 7th international workshop on spoken language translation, Paris,
pp 345-352</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e810a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e814" publication-type="other">
Wuebker J, Mauser A, Ney H (2010) Training phrase translation models with leaving-one-out. In: ACL 2010,
48th annual meeting of the association for computational linguistics, proceedings of the conference,
Uppsala, pp 475-484</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d630687e827a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d630687e831" publication-type="other">
Zens R, Ney H (2007) Efficient phrase-table representation for machine translation with applications to
online MT and speech translation. In: Human language technologies 2007: the conference of the North
American chapter of the association for computational linguistics, proceedings of the main conference,
Rochester, pp 492-499</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


