<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90007066</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Research on Wind Energy Potential at Karamay</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Jiang</surname>
                  <given-names>Yingni</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Department of Architecture Engineering Logistics University of People’s Armed Police Force Tianjin 300309, China.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>39</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e90007065</issue-id>
         <fpage>229</fpage>
         <lpage>236</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90007066"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The Weibull density function is used to estimate the wind energy potential of Karamay station (45.6°N, 84.9°E) situated in xinjiang province of China. The scale and shape parameters of Weibull model are estimated using 10 years’ (1995–2004) daily average wind speed data. The probability density distributions are derived from the time-series data and the wind energy potential of Karamay station is also evaluated by the Weibull model.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>Weibull model</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>wind energy potential</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>probability density</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu Yuehua, Jiang Yingni and Cheng Xiaojun. Research on wind energy potential at Zhurihe. Wind engineering 2012; 2(36): 123–130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jiang Yingni, Yuan Xiuling, Cheng Xiaojun and Peng Xiaoyun. Wind potential assessment using the Weibull model at the Inner Mongolia of China. Energy Exploration and Exploitation 2006; 24(3): 211–221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yeliz Mert Kantar and Ilhan Usta. Analysis of wind speed distributions: Wind distribution-function derived from minimum cross entropy principlesas better alternative to Weibull function. Energy Conversion and Management 2008; 49(4): 962–973.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tian Pau Chang. Performance comparison of six numerical methods in estimating Weibull parameters for wind energy application. Applied Energy 2011; 88(1): 272–282.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S.A. Akdag, H.S. Bagiorgas and G. Mihalakakou. Use of two-component Weibull mixtures in the analysis of wind speed in the Eastern Mediterranean. Applied Energy 2010; 87(8): 2566–2573.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seyit A. Akdag and Ali Dinler. A new method to estimate Weibull parameters for wind energy applications. Energy Conversion and Management 2009; 50(7): 1761–1766.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bonfils Safari and Jimmy Gasore. A statistical investigation of wind characteristics and wind energy potential based on the Weibull and Rayleigh models in Rwanda. Renewable Energy 2010; 35(12): 2874–2880.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Penélope Ramírez and José Antonio Carta. Influence of the data sampling interval in the estimation of the parameters of the Weibull wind speed probability density distribution: a case study. Energy Conversion and Management 2005; 46(15–16): 2419–2438.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siaka Toure. Investigations on the Eigen-coordinates method for the 2-parameter weibull distribution of wind speed. Renewable Energy 2005; 30(4): 511–521.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nicholas J. Cook and R. Ian Harris. Postscript to ‘Exact and general FT1 penultimate distributions of extreme wind speeds drawn from tail-equivalent Weibull parents’. Structural Safety 2008; 30(1): 1–10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li Meishen and Li Xianguo. MEP-type distribution function: a better alternative to Weibull function for wind speed distributions. Renewable Energy 2005; 30(8): 1221–1240.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
