<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">mathcomp</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100273</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Mathematics of Computation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>American Mathematical Society</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00255718</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">10886842</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">80</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">275</issue>
         <issue-id>i23075006</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23075359</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>DISCONTINUOUS GALERKIN ERROR ESTIMATION FOR LINEAR SYMMETRIZABLE HYPERBOLIC SYSTEMS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>SLIMANE</given-names>
                  <surname>ADJERID</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>THOMAS</given-names>
                  <surname>WEINHART</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2011</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1335</fpage>
         <lpage>1367</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2011 American Mathematical Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23075359"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We present an a posteriori error analysis for the discontinuous Galerkin discretization error of first-order linear symmetrizable hyperbolic systems of partial differential equations with smooth solutions. We perform a local error analysis by writing the local error as a series and showing that its leading term can be expressed as a linear combination of Legendre polynomials of degree p and p + 1. We apply these asymptotic results to show that projections of the error are pointwise 𝓞(h
              p+2
              )-superconvergent. We solve relatively small local problems to compute efficient and asymptotically exact estimates of the finite element error. We present computational results for several linear hyperbolic systems in acoustics and electromagnetism.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1949106e488a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e495" publication-type="other">
M. Abramowitz and I. A. Stegun, Handbook of mathematical functions, Dover, New York,
1965.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e505a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e512" publication-type="other">
S. Adjerid and M. Baccouch, The discontinuous Galerkin method for two-dimensional hy-
perbolic problems Part I: Superconvergence error analysis, Journal of Scientific Computing
33 (2007), 75-113. MR2338333 (2008j:65189)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e525a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e532" publication-type="other">
-, Asymptotically exact a posteriori error estimates for a one-dimensional linear hy-
perbolic problem, submitted, 2009.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e542a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e549" publication-type="other">
-, The discontinuous Galerkin method for two-dimensional hyperbolic problems Part II:
A Posteriori error estimation, Journal of Scientifc Computing 38 (2009), 15-49. MR2472217</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e560a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e567" publication-type="other">
S. Adjerid, K. D. Devine, J. E. Flaherty, and L. Krivodonova, A posteriori error estimation
for discontinuous Galerkin solutions of hyperbolic problems, Computer Methods in Applied
Mechanics and Engineering 191 (2002), 1097-1112. MR1877682 (2002k:65137)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e580a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e587" publication-type="other">
S. Adjerid and T. C. Massey, A posteriori discontinuous finite element error estimation for
two-dimensional hyperbolic problems, Computer Methods in Applied Mechanics and Engi-
neering 191 (2002), 5877-5897. MR1942623 (2003j:65110)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e600a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e607" publication-type="other">
-, Superconvergence of discontinuous finite element solutions for nonlinear hyperbolic
problems, Computer Methods in Applied Mechanics and Engineering 195 (2006), 3331-3346.
MR2220922 (2006k:65304)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e620a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e627" publication-type="other">
S. Adjerid and T. Weinhart, Asymptotically exact discontinuous Galerkin error estimates for
linear symmetric hyperbolic systems, submitted, 2009.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e637a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e644" publication-type="other">
-, Discontinuous Galerkin error estimation for linear symmetric hyperbolic sys-
tems, Computer Methods in Applied Mechanics and Engineering 198 (2009), 3113-3129.
MR2567860</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e657a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e664" publication-type="other">
-, Discontinuous Galerkin error estimation for linear symmetric hyperbolic systems
with Lax Friedricks flux, in preparation, 2009.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e675a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e682" publication-type="other">
S. Benzoni-Gavage and D. Serre, Multidimensional hyperbolic partial differential equations,
Oxford University Press, 2007. MR2284507 (2008k:35002)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e692a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e699" publication-type="other">
Y. Cheng and C.-W. Shu, Superconvergence and time evolution of discontinuous Galerkin
finite element solutions, Journal of Computational Physics 227 (2008), 9612-9627.
MR2467636 (2009k:65182)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e712a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e719" publication-type="other">
-, Superconvergence of local discontinuous Galerkin methods for one-dimensional
convection-diffusion equations, Computers &amp; Structures 87 (2009), 630-641.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e729a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e736" publication-type="other">
-, Superconvergence of discontinuous Galerkin and local discontinuous galerkin
schemes for linear hyperbolic and convection-diffusion equations in one space dimension,
SIAM Journal on Numerical Analysis 47 (2010), 4044-4072. MR2585178</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e749a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e756" publication-type="other">
B. Cockburn, A simple introduction to error estimation for nonlinear hyperbolic conservation
laws, Proceedings of the 1998 EPSRC Summer School in Numerical Analysis, SSCM, volume
26 of the Graduate Student's Guide for Numerical Analysis, pages 1-46 (Berlin), Springer,
1999. MR1715030</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e772a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e779" publication-type="other">
B. Cockburn and P. A. Gremaud, Error estimates for finite element methods for nonlinear
conservation laws, SIAM Journal on Numerical Analysis 33 (1996), 522-554. MR1388487
(97e:65096)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e793a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e800" publication-type="other">
B. Cockburn, S. Hou, and C. W. Shu, TVB Runge-Kutta local projection discontinuous
Galerkin finite element method for conservation laws IV: The multidimensional case, Math.
Comp. 54 (1990), 545-581. MR1010597 (90k:65162)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e813a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e820" publication-type="other">
B. Cockburn, S. Y. Lin, and C. W. Shu, TVB Runge-Kutta local projection discontinuous
Galerkin methods of scalar conservation laws III: One dimensional systems, Journal of Com-
putational Physics 84 (1989), 90-113. MR1015355 (90k:65161)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e833a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e840" publication-type="other">
B. Cockburn and C. W. Shu, The Runge-Kutta local projection pl-discontinuous Galerkin
method for scalar conservation laws, RAIRO Model. Math. Anal. Numer. 25 (1991), 337-361.
MR1103092 (92e:65128)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e853a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e860" publication-type="other">
J. R. Dormand and P. J. Prince, A family of embedded Runge-Kutta formula, Journal of
Computational and Applied Mathematics 6 (1980), no. 1, 19-26. MR568599 (81g:65098)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e870a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e877" publication-type="other">
R. Hartmann and P. Houston, Adaptive discontinuous Galerkin finite element methods
for nonlinear hyperbolic conservations laws, SIAM J. Sci. Comput. 24 (2002), 979—1004.
MR1950521 (2004b:65149)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e890a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e897" publication-type="other">
L. Krivodonova and J. E. Flaherty., Error estimation for discontinuous Galerkin solutions of
two-dimensional hyperbolic problems, Advances in Computational Mathematics 19 (2003),
57-71. MR1973459 (2004e:65112)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e911a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e918" publication-type="other">
M. Larson and T. Barth, A posteriori error estimation for adaptive discontinuous Galerkin
approximation of hyperbolic systems, Proc. International Symposium on Discontinuous
Galerkin Methods Theory, Computation and Applications (Berlin) (B. Cockburn, G. E. Kar-
niadakis, and C. W. Shu, eds.), Springer, 2000. MR1842194 (2002f:65163)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e934a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e941" publication-type="other">
P, LeSaint and P. Raviart, On a finite element method for solving the neutron transport
equations, Mathematical Aspects of Finite Elements in Partial Differential Equations (New
York) (C. de Boor, ed.), Academic Press, 1974, pp. 89-145. MR0658142 (58:31918)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e954a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e961" publication-type="other">
W. H. Reed and T. R. Hill, Triangular mesh methods for the neutron transport equation,
Tech. Report LA-UR-73-479, Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, Los Alamos, 1973.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e971a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e978" publication-type="other">
Uriel G. Rothblum, A representation of the Drazin inverse and characterizations of the index,
SIAM Journal on Applied Mathematics 31 (1976), no. 4, 646-648. MR0422303 (54:10294)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1949106e988a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1949106e995" publication-type="other">
J. C. Tannehill, D. A. Anderson, and R. H. Pletcher, Computational fluid mechanics and
heat transfer, 2nd ed., Taylor &amp; Francis, 1997.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


