<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277570</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Combustion Studies with FACE Diesel Fuels</article-title>
            <subtitle>A Literature Review</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kim</surname>
                  <given-names>Junghwan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sluder</surname>
                  <given-names>C. Scott</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wagner</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Oak Ridge National Laboratory</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>December 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277559</issue-id>
         <fpage>1648</fpage>
         <lpage>1660</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277570"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The CRC Fuels for Advanced Combustion Engines (FACE) Working Group has provided a matrix of experimental diesel fuels for use in studies on the effects of three parameters, Cetane number (CN), aromatics content, and 90 vol% distillation temperature (T90), on combustion and emissions characteristics of advanced combustion strategies. Various types of fuel analyses and engine experiments were performed in well-known research institutes. This paper reviews a collection of research findings obtained with these nine fuels.</p>
            <p>An extensive collection of analyses were performed by members of the FACE working group on the FACE diesel fuels as a means of aiding in understanding the linkage between fuel properties and combustion and emissions performance. These analyses included non-traditional chemical techniques as well as established ASTM tests. In a few cases, both ASTM tests and advanced analyses agreed that some design variables differed from their target values when the fuels were produced.</p>
            <p>This review summarizes six collective engine experimental studies performed with FACE fuels with various types of engines under a range of conditions. Engine experiments under various operating conditions were performed with a 0.517- liter HCCI single cylinder engine (SCE) and 4-cylinder 1.9-liter high-speed direct-injection (HSDI) diesel engine at Oak Ridge National Laboratory (ORNL), 0.744-liter DI diesel SCE at Navistar, and 2.44-liter DI diesel SCE and Cooperative Fuel Research (CFR) engine at National Research Council Canada (NRCC). The engine operating conditions of the six experimental programs can be categorized into one conventional diesel combustion (CDC), two homogeneous-charge compression ignition (HCCI), and three low-temperature combustion (LTC) modes. All six programs agreed that CN exhibited the strongest impacts on both combustion and emissions among the three design variables. As expected lower CN fuels exhibited longer ignition delay, which provided longer mixing periods. However, effects of aromatics were rather inconsistent in the engine experiments. In the HCCI studies higher aromatics fuels exhibited higher soot but little effect on NOx. In the two LTC studies higher aromatics and lower CN fuels exhibited higher NO<sub>X</sub>, whereas the aromatic impact on soot production was negligible. T90 effects were similar to those of CN, but at a lesser magnitude. Higher T90 fuels exhibited longer ignition delay in all experiments.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakakita, K., Ban, H., Takasu, S., Hotta, Y. et al., “Effect of Hydrocarbon Molecular Structure in Diesel Fuel on In-Cylinder Soot Formation and Exhaust Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1914, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1914.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takahashi, S., Wakimoto, K., Iida, N., and Nikolic, D., “Effects of Aromatics Content and 90% Distillation Temperature of Diesel Fuels on Flame Temperature and Soot Formation,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1940, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1940.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kee, S., Mohammadi, A., Kidoguchi, Y., and Miwa, K., “Effects of Aromatic Hydrocarbons on Fuel Decomposition and Oxidation Processes in Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2086, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alnajjar, M., Cannella, B., Dettman, H., Fairbridge, C., Franz, J., Gallant, T., Gieleciak, R., Hager, D., Lay, C., Lewis, S., Ratcliff, M., Sluder, S., Storey, J., Yin, H., and Zigler, B., “Chemical and Physical Properties of the Fuels For Advanced Combustion Engines (FACE) Research Diesel Fuels,” CRC Report FACE-1, Coordinating Research Council, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bunting, B., Eaton, S., and Crawford, R., “Performance Evaluation and Optimization of Diesel Fuel Properties and Chemistry in an HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2645, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-2645.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hosseini, V., Neill, W., Guo, H., Dumitrescu, C. et al., “Effects of Cetane Number, Aromatic Content and 90% Distillation Temperature on HCCI Combustion of Diesel Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2168, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2168.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cho, K., Han, M., Sluder, C., Wagner, R. et al., “Experimental Investigation of the Effects of Fuel Characteristics on High Efficiency Clean Combustion in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2669, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2669.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dumitrescu, C. E., Neill, W. S., Guo, H., Hosseini, V., Chippior, W. L., “Fuel Property Effects on PCCI Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine”, ASME Internal Combustion Engine Fall Technical Conference, ICEF2010-35194, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Ojeda, W., Bulicz, T., Han, X., Zheng, M. et al., “Impact of Fuel Properties on Diesel Low Temperature Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):188-201, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0329.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bunce, M., Bunting, B., Wang, J., and Crawford, R., “Experimental and Statistical Comparison of Engine Response as a Function of Fuel Chemistry and Properties in CI and HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0857, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0857.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
