<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24910563</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>International/Cross-Cultural Effects in Organizational Decision Making</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Matos</surname>
                  <given-names>Rafael E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Mr. Rafael E. Matos was born in San Juan, Puerto Rico. He obtained a bachelor of science degree in natural sciences from the University of Puerto Rico, and a master of science degree in operations analysis from the Naval Postgraduate School. Mr. Matos is currently a consultant for Whitney, Bradley &amp; Brown Consulting. He is a key member of the Operational Concepts and Analysis sector, lead modeler and architect in the modeling and simulation center of excellence, and the lead instructor for the WBB Operations Analysis Training Course. His areas of expertise are statistical analysis, modeling and simulation, decision analysis, and organizational decision support facilitation. Mr. Matos is MORS’ Vice-President for Member Services. He co-chairs the MORS Human Behavior and Performance Working Group and is a contributor to the Decision Analysis and Computational Social Sciences Working Groups. He is also a member of the American Psychological Association, the Society for Industrial and Organizational Psychology, INFORMS, the Military Officers of America Association (MOAA), and the National Society for Hispanic Professionals (NSHP). Currently Mr. Matos is completing the requirements for a doctoral degree in organizational psychology at Walden University.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>JUNE 2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>44</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e24910547</issue-id>
         <fpage>27</fpage>
         <lpage>33</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2011, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24910563"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adler, N. and Gunderson, A. (2008). International Dimensions of Organizational Behavior (5th ed.). Cincinnati, OH: Southwestern.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baker, J. C. (1975). An analysis of how the US multinational company considers the wife of American expatriate managers. Academy of Management Proceedings, 35, 258-260.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bhatta, G. D., and Doppler, W. (2010). Farming differentiation in the rural-urban interface of the middle mountains, Nepal: Application of analytic hierarchy process (AHP) modeling. Journal of Agricultural Science, 2(4), 37-51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brenner, S. N., and Molander, E. A. (1977). Is the ethics of business changing. Harvard Business Review, 55(1), 57-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brooks, M. E., Highhouse, S., Russell, S. S., and Mohr, D. C (2003). Familiarity, ambivalence, and firm reputation: Is corporate fame a double-edged sword? Journal of Applied Psychology, 88(5), 904-915.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cabantous, L., Gond, J., and Johnson-Cramer, M. (2010). Decision Theory as Practice: Crafting Rationality in Organizations. Organization Studies, 31(11), 1531–1566.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Department of Defense (2010). Department of Defense Fiscal Year (FY) 2011 President’s Budget. Exhibit R-2A, Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation (RDT&amp;E) Project Justification. Retrieved from on January 9, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dewey, J. (1933). How we think. Boston, Massachusets: D.C. Health.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Driver, M. J. (1979). Individual decision making and creativity, in Kerr, S. Organizational Behavior. Columbus, Ohio: Grid Publishing, 59-91.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Du-Babcock, B. 2006. An analysis of topic management and turn-taking behavior in the Hong Kong bilingual environment: The impact of culture and language use. Journal of Business Communication, 43(1), 21–42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dyer, J. R., Johansson, A., Helbing, D., Couzin, I. D., Krause, J. (2009). Leadership, consensus decision making and collective behaviour in humans. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society, 364(1518), 781-789.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eagan, P. and Weinberg, L. (1999). Application of analytic hierarchy process techniques to streamlined life-cycle analysis of two anodizing processes. Environment Science and Technology, 33(9), 1495-1500.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Early, P., and Erez, M. (eds) (1997). New Perspectives on International Industrial/Organizational Psychology. San Francisco, CA, US: Pfeiffer.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goldratt, E. M. (1992). An introduction to theory of constraints: The production approach. New Haven, CT: Avraham Y. Goldratt Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graham, J. L. (1985). The influence of culture on the process of business negotiations: An exploratory study. Journal of International Business Studies, 16(1), 81–96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graham, J. L. (2004). A linguistic-based measure of cultural distance and its relationship to managerial values. Management International Review, 44(3), 239–261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gyllenhammar, P. G. (1977). How Volvo adapts work to people. Harvard Business Review, 55(4), 102-113.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guilfoyle, D. (2008). Piracy off Somalia: UN security council resolution 1816 and IMO regional counter-piracy efforts. International and Comparative Law Quarterly, 57(3), 690-699.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guilfoyle, D. (2010). Counter-piracy law enforcement and human rights. International &amp; Comparative Law Quarterly, 59(1),141-169.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hersh, M. A. (1999). Sustainable decision making: The role of decision support systems. IEEE Transactions on systems, man, and cybernetics—part c: Applications and reviews, 29(3), 395-408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kahneman, D., Slovic, P., and Tversky, A. (1982), Judgment under uncertainty: Heuristics and biases. Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keeney, R., and McDaniels, T. L. (1992). Value-focused thinking about strategic decisions at BC Hydro. Interfaces, 22(6), 94–109.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matos, R. E. (2010). Cognitive psychology and decision analysis methods. Final academic term paper for PSYC-8237, Cognitive Psychology. Walden University. Morton, A., and Fasolo, B. (2009).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Behavioural decision theory for multicriteria decision analysis: A guided tour. Journal of the Operational Research Society, 60(2), 268-275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dixon, J. C., and Rosenbaum, M. S. (2004). Nice to Know You? Testing Contact, Cultural, and Group Threat Theories of Anti-Black and Anti-Hispanic Stereotypes. Social Science Quarterly, 85(2), 257-280.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pollock, S. M., and Chen, K. (1986). Strive to conquer the black stink: Decision analysis in the People’s Republic of China. Interfaces 16(2), 31–37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Porter, T. M. (1996). Making Things Quantitative. In Accounting and Science: Natural Inquiry and Commercial Reason. New York: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Poyhonen, M., and Hamalainen, R. P. (2000). There is hope in attribute weighting. INFOR, 38(3), 272-282.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Raiffa, H. (2002). Decision analysis: A personal account of how it got started and evolved. Operations Research, 50(1). 179–185.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Su, S. (2006). Cultural differences in determining the ethical perception and decision making of future accounting professionals: A comparison between accounting students from Taiwan and the United States. Journal of American Academy of Business, 9(1), 147-158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Whitaker, R. (2007). Validation examples of the analytic hierarchy process and analytic network process. Mathematical and Computer Modeling, 46(7-8), 840-859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Winn, M. I., (2001). Building stakeholder theory with a decision modeling methodology. Business and Society, 40(2), 133-166.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
