<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i24464784</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24464822</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Informational Holdup and Performance Persistence in Venture Capital</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Yael V.</given-names>
                  <surname>Hochberg</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alexander</given-names>
                  <surname>Ljungqvist</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Annette</given-names>
                  <surname>Vissing-Jørgensen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>102</fpage>
         <lpage>152</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24464822"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Why don't VCs eliminate excess demand for follow-on funds by raising fees? We propose a model of learning that leads to informational holdup. Current investors learn about skill whereas outside investors observe only returns. This gives current investors holdup power when the VC raises his next fund: Without their backing, no-one will fund him, as outside investors interpret the lack of backing as a sign of low skill. Holdup power diminishes the VC's ability to increase fees in line with performance, leading to return persistence. Empirical evidence supports the model. We estimate that up to two-thirds of VC firms lack skill.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d64e229a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e236" publication-type="other">
For empirical evidence of the importance of soft information in learning about corporate managers' skill, see
Cornelli, Kominek, and Ljungqvist (2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e246a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e253" publication-type="other">
Lerner, Schoar, and Wongsunwai (2007) note that "Reinvestment decisions by LPs are particularly important in
the private equity industry, where information about the quality of different private equity groups is more difficult
to learn and often restricted to existing investors." Lerner and Schoar (2004) argue that LPs typically demand
wide-ranging information rights to inform their reinvestment decision. Chung et al. (2012) use a learning model
to calibrate the incentive effects of future fundraising in the VC market.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e272a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e279" publication-type="other">
Blaydon and Horvath (2002) document that absent agreed valuation standards in the VC industry, different VC
funds report radically different valuations for the same portfolio companies at a given point in time.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e289a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e296" publication-type="other">
Ljungqvist, Richardson, and Wolfenzon (2007) model agency problems among fund managers in a learning
setting.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e307a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e314" publication-type="other">
The log function captures decreasing returns to scale. This is similar to Berk and Green's (2004) assumption for
mutual funds.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e324a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e331" publication-type="other">
Our two-fund setup is intended to capture the two key "periods" in institutional reality—the period in which
everyone lacks good information about the VC's true skill (the "first fund") and a subsequent period when
insiders, due to their access as LPs, have managed to learn the VC's true skill through gathering soft information
(the "follow-on fund"). In practice, a VC may need to raise more than one "first fund" before his skill is revealed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e347a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e354" publication-type="other">
The normal distribution of cash flows and the uniform distribution of GP types allow us to obtain more closed-
form solutions but do not qualitatively drive our results. The more important choice is the functional form of the
relation between cash flows and investment, which requires a functional form whereby C3//1 is increasing in
GP type /x' even when I\ is chosen optimally to reflect GP skill.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e370a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e377" publication-type="other">
While modeling the optimal number of LPs would make the model intractable, the intuition for why multiple
informed LPs do not compete away their holdup power does not, as we will show, depend on the number of LPs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e387a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e394" publication-type="other">
In practice, LPs typically contribute 99% of a fund's capital, with the GP providing the remainder.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e401a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e408" publication-type="other">
Having incumbent LPs learn the GP's skill perfectly at / = 1 is stronger than necessary. All that is required for
our results to go through is that incumbent LPs receive a more precise signal at t = 1 than do outside investors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e419a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e426" publication-type="other">
Fees in VC contracts are usually expressed in percentage terms. For tractability, we model fees in dollars. Once
the optimal fund size has been derived, one can easily calculate the implied percentage fee.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e436a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e443" publication-type="other">
Restricting incumbent LP offers to supply either half or all of the capital for the follow-on fund simplifies the
analysis, while allowing the LPs to compete against each other. Given the parallels between our setup and the
procurement setup of Anton and Yao (1989), our results should be robust to allowing for splits other than a half.
This is because each LP effectively can veto any split other than the most collusive one by offering the GP a very
unattractive fee for providing his share of the funds. See Anton and Yao (1989, 539) for an example that shows
that results on supplier collusion do not hinge on restricting offers to be for either half or all of the amount.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e466a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e473" publication-type="other">
In the VC setting, this could capture the possibility that the GP's network contacts become stale while he is
fundraising or that another GP makes deals with the relevant entrepreneurs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e483a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e490" publication-type="other">
While the Appendix proves that the above is a subgame perfect equilibrium, we cannot prove uniqueness. If one
restricted GP and LP strategies to split offers, then the equilibrium in Proposition 1 would be unique, following
the argument given in the proof of Result 1 in Binmore, Osborne, and Rubinstein (1992). However, the possibility
that the parties can make sole offers complicates the setting so that we are unable to prove uniqueness.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e506a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e513" publication-type="other">
The risk-adjustment is defined as the reduction in expected return such that each LP would be
indifferent between earning the actual ry-0//0u,_0„ finai and earning a riskless return equal to
^(rfollow-on, final^rfirst, interim'l1' &gt; ^ ^\,split^r first, interim' ^ &gt; ^ )"</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e526a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e533" publication-type="other">
Because only a small amount of information asymmetry is required to induce outside investors to withdraw from
the market, it does not matter whether the information asymmetry is reduced over time as the performance of
later funds is observed. What matters is simply that the information asymmetry remains positive.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e547a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e554" publication-type="other">
An alternative version of informational dynamics which retains persistence beyond second funds involves the
(realistic) possibility that a GP's skill may change gradually over time. This could happen if, for example, the
GP team changes over time as some general partners retire and new ones are hired. Then as long as incumbents
are always better informed about the GP team's current skill, outside investors will choose not to participate in
third and later funds so that the incumbent LPs retain their informational holdup over the GP.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e573a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e580" publication-type="other">
We define all funds listed as focusing on start-up, early-stage, development, late-stage, or expansion investments,
and those listed as "venture (general)" or "balanced" funds as VC funds. Where VE and PREQIN classify a fund
differently, we verify fund type using secondary sources, such as Pratt's Guide, CapitallQ, Galante 's, and a Web
search. We screen out funds of funds, buyout funds, hedge funds, venture leasing funds, evergreen funds (i.e.,
funds without a predetermined dissolution date), corporate VCs, bank-affiliated funds, SBICs, side funds, and
foreign VCs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e603a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e610" publication-type="other">
VE has the better coverage. Of the 2,257 sample funds, 729 appear in both VE and PREQIN, 37 appear only in
PREQIN, and the remaining 1,491 appear only in VE.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e620a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e627" publication-type="other">
While 1980 is our first sample year, not all 1980 vintage funds in the sample are first-time funds. This reflects
the fact that our sample contains VC firms founded prior to 1980.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e637a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e644" publication-type="other">
Defunct VC firms are those CapitallQ labels "out of business," "dissolved," "liquidating," "no longer investing,"
or "reorganizing." We also assume that firms that last raised a fund in 2002 or earlier are defunct as of 2012.
Some of these are listed in CapitallQ as having "launched" a fund in, say 2004, but evidently without success.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e657a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e664" publication-type="other">
As Ljungqvist and Richardson (2003) show, over a fund's life, performance follows a "J-curve," in the sense
that cash-on-cash IRRs in respect of exited investments (rather than reported interim IRRs based on unrealized
investments) tend to be negative in the first few years as the fund is mainly in investment mode and then turn
positive after five or six years as the fund begins to exit its investments through IPOs or M&amp;A transactions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e681a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e688" publication-type="other">
The data are thus skewed to the right. However, winsorizing the data does not materially affect our results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e695a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e702" publication-type="other">
We have more than 10x944 fund-years because VE and PREQIN report IRRs beyond a fund's tenth anniversary.
Usually, IRRs change little after year 10.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e712a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e719" publication-type="other">
For this reason, VE and PREQIN often mark IRRs as "not meaningful" in the first 2-3 years of a fund's life.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e726a1310">
            <label>2^</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e733" publication-type="other">
Note that there are no apparent performance differences between funds for which we do and do not have interim
IRRs: both return between 15% and 16% a year on average over their lifetimes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e743a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e750" publication-type="other">
Important learning milestones, in practice, are whether the GP managed to find enough deals to deploy all his
capital and whether any of the deals could be successfully exited.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e760a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e767" publication-type="other">
In the model, once the GP's skill is known to the GP and the incumbent LPs, fund size is a sufficient statistic for
skill. In practice, fund size may not fully reveal skill for a variety of reasons. We follow standard practice and
control for log fund size in our empirical specifications.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e781a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e788" publication-type="other">
This remains the case if we condition not only on the prior fund's interim IRR but on hard information relating to
the performance of all the funds the GP managed before. For example, the coefficient on a variable capturing the
highest return the GPever achieved before the prior fund is insignificant (p=0.381), and including this variable
has next to no effect on the point estimates of the prior fund's interim and final IRRs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e804a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e811" publication-type="other">
Another potential confound is due to the fact that funds overlap in time and so are subject to similar economic
conditions. This affects ex post IRRs, but, by construction, not interim IRRs at fundraising.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e821a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e828" publication-type="other">
This echoes the findings of Kaplan and Schoar (2005), who show that ex post IRRs predict fundraising outcomes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e835a1310">
            <label>34</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e842" publication-type="other">
Exactly why such expected return smoothing would be used is not clear in this story.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d64e858a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e862" publication-type="other">
Anton, J., and D. Yao. 1989. Split awards, procurement, and innovation. RAND Journal of Economics 20:538-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e869a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e873" publication-type="other">
Berk, J., and R. Green. 2004. Mutual fund flows and performance in rational markets. Journal of Political
Economy</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e883a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e887" publication-type="other">
Binmore, K., A. Rubinstein, and A. Wolinsky. 1986. The Nash bargaining solution in economic modelling. RAND
Journal of Economics 17:176-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e897a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e901" publication-type="other">
Binmore, K., M. J. Osborne, and A. Rubinstein. 1992. Non-cooperative models of bargaining. In Handbook of
game theory with economic applications, Vol. 1. Eds. R. J. Aumann and S. Hart. Amsterdam, The Netherlands:
North Holland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e915a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e919" publication-type="other">
Blaydon, C., and M. Horvath. 2002. What's a company worth? Depends which GP you ask. Venture Capital
Journal May:40-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e929a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e933" publication-type="other">
Chung, J. W., B. A. Sensoy, L. H. Stern, and M. S. Weisbach. 2012. Pay for performance from future fund flows:
The case of private equity. Review of Financial Studies 25:3259-304.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e943a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e947" publication-type="other">
Comelli, F., Z. Kominek, and A. Ljungqvist. 2013. Monitoring managers: Does it matter? Journal of Finance
68:431-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e957a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e961" publication-type="other">
Da Rin, M., and L. Phalippou. 2011. On the heterogeneity of private equity investors. Working Paper, Oxford
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e971a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e975" publication-type="other">
Glode, V., and R. Green. 2011. Information spillovers and performance persistence for hedge funds. Journal of
Financial Economics 101:1-17.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e985a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e989" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P. A. 1996. Grandstanding in the venture capital industry. Journal of Financial Economics 43:133-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e997a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1001" publication-type="other">
Hochberg, Y. V., Ljungqvist A., and Y. Lu. 2007. Whom you know matters: Venture capital networks and
investment performance. Journal of Finance 62:251-301.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1011a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1015" publication-type="other">
Jones, C., and M. Rhodes-Kropf. 2003. The price of diversifiable risk in venture capital and private equity.
Working Paper, Columbia University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1025a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1029" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S. N., and A. Schoar. 2005. Private equity performance: Returns, persistence, and capital flows. Journal
of Finance 61:1791-823.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1039a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1043" publication-type="other">
Lerner, J., and A. Schoar. 2004. The illiquidity puzzle: Evidence from private equity partnerships. Journal of
Financial Economics 72:3-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1053a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1057" publication-type="other">
Lerner, J., A. Schoar, and W. Wongsunwai. 2007. Smart institutions, foolish choices? The limited partner
performance puzzle. Journal of Finance 62:731-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1067a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1071" publication-type="other">
Ljungqvist, A., and M. Richardson. 2003. The cash flow, return, and risk characteristics of private equity. Working
Paper, NBER No. 9454.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1082a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1086" publication-type="other">
Ljungqvist, A., M. Richardson, and D. Wolfenzon. 2007. The investment behavior of buyout fund managers.
Working Paper, New York University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1096a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1100" publication-type="other">
Malkiel, B. G 1995. Returns from investing in equity mutual funds 1971-1991. Journal of Finance 50:549-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1107a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1111" publication-type="other">
Rajan, R. 1992. Insiders and outsiders: The choice between informed and arm's length debt. Journal of Finance
47:1367-400.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1121a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1125" publication-type="other">
Rubinstein, A. 1982. Perfect equilibrium in a bargaining model. Econometrica 50:97-109.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1132a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1136" publication-type="other">
Sharpe, S. A. 1990. Asymmetric information, bank lending and implicit contracts: A stylized model of customer
relationships. Journal of Finance 45:1069-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1146a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1150" publication-type="other">
Sorensen, M., N. Wang, and J. Yang. 2012. Valuing private equity. Working Paper, Columbia University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


