<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i40026502</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40604819</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Market Price of Aggregate Risk and the Wealth Distribution</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>YiLi</given-names>
                  <surname>Chien</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Hanno</given-names>
                  <surname>Lustig</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2010</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1596</fpage>
         <lpage>1650</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2010 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40604819"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We introduce limited liability in a model with a continuum of ex ante identical agents who face aggregate and idiosyncratic income risk. These agents can trade a complete menu of contingent claims, but they cannot commit to honor their promises, and their shares in a Lucas tree serve as collateral to back up their state-contingent promises. The limited-liability option gives rise to a second risk factor, in addition to aggregate consumption growth risk.This liquidity risk is created by binding solvency constraints, and it is measured by the growth rate of one moment of the wealth distribution. The economy is said to experience a negative liquidity shock when this growth rate is high and a large fraction of agents faces severely binding solvency constraints. The adjustment to the Breeden-Lucas stochastic discount factor induces substantial time variation in equity risk-premims that is consistent with the data at business cycle frequencies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d17e210a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d17e217" publication-type="other">
Verarcierto (1998)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d17e224a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d17e231" publication-type="other">
He and Modest 1995</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d17e237" publication-type="other">
Grossman and Shiller 1982</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d17e244a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d17e251" publication-type="other">
Zhang (1997)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d17e258a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d17e265" publication-type="other">
Detemple and Serrat (2003)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d17e273a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d17e280" publication-type="other">
Krueger and Uhlig (2005)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d17e287a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d17e294" publication-type="other">
Telmer, and Yaron (2007)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d17e301a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d17e308" publication-type="other">
Pastor and Stambaugh (2003)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>Reference</title>
        <ref id="d17e324a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e328" publication-type="other">
Abel, A. B. 1999. Risk Premia and Term Premia in General Equilibrium. Journal of Monetary Economics
43:3-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e338a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e342" publication-type="other">
Acharya, V. V., and L. H. Pedersen. 2005. Asset Pricing with Liquidity Risk. Journal of Financial Economics
77:375^*10.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e352a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e356" publication-type="other">
Aiyagari, S. R., and M. Gertler. 1991. Asset Returns with Transaction Costs and Uninsured Individual Risk.
Journal of Monetary Economics 27:311-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e366a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e370" publication-type="other">
Alvarez, F., and U. Jermann. 2000. Efficiency, Equilibrium, and Asset Pricing with Risk of Default. Econometrica
68:775-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e381a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e385" publication-type="other">
Alvarez, F., and U. Jermann. 2001. Quantitative Asset Pricing Implications of Endogenous Solvency Constraints.
Review of Financial Studies 14:1117-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e395a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e399" publication-type="other">
Amihud, Y., and H. Mendelson. 1986. Asset Pricing and the Bid-Ask Spread. Journal of Financial Economics
17:223-^*9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e409a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e413" publication-type="other">
Anderson, E. 1998. Uncertainty and the Dynamics of Pareto Optimal Allocations. 1998. Working Paper, Univer
sity of North Carolina.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e423a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e427" publication-type="other">
Atkeson, Α., and R. E. Lucas. 1992. On Efficient Distribution with Private Information. Review of Economic
Studies 59:427-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e437a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e441" publication-type="other">
Atkeson, Α., and R. E. Lucas. 1995. Efficiency and Equality in a Simple Model of Unemployment Insurance.
Journal of Economic Theory 66:64-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e451a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e455" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., and A. Yaron. 2004. Risks for the Long-Run: A Potential Resolution of Asset Pricing Puzzles. Journal
of Finance 59:1481-509.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e466a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e470" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, G., R. Harvey, and Lundblad. 2007. Liquidity and Expected Returns: Lessons from Emerging
Markets. Review of Financial Sudies 20:1783-831.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e480a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e484" publication-type="other">
Breeden, D. T. 1979. An Intertemporal Asset Pricing Model with Stochastic Consumption and Investment
Opportunities. Journal of Financial Economics 7:265-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e494a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e498" publication-type="other">
Brennan, M. J., and A. Subrahmanyam. 1996. Market Microstructure and Asset Pricing: On the Compensation
for Illiquidity in Stock Returns. Journal of Financial Economics 41:441-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e508a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e512" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., and J. H. Cochrane. 1999. By Force of Habit: A Consumption-Based Explanation of Aggregate
Stock Market Behavior. Journal of Political Economy 107:205-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e522a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e526" publication-type="other">
Chien, Y., H. Cole, and H. Lustig. 2008. A Multiplier Approach to Understanding the Macro Implications of
Household Finance. http://ssrn.com/abstract=1023184.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e536a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e540" publication-type="other">
Cogley, T. 2002. Idiosyncratic Risk and the Equity Premium: Evidence from the Consumer Expenditure Survey.
Journal of Monetary Economics 49:309-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e551a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e555" publication-type="other">
Constantinides, G. M., and D. Duffie. 1996. Asset Pricing with Heterogeneous Consumers. Journal of Political
Economy 104:219-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e565a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e569" publication-type="other">
Detemple, J., and A. Serrat. 2003. Dynamic Equilibrium and Liquidity Constraints. Review of Financial Studies
16:597-629.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e579a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e583" publication-type="other">
Epstein, L., and S. Zin. 1989. Substitution, Risk Aversion and the Temporal Behavior of Consumption and Asset
Returns: A Theoretical Framework. Econometrica 57:937-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e593a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e597" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and K. R. French. 1989. Business Conditions and Expected Returns on Stocks and Bonds. Journal
of Financial Economics 25:23-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e607a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e611" publication-type="other">
Geanakoplos, J., and W. R. Zame. 1998. Collateral, Default and Market Crashes. Working Paper, Yale and
University of California at Los Angeles.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e621a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e625" publication-type="other">
Goyenko, R. 2005. Stock and Bond Pricing with Liquidity Risk. Working Paper, Indiana University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e633a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e637" publication-type="other">
Grossman, S., and R. Shiller. 1982. Consumption Correlatedness and Risk Measurement in Economies with
Non-Traded Assets and Heterogeneous Information. Journal of Financial Economics 10:195-210.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e647a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e651" publication-type="other">
Hansen, L. P., and K. Singleton. 1982. Generalized Instrumental Variable Estimation of Nonlinear Rational
Expectation Models. Econometrica 50:1269-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e661a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e665" publication-type="other">
He, H., and D. M. Modest. 1995. Market Frictions and Consumption-Based Asset Pricing. Journal of Political
Economy 103:94-117.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e675a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e679" publication-type="other">
He, H., and N. Pearson. 1991. Consumption and Portfolio Choices with Incomplete Markets and Short-Sale
Constraints: The Infinite Dimensional Case. Journal of Economic Theory 54:259-304.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e689a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e693" publication-type="other">
Heaton, J., and D. Lucas. 1996. Evaluating the Effects of Incomplete Markets on Risk Sharing and Asset Pricing.
Journal of Political Economy 104:668-712.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e703a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e707" publication-type="other">
Holmstrom, B. R., and J. Tirole. 1998. LAPM: A Liquidity-Based Asset Pricing Model, http://ssrn.com/
abstract=123436.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e718a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e722" publication-type="other">
Jones, C. A. 2002. A Century of Stock Market Liquidity and Trading Costs. Working Paper, Columbia University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e729a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e733" publication-type="other">
Kehoe, T., and D. K. Levine. 1993. Debt Constrained Asset Markets. Review of Economic Studies 60:856-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e740a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e744" publication-type="other">
Kocherlakota, N. 1996. Implications of Efficient Risk Sharing without Commitment. Review of Economic Studies
63:595-610.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e754a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e758" publication-type="other">
Kreps, D., and E. L. Porteus. 1978. Temporal Resolution of Uncertainty and Dynamic Choice Theory. Econo-
metrica 46:185-200.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e768a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e772" publication-type="other">
Krueger, D. 1999. Risk Sharing in Economies with Incomplete Markets. PhD dissertation, University of
Minnesota.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e782a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e786" publication-type="other">
Krueger, D., and H. Lustig. 2007. When Is Market Incompleteness Irrelevant for the Price of Aggregate Risk
(And When Is It Not)? http://ssrn.com/abstract=954149.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e797a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e801" publication-type="other">
Krueger, D., and H. Uhlig. 2005. Competitive Risk Sharing with One-Sided Commitment. Journal of Monetary
Economics 53:1661-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e811a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e815" publication-type="other">
Kubler, F., and K. Schmedders. 2003. Stationary Equilibria in Asset-Pricing Models with Incomplete Markets
and Collateral. Econometrica 71:1767-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e825a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e829" publication-type="other">
Lettau, M. 2002. Idiosyncratic Risk and Volatility Bounds, or Can Models with Idiosyncratic Risk Solve the
Equity Premium Puzzle? Review of Economics and Statistics 84:376-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e839a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e843" publication-type="other">
Lettau, M., and S. C. Ludvigson. 2001. Consumption, Aggregate Wealth and Expected Stock Returns. The
Journal of Finance 56:815-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e853a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e857" publication-type="other">
Lettau, M, and S. C. Ludvigson. 2008. Measuring and Modeling Variation in the Risk-Return Tradeoff. In Yacine
Ait-Sahalia and Lars Peter Hansen (eds.), Handbook of Financial Econometrics, p. 94. New York: Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e867a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e871" publication-type="other">
Lucas, D. 1994. Asset Pricing with Unidiversifiable Income Risk and Short Sales Constraints: Deepening the
Equity Premium Puzzle. Journal of Monetary Economics 34:325-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e882a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e886" publication-type="other">
Lucas, R. 1978. Asset Prices in an Exchange Economy. Econometrica 46:1429-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e893a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e897" publication-type="other">
Luenberger, D. G. 1969. Optimization by Vector Space Methods. New York: John Wiley and Sons.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e904a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e908" publication-type="other">
Lustig, H., and S. Van Nieuwerburgh. 2005. Housing Collateral, Consumption Insurance and Risk Premia: An
Empirical Perspective. Journal of Finance 60:1167-219.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e918a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e922" publication-type="other">
Lustig, H., and S. Van Nieuwerburgh. 2006. Can Housing Collateral Explain Long-Run Swings in Asset Returns?
Working Paper, University of California, Los Angeles, and New York University Stern School of Business.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e932a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e936" publication-type="other">
Lustig, H., and S. Van Nieuwerburgh, and A. Verdelhan. 2008. The Wealth-Consumption Ratio. SSRN:
http://ssrn.com/abstract=967432.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e946a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e950" publication-type="other">
Luttmer, E. 1992. Asset Pricing in Economies with Frictions. PhD dissertation, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e958a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e962" publication-type="other">
Marcet, A., and R. Marimon. 1999. Recursive Contracts. Working Paper, Universitat Pompeu Fabra.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e969a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e973" publication-type="other">
Mehra, R., and E. C. Prescott. 1985. The Equity Premium: A Puzzle. Journal of Monetary Economics 15:145-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e980a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e984" publication-type="other">
Pastor, L., and R. F. Stambaugh. 2003. Liquidity Risk and Expected Stock Returns. Journal of Political Economy
3:642-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e994a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e998" publication-type="other">
Rubinstein, M. 1974. An Aggregation Theorem for Securities Markets. Journal of Financial Economics 1:225-
44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e1008a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e1012" publication-type="other">
Stokey, N., R. E. Lucas, and E. C. Precott. 1989. Recursive Methods in Economic Dynamics. Cambridge, MA:
Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e1022a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e1026" publication-type="other">
Storesletten, K., C. Telmer, and A. Yaron. 2001. Asset Pricing with Idiosyncratic Risk and Overlapping Genera-
tions. Institute for International Economic Studies Seminar Paper No. 703.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e1037a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e1041" publication-type="other">
Storesletten, K., C. Telmer, and A. Yaron. 2004. Cyclical Dynamics in Idiosyncratic Labor-Market Risk. Journal
of Political Economy 112:695-717.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e1051a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e1055" publication-type="other">
Storesletten, K., C. Telmer, and A. Yaron. 2007. Asset Pricing with Idiosyncratic Risk and Overlapping Genera-
tions. Review of Economic Dynamics 10:519-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e1065a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e1069" publication-type="other">
Telmer, C. 1993. Asset-Pricing Puzzles and Inomplete Markets. Journal of Finance 48:1803-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e1076a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e1080" publication-type="other">
Verarcierto, M. 1998. Plant Level Irreversible Investment and Equilibrium Business Cycles. Working Paper,
Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e1090a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e1094" publication-type="other">
Wachter, J. 2005. A Consumption-Based Model of the Term Structure of Interest Rates. Journal of Financial
Economics 79:365-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d17e1104a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d17e1108" publication-type="other">
Zhang, H. H. 1997. Endogenous Borrowing Constraints with Incomplete Markets. Journal of Finance 52:2187-
209.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


