<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277719</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental Characterization of the Geometrical Shape of<italic>ks-hole</italic>and Comparison of its Fluid Dynamic Performance Respect to Cylindrical and<italic>k-hole</italic>Layouts</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Brusiani</surname>
                  <given-names>Federico</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bianchi</surname>
                  <given-names>Gian Marco</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Di Gioia</surname>
                  <given-names>Rita</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Magneti Marelli Powertrain SPA</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>September 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277710</issue-id>
         <fpage>1553</fpage>
         <lpage>1565</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277719"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Diesel engine performances are strictly correlated to the fluid dynamic characteristics of the injection system. Actual Diesel engines employ injector characterized by micro-orifices operating at injection pressure till 20MPa. These main injection characteristics resulted in the critical relation between engine performance and injector hole shape.</p>
            <p>In the present study, the authors’ attention was focused on the hole geometry influence on the main injector fluid dynamic characteristics. At this purpose, three different nozzle hole shapes were considered: cylindrical,<italic>k</italic>, and<italic>ks</italic>nozzle shapes.</p>
            <p>Because of the lack of information available about<italic>ks-hole</italic>real geometry, firstly it was completely characterized by the combined use of two non-destructive techniques. Secondly, all the three nozzle layouts were characterized from the fluid dynamic point of view by a fully transient CFD multiphase simulation methodology previously validated by the authors against experimental results. The experimental characterization of the<italic>ks-hole</italic>geometry was a mandatory task to assure a good numerical simulation accuracy.</p>
            <p>From the fluid dynamic point of view, the three nozzle layouts were compared by the average fluid dynamic conditions recorded on the nozzle hole outlet sections and by the cavitating flow evolution inside the injector hole themselves.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mahr, B., “Future and Potential of Diesel Injection Systems”, THIESEL 2002 Conference on Thermo- and Fluid-Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bianchi, G., Falfari, S., Brusiani, F., Pelloni, P. et al., “Numerical Investigation of Critical Issues in Multiple-Injection Strategy Operated by a New C.R. Fast-Actuation Solenoid Injector,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1236, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1236.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bianchi, G., Falfari, S., Brusiani, F., Pelloni, P. et al., “Advanced Modelling of a New Diesel Fast Solenoid Injector and Comparison with Experiments,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0019, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-0019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mulemane, A., Han, J., Lu, P., Yoon, S. et al., “Modeling Dynamic Behavior of Diesel Fuel Injection Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0536, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0536.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, F., Margot, X., Patouna, S., Ravet, F. et al., “A CFD Study of the Effect of the Needle Movement on the Cavitation Pattern of Diesel Injectors,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-24-0025, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-24-0025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Som, S., Aggarwal, S., El-Hannouny, E., and Longman, D., “Investigation of nozzle flow and cavitation characteristics in a diesel injector”, Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, vol. 132, no. 4, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NISHIDA, K., ZHANG, W., and MANABE, T., “Effects of Micro-Hole and Ultra-High Injection Pressure on Mixture Properties of D.I. Diesel Spray,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1890, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-1890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blessing, M., König, G., Krüger, C., Michels, U. et al., “Analysis of Flow and Cavitation Phenomena in Diesel Injection Nozzles and Its Effects on Spray and Mixture Formation,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1358, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1358.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, J., Lu, P., Xie, X., Lai, M. et al., “Investigation of Diesel Spray Primary Break-up and Development for Different Nozzle Geometries,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2775, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2775.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, L. and Ruiz, F., “Effect of Cavitation on Flow and Turbulence in Plain Orifice for High-Speed Atomization”, Atomization and Sprays, 1995. 5(6):pp. 569-584.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Soteriou, C., Andrews, R.J., Torres, N., Smith, M., and Kunkulagunta, R., “Through the Diesel Nozzle Hole - A Journey of Discovery II”. in Proc. ILASSEurope, Zurich, Switzerland, September 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Asi O. 2006, “Failure of a diesel engine injector nozzle by cavitation damage”, Engin. Failure Analysis 13 112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J, Pastor, J.V., Payri, R., Plazas, A. H., “Analysis of the Influence of Diesel Nozzle Geometry in the Injection Rate Characteristics,” J. Fluids Eng 2004; 126:63-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, R., Garcia, J.M., Salvador, F.J., Gimeno, J., “Using Spray Momentum Flux Measurements to Understand the Influence of Diesel Nozzle Geometry on Spray Characteristics,” Fuel 2005; 84:551-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brusiani, F., Negro, S., Bianchi, G., Moulai, M. et al., “Comparison of the Homogeneous Relaxation Model and a Rayleigh Plesset Cavitation Model in Predicting the Cavitating Flow Through Various Injector Hole Shapes,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1613, 2013, doi: 10.4271/2013-01-1613.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Product Information. Giessen: Werth Messtechnik, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baltes, H., Brand, O., Fedder, G.K., Hierold, C., Korvink, O., Tabata, D., “Microengineering of Metals and Ceramics: Part II,” Editor(s): Löhe Detlef, Haußelt Jürgen, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Macian, V., Bermudez, V., Payri, R., Gimeno, J., “New Technique for Determination of Internal Geometry of a Diesel Nozzle with the Use of Silicon Methodology,” Innovative Measurement Techniques Series: Part 3, March/April 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bianchi, G., Falfari, S., Brusiani, F., Pelloni, P. et al., “Numerical Investigation of Critical Issues in Multiple- Injection Strategy Operated by a New C.R. Fast-Actuation Solenoid Injector,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1236, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1236.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fluent v12 User Manual, Fluent Inc.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Versteeg, H.K., Malalasekera, W., “An Introduction to Computational Fluid Dynamics: The Finite Volume Method (2nd edition)”, Longman, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singhal, A. K., Li, H. Y., Athavale, M. M., and Jiang, Y., “Mathematical Basis and Validation of the Full Cavitation Model”, ASME FEDSM'01, New Orleans, Louisiana, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Winklhofer, E., Kull, E., Kelz, E., and Morozov, A., “Comprehensive hydraulic and flow field documentation in model throttle experiments under cavitation conditions,” 17th Annual Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems, Zurich, Switzerland, September 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mirosław Chorazewski, M., Dergal, F., Sawaya, T., Mokbel, I., Grolier J.P., Jose, J., “Thermophysical properties of Normafluid (ISO 4113) over wide pressure and temperature ranges,” Fuel Volume 105 2013 440 - 450.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Som, S., Ramirez, A.I., Longman, D.E., Aggarwal, S.K., Kastengren, A.L., El-Hannouny, E.M., “Effect of Nozzle Orifice Geometry on Spray, Combustion, and Emission Characteristics under Diesel Engine Conditions,” Fuel 90 (2011) pp. 1267-1276.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sallam, K. A., and Faeth, G. M., “Surface Properties During Primary Breakup of Turbulent Liquid Jets in Still Air”, AIAA Journal, Vol. 41, No. 8, August, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brusiani, F., Bianchi, G., and Tiberi, A., “Primary Breakup Model for Turbulent Liquid Jet Based on Ligament Evolution,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0460, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0460.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
