<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278210</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Hybrid Electric Vehicle Powertrain and Control Strategy Optimization to Maximize the Synergy with a Gasoline HCCI Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lawler</surname>
                  <given-names>Benjamin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ortiz-Soto</surname>
                  <given-names>Elliott</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gupta</surname>
                  <given-names>Rohit</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Peng</surname>
                  <given-names>Huei</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Filipi</surname>
                  <given-names>Zoran S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Michigan</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1115</fpage>
         <lpage>1126</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278210"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This simulation study explores the potential synergy between the HCCI engine system and three hybrid electric vehicle (HEV) configurations, and proposes the supervisory control strategy that maximizes the benefits of combining these two technologies. HCCI operation significantly improves fuel efficiency at part load, while hybridization aims to reduce low load/low speed operation. Therefore, a key question arises: are the effects of these two technologies additive or overlapping? The HEV configurations include two parallel hybrids with varying degrees of electrification, e.g. with a 5kW integrated starter/motor (“Mild”) and with a 10 kW electric machine (“Medium”), and a power-split hybrid. The engine is a dual-mode, SI-HCCI system and the engine map reflects the impact of HCCI on brake specific fuel consumption. The new HEV supervisory controller, called e-HCCI, is proposed considering two additional criteria: (i) maximize the time spent in the HCCI operating region, and (ii) minimize SI-HCCI mode transitions. The relative fuel economy improvements of using a dual-mode SI-HCCI engine over an SI engine for a conventional powertrain (non-hybrid) is 17%. When the dual-mode engine is used in the “Mild” HEV using the e-HCCI strategy, the percent improvement jumps to 35%. This indicates a strong synergy, and creates a very compelling case for the “Mild” parallel HEV w/ HCCI. Gains on a relative basis diminish somewhat with the “Medium” hybrid and significantly more with stronger power-split hybrids, as the latter typically moves engine load above the HCCI knock limit.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">An, F. and Santini, D.J., “Mass Impacts on Fuel Economies of Conventional vs. Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0572, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-0572.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ochiai, S. and Ohnuki, Y., “Description of the Hybrid Technology Mounted to Production Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3418, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3418.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hattori, N., Aoyama, S., Kitada, S., and Matsuo, I., “Functional Design of a Motor Integrated CVT for a Parallel HEV,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0753, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-0753.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Muta, K., Yamazaki, M., and Tokieda, J., “Development of New-Generation Hybrid System THS II - Drastic Improvement of Power Performance and Fuel Economy,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0064, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-0064.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jaura, A.K., Buschhaus, W., and Tamor, M.A., “Systems Approach in Achieving Higher Fuel Economy in Hybrid Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1585, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-1585.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tamai, G., Jeffers, M., Lo, C., Thurston, C. et al., “Development of the Hybrid System for the Saturn VUE Hybrid,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1502, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-1502.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stanglmaier, R.H., and Roberts, C.E., “Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI): Benefits, Compromises, and Future Engine Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3682, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-3682.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Epping, K., Aceves, S., Bechtold, R., and Dec, J., “The Potential of HCCI Combustion for High Efficiency and Low Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1923, 2002, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-1923.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hyvonen, J., Haraldsson, G., and Johansson, B., “Operating Range in a Multi-Cylinder HCCI Engine Using Variable Compression Ratio,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1829, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1829.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Delorme, A., Rousseau, A., Wallner, T., Ortiz-Soto, E., Babajimopoulos, A., Assamis, D., “Evaluation of Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Engine Fuel Savings for Various Electric Drive Powertrains”, EVS-25, Shenzhen, China, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.-C., Filipi, Z., Wang, Y., Louca, L. et al., “Integrated, Feed-Forward Hybrid Electric Vehicle Simulation in SIMULINK and its Use for Power Management Studies,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1334, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1334.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, J., “Modeling, Configuration and Control Optimization of Power-Split Hybrid Vehicles”, Ph.D. Dissertation, University of Michigan, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T., Rackmil, C.I., Keribar, R., and Jennings, M.J., “Model for Heat Transfer and Combustion in Spark Ignited Engines and Its Comparison with Experiments,” SAE Technical Paper 880198, 1988, doi: 10.4271/880198.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blizzard, N.C. and Keck, J.C., “Experimental and Theoretical Investigation of Turbulent Burning Model for Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 740191, 1974, doi: 10.4271/740191.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tabaczynski, R. J., Trinker, F.H., Shannon, B. A.S., “Further Refinement and Validation of a Turbulent Flame Propagation Model for Spark-Ignition Engines”, Combustion and Flame, 39(2), pp. 111-121</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hires, S.D., Tabaczynski, R.J., and Novak, J.M., “The Prediction of Ignition Delay and Combustion Intervals for a Homogeneous Charge, Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 780232, 1978, doi: 10.4271/780232.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, X., Wooldridge, M.S., Atreya, A., “An Experimental and Modeling Study of Iso-octane Ignition Delay Times under Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Conditions”, Combustion and Flame, 2005, 142, pp. 266-275</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mo, Y., “HCCI Heat Release Rate and Combustion Efficiency: A Coupled KIVA Multi-Zone Modeling Study”, PhD Dissertation, University of Michigan, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang, K., Babajimopoulos, A., Lavoie, G.A., Filipi, Z.S. et al., “Analysis of Load and Speed Transitions in an HCCI Engine Using 1-D Cycle Simulation and Thermal Networks,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1087, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-1087.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang, K., Lavoie, G.A., Babajimopoulos, A., Filipi, Z.S. et al., “Control of a Multi-Cylinder HCCI Engine During Transient Operation by Modulating Residual Gas Fraction to Compensate for Wall Temperature Effects,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0204, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang, J., Güralp, O., Filipi, Z., Assanis, D. et al., “New Heat Transfer Correlation for the HCCI Engine Derived from Measurements of Instantaneous Surface Heat Flux,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2996, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-2996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ortiz-Soto, E.A., “Dual-Mode SI-HCCI Operation for Improved Drive-Cycle Fuel-Economy: Modeling Framework Development and Implementation for Comparative Fuel- Economy Study,” MSE Thesis, University of Michigan, May 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babajimopoulos, A., Challa, V.S.S.P., Lavoie, G.A., Assanis, D.N., “Model-Based Assessment of Two Variable Cam Timing Strategies for HCCI Engines: Recompression vs. Rebreathing,” ICES2009-76103, Proceedings of the ASME Internal Combustion Engine Division, Milwaukee, WI</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun, R., Thomas, R., and Gray, C.L., “An HCCI Engine: Power Plant for a Hybrid Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0933, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0933.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santoso, H., Matthews, J., and Cheng, W.K., “Managing SI/HCCI Dual-Mode Engine Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0162, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0162.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jillian, A., Hardy, J.J., Heywood, J.B., and Kenney, T.E., “Fuel Economy Benefits and Aftertreatment Requirements of a Naturally Aspirated HCCI-SI Engine System,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1): 1263-1277, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2512.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Delorme, A., Rousseau, A., Wallner, T., “Evaluation of Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Engine Fuel Savings for Various Powertrains”, VSATT Meeting, January 6, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C., Filipi, Z., Loucas, L., Peng, H., Assanis, D., Stein, J., “Modeling and Control for a Medium-Duty Hybrid Electric Truck”, International Journal of Heavy Vehicle Systems, Vol. 11, Nos. 3/4*, 2004, pp. 349-370</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
