<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26794495</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Macroeconomic Applications of Sufficient Statistics</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Inequality and Aggregate Demand</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Auclert</surname>
                  <given-names>Adrien</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rognlie</surname>
                  <given-names>Matthew</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">110</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26794387</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>81</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26794495"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We explore the transmission mechanism of income inequality to output. In the short run, higher inequality reduces output because marginal propensities to consume are negatively correlated with incomes, but this effect is quantitatively small in the data and in our model. In the long run, the output effects of income inequality are small if inequality is caused by rising dispersion in individual fixed effects, but can be large if it is the manifestation of higher individual income risk. We formalize the connection between partial and general equilibrium effects, and show that the two are closely related under standard assumptions about the behavior of monetary policy. Our economy features a depressed long-run real interest rate, allowing us to quantify the potential contribution of income inequality to secular stagnation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Achdou, Yves, Jiequn Han, Jean-Michel Lasry, Pierre-Louis Lions, and Benjamin Moll, “Income and Wealth Distribution in Macroeconomics: A Continuous-Time Approach,” Manuscript, November 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Athreya, Kartik, Andrew Owens, and Felipe Schwartzman, “Does Redistribution Increase Output? The Centrality of Labor Supply,” Quantitative Economics, October 2017, 8 (3), 761-808.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Auclert, Adrien, “Monetary Policy and the Redistribution Channel,” Manuscript, May 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Auclert, Adrien and Matthew Rognlie, “Aggregate Demand and the Top 1 Percent,” American Economic Review Papers and Proceedings, May 2017, 107 (5), 588–592.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Auclert, Adrien and Matthew Rognlie, “A Note on Multipliers in NK Models with GHH Preferences,” Manuscript, August 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Auclert, Adrien, Matthew Rognlie, and Ludwig Straub, “The Intertemporal Keynesian Cross,” Manuscript, December 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Autor, David H., David Dorn, and Gordon H. Hanson, “The China Syndrome: Local Labor Market Effects of Import Competition in the United States,” American Economic Review, 2013, 103 (6), 2121–68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Barkai, Simcha, “Declining Labor and Capital Shares,” Manuscript, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Basu, Susanto and Brent Bundick, “Uncertainty Shocks in a Model of Effective Demand,” Econometrica, May 2017, 85 (3), 937–958.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Bayer, Christian, Ralph Lütticke, Lien Pham-Dao, and Volker von Tjaden, “Precautionary Savings, Illiquid Assets, and the Aggregate Consequences of Shocks to Household Income Risk,” Manuscript, May 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Berger, David, Veronica Guerrieri, Guido Lorenzoni, and Joseph Vavra, “House Prices and Consumer Spending,” Review of Economic Studies, 2018, Forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Bernanke, Ben S., Mark Gertler, and Simon Gilchrist, “Chapter 21 – The Financial Accelerator in a Quantitative Business Cycle Framework,” in John B. Taylor and MichaelWoodford, eds., Handbook of Macroeconomics, Vol. 1, Part C, Elsevier, 1999, pp. 1341–1393.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Bewley, Truman, “The Permanent Income Hypothesis: A Theoretical Formulation,” Journal of Economic Theory, December 1977, 16 (2), 252–292.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Blanchard, Olivier Jean and Charles M. Kahn, “The Solution of Linear Difference Models under Rational Expectations,” Econometrica, July 1980, 48 (5), 1305–1311.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Blinder, Alan S., “Distribution Effects and the Aggregate Consumption Function,” Journal of Political Economy, June 1975, 83 (3), 447–475.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Boar, Corina, “Dynastic Precautionary Savings,” Manuscript, February 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Bohn, Henning, “The Behavior of U.S. Public Debt and Deficits,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1998, 113 (3), 949–963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Browning, Martin and Annamaria Lusardi, “Household Saving: Micro Theories and Micro Facts,” Journal of Economic Literature, December 1996, 34 (4), 1797–1855.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Card, David, Jörg Heining, and Patrick Kline, “Workplace Heterogeneity and the Rise ofWest GermanWage Inequality,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, August 2013, 128 (3), 967–1015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Carroll, Christopher D. and Andrew A. Samwick, “The Nature of Precautionary Wealth,” Journal of Monetary Economics, September 1997, 40 (1), 41–71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Cesarini, David, Erik Lindqvist, Matthew J. Notowidigdo, and Robert Östling, “The Effect of Wealth on Individual and Household Labor Supply: Evidence from Swedish Lotteries,” American Economic Review, December 2017, 107 (12), 3917–3946.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Challe, Edouard, Julien Matheron, Xavier Ragot, and Juan F. Rubio-Ramirez, “Precautionary Saving and Aggregate Demand,” Quantitative Economics, July 2017, 8 (2), 435–478.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Chetty, Raj, Adam Guren, Day Manoli, and AndreaWeber, “Are Micro and Macro Labor Supply Elasticities Consistent? A Review of Evidence on the Intensive and Extensive Margins,” American Economic Review Papers and Proceedings, 2011, 101 (3), 471–75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Coibion, Olivier, Yuriy Gorodnichenko, and Johannes Wieland, “The Optimal Inflation Rate in New Keynesian Models: Should Central Banks Raise Their Inflation Targets in Light of the Zero Lower Bound?,” Review of Economic Studies, October 2012, 79 (4), 1371–1406.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Coibion, Olivier, Yuriy Gorodnichenko, Lorenz Kueng, and John Silvia, “Innocent Bystanders? Monetary Policy and Inequality,” Journal of Monetary Economics, June 2017, 88, 70–89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Congressional Budget Office, The Distribution of Household Income and Federal Taxes in 2006 November 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Council Of Economic Advisers, Economic Report of the President, Washington, D.C.: U.S. Government Printing Office, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">de Loecker, Jan and Jan Eeckhout, “The Rise of Market Power and the Macroeconomic Implications,” Working Paper 23687, National Bureau of Economic Research, August 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">den Haan, Wouter J., Pontus Rendahl, and Markus Riegler, “Unemployment (Fears) and Deflationary Spirals,” Journal of the European Economic Association, 2018, Forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Eggertsson, Gauti B., “What Fiscal Policy Is Effective at Zero Interest Rates?,” NBER Macroeconomics Annual, January 2011, 25 (1), 59–112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Eggertsson, Gauti B., Neil R. Mehrotra, and Jacob A. Robbins, “A Model of Secular Stagnation: Theory and Quantitative Evaluation,”Working Paper 23093, National Bureau of Economic Research January 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Fagereng, Andreas, Martib B. Holm, and Gisle J. Natvik, “MPC Heterogeneity and Household Balance Sheets,”Working Paper 2861053, SSRN, October 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Favilukis, Jack, “Inequality, Stock Market Participation, and the Equity Premium,” Journal of Financial Economics, March 2013, 107 (3), 740–759.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Feenstra, Robert C. and Gordon H. Hanson, “The Impact of Outsourcing and High- Technology Capital on Wages: Estimates for the United States, 1979-1990,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1999, 114 (3), 907–940.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Francese, Maura and Carlos Mulas-Granados, “Functional Income Distribution and Its Role in Explaining Inequality,” IMF Working Paper no 15/244, November 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Galí, Jordi and Roberto Perotti, “Fiscal Policy and Monetary Integration in Europe,” Economic Policy, October 2003, 18 (37), 533–572.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Garicano, Luis and Esteban Rossi-Hansberg, “Inequality and the Organization of Knowledge,” American Economic Review, 2004, 94 (2), 197–202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Gilchrist, Simon and Charles P. Himmelberg, “Evidence on the Role of Cash Flow for Investment,” Journal of Monetary Economics, December 1995, 36 (3), 541–572.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Gornemann, Nils, Keith Kuester, and Makoto Nakajima, “Doves for the Rich, Hawks for the Poor? Distributional Consequences of Monetary Policy,” Manuscript, Federal Reserve Board, University of Bonn, and Philadelphia Fed, March 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Gottschalk, Peter and Robert Moffitt, “The Growth of Earnings Instability in the U.S. Labor Market,” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, January 1994, 1994 (2), 217–272.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Greenwood, Jeremy, Zvi Hercowitz, and Gregory W. Huffman, “Investment, Capacity Utilization, and the Real Business Cycle,” American Economic Review, June 1988, 78 (3), 402–417.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Guerrieri, Veronica and Guido Lorenzoni, “Credit Crises, Precautionary Savings, and the Liquidity Trap,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, August 2017, 132 (3), 1427–1467.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Guvenen, Fatih, Sam Schulhofer-Wohl, Jae Song, and Motohiro Yogo, “Worker Betas: Five Facts about Systematic Earnings Risk,” American Economic Review Papers and Proceedings, May 2017, 107 (5), 398–403.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Guvenen, Fatih, Serdar Ozkan, and Jae Song, “The Nature of Countercyclical Income Risk,” Journal of Political Economy, June 2014, 122 (3), 621–660.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Heathcote, Jonathan and Fabrizio Perri, “Wealth and Volatility,” Review of Economic Studies, 2018, Forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Heathcote, Jonathan, Kjetil Storesletten, and Giovanni L. Violante, “The Macroeconomic Implications of Rising Wage Inequality in the United States,” Journal of Political Economy, August 2010, 118 (4), 681-722.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Iacoviello, Matteo, “Household Debt and Income Inequality, 1963–2003,” Journal of Money, Credit and Banking, August 2008, 40 (5), 929–965.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">IMF, “Chapter 3: Understanding the Downward Trend in Labor Income Shares,” in “World Economic Outlook,”Washington, D.C.: International Monetary Fund, April 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Jappelli, Tullio and Luigi Pistaferri, “Fiscal Policy and MPC Heterogeneity,” American Economic Journal: Macroeconomics, October 2014, 6 (4), 107–136.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Kaldor, Nicholas, “Alternative Theories of Distribution,” Review of Economic Studies, January 1955, 23 (2), 83–100.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Kaplan, Greg, Benjamin Moll, and Gianluca Violante, “Monetary Policy According to HANK,” Manuscript, January 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Katz, Lawrence F. and Kevin M. Murphy, “Changes in RelativeWages, 1963-1987: Supply and Demand Factors,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, February 1992, 107 (1), 35–78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Kaymak, Barıs and Markus Poschke, “The Evolution of Wealth Inequality Over Half a Century: The Role of Taxes, Transfers and Technology,” Journal of Monetary Economics, February 2016, 77, 1–25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Keynes, John Maynard, The General Theory of Employment, Interest, and Money, London: Macmillan, 1936.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Kopczuk, Wojciech, Emmanuel Saez, and Jae Song, “Earnings Inequality and Mobility in the United States: Evidence from Social Security Data Since 1937,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, February 2010, 125 (1), 91–128.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Kreamer, Jonathan, “Household Debt, Unemployment, and Slow Recoveries,” Manuscript, January 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Krugman, Paul, “Robber Baron Recessions,” The New York Times, April 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Kumhof, Michael, Romain Rancière, and Pablo Winant, “Inequality, Leverage, and Crises,” American Economic Review, March 2015, 105 (3), 1217–1245.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Laubach, Thomas and John C. Williams, “Measuring the Natural Rate of Interest Redux,” Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco Working Paper Series, October 2015, 16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Leeper, Eric M., “Equilibria Under ‘Active’ and ‘Passive’ Monetary and Fiscal Policies,” Journal of Monetary Economics, February 1991, 27 (1), 129–147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">McKay, Alisdair and Ricardo Reis, “The Role of Automatic Stabilizers in the U.S. Business Cycle,” Econometrica, January 2016, 84 (1), 141–194.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <mixed-citation id="c62">McKay, Alisdair, Emi Nakamura, and Jón Steinsson, “The Power of Forward Guidance Revisited,” American Economic Review, October 2016, 106 (10), 3133–3158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Nardi, Mariacristina De and Giulio Fella, “Saving and Wealth Inequality,” CEPR Discussion Paper No 11746, January 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Parker, Jonathan A. and Nicholas S. Souleles, “Reported Preference vs. Revealed Preference: Evidence from the Propensity to Spend Tax Rebates,”Working Paper 23920, National Bureau of Economic Research, October 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r65">
            <mixed-citation id="c65">Philippon, Thomas, “Has the US Finance Industry Become Less Efficient? On the Theory and Measurement of Financial Intermediation,” American Economic Review, April 2015, 105 (4), 1408–1438.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r66">
            <mixed-citation id="c66">Pigou, Arthur C., The Economics of Welfare, Palgrave Macmillan, 1920.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r67">
            <mixed-citation id="c67">Piketty, Thomas and Emmanuel Saez, “Income Inequality in the United States, 1913–1998,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, February 2003, 118 (1), 1–41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r68">
            <mixed-citation id="c68">Quadrini, Vincenzo and José-Victor Rıos-Rull, “Understanding the US Distribution of Wealth,” Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis Quarterly Review, 1997, 21 (2), 22–36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r69">
            <mixed-citation id="c69">Ravn, Morten O. and Vincent Sterk, “Job Uncertainty and Deep Recessions,” Journal of Monetary Economics, October 2017, 90 (Supplement C), 125–141.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r70">
            <mixed-citation id="c70">Reiter, Michael, “Solving Heterogeneous-Agent Models by Projection and Perturbation,” Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control, March 2009, 33 (3), 649–665.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r71">
            <mixed-citation id="c71">Rognlie, Matthew, “Deciphering the Fall and Rise in the Net Capital Share,” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, 2015, 2015 (2), forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r72">
            <mixed-citation id="c72">Rognlie, Matthew, “What Lower Bound? Monetary Policy with Negative Interest Rates,” Manuscript, MIT, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r73">
            <mixed-citation id="c73">Rosen, Sherwin, “The Economics of Superstars,” American Economic Review, December 1981, 71 (5), 845–858.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r74">
            <mixed-citation id="c74">Schmitt-Grohé, Stephanie and Martín Uribe, “Downward Nominal Wage Rigidity, Currency Pegs, and Involuntary Unemployment,” Journal of Political Economy, August 2016, 124 (5), 1466–1514.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r75">
            <mixed-citation id="c75">Song, Jae, David J. Price, Fatih Guvenen, Nicholas Bloom, and Till von Wachter, “Firming Up Inequality,” Manuscript, June 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r76">
            <mixed-citation id="c76">Storesletten, Kjetil, Chris I. Telmer, and Amir Yaron, “Cyclical Dynamics in Idiosyncratic Labor Market Risk,” Journal of Political Economy, June 2004, 112 (3), 695–717.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r77">
            <mixed-citation id="c77">Straub, Ludwig, “Consumption, Savings, and the Distribution of Permanent Income,” Manuscript, November 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r78">
            <mixed-citation id="c78">Summers, Lawrence H., “Demand Side Secular Stagnation,” American Economic Review, May 2015, 105 (5), 60–65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r79">
            <mixed-citation id="c79">Teschl, Gerald, Topics in Real and Functional Analysis Graduate Studies in Mathematics, Providence, Rhode Island: American Mathematical Society, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r80">
            <mixed-citation id="c80">Werning, Iván, “Managing a Liquidity Trap: Monetary and Fiscal Policy,” Manuscript, April 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r81">
            <mixed-citation id="c81">Werning, Iván, “Incomplete Markets and Aggregate Demand,” Working Paper 21448, National Bureau of Economic Research, August 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Calibration parameters</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Retrospective and prospective income inequality paths.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Partial equilibrium effect of increasing inequality</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Sufficient statistic prediction vs. nonlinear model solution</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Sufficient statistics, data vs. model; linear vs. nonlinear</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>General equilibrium</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Increase in income inequality: from partial to general equilibrium</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Determinants of multipliers: monetary, fiscal, inequality</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Effect of increasing shock persistence</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Partial equilibrium effect of increasing inequality: permanent shock case</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Response of savings to income process changes</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Monetary policy rule and equilibrium determination (special case)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Role of fiscal policy and income incidence</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 11:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>General equilibrium</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 12:</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Alternative general equilibrium adjustments</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 13:</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Inequality and the r* decline</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure B.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Individual holdings of equity in the SCF</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure B.2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>γ function calibration</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table B.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Estimated fiscal rules</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure B.3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Lorenz curves for consumption, income and wealth at steady-state</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table B.2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Calibration parameters for 1980 steady state</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure D.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>General equilibrium for temporary shock with Taylor rules</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure D.2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>General equilibrium for permanent shock with Taylor rules</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure D.3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Permanent shock under alternative initial portfolio allocations</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure D.4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>Possibility of multiple equilibria with countercyclical income risk</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
