<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">21</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i30219113</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">30219115</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="pub-doi">10.1007/s10590-008-9045-2</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Bilingual LSA-Based Adaptation for Statistical Machine Translation</article-title>
          </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Yik-Cheung</given-names>
                  <surname>Tam</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ian</given-names>
                  <surname>Lane</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Tanja</given-names>
                  <surname>Schultz</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
          </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2007</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>187</fpage>
         <lpage>207</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2008 Springer Science Business Media B.V.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/30219115"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>We propose a novel approach to cross-lingual language model and translation lexicon adaptation for statistical machine translation (SMT) based on bilingual latent semantic analysis. Bilingual LSA enables latent topic distributions to be efficiently transferred across languages by enforcing a one-to-one topic correspondence during training. Using the proposed bilingual LSA framework, model adaptation can be performed by, first, inferring the topic posterior distribution of the source text and then applying the inferred distribution to an n-gram language model of the target language and translation lexicon via marginal adaptation. The background phrase table is enhanced with the additional phrase scores computed using the adapted translation lexicon. The proposed framework also features rapid bootstrapping of LSA models for new languages based on a source LSA model of another language. Our approach is evaluated on the Chinese-English MTO6 test set using the medium-scale SMT system and the GALE SMT system measured in BLEU and NIST scores. Improvement in both scores is observed on both systems when the adapted language model and the adapted translation lexicon are applied individually. When the adapted language model and the adapted translation lexicon are applied simultaneously, the gain is additive. At the 95% confidence interval of the unadapted baseline system, the gain in both scores is statistically significant using the medium-scale SMT system, while the gain in the NIST score is statistically significant using the GALE SMT system.</p>
          </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>Bilingual latent semantic analysis</kwd>
            <kwd>Latent Dirichlet-tree allocation</kwd>
            <kwd>Cross-lingual language model adaptation</kwd>
            <kwd>Lexicon adaptation</kwd>
            <kwd>Topic distribution transfer</kwd>
            <kwd>Statistical machine translation</kwd>
          </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
              <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
              <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
          </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
        
         <fn-group>
            <title>[Footnotes]</title>
            <fn id="d2757384e296a1310">
               <label>1</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e303" publication-type="other">
http://www.dcs.gla.ac.uk/idom/ir_resources/linguistic_utils/stop_words, last consulted 22 October
2008</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      
        
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d2757384e322a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e326" publication-type="other">
Bellegarda JR (2000) Large vocabulary speech recognition with multispan statistical language models.
IEEE Trans Speech Audio Process 8:76-84</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e336a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e340" publication-type="other">
Blei D, Ng A, Jordan M (2003) Latent Dirichlet allocation. J Mach Learn Res 3:1107-1135</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e347a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e351" publication-type="other">
Brown PF, Della Pietra SA, Della Pietra VJ, Mercer RL (1994) The mathematics of statistical machine
translation: parameter estimation. Comput Linguist 19:263-311</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e361a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e365" publication-type="other">
Darroch JN, Ratcliff D (1972) Generalized iterative scaling for log-linear models. Ann Math Stat 43:1470-
1480</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e376a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e380" publication-type="other">
Deerwester SC, Dumais ST, Landauer TK, Furnas GW, Harshman RA (1990) Indexing by latent semantic
analysis. J Am Soc Inf Sci 41:391-407</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e390a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e394" publication-type="other">
Doddington G (2002) Automatic evaluation of MT quality using n-gram co-occurrence statistics. In:
Proceedings of human language technology conference 2002, San Diego, CA, pp 138-145</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e404a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e408" publication-type="other">
Griffiths TL, Steyvers M, Blei DM, Tenenbaum JB (2004) Integrating topics and syntax. In: Saul LK, Weiss
Y, Bottou L (eds) Advances in neural information processing systems 17, Proceedings of the 2004
conference, MIT Press, Cambridge MA, pp 537-544</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e421a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e425" publication-type="other">
Hofmann T (1999) Probabilistic latent semantic indexing. In: UAI '99, proceedings of the fifteenth confer-
ence on uncertainty in artificial intelligence, Stockholm, Sweden, pp 289-296</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e435a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e439" publication-type="other">
Hsu B-J(P), Glass J (2006) Style &amp; topic language model adaptation using HMM-LDA. In: EMNLP 2006,
2006 conference on empirical methods in natural language processing, Sydney, Australia, pp 373-381</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e449a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e453" publication-type="other">
Iyer R, Ostendorf M (1996) Modeling long distance dependence in language: topic mixtures vs. dynamic
cache models. In: ICSLP 96, fourth international conference on spoken language processing,
Philadelphia, PA, pp 236-239</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e467a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e471" publication-type="other">
Jolliffe IT (2002) Principal component analysis, 2nd edn. Springer, New York</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e478a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e482" publication-type="other">
Kim W, Khudanpur S (2003) LM adaptation using cross-lingual information. In: 8th European conference on
speech communication and technology (Eurospeech 2003 - Interspeech 2003), Geneva, Switzerland,
pp 3129-3132</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e495a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e499" publication-type="other">
Kim W, Khudanpur S (2004) Cross-lingual latent semantic analysis for LM. In: 2004 IEEE international
conference on acoustics, speech, and signal processing, vol 1. Montreal, Quebec, Canada, pp 257-260</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e509a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e513" publication-type="other">
Kneser R, Peters J, Klakow D (1997) Language model adaptation using dynamic marginals. In: Proceed-
ings of Eurospeech '97, 5th European conference on speech communication and technology, Rhodes,
Greece, pp 1971-1974</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e526a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e530" publication-type="other">
Mrva D, Woodland PC (2006) Unsupervised language model adaptation for Mandarin broadcast conversa-
tion transcription. In: Interspeech 2006 - ICSLP, ninth international conference on spoken language
processing, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, paper 1549-ThulA2O.3</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e543a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e547" publication-type="other">
Och FJ (2003) Minimum error rate training in statistical machine translation. In: ACL-03, 41st annual
meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Sapporo, Japan, pp 160-167</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e558a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e562" publication-type="other">
Papineni K, Roukos S, Ward T, Zhu W (2002) BLEU: a method for automatic evaluation of machine
translation. In: 40th annual meeting of the Association of Computational Linguistics, Philadelphia,
Pennsylvania, pp 311-318</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e575a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e579" publication-type="other">
Paulik M, Filgen C, Schaaf T, Schultz T, Striker S, Waibel A (2005) Document driven machine transla-
tion enhanced automatic speech recognition. In: Proceedings of Interspeech'2005 - Eurospeech, 9th
European conference on speech communication and technology, Lisbon, Portugal, pp 2261-2264</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e592a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e596" publication-type="other">
Rottmann K, Vogel S (2007) Word reordering in statistical machine translation with a POS-based dis-
tortion model. In: TMI 2007, proceedings of the 11th international conference on theoretical and
methodological issues in machine translation, Sk6vde, pp 171-180</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e609a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e613" publication-type="other">
Stolcke A (2002) SRILM - an extensible language modeling toolkit. In: Proceedings of the 7th international
conference on spoken language processing ICSLP/Interspeech, Denver, Colorado, pp 901-904</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e623a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e627" publication-type="other">
Tam YC, Schultz T (2005) Language model adaptation using variational Bayes inference. In: Proceedings of
Interspeech'2005 - Eurospeech, 9th European conference on speech communication and technology,
Lisbon, Portugal, pp 5-8</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e640a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e644" publication-type="other">
Tam YC, Schultz T (2006) Unsupervised language model adaptation using latent semantic marginals. In:
Interspeech 2006 - ICSLP, ninth international conference on spoken language processing, Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania, paper 1705-Thul A2O.2</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e658a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e662" publication-type="other">
Tam YC, Schultz T (2007) Correlated latent semantic model for unsupervised language model adaptation.
In: Proceedings of ICASSP 2007, international conference on acoustics, speech, and signal processing,
vol IV. Honolulu, Hawaii, pp 41-44</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e675a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e679" publication-type="other">
Tseng H, Chang P, Andrew G, Jurafsky D, Manning C (2005) A conditional random field word segmenter. In:
IJCNLP-05, fourth SIGHAN workshop on Chinese language processing, Jeju Island, Korea, pp 168-
171</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e692a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e696" publication-type="other">
Vogel S, Zhang Y, Huang F, Tribble A, Venugopal A, Zhao B, Waibel A (20031) The CMU statistical trans-
lation system. In: MT summit IX, proceedings of the ninth machine translation summit, New Orleans,
pp 402-409</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e709a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e713" publication-type="other">
Zhang Y, Vogel S (2004) Measuring confidence intervals for the machine translation evaluation metrics. In:
Proceedings of the tenth conference on theoretical and methodological issues in machine translation
TMI-04, Baltimore, Maryland, pp 85-94</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e726a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e730" publication-type="other">
Zhao B. Xing EP (2006) BiTAM: Bilingual topic admixture models for word alignment. In: Coling - ACL
2006, 21st international conference on computational linguistics and 44th annual meeting of the Asso-
ciation for Computational Linguistics, proceedings of the main conference poster sessions, Sydney,
Australia, pp 969-976</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2757384e746a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2757384e750" publication-type="other">
Zhao B, Xing EP (2007) HM-BiTAM: Bilingual topic exploration, word alignment, and translation. In:
Twenty-second annual conference on neural information processing systems, Vancouver BC, Canada</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      </back>
</article>
