<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278152</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Analytical Approach to Model a Saturated Interior Permanent Magnet Synchronous Motor for a Hybrid Electric Vehicle</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Abdelli</surname>
                  <given-names>Abdenour</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Le Berr</surname>
                  <given-names>Fabrice</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>IFP Energies nouvelles</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>301</fpage>
         <lpage>313</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278152"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper presents an analytical approach to model an interior permanent magnet motor for a hybrid electric vehicle. Therefore, an analytical model for the calculation of parameters of an interior permanent magnet motor is presented. Furthermore, these parameter values are compared with good agreement to those from finite-element analysis and experimental data. An analytical model to simulate the behaviour of the motor and its control are developed and validated by comparison with experimental data. The thermal analysis of the motor prototype is also done. At the end, the presented model is embedded in the hybrid vehicle simulator and improvements are proposed, such as an analytical approach based on the finite element results to include the core saturation effect.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Paganelli, G., Guerra, T.M., Delprat, S., Santin, J.J., Delhom, M., Combes, E., Simulation and assessment of power control strategies for a parallel hybrid car, Journal of automobileengineering, IMechE, IEE, n°214, p 705-718, 2000C</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hwang, C., Chang, S.M., Pan, C.T., Chang, T.Y., Estimation of parameters of interior permanent magnet synchronous motors, J. Magn.Magn. Mater. (2002) 600-603.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, T.J.E., Brushless Permanent-Magnet and Reluctance Motor Drives, Clarendon Press, Oxford, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arjona L., M. A., Macdonald, D. C., A New Lumped Steady--State Synchronous Machine Model Derived from Finite Element Analysis. IEEE Trans. on Energy Conversion, Vol.14, No. 1, March 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hengelmann, R. and minddendrof, W.H., Handbook of electric motors, Marcel Dekker, New york, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Staunton, R. H., Ayers, C. W., Marlino, L. D., Chiasson, J. N., “Evaluation of 2004 Toyota Prius Hybrid Electric Drive System”, ORNL/TM-2004/137, UT-Battelle, LLC, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, Tennessee, May 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burress, T. A., Coomer, C. L., Campbell, S. L.,Seiber, L. E., Marlino, L. D., Staunton, R. H., Cunningham, J. P., Evaluation of the 2007 Toyota Camry hybrid synergy drive system, UT-Battelle, LLC, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, Tennessee, January 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vinot, E., Scordia, J., Trigui, R., Jeanneret, B., Badin, F., Model simulation, validation and case study of the 2004 THS of Toyota Prius, International Journal of Vehicle Systems Modelling and Testing. Vol. 3, no. 3, pp. 139-167. 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roshen, W., Iron Loss Model for permanent -Magnet synchronous Motors, IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON MAGNETICS, Vol. 43, NO, 8, AUGUST 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Soong, W., “Design and modeling of axially-laminated interior permanent magnet motor drives for field-weakening applications,” Ph.D. dissertation, Electron. Elect. Eng., Univ. Glasgow, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jahns, T. M., Kliman, G. B., and Neumann, T. W., “Interior PM synchronous motors for adjustable speed drives,” IEEE Trans. Ind. Applicat., vol. IA-22, pp. 738-747, July/Aug 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lovelace, E. C., Jahns, T. M., and Lang, J. H., “A saturating lumped parameter model for an interior PM synchronous machine,” IEEE Trans. Ind. Applicat., vol. 38, pp. 645-650, May/June 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdelli, A., Optimisation multicritère d'une chaîne éolienne passive, Thèse de doctorat (PHD) de l'INP Toulouse, 15 Octobre 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
