<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24910731</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PROFESSIONAL FEATURE</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Raking:</article-title>
            <subtitle>An Important and Often Overlooked Survey Analysis Tool</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Anderson</surname>
                  <given-names>Lew</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>LCDR Lew Anderson is a US Navy SEAL officer currently stationed at Special Operations Command Korea. He has attended many specialty schools such as Basic Underwater Demolition/SEALs (BUD/S), Dive Supervisor, and Military Free Fall School, but the most mentally challenging school he has ever attended was Naval Postgraduate School, where he received an MS in operations research. LCDR Anderson has a BS in mathematics education from Purdue University and actually used this degree, teaching Algebra I to eighth graders in Tell City, Indiana.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Fricker,</surname>
                  <given-names>Ronald D.</given-names>
                  <suffix>Jr.</suffix>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Ronald D. Fricker, Jr. is the head of the Statistics Department at Virginia Tech. He was formerly a professor in the Operations Research Department of the Naval Postgraduate School. He received his PhD in statistics from Yale University. An author of more than 70 papers, monographs, and book chapters, Professor Fricker is a Fellow of the American Statistical Association and an Elected Member of the International Statistical Institute. He is on the editorial boards of Statistics, Politics, and Policy and the International Journal of Quality Engineering and Technology.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>September 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>48</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e24910718</issue-id>
         <fpage>36</fpage>
         <lpage>42</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24910731"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bishop, Y., Fienberg, S., and Holland, P. 1975. Discrete Multivariate Analysis: Theory and Practice. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cochran, W. T. 1977. Sampling Techniques, 3rd ed. Wiley, New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DeBell, M., and Krosnick, J. A. 2009. Computing Weights for American National Election Study Survey Data. ANES Technical Re-port nes012427. American National Election Studies. Ann Arbor, MI, and Palo Alto, CA, http://www.electionstudies.org/resources/papers/nes012427.pdf .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kish, L. 1995. Survey Sampling. Wiley, New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lohr, S. L. 1999. Sampling: Design and Analysis, 2nd ed. Duxbury Press, Pacific Grove, CA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lumley, T. 2010. Complex Surveys: A Guide to Analysis Using R. Wiley, New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
