<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437686</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Balance between Specific and "Ad Valorem" Taxation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>MICHAEL</given-names>
                  <surname>KEEN</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>1998</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">19</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437683</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>37</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 1998</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437686"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>A recurring issue in indirect tax design — most obviously, but not only, for goods traditionally subject to heavy excises — is the appropriate balance between specific and ad valorem taxation. Recent work has developed new perspectives on the issue, which is also one of the oldest in the formal study of public finance. This paper provides a broadly non-technical account of the central considerations that arise in choosing the balance between specific and ad valorem taxation, reviewing and somewhat extending the lessons of theory and experience. There emerge clear presumptions as to the relative effects of the two kinds of tax on such attributes as price, profits, product quality and variety. But the socially optimal balance between them is likely to be quite sensitive to the characteristics of the market at issue.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d22e123a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e130" publication-type="other">
For brevity, we do not consider the comparison between specific and ad valorem tariffs that has received some
attention in discussions of international trade: see, for example. Helpman and Krugman (1989). Many of the
issues that arise there, of course, also arise, albeit in somewhat different form, in the purely domestic context
with which we are concerned.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e146a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e153" publication-type="other">
At least in the absence (assumed throughout) of foreign ownership.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e160a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e167" publication-type="other">
Thus v is the 'tax-inclusive' tax rate; the discussion could equally well be cast in terms of the 'tax-exclusive'
rate v/(l-v), which expresses tax paid as a proportion of the producer price (the only difference being that the
latter is a bigger number).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e180a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e187" publication-type="other">
Lockwood (1996) makes the interesting point that the distinction between specific and ad valorem taxes is
liable to matter, even under perfect competition, for the outcome in standard models of interjurisdictional tax
competition. For the standard approach in such models is to focus on Nash equilibria in which each country
takes the others' tax rates to be independent of its own. But it generally cannot be the case that taxes remain
unchanged in both ad valorem and specific forms: if a specific tax remains unchanged, for example, when the
world price of the taxed good falls, then the equivalent ad valorem rate must rise. The issue thus essentially
concerns how one models equilibrium and the conjectures that support it rather than the form in which taxes
are actually imposed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e217a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e224" publication-type="other">
The impact of this on the market shares of the two brands will depend on their relative income elasticities of
demand: if, as one might expect, the high-quality brand has the higher income elasticity, then the income effect
will reduce its market share.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e237a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e244" publication-type="other">
This case was the subject of the classic analyses of Cournot ( 1960), Wicksell ( 1959) and Suits and Musgrave
(1955).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e254a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e261" publication-type="other">
This might at first sight seem inconsistent with the earlier claim that ad valorem and specific taxes are equally
effective in eliminating the monopoly distortion altogether: the reconciliation lies in noting that the argument
just given relies on so being strictly positive (perhaps because the government does need to raise some revenue),
whereas the specific tax required to eliminate the monopoly distortion is strictly negative.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e277a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e284" publication-type="other">
Dierickx, Matutes and Neven (1988) and Denicolö and Matteuzzi (undated) examine the case in which firms
differ in cost structure. Such asymmetries raise an additional consideration that tends to favour ad valorem
taxation: the multiplier effect means that it disadvantages the less efficient firms (which, in a more competitive
environment, would cease to exist),</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e300a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e307" publication-type="other">
We take this to be a final consumption good; additional issues that arise in comparing ad valorem and specific
taxes on intermediate goods in the context of imperfect competition are discussed by Colangelo and Galmarini
(1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e320a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e327" publication-type="other">
The main results referred to in what follows remain valid with more general conjectures.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e335a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e342" publication-type="other">
Replacing a specific tax.to &gt; 0 by an ad valorem tax vo s so/MR has no effect on output or (hence) the
consumer price, since (1 - v»)MR = MR -.to (where MR is the marginal revenue perceived by the typical firm),
but increases tax revenue because v»P -.to =.to f —-— 1 I &gt; 0.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e355a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e362" publication-type="other">
See Proposition 2 of Delipalla and Keen (1992).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e369a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e376" publication-type="other">
In the monopoly case, of course, there is no such external effect at work.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e383a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e390" publication-type="other">
Dillén (1995) derives a similar result in a somewhat different setting.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e397a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e404" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Mankiw and Whinston (1986).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e411a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e418" publication-type="other">
More precisely, we define MWP to be the largest amount that the consumer is willing to pay for a small
increase in q, so that (denoting derivatives by subscripts) MWP(P.q) = -VJV?.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e429a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e436" publication-type="other">
The natural alternative of supposing MQ to increase with q introduces additional effects that
straightforwardly reinforce those now discussed in the text.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e446a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e453" publication-type="other">
More precisely, the optimum has the feature that quality is unaffected by a small intensification of v and .9.
Though not noted by them, this follows from the analysis in Delipalla and Keen (1996): from their equation (3),
the effect on equilibrium quality of a reform (dr. d.v) = a (v,s) that changes both specific and ad valorem taxes
by the same (small) proportion a is proportional to 9 (vP+s) - vP, where 9 = 3ln(-V(; IVp)/dP is the price
elasticity of MWP\ but their central result, discussed shortly, is that vP/(vP+s) = 9 at an optimum.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e472a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e479" publication-type="other">
Note that the result is nevertheless consistent with the usual second-best presumption that if one margin of
choice must be distorted — as pricing decisions must be here in order to raise revenue — so too should others:
for the rule (2) associated with quality choice typically is affected by the optimal tax system. The point rather is
that the impact of this on q is offset by the consequences of the tax effects on P</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e495a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e502" publication-type="other">
They do not, however, bound all possibilities: one can conceive of still more extreme circumstances, in which
optimal policy will require either an ad valorem or a specific subsidy.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e512a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e519" publication-type="other">
This is for the case in which the marginal utility of income is constant.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e526a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e533" publication-type="other">
That of Salop (1979).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e541a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e548" publication-type="other">
A qualitatively similar conclusion is reached, in a different model of product differentiation, by Anderson, de
Palma and Kreider ( 1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e558a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e565" publication-type="other">
The objective function is the simple sum of utilities, with individuals differing in the strength of their taste for
the differentiated good.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e575a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e582" publication-type="other">
A rather different conclusion is reached by Anderson, de Palma and Kreider ( 1997), who examine a model of
vertical product differentiation in which product qualities are fixed. They find that specific taxation is more
efficient if (inter alia) the cost difference between the variants is small: for then it is especially desirable to
counteract the tendency to under-provision of the high-quality good by narrowing the relative differential in
consumer prices.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e601a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e608" publication-type="other">
Another way in which uncertainty might affect the choice between specific and ad valorem taxation is raised
and explored by Fraser (1985), apparently with small-scale agricultural producers in mind: since the two taxes
have quite different risk-sharing properties — under an ad valorem tax, but not under a specific, for instance,
price uncertainty is in part bome by the government — they will not be equivalent from the perspective of a
risk-averse producer.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e627a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e634" publication-type="other">
By setting the derivative of revenue with respect to P to zero.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e641a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e648" publication-type="other">
The first statement of this result seems to be that in Tobacco Advisory Council (1980).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e656a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e663" publication-type="other">
Note that this means a specific subsidy if revenue is positive and E &gt; I</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e670a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e677" publication-type="other">
With total expenditure constant at M, and denoting by T the tax rate on other expenditure, total revenue,
{vP +s)X(P)+ t{M - PX(P)}, is unaffected by a small change in P if and only if
E + T(1 - £).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e690a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e697" publication-type="other">
This is a general principle, not a universal truth: there may be circumstances in which instruments other than
those most directly related to the distortion have a role. In the environmental context, this may be the case, for
example, when individuals are heterogeneous and the optimal corrective tax is consequently differentiated
across individuals: if person-specific taxes are for some reason impossible, indirect instruments — taxes or
subsidies on goods other than the one that generates the externality — may be optimal: see the discussion in
Myles (1995). We have in mind in this subsection the case in which individuals are identical, leaving to future
work the interesting question of whether heterogeneity and the potential case for indirect instruments affect the
optimal balance between specific and ad valorem taxation on the externality-generating activity itself.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e726a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e733" publication-type="other">
Matters become more complicated if the relevant market is vulnerable to exogenous shocks, but with no clear
implications for the choice of instrument: it is a merit (respectively, weakness) of ad valorem taxation, for
example, that the expansion of output induced by an unexpected shift of the demand (supply) curve is
accompanied by an increase (reduction) in the tax wedge vP that mitigates (worsens) any adverse external
effect of that expansion. See Dickie and Trandel (1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e752a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e759" publication-type="other">
Vertical differentiation in the model of Cremer and Thisse (1994) discussed in Section II(2)(b), in contrast, is
driven by differences in strength of taste towards the differentiated good.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e769a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e776" publication-type="other">
There is an interesting similarity here with the result of Cremer and Thisse (1994) mentioned above, though
these two models of vertical differentiation are quite different.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e787a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e794" publication-type="other">
Imagine two curves showing utility (on the vertical axis) as a function of income, one drawn on the
assumption that the low-quality good is consumed, the other assuming that it is the high-quality good which is
consumed. If those with low incomes prefer to consume the low-quality good while those on high incomes
consume the high-quality good, then the latter curve must somewhere cut the former from below, at which
point it must have the steeper slope (that is, the higher marginal utility of income).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e813a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e820" publication-type="other">
Sumner (1981) is an early example; more recent studies include Baker and Brechling (1992) and Besley and
Rosen (1994).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e830a1310">
            <label>37</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e837" publication-type="other">
It is reassuring that Johnson (1978) finds there to be a distinct tax effect even when controlling for state-
specific effects; less so that he notes (in footnote 7) that the effect of the ad valorem tax in Hawaii — omitted
in Barzel (1976) — runs counter to theory.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e850a1310">
            <label>38</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e857" publication-type="other">
The discussion here draws on London Economics (1995), where other (somewhat less informative) episodes
are also considered.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e867a1310">
            <label>39</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e874" publication-type="other">
Here we use the observation that perturbing revenue, R = TX(P), shows the proportional changes in revenue
and the tax rate, T, to be roughly (when dP = AT) AR/R = {\-(TIP)E)ATIT. The counterfactual is too simple, of
course, in that it ignores RYO. But with the real price of RYO rising in 1984 by 19 per cent, the essential point
is unaffected.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e890a1310">
            <label>40</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e897" publication-type="other">
requirements led to further reforms in 1995 and 1997, but these are of no special interest for our present
concerns.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e908a1310">
            <label>41</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e915" publication-type="other">
World Drink Trends 1995: International Beverage Consumption and Production Trends, NTC, Henley-on-
Thames.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e925a1310">
            <label>42</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e932" publication-type="other">
This interpretation also follows on noting, as is shown in Dixit and Stiglitz, that (1 + ß)/ß is the elasticity of
substitution between any two variants: the lower is ß, the easier it is to substitute between them and, in that
sense, the less valuable is diversity.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e945a1310">
            <label>43</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e952" publication-type="other">
Data for which are taken fro IMF Financial statistics</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e959a1310">
            <label>44</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e966" publication-type="other">
Results from ordinary least squares (OLS) are almost identical to those reported here.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e973a1310">
            <label>45</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e980" publication-type="other">
The null hypothesis that the coefficient on the lagged residuals from the regression in equation (B.3) is zero
cannot be rejected at standard significance levels.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d22e999a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1003" publication-type="other">
Anderson, S. P., de Palma, A. and Kreider, B. (1997), 'Tax incidence and efficiency in
differentiated product oligopoly', mimeo, University of Virginia.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1013a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1017" publication-type="other">
Baker, P. and Brechling, V. (1992), 'The impact of excise duty changes on retail prices in the UK',
Fiscal Studies, vol. 13, no. 2, pp. 48-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1027a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1031" publication-type="other">
Barnett, P. G., Keeler, T. E. and Hu, T. (1995), 'Oligopoly structure and the incidence of cigarette
excise taxes', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 57, pp. 457-70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1041a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1045" publication-type="other">
Barzel, Y. (1976), 'An alternative approach to the analysis of taxation', Journal of Political
Economy, vol. 84, pp. 1177-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1056a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1060" publication-type="other">
Besley, T. and Rosen, H. (1994), 'Sales taxes and prices: an empirical analysis', mimeo, Princeton
University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1070a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1074" publication-type="other">
Bohanon, C. E. and van Cott, T. N. (1984), 'Specific taxes, product quality and rate-revenue
analysis', Public Finance Quarterly, vol. 12, pp. 500-11.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1084a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1088" publication-type="other">
— and — (1991), 'Product quality and taxation: a reconciliation', Public Finance Quarterly, vol.
19, pp. 233-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1098a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1102" publication-type="other">
Colangelo, G. and Galmarini, U. (1996), 'Ad valorem taxation on intermediate goods in oligopoly',
mimeo, Université Cattolica del Sacro Cuore.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1112a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1116" publication-type="other">
Cournot, A. (1960, originally published 1838), Researches into the Mathematical Principles of the
Theory of Wealth, London: Frank Cass &amp; Co.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1126a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1130" publication-type="other">
Cremer, H. and Thisse, J.-F. (1994), 'Commodity taxation in a differentiated oligopoly',
International Economic Review, vol. 35, pp. 613-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1141a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1145" publication-type="other">
Delipalla, S. (1995), 'Specific versus ad valorem taxation: empirical evidence from the European
cigarette industry', mimeo, University of Kent.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1155a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1159" publication-type="other">
— and Keen, M. J. (1992), 'The comparison between ad valorem and specific taxation under
imperfect competition', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 49, pp. 351-67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1169a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1173" publication-type="other">
— and — (1996), 'Product quality and the optimal structure of commodity taxes', mimeo,
University of Essex.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1183a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1187" publication-type="other">
Denicölo, V. and Matteuzzi, M. (undated), 'A note on the comparison between specific and ad
valorem taxation in oligopoly', mimeo, Université di Bologna.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1197a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1201" publication-type="other">
Dickie, M. and Trandel, G. A. (1996), 'Comparing specific and ad valorem Pigouvian taxes and
output quotas', Southern Economic Journal, vol. 63, pp. 388-405.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1211a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1215" publication-type="other">
Dierickx, I., Matutes, C. and Neven, D. (1988), 'Indirect taxation and Cournot equilibrium'.
International Journal of Industrial Organisation, vol. 6, pp. 385-99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1226a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1230" publication-type="other">
Dillén, M. (1995), 'Corrective tax and subsidy policies in economies with imperfect competition',
Journal of Public Economics, vol. 58, pp. 267-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1240a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1244" publication-type="other">
Dixit, A. K. and Stiglitz, J. E. (1977), 'Monopolistic competition and optimum product diversity',
American Economic Review, vol. 67, pp. 297-308.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1254a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1258" publication-type="other">
Fraser, R. W. (1985), 'Commodity taxes under uncertainty', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 28,
pp. 127-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1268a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1272" publication-type="other">
Fry, V. and Pashardes, P. (1988), Changing Patterns of Smoking: Are there Economic Causes?,
Report Series no. 30, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1282a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1286" publication-type="other">
Helpman, E. and Krugman, P. R. (1989), Trade Policy and Market Structure, Cambridge, Mass.:
MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1296a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1300" publication-type="other">
HM Customs and Excise (1995), Landfill Tax: A Consultation Paper, London: HM Customs and
Excise.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1311a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1315" publication-type="other">
Johnson, T. R. (1978), 'Additional evidence on the effects of alternative taxes on cigarette prices',
Journal of Political Economy, vol. 86, pp. 325-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1325a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1329" publication-type="other">
Kay, J. A. and Keen, M. J. (1982), The Structure of Tobacco Taxes in the European Community,
Report Series no. 1, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1339a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1343" publication-type="other">
— and — (1983), 'How should commodities be taxed?', European Economic Review, vol. 23, pp.
339-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1353a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1357" publication-type="other">
— and — (1987a), 'Commodity taxation for maximum revenue', Public Finance Quarterly, vol.
15, pp. 371-85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1367a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1371" publication-type="other">
— and — (1987b), 'Alcohol and tobacco taxes: criteria for harmonisation', in S. Cnossen (ed.).
Tax Coordination in the European Community, Deventer: Kluwer Law and Taxation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1381a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1385" publication-type="other">
— and — (1991), 'Product quality under specific and ad valorem taxation'. Public Finance
Quarterly, vol. 19, pp. 238-47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1396a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1400" publication-type="other">
Konishi, J., Okuno-Fujiwara, M. and Suzumura, K. (1990), 'Oligopolistic competition and
economic welfare', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 41, pp. 67-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1410a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1414" publication-type="other">
Lockwood, B. (1996), 'Choice of numeraire and Nash equilibrium in tax and tariff policy games',
mimeo, University of Exeter.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1424a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1428" publication-type="other">
London Economics (1995), The Choice of Cigarette Excise Taxation: Ad Valorem or Specific?,
London: London Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1438a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1442" publication-type="other">
Mankiw, N. G. and Whinston, M. D. (1986), 'Free entry and social inefficiency'. Rand Journal of
Economics, vol. 17, pp. 48-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1452a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1456" publication-type="other">
Myles, G. (1988), 'Some implications of quality differentials for optimal taxation', Economic
Journal, vol. 98, Conference Issue, pp. 148-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1466a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1470" publication-type="other">
— (1994), 'Imperfect competition and the optimal combination of ad valorem and specific
taxation', International Tax and Public Finance, vol. 3, pp. 29-44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1481a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1485" publication-type="other">
— (1995), Public Economics, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1492a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1496" publication-type="other">
Pirttilä, J. (1997), 'Aspects of environmental taxation under imperfect competition', mimeo,
University of Essex.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1506a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1510" publication-type="other">
Salop, S. C. (1979), 'Monopolistic competition with outside goods', Bell Journal of Economics,
vol. 10, pp. 141-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1520a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1524" publication-type="other">
Skeath, S. E. and Trandel, G. E. (1994), 'A Pareto comparison of ad valorem and specific taxation
in noncompetitive environments', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 53, pp. 53-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1534a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1538" publication-type="other">
Stern, N. H. (1987), 'The effects of taxation, price control and government contracts in oligopoly
and monopolistic competition', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 32, pp. 133-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1548a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1552" publication-type="other">
Suits, D. B. and Musgrave, R. A. (1955), 'Ad valorem and unit taxes compared'. Quarterly Journal
of Economics, vol. 67, pp. 598-604.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1563a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1567" publication-type="other">
Sumner, D. A. (1981), 'Measurement of monopoly behaviour: an application to the cigarette
industry', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 89, pp. 1010-19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1577a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1581" publication-type="other">
Sumner, M. (1993), 'Tax on price: a comment', Public Finance, vol. 48, pp. 297-302.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1588a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1592" publication-type="other">
Tarn, M.-Y. S. (1991), 'Tax on price: a new commodity tax structure for efficiency', Public
Finance, vol. 46, pp. 123-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1602a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1606" publication-type="other">
Tobacco Advisory Council (1980), Cigarette Taxation in the European Community, London:
Tobacco Advisory Council.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1616a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1620" publication-type="other">
Wicksell, K. (1959, originally published 1896), 'Taxation in the monopoly case', in R. A.
Musgrave and C. S. Shoup (eds), Readings in the Economics of Taxation, London: Allen &amp;
Unwin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
