<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277685</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>New Approach for Modeling Cycle-to-Cycle Variations within the Framework of a Real Working-Process Simulation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wenig</surname>
                  <given-names>Markus</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IVK Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Grill</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FKFS</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bargende</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FKFS</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>1099</fpage>
         <lpage>1115</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277685"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>For a reliable and accurate simulation of SI engines reproduction of their operation limits (misfiring and knock limit) and in this context the knowledge of cyclic combustion variations and their influence on knock simulation are mandatory. For this purpose in this paper a real working-process simulation approach for the ability to predict cycle-to-cycle variations (ccv) of gasoline engines is proposed. An extensive measurement data base of four different test engines applying various operation strategies was provided in order to gain a better understanding of the physical background of the cyclic variations. So the ccv initiated by dilution strategies (internal EGR, lean operation), the ccv at full load and at the knock limit could be investigated in detail. Finally, the model was validated on the basis of three further engines which were not part of the actual development process. In order to obtain a thorough understanding of the ccv phenomenology additionally the so-called residual gas feedback effect had to be examined. Therefore a one dimensional CFD simulation was implemented since in this case gas dynamic processes are essential. Basing on the final ccv model it was possible to evaluate the influence of a fluctuating combustion on knock simulation. A zero-dimensional knock model approach was implemented within the ccv model in order to ascertain the benefit maintained by single cycle resolved knock simulations. However, in correspondence with the measurement data analysis of knocking single cycles, it comes to a conclusion that an accurate prediction of knock phenomena requires the consideration of further influences beyond the mere influence of cyclic variations.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdi Aghdam, E., Burluka, A., Hattrell, T., Liu, K. et al., “Study of Cyclic Variation in an SI Engine Using Quasi-Dimensional Combustion Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0939, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0939.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ayala, F. and Heywood, J., “Lean SI Engines: The role of combustion variability in defining lean limits,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0030, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-24-0030.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BARGENDE, M.: Schwerpunkt-Kriterium und automatische Klingelerkennung. MTZ Motorentechnische Zeitschrift 56, 1995, S. 632-638.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FRANZKE, D.: Beitrag zur Ermittlung eines Klopfkriteriums der ottomotorischen Verbrennung und zur Vorausberechnung der Klopfgrenze. München, Technische Universität, Diss., 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">HERDEN, W.: Zündung und Entflammung bei Benzindirekteinspritzung. In: Diesel- und Benzindirekteinspritzung, Renningen: expert, 2001, S 223-237.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ozdor, N., Dulger, M., and Sher, E., “Cyclic Variability in Spark Ignition Engines A Literature Survey,” SAE Technical Paper 940987, 1994, doi:10.4271/940987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SCHMID, A.; GRILL, M.; BERNER, H.-J.; BARGENDE, M.: Ein neuer Ansatz zur Vorhersage des ottomotorischen Klopfens. In: 3. Tagung: Ottomotorisches Klopfen, Berlin, 2010, S 256-277.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grill, M., Billinger, T., and Bargende, M., “Quasi-Dimensional Modeling of Spark Ignition Engine Combustion with Variable Valve Train,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1107, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-1107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grill, M. and Bargende, M., “The Development of an Highly Modular Designed Zero-Dimensional Engine Process Calculation Code,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):1-11, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adomeit, P., Lang, O., Pischinger, S., Aymanns, R. et al., “Analysis of Cyclic Fluctuations of Charge Motion and Mixture Formation in a DISI Engine in Stratified Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1412, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GORENFLO, E.: Einfluss der Luftverhältnisstreuung auf die zyklischen Schwankungen beim Ottomotor. Düsseldorf: VDI, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Choi, S., Lim, J., Ki, M., Min, K. et al., “Analysis of Cyclic Variation and the Effect of Fuel Stratification on Combustion Stabilityin a Port Fuel Injection (PFI) CAI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0670, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0670.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bianco, Y., Cheng, W., and Heywood, J., “The Effects of Initial Flame Kernel Conditions on Flame Development in SI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 912402, 1991, doi:10.4271/912402.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FISCHER, J.: Einfluss variabler Einlassströmung auf zyklische Schwankungen bei Benzin-Direkteinspritzung. Karlsruhe, Universität Karlsruhe, Diss., 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johansson, B., “Cycle to Cycle Variations in S.I. Engines - The Effects of Fluid Flow and Gas Composition in the Vicinity of the Spark Plug on Early Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 962084, 1996, doi: 10.4271/962084.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edwards, K., Wagner, R., Chakravarthy, V., Daw, C. et al., “A Hybrid 2-Zone/WAVE Engine Combustion Model for Simulating Combustion Instabilities During Dilute Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3801, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3801.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">VERMOREL, O.; RICHARD, S.; COLIN, O.; ANGELBERGER C.; BENKENIDA, A.; VEYNANTE, D.: Towards the understanding of cyclic variability in a spark ignited engine using multi-cycle LES, Combustion and Flame 156, 2009, S.1525-1541.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dai, W., Trigui, N., and Lu, Y., “Modeling of Cyclic Variations in Spark-Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2036, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-2036.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shen, H., Hinze, P., and Heywood, J., “A Study of Cycle-to-Cycle Variations in SI Engines Using a Modified Quasi-Dimensional Model,” SAE Technical Paper 961187, 1996, doi:10.4271/961187.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chakravarthy, K., Wagner, R., and Daw, S., “On the Use of Thermodynamic Modeling for Predicting Cycle-to-Cycle Variations in a SI Engine under Lean Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3802, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3802.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ETHERIDGE, J.; MOSBACH, S.; KRAFT, M.; WU, H.; COLLINGS, N.: Modelling cycle to cycle variations in an SI engine with detailed chemical kinetics, Combustion and Flame 158, 2011, S.179-188.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bozza, F., Siano, D., and Torella, E., “Cycle-by-Cycle Analysis, Knock Modeling and Spark-Advance Setting of a “Downsized” Spark-Ignition Turbocharged Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):381-389, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2009-24-0020.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">HEYWOOD, J. B.: Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals. McGraw-Hill Series in Mechanical Engineering, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BARGENDE, M.: Ein Gleichungsansatz zur Berechnung der instationären Wandwärmeverluste im Hochdruckteil von Ottomotoren. Dissertation TH Darmstadt, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martin, J., Plee, S., and Remboski, D., “Burn Modes and Prior-Cycle Effects on Cyclic Variations in Lean-Burn Spark-Ignition Engine Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 880201, 1988, doi:10.4271/880201.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brehob, D. and Newman, C., “Monte Carlo Simulation of Cycle by Cycle Variability,” SAE Technical Paper 922165, 1992, doi: 10.4271/922165.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pera, C., Richard, S., and Angelberger, C., “Exploitation of Multi-Cycle Engine LES to Introduce Physical Perturbations in 1D Engine Models for Reproducing CCV,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0127, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0127.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
