<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i40023373</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40542067</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="pub-doi">10.1007/s10590-009-9068-3</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Automatically Generated Parallel Treebanks and Their Exploitability in Machine Translation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
                  <surname>Tinsley</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Andy</given-names>
                  <surname>Way</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>22</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2009 Springer Science+Business Media B.V.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40542067"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Given much recent discussion and the shift in focus of the field, it is becoming apparent that the incorporation of syntax is the way forward for improvements to the current state-of-the-art in machine translation (MT). Parallel treebanks are a relatively recent innovation and appear to be ideal candidates for MT training material. However, until recently there has been no other means to build them than by hand. In this paper, we describe how we make use of new tools to automatically build a large parallel treebank and extract a set of linguistically-motivated phrase pairs from it. We show that adding these phrase pairs to the translation model of a baseline phrase-based statistical MT (PB-SMT) system leads to significant improvements in translation quality. Following this, we describe experiments in which we exploit the information encoded in the parallel treebank in other areas of the PB-SMT framework, while investigating the conditions under which the incorporation of parallel treebank data performs optimally. Finally, we discuss the possibility of exploiting automatically-generated parallel treebanks further in syntax-aware paradigms of MT.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>Parallel treebanks</kwd>
            <kwd>Statistical machine translation</kwd>
            <kwd>Phrase-based statistical machine translation</kwd>
            <kwd>Syntax in machine translation</kwd>
            <kwd>Sub-tree alignment</kwd>
            <kwd>Translation modelling</kwd>
            <kwd>Resource combination</kwd>
            <kwd>Word alignment</kwd>
            <kwd>Phrase alignment</kwd>
            <kwd>Hybrid models</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d644716e348a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d644716e355" publication-type="other">
Tinsley et al. (2007b)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d644716e371a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e375" publication-type="other">
Ahrenberg L (2007) LinES: an English-Swedish parallel treebank. In: Proceedings of the 16th Nordic
conference of computational linguistics (NOLADIA'07). Tartu, Estonia, pp 270-274</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e385a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e389" publication-type="other">
Banerjee S, Lavie A (2005) METEOR: an automatic metric for MT evaluation with improved correlation
with human judgments. In: Proceedings of workshop on intrinsic and extrinsic evaluation measures for
MT and/or summarization at the 43th annual meeting of the association of computational linguistics
(ACL-05). Ann Arbor, MI</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e405a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e409" publication-type="other">
Bikel D (2002) Design of a multi-lingual, parallel-processing statistical parsing engine. In: Human language
technology conference (HLT). San Diego, CA</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e419a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e423" publication-type="other">
Carpuat M, Wu D (2007) How phrase sense disambiguation outperforms word sense disambiguation for
statistical machine translation. In: Proceedings of the 11th international conference on theoretical and
methodological issues in machine translation (TMI-07). Skövde, Sweden, pp 43-52</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e437a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e441" publication-type="other">
Chiang D (2005) A hierarchical phrase-based model for statistical machine translation. In: 43rd annual
meeting of the association for computational linguistics (ACL' 05). Ann Arbor, MI, pp 263-270</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e451a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e455" publication-type="other">
Chiang D (2007) Hierarchical phrase-based translation. Comput Linguist 33(2):20 1-228</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e462a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e466" publication-type="other">
Chrupafa G, van Genabith J (2006) Using machine-learning to assign function labels to parser output for
Spanish. In: 44th annual meeting of the association for computational linguistics (ACL' 06). Sydney,
Australia, pp 136-143</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e479a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e483" publication-type="other">
Civit M, Martí MA (2004) Building Cast3LB: a Spanish treebank. Res Lang Comput 2(4):549-574</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e490a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e494" publication-type="other">
Čmejrek M, Cuěín J, Havelka J, Hajiǔ J, Kuboř V (2004) Prague Czech-English dependency treebank.
Syntactically annotated resources for machine translation. In: Proceedings of the 4th international
conference on language resources and evaluation. Lisbon, Portugal, pp 1597-1600</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e507a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e511" publication-type="other">
Cyrus L, Feddes H, Schumacher F (2003) FuSe -a multi-layered parallel treebank. In: Proceedings of the
second workshop on treebanks and linguistic theories (TLT'03). Växjö, Sweden, pp 213-216</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e522a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e526" publication-type="other">
Doddington G (2002) Automatic evaluation of machine translation quality using N-gram co-occurrence
statistics. In: Human language technology: notebook proceedings. San Diego, CA, pp 128-132</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e536a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e540" publication-type="other">
Eck M, Vogel S, Waibel A (2005) Low cost portability for statistical machine translation based on n-gram
coverage. In: Machine translation summit X. Phuket, Thailand, pp 227-234</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e550a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e554" publication-type="other">
Galley M, Graehl J, Knight K, Marcu D, DeNeefe S, Wang W, Thayer I (2006) Scalable inference and
training of context-rich syntactic translation models. In: Proceedings of the 44th annual meeting of
the association for computational linguistics. Sydney, Australia, pp 961-968</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e567a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e571" publication-type="other">
Groves D (2007) Hybrid data-driven models of machine translation. Ph.D. thesis, Dublin City University,
Dublin, Ireland</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e581a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e585" publication-type="other">
Gustafson-Ĉapková S, Samuelsson Y, Volk M (2007) SMULTRON-the Stockholm MULtilingual parallel
TReebank.www.ling.su.se/dali/research/smultron/index</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e595a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e599" publication-type="other">
Han C, Han N-R, Ko E-S, Palmer M (2002) Development and evaluation of a Korean treebank and its
application to NLP. In: Proceedings of the 3rd international conference on language resources and
evaluation (LREC'02). Canary Islands, Spain, pp 1635-1642</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e613a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e617" publication-type="other">
Hanneman G, Lavie A (2009) Decoding with syntactic and non-syntactic phrases in a syntax-based
machine translation system. In: Proceedings of the third workshop on syntax and structure in statistical
translation at the 2009 meeting of the North-American chapter of the association for computational
linguistics (NAACL-HLT-2009). Boulder, CO, June 2009</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e633a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e637" publication-type="other">
Hansen-Schirra S, Neumann S, Vela M (2006) Multi-dimensional annotation and alignment in an English-
German translation corpus. In: Proceedings of the workshop on multi-dimensional markup in natural
language processing (NLPXML-2006) at EACL. Trento, Italy, pp 35-42</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e650a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e654" publication-type="other">
Hassan H, Sima'an K, Way A (2007) Supertagged phrase-based statistical machine translation. In: 45th
annual meeting of the association for computational linguistics (ACL'07). Prague, Czech Republic,
pp 288-295</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e667a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e671" publication-type="other">
Hearne M (2005) Data-oriented models of parsing and translation. Ph.D. thesis, Dublin City University,
Dublin, Ireland</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e681a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e685" publication-type="other">
Hearne M, Tinsley J, Zhechev V, Way A (2007) Capturing translational divergences with a statistical tree-
to-tree aligner. In: Proceedings of the 11th international conference on theoretical and methodological
issues in machine translation (TMI-07). Skövde, Sweden, pp 83-94</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e698a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e702" publication-type="other">
Hearne M, Ozdowska S, Tinsley J (2008) Comparing constituency and dependency representations for
SMT phrase-extraction. In: 15ème Conférence sur le Traitement Automatique des Langues Naturelles
(TALN'08). Avignon, France</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e716a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e720" publication-type="other">
Johnson H, Martin J, Foster G, Kuhn R (2007) Improving translation quality by discarding most of the phras-
etable. In: Proceedings of the 2007 joint conference on empirical methods in natural language process-
ing and computational natural language learning (EMNLP-CoNLL 2007). Prague, Czech Republic,
pp 967-975</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e736a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e740" publication-type="other">
Koehn Ρ (2004) Statistical significance tests for machine translation evaluation. In: Proceedings of the 2004
conference on empirical methods in natural language processing. Barcelona, Spain, pp 388-395</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e750a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e754" publication-type="other">
Koehn Ρ (2005) Europarl: a parallel corpus for statistical machine translation. In: Machine translation
summit X. Phuket, Thailand, pp 79-86</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e764a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e768" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Hoang H (2007) Factored translation models. In: Proceedings of the joint conference on empirical
methods in natural language processing and computational natural language learning (EMNLP-CoN-
LL). Prague, Czech Republic, pp 868-876</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e781a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e785" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Och FJ, Marcu D (2003) Statistical phrase-based translation. In: Proceedings of the 2003 con-
ference of the North American chapter of the association for computational linguistics on human
language technology (NAACL'03). Edmonton, Canada, pp 48-54</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e798a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e802" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Hoang H, Birch A, Callison-Burch C, Federico M, Beitoldi Ν, Cowan Β, Shen W, Moran C,
Zens R, Dyer C, Bojar O, Constantin A, Herbst E (2007) Moses: open source toolkit for statistical
machine translation. In: 45th annual meeting of the association for computational linguistics (ACL),
demonstration session. Prague, Czech Republic, pp 177-180</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e819a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e823" publication-type="other">
Lavie A (2008) Stat-XFER: a general search-based syntax-driven framework for machine translation.
In: Proceedings of the 9th international conference on intelligent text processing and computational
linguistics (CICLing-08)-invited paper. Haifa, Israel, pp 362-375</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e836a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e840" publication-type="other">
Lavie A, Parlikar A, Ambati V (2008) Syntax-driven learning of sub-sentential translation equivalents and
translation rules from parsed parallel corpora. In: Proceedings of the second workshop on syntax and
structure in statistical translation (SSST-2). Columbus. OH</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e853a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e857" publication-type="other">
Lu Y, Huang J, Liu Q (2007) Improving statistical machine translation performance by training data selec-
tion and optimization. In: Proceedings of the 2007 joint conference on empirical methods in natural
language processing and computational natural language learning (EMNLP-CoNLL 2007). Prague,
Czech Republic, pp 343-350</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e873a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e877" publication-type="other">
Marton Y, Resnik Ρ (2008) Soft syntactic constraints for hierarchical phrased-based translation. In: Proceed-
ings of the 46th annual meeting of the association for computational linguistics (ACL' 08). Columbus,
OH, pp 1003-1011</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e890a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e894" publication-type="other">
Papineni K, Roukos S, Ward T, Zhu W-J (2002) BLEU: a method for automatic evaluation of machine trans-
lation. In: 40th annual meeting of the association for computational linguistics (ACL-02). Philadelphia,
PA, pp 311-318</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e907a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e911" publication-type="other">
Petrov S, Klein D (2007) Improved inference for unlexicalized parsing. In: Human language technologies
2007: the conference of the North American chapter of the association for computational linguistics.
Rochester, NY, pp 404-411</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e925a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e929" publication-type="other">
Samuelsson Y, Volk M (2007) Alignment tools for parallel treebanks. In: Proceedings of the biennial GLDV
conference. Tübingen, Germany</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e939a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e943" publication-type="other">
Stolcke A (2002) SRILM-an extensible language modeling toolkit. In: Proceedings of the international
conference spoken language processing. Denver, CO</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e953a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e957" publication-type="other">
Stroppa N, van den Bosch A, Way A (2007) Exploiting source similarity for SMT using context-informed
features. In: Proceedings of the 11th international conference on theoretical and methodological issues
in machine translation (TMI-07). Skövde, Sweden, pp 231-240</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e970a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e974" publication-type="other">
Tinsley J, Hearne M, Way A (2007a) Exploiting parallel treebanks to improve phrase-based statistical
machine translation. In: Proceedings of the sixth international workshop on treebanks and linguistic
theories (TLT-07). Bergen, Norway, pp 175-187</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e987a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e991" publication-type="other">
Tinsley J, Zhechev V, Hearne M, Way A (2007b) Robust language-pair independent sub-tree alignment.
In: Machine translation summit XI. Copenhagen, Denmark, pp 467-474</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e1001a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e1005" publication-type="other">
Vilar D, Stein D, Ney H (2008) Analysing soft syntax features and heuristics for hierarchical phrase based
machine translation. International workshop on spoken language translation</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e1016a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e1020" publication-type="other">
Volk M, Samuelsson Y (2004) Bootstrapping parallel treebanks. In: Proceedings of the 7th conference of
the workshop on linguistically interpreted corpora (LINC). Geneva, Switzerland, pp 71-77</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e1030a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e1034" publication-type="other">
Yamada K, Knight Κ (2001) A syntax-based statistical translation model. In: Proceedings of the 39th annual
meeting of the association for computational linguistics (ACL' 01). Toulouse, France, pp 523-530</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e1044a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e1048" publication-type="other">
Zhechev V, Way A (2008) Automatic generation of parallel treebanks. In: Proceedings of the 22nd interna-
tional conference on computational linguistics (CoLing'08). Manchester, UK, pp 1105-1112</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d644716e1058a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d644716e1062" publication-type="other">
Zollmann A, Venugopal A, Och F, Ponte J (2008) A systematic comparison of phrase-based, hierarchi-
cal and syntax-augmented statistical MT. In: Proceedings of the 22nd international conference on
computational linguistics (CoLing'08). Manchester, England, pp 1145-1152</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


