<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24438329</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Croatian Profit Tax: An ACE in Practice</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>MICHAEL</given-names>
                  <surname>KEEN</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>JOHN</given-names>
                  <surname>KING</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2002</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24438323</issue-id>
         <fpage>401</fpage>
         <lpage>418</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2002</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24438329"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper discusses the experience of Croatia in applying, from 1994 to the beginning of 2001, a profit tax that was charged only on equity income in excess of an imputed normal return — and was thus, in essence, an 'Allowance for Corporate Equity' (ACE) scheme of the kind advocated by the IFS Capital Taxes Group and others. The computation of taxable profit under this system is summarised, and the theoretical attractions of the system are described. The paper then discusses a variety of criticisms that were made of the system in Croatia, including an alleged bias in favour of capital-intensive enterprises (and, in particular, large State-owned enterprises with overvalued assets), international complications, the complexity of the computations of taxable profit, the possibility that the rate of protective interest was set at an inappropriate level, and excessive revenue cost.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d15e162a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e169" publication-type="other">
For an account of the reform by its principal architects, see Rose and Wiswesser (1998) and Schmidt, Wissel
and Stockier (1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e179a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e186" publication-type="other">
Isaac (1997) provides a conceptual critique of the ACE in the UK context.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e193a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e200" publication-type="other">
Austria, Brazil and Italy have operated 'partial ACE' profit taxes, in the sense that imputed equity income
(defined somewhat differently in the three cases) is taxed at a reduced rate, but not (as in Croatia) wholly
exempt. Under the Italian system, for instance, additions to the stock of equity since the introduction of the tax
in 1998 were taxed at 19 per cent rather than the regular rate (latterly) of 34 per cent: see Bordignon, Giannini
and Panteghini (2001) for an assessment. The Italian system was frozen by the new government elected in
2001, and is scheduled to be wholly removed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e223a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e230" publication-type="other">
The intellectual origins of the ACE are to be found in Boadway and Bruce (1984), with explicit development
by IFS Capital Taxes Group (1991) and Devereux and Freeman (1991). Jacobs and Schmidt (1997) assess the
ACE (positively) as a method of corporate tax harmonisation in the EU.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e244a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e251" publication-type="other">
The description that follows is of the tax as it was in mid-2000.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e258a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e265" publication-type="other">
The same approach — starting from the balance sheet — is taken by many profit tax systems in Europe (such
as Germany's), though others (such as that of the UK) start directly from the profit and loss account. Given the
ways in which the various accounts are linked to one another in a double-entry bookkeeping system, the
difference is one of form rather than substance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e281a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e290" publication-type="other">
That is, the 'marginal effective tax rate' (METR) — defined as the difference between the pre-tax and post-tax
rates of return on a marginal project undertaken by the enterprise (expressed as a percentage of the pre-tax
return) — is zero for all types of investment. Once again, it is, of course, crucial here that the assumed discount
rate for the enterprise is the same as the rate of protective interest.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e306a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e313" publication-type="other">
In terms of the algebra of Box 1, this acceleration of depreciation allowances reduces 17» (and hence B,) by 1.
But (from (2)) it also reduces E by 1 — and so reduces the protective interest allowance by p — and increases
77i by 1 (through recovery of the depreciation brought forward). In present value, and so long as the tax rate
remains unchanged, the tax base reduction of 1 in period I is exactly offset by a tax base increase in period 2 of
1 +p.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e332a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e341" publication-type="other">
In practice, maximum depreciation rates (defined on a straight-line basis) were applied in Croatia, and
depreciation shown in the accounts in excess of these rates was carried forward — as shown in the
computations presented in Table 1. However, since accelerated depreciation (of up to twice the prescribed rate
for each class of asset) was permitted, the maximum allowable rates — although irrelevant in present-value
terms — were very high by international standards. For example, before acceleration, road transport vehicles
were depreciated according to the prescribed rate over four years, machinery and equipment over eight years,
office equipment over five years and buildings over 25 years.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e367a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e374" publication-type="other">
in Croatia, enterprises may revalue their fixed assets (and they may opt for LIFO methods of inventory
valuation). These features of accounting practice remove some of the potential distortions to measured profit in
times of inflation. In the presence of the PI deduction, they did not, however, result in a double allowance for
inflation, because the revaluations are reflected in reserves that were included in the measure of 'equity' on
which the profit tax computation was based.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e394a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e401" publication-type="other">
'For this reason, the IFS Capital Taxes Group also anticipated that the ACE would operate in conjunction with
the exemption of investment income at personal level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e411a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e418" publication-type="other">
Except perhaps to the extent that these schemes create tax losses that can be carried forward and that will, in
practice, be deducted from taxable profits in future periods.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e428a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e435" publication-type="other">
The sum of equity and debt would be a better indicator, but data on debt (or enabling its estimation) are not
available.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e445a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e452" publication-type="other">
The equation is
PI ratio = 0.15 + 0.010 EPE R2 = 0.74
(0.04) (0.002)
where the figures in parentheses are standard errors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e468a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e475" publication-type="other">
See McLure and Zodrow (1998) for a dissenting opinion on the usual view that rent taxes are not in principle
creditable in the USA.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e485a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e492" publication-type="other">
See the discussion of the implications of a PI system in Isaac (1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e500a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e507" publication-type="other">
A tax sparing agreement would be needed to preserve the benefit of PI to investors from a resident country
operating the credit system and charging tax at a higher rate than the Croatian. Residence countries might well
be unwilling to offer such sparing; the USA never does.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e520a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e527" publication-type="other">
For example, a referee points out that the low Irish tax rate of 10 per cent for manufacturing and Dublin-based
financial activities seems to have been attractive to US companies.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e537a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e544" publication-type="other">
The argument here draws heavily on Bond and Devereux (1995 and 1999); the latter paper explicitly develops
the case for the use of the risk-free rate of return in the context of an ACE.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e554a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e561" publication-type="other">
The 'S-base' cash-flow tax does this directly by taxing in each period net distributions to shareholders (that
is, dividends less new equity). The PI system, in contrast, gives a deduction only on the imputed returns on new
equity, at rate p (using the notation of Box 1); discounted at the rate p, however, this is equivalent in present
value to an immediate deduction of new equity.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e577a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e584" publication-type="other">
Neutrality also requires that losses be treated symmetrically with gains, which was broadly achieved in
Croatia by the provision for carry-forward of losses at interest. It is also necessary, in principle, that investors
receive a payment in the event of the firm's ceasing operations equal in present value to the unrelieved part of
their initial equity investment. It is not clear that this last provision was met in Croatia.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e600a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e607" publication-type="other">
One might wonder why it could not equally well be argued that interest on debt should be deducted only at
the risk-free rate rather than the rate actually paid. The difference is that so long as debt is competitively
supplied, all rents from the underlying investment accrue to the shareholders; and it is these we are trying to
tax.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d15e632a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e636" publication-type="other">
Boadway, R. and Bruce, N. (1984), 'A general proposition on the design of a neutral business tax',
Journal of Public Economics, vol, 24, pp. 231-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e646a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e650" publication-type="other">
Bond, S. R. and Devereux, M. P. (1995), 'On the design of a neutral business tax under
uncertainty', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 58, pp. 57-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e660a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e664" publication-type="other">
— and — (1999), 'Generalised R-based and S-based taxes under uncertainty', Institute for Fiscal
Studies, Working Paper no. 99/9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e674a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e678" publication-type="other">
Bordignon, M., Giannini, S. and Panteghini, P. (2001), 'Reforming business taxation: lessons from
Italy?', International Tax and Public Finance, vol. 8, pp. 191-210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e689a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e693" publication-type="other">
Devereux, M. P. and Freeman, H. (1991), 'A general neutral profits tax', Fiscal Studies, vol. 12,
no. 3, pp. 1-15.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e703a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e707" publication-type="other">
IFS Capital Taxes Group (1991), Equity for Companies: A Corporation Tax for the 1990s,
Commentary no. 26, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e717a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e721" publication-type="other">
Isaac, J. (1997), 'A comment on the viability of the allowance for corporate equity', Fiscal Studies,
vol. 18, pp. 303-18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e731a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e735" publication-type="other">
Jacobs, O. H. and Schmidt, F. (1997), 'The Allowance for Corporate Equity as a method of
harmonizing corporate taxation in Europe?', Intertax, vol. 25, pp. 232-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e745a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e749" publication-type="other">
McLure, C. E., Jr and Zodrow, G. E. (1998), 'The economic case for foreign tax credits for cash
flow taxes', National Tax Journal, vol. 51, pp. 1-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e759a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e763" publication-type="other">
Meade Committee (1978), The Structure and Reform of Direct Taxation: Report of a Committee
Chaired by Professor James Meade, London: Allen &amp; Unwin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e774a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e778" publication-type="other">
Rose, M. and Wiswesser, R. (1998), 'Tax reform in transition economies: experiences from the
Croatian tax reform process of the 1990s', in P. B. Sprensen (ed.), Public Finance in a
Changing World, Basingstoke: Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e791a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e795" publication-type="other">
Schmidt, P., Wissel, H. and Stockler, M. (1996), 'The new Croatian tax system'. Bulletin of
International Fiscal Documentation, vol. 50, pp. 155-63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
