<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">116</volume>
         <issue-id>i40196102</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44687836</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Document Management for Vehicle Type Approval used in Tata Motors through Teamcenter</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Upendra</given-names>
                  <surname>Kulkarni</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Vivek</given-names>
                  <surname>Pande</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2007</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>705</fpage>
         <lpage>712</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44687836"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>To "Be on the Path for Best Practices" without "Loss of desired Legacy (DENIS) capabilities" is the approach followed in Tata Motors for implementing document management Maximize early "Removal of Pain Areas" while minimizing rework &amp; ensuring right thing at first stage. Objective ----- • Deliver products as per the defined NPI on time, within budget and at the specified quality and cost. • Efficiently manage data and processes for downstream activities • Enable Collaborative Product Development environment. Deployment of document Management is the first phase of implementing Teamcenter Present Application Document is being used to capture technical details of a vehicle under certification. Respective Engineering Research Centre departments' enter data against the set of clauses assigned to them. Then a consolidated report in the prescribed format is obtained through the system. This application document duly signed by authorized signatory along with Type Approval Vehicle is then sent to test agency for certification. Based on this application document and tests carried out on the type approval vehicle, test agency issues a compliance certificate. This Paper presents the Document Management system implemented in Team center in compliance with the Domestic safety regulation &amp; International regulation In view of earlier system used by Tata Motors has some limitation in terms of functionality &amp; applicability. Overcoming these limitation, gap analysis is done &amp; ensured all existing function as well as best practices used for document management.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


