<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24908680</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Taking a Functional Approach to M&amp;S Policy</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Smither</surname>
                  <given-names>Gerry</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Lieutenant Colonel Gerry Smither was a co-chair of the Integrated Product Team that developed AFI 16-1002, M&amp;S Support to Acquisition. Until recently, Lt Col Smither was the Air Force Program Element Monitor for Modeling and Simulation working in the office of the Secretary of the Air Force (Acquisition), Information Dominance Directorate, SAF/AQI. This office is responsible for acquisition modeling and simulation policy within the Air Force and acquisition oversight of modeling and simulation programs. Lt Col Smither is now with the Single Integrated Air Picture (SIAP) System Engineering Task Force.</p>
                  <p>Lieutenant Colonel Skip Langbehn was a co-chair of the Integrated Product Team that developed AFI 16-1002, M&amp;S Support to Acquisition. Until recently, Lt Col Langbehn was a member of the Air Staff as Chief, Analysis Development Branch, MS&amp;A Programs Division, Directorate of Command and Control (AF/XOC). This office is responsible for Air Force Modeling and Simulation policy and programs. Lt Col Langbehn is now with the Joint Staff in J-8/Forces Division.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2002</year>
            <string-date>March 2002</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>35</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e24908669</issue-id>
         <fpage>16</fpage>
         <lpage>18</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24908680"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
