<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24911129</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>FEATURE</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Complexity:</article-title>
            <subtitle>Identifying the Signal when Modeling Operational Problems</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Brown</surname>
                  <given-names>Mark A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr. Mark Brown is currently serving as a Senior Operations Research Analyst at US Strategic Command and is working on the Commander's Design Team. Previous assignments at US Strategic Command since 2004 included management of the command's input to the Department of Defense's Analytic Agenda, development of the command's Information Strategy, and serving as the chief of Science and Technology Management. Prior to joining US Strategic Command he taught computer science (architecture and network security) and mathematics (calculus and linear programming) at Hamilton College and Midland Lutheran College. While on active duty, he graduated from Airborne and Ranger schools and served in a variety of positions including platoon leader and company commander and on staff's at the brigade and theater levels as well as the Army Staff. He is an Air War College Graduate and holds a BS from the US Military Academy, a Masters from the University of Southern California, and a doctorate in Computer Science from Nova Southeastern University.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>March 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>46</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e24911107</issue-id>
         <fpage>26</fpage>
         <lpage>29</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2013, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24911129"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>This article approaches the difficulties of modeling in a complex environment from a western perspective. In order to improve modeling to support complex operations, it provides a working definition of complexity and seven metaphors to foster discussions on sources of complexity. The author notes three advantages to indicate potential usefulness of seven metaphors when communicating about complexity. Balancing these advantages the article notes four caveats for using metaphors. The summary reviews the completed efforts and provides suggested additional research topics.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Box, G. E. P. 1979. Robustness in the Strategy of Scientific Model Building. Robustness in Statistics: Proceedings of a Workshop. Launer, R. L., and Wilkinson, G. N., eds.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Joint Staff. 2011. Joint Operation Planning. Joint Publication 5-0. Washington, DC. 11 August. www.dtic.mil/doctrine/new_ pubs/jp5_0.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lai, D. 2004. Learning from the Stones: A Go Approach to Mastering China’s Strategic Concept, Shi. Strategic Studies Institute; www.fas.org/man/eprint/lai.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mitchell, M. 2009. Complexity: A Guided Tour. Oxford University Press. Kindle edition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Silver, N. 2012. Why So Many Predictions Fail—but Some Don’t. Penguin Press. Kindle edition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
