<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023189</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Fiscal Federalism and Fiscal Competition</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Assignment and Division of the Tax Base in a System of Hierarchical Governments</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hoyt</surname>
                  <given-names>William H.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>
                  <addr-line>Department of Economics</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>Gatton College of Business and Economics, and Martin School of Public Policy and Administration</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>University of Kentucky</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>Lexington, KY 40506</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>(859)257-2518 (O)</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>(859)323-1920 (Fax)</addr-line>
               </aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>23</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023189"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Vertical externalities, changes in one level of government’s policies that affect the budget of another level of government, may lead to non-optimal government policies. These externalities are associated with tax bases that are shared or “co-occupied” by two levels of government. Here we consider whether the co-occupancy of tax bases is desirable. We examine the optimal extent of the tax bases of a lower level of government (local) and a higher level (state). While we find that it is not optimal to have co-occupancy in the absence of other corrective policies, eliminating co-occupancy does not eliminate fiscal externalities, meaning that tax rates can still be above or now below the socially-optimal levels. Elimination of co-occupancy is not a substitute for a policy such as intergovernmental matching grants which directly eliminates fiscal externalities. We show that if policies are available that eliminate fiscal externalities, co-occupancy will, in fact, be desirable.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Boadway, M. Keen, Efficiency and the optimal direction of federal-state transfers, International Tax and Public Finance 3 (1996) 137-155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Boadway, M. Marchand, M. Vigneault, The consequences of overlapping tax bases for redistribution and public spending in a federation, Journal of Public Economics 68 (1998) 453-478.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">B. Dahlby, Fiscal Externalities and the Design of Intergovernmental Grants, International Tax and Public Finance 3 (1996) 397-412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">B. Dahlby, Taxing choices: issues in the assignment of taxes in federations, International Social Science Journal (2001) 93-100.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">B. Dahlby, J. Mintz, and S. Wilson, The deductibility of provincial business taxes in a federation with verti-cal fiscal externalities, The Canadian Journal of Economics 33 (2000) 677-694.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">B. Dahlby, L. Wilson, Fiscal capacity, tax effort, and optimal equalization grants, Canadian Journal of Eco-nomics 27 (1994) 657-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">B. Dahlby, L. Wilson, Vertical fiscal externalities in a federation, Journal of Public Economics 87 (2003) 917-930.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J.F. Dillon, Commentaries on the Law of Municipal Corporations, vol. 1, 5<sup>th</sup> edition (J. Crockfott, Boston, MA) (1911).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">L. Flochel, T. Madies, Interjurisdictional tax competition in a federal system of overlapping revenue maxi-mizing governments, International Tax and Public Finance, 9 (2002) 121-141.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Flowers, Shared tax sources in a Leviathan model of federation, Public Finance Quarterly 16 (1988) 67-77.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. H. Hoyt, Tax policy coordination, vertical externalities, and optimal taxation in a system of hierarchical governments, Journal of Urban Economics 50 (2001) 491-516.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. R. Johnson, Income redistribution in a federal system, American Economic Review 78 (1988) 570-573.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Keen, Pursuing Leviathan: fiscal federalism and international tax competition, paper prepared for the In-ternational Institute of Public Finance, (unpublished; Colchester, England: University of Essex) (1995).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Keen, Vertical externalities in the theory of fiscal federalism, International Monetary Fund Papers 45 (1998) 454-84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Keen, C. Kotsogiannis, Does federalism lead to excessively high taxes? American Economic Review 92 (2002) 363-370.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Keen, C. Kotsogiannis, Tax competition in federations and the welfare consequences of decentralization, Journal of Urban Economics 56 (2004) 397-407.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. A. Musgrave, Who should tax, where and what? in Tax Assignment in Federal Countries, ed. by C. E. McLure, Australian National University Press, Canberrra, Australia (1983).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. A. Musgrave, P. A. Musgrave, Public Finance in Theory and Practice, McGraw-Hill, New York, NY, 5<sup>th</sup> edition (1989).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. E. Oates, Federalism and government finance, in Modern Public Finance ed. by John M. Quigley and Eugene Smolensky, Harvard University Press, Cambridge, MA (1994).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Sato, Fiscal externalities and efficient transfers in a federation, International Tax and Public Finance 7 (2000) 119-139.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J.D. Wilson, On the optimal tax base for commodity taxation, The American Economic Review 79 1989 1196-1206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J.D. Wilson, Theories of tax competition, National Tax Journal 52 (1999) 269-304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J.D. Wilson, E. Janeba, Decentralization and international tax competition, Journal of Public Economics 89 (2005)1211-1229.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Wrede, Vertical and horizontal tax competition: Will uncoordinated Leviathans end up on the wrong side of the Laffer curve? Finanzarchiv 53 (1996) 461-79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Wrede, Shared tax sources and public expenditures, International Tax and Public Finance 7 (2000)163-175.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article> 

