<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277672</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Towards the LES Simulation of IC Engines with Parallel Topologically Changing Meshes</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Piscaglia</surname>
                  <given-names>Federico</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Montorfano</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrea</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Onorati</surname>
                  <given-names>Angelo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>926</fpage>
         <lpage>940</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277672"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The implementation and the combination of advanced boundary conditions and subgrid scale models for Large Eddy Simulation (LES) in the multi-dimensional open-source CFD code OpenFOAM® are presented. The goal is to perform reliable cold flow LES simulations in complex geometries, such as in the cylinders of internal combustion engines. The implementation of a boundary condition for synthetic turbulence generation upstream of the valve port and of the compressible formulation of the Wall-Adapting Local Eddy-viscosity sgs model (WALE) is described. The WALE model is based on the square of the velocity gradient tensor and it accounts for the effects of both the strain and the rotation rate of the smallest resolved turbulent fluctuations and it recovers the proper<italic>y</italic>³ near-wall scaling for the eddy viscosity without requiring dynamic procedure; hence, it is supposed to be a very reliable model for ICE simulation. Validation of the implemented models has been performed separately on two steady state flow benches, where experimental data were available: a backward facing step geometry and a simple IC engine geometry with one axed central valve. A method to evaluate the turbulence resolution of LES simulation based on a Length Scale Resolution (LSR) parameter has been proposed and a discussion about the completeness of the LES simulation (i.e. LES simulation quality) is presented. Finally, the implementation of a fully parallel algorithm for the management of topologically changing meshes in the OpenFOAM®-2.1.x technology is described. The aim is to implement a reliable framework to perform LES simulation of internal combustion engines by the OpenFOAM<sup>®</sup>technology.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferziger J. H. and Perić M.. Computational Methods for Fluid Dynamics. Springer, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Versteeg H. K. and Malalasekera W.. An Introduction to Computational Fluid Dynamics. Longman Scientific and Technical, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sagaut P.. Large eddy simulation for incompressible flows: an introduction. Scientific computation. Springer-Verlag, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nicoud F. and Ducros F.. Subgrid-scale stress modelling based on the square of the velocity gradient tensor. Flow, Turbulence and Combustion, 62:183-200, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eaton J., Johnston J., and Westphal R.. Experimental study of flow reattachment in a single-sided sudden expansion. Contractor report 3765, NASA Ames Research Center, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thobois, L., Rymer, G., Soulères, T., and Poinsot, T., “Large-Eddy Simulation in IC Engine Geometries,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1854, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1854.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brusiani, F., Forte, C., and Bianchi, G., “Assessment of a Numerical Methodology for Large Eddy Simulation of ICE Wall Bounded Non- Reactive Flows,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4145, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-4145.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piscaglia F., Montorfano A., Onorati A., and Brusiani F.. Boundary conditions and subgrid scale models for les simulation of ic engines. In Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piscaglia F., Montorfano A., and Onorati A.. Improving the simulation of the acoustic performance of complex silencers for ice by a multidimensional non-linear approach. Journal of Sound and Vibration, X(X):xxx-xxx, 2013. doi:10.1016/j.jsv.2012.09.030.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piscaglia F., Montorfano A., and Onorati A.. Improving the simulation of the acoustic performance of complex silencers for ICE by a Multi- Dimensional non-linear approach. SAE Int. J. Engines, 2(5):633-648, 2012. doi:10.4271/2012-01-0828.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piscaglia F., Montorfano A., and Onorati A.. Development of NSCBC for compressible navier-stokes equations in Open-FOAM. In Sixth OpenFOAM Workshop, Penn State, June 12th-16th, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montorfano A., Piscaglia F., and Ferrari G.. Inlet boundary conditions for incompressible les: A comparative study. Mathematical and Computer Modelling, 2011. doi:10.1016/j.mcm.2011.10.077.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tabor G. R. and Baba-Ahmadi M. H.. Inlet conditions for large eddy simulation: A review. Computers &amp; Fluids, 39(4):553 - 567, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davidson L.. Using isotropic synthetic fluctuations as inlet boundary conditions for unsteady simulations. Advances and Applications in Fluid Mechanics, 1(1):1-35, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Billson M.. Computational Techniques for Turbulence Generated Noise. PhD thesis, Chalmers University of Technology, Göteborg, Sweden, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Germano M., Piomelli U., Moin P., and Cabot W. H.. A dynamic subgrid-scale eddy viscosity model. Physics of fluids A, 3:1760, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wollblad C., Davidson L., and Eriksson L.. Large eddy simulation of transonic flow with shock wave/turbulent boundary layer interaction. AIAA Journal, 44(10):2340-2353, 2006. doi:10.2514/1.20358.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pope S. B.. Turbulent Flows. Cambridge University Press, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brusiani, F., Bianchi, G., Baritaud, T., and d'Espinosa, A., “Using LES for Predicting High Performance Car Airbox Flow,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 2(1):1050-1064, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OpenCFD. OpenFOAM Programmer's Guide. OpenCFD Ltd., 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piscaglia F., Montorfano A., Onorati A., and Keskinen J. P.. Boundary conditions and subgrid scale models for les simulation of internal combustion engines. In International Multidimensional Engine Modeling User's Group Meeting 2012, Detroit, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akselvoll K. and Moin P.. Large eddy simulation of turbulent confined coanular jets and flow over a backward-facing step. Rept. TF-63, Thermosciences Division, Department of Mechanical Engineering, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davidson Lars. Large eddy simulations: How to evaluate resolution. International Journal of Heat and Fluid Flow, 30(5):1016 - 1025, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spalding D. B.. A single formula for the law of the wall. Journal of Applied Mechanics, Trans. ASME, Series E, 28:455-458, 1961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greenshields Christopher J., Weller Henry G., Gasparini Luca, and Reese Jason M.. Implementation of semi-discrete, non-staggered central schemes in a colocated, polyhedral, finite volume framework, for highspeed viscous flows. International Journal for Numerical Methods in Fluids, 63(1):1-21, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OpenCFD. OpenFOAM User's Guide, v2.0.0. OpenCFD Ltd., 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Juretić F. and Gosman A. D.. Error analysis of the finite-volume method with respect to mesh type. Numerical heat transfer, part B: fundamentals, 57:414-439, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jasak H. and Tukovic Z.. Automatic mesh motion for the unstructured finite volume method. Transactions of FAMENA, 30(2), 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lucchini, T., D'Errico, G., Jasak, H., and Tukovic, Z., “Automatic Mesh Motion with Topological Changes for Engine Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0170, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0170.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jasak H.. OpenFOAM® -extend project: Community-driven releases of OpenFOAM®, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OpenCFD. OpenFOAM®: The open source cfd toolbox, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jasak H.. Error analysis and estimation in the Finite Volume method with applications to fluid flows. PhD thesis, Imperial College, University of London, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
