<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">8</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466874</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466876</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Shareholder Voting and Corporate Governance Around the World</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Peter</given-names>
                  <surname>Iliev</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Karl V.</given-names>
                  <surname>Lins</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Darius P.</given-names>
                  <surname>Miller</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Lukas</given-names>
                  <surname>Roth</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2167</fpage>
         <lpage>2202</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466876"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Using a sample of non-U.S. firms from 43 countries, we investigate whether laws and regulations as well as votes cast by U.S. institutional investors are consistent with an effective shareholder voting process. We find that laws and regulations allow for meaningful votes to be cast, as shareholder voting is both mandatory and binding for important elections. For votes cast, we find there is greater dissent voting when investors fear expropriation. Further, greater dissent voting is associated with higher director turnover and more M&amp;A withdrawals. Our results suggest that shareholder voting is an effective mechanism for exercising governance around the world.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d623241e223a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e230" publication-type="other">
Examples of research indicating that institutional investors actively express governance concerns via private
engagement include Brav, Jiang, Partnoy, and Thomas (2008), Becht, Franks, Mayer, and Rossi (2009), Klein
and Zur (2009), and McCahery, Sautner, and Starks (2010). Evidence indicating that investors express discontent
by "voting with their feet" by selling their shares in firms that do not implement stronger governance practices
includes Parrino, Sias, and Starks (2003) and Leuz, Lins, and Warnock (2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e249a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e256" publication-type="other">
This finding is consistent with the research on voting rules and strategies to circumvent a shareholder vote for
U.S.-domiciled acquirer firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e266a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e273" publication-type="other">
We obtain votes from Form N-PX reports filed by U.S. registered investment companies. The vast majority of
these investment companies are mutual funds. Hedge funds are not required to report how they vote their shares
and, thus, are not part of our dataset.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e286a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e293" publication-type="other">
Jacobsen (2014) finds that managers of U.S. firms who show restraint by withdrawing marginal deals are
rewarded in the capital and labor markets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e304a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e311" publication-type="other">
In particular, one of the questions covered is "How are directors appointed and removed? Is shareholder approval
required?"</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e321a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e328" publication-type="other">
Exceptions are sometimes given for employee representatives or directors appointed by significant block holders.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e335a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e342" publication-type="other">
Table 1 also shows that the country guides provide more complete coverage of the shareholder voting laws and
regulations pertaining to director elections compared with M&amp;A elections.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e352a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e359" publication-type="other">
See also Nenova (2003) for an analysis of country-level legal environments and several takeover regulations that
govern procedures for setting the price that minority target shareholders must be offered.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e369a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e376" publication-type="other">
A recent cross-border example of these dynamics, involving a U.S. acquirer, was Kraft's acquisition of Cadbury.
Kraft revised the initial offer to finance the acquisition with less than 20% of stock to circumvent the requirement
of shareholder approval of the deal. This strategy was strongly opposed by Warren Buffett, the largest shareholder
of Kraft. This and other approaches seem rather common in the United States; for example, Hsieh and Wang
(2008) report that only 53% of the acquisitions required shareholder approval in the United States during the
1990 to 2005 period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e399a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e406" publication-type="other">
We exclude votes of shareholder-initiated proposals in our final sample but note here that our results are also robust
to including them. We also remove the small number of management-initiated proposals that occur in tandem
with a shareholder-initiated proposal for the same agenda item that is opposed by management (161 firm-year
observations) because there is a mechanical relationship of lesser shareholder support for these management-
initiated proposals. For evidence on shareholder-initiated proposals, see Alexander, Chen, Seppi, and Spatt
(2010), Buchanan, Netter, and Yang (2010), and Gillan and Starks (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e430a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e437" publication-type="other">
In our sample, we use only annual meetings held after July 1, 2003, to ensure the funds reported under the
mandate of SEC Final Rule No. 33-8188 that required the enhanced disclosure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e447a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e454" publication-type="other">
Cai, Garner, and Walkling (2009) also use the average vote percentage compiled for each firm-year in their tests.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e461a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e468" publication-type="other">
We confirm all our results when we instead use a measure of voluntary disclosure obtained from Bushman
et al. (2004). This voluntary disclosure intensity measure is the average number of 90 accounting and non-
accounting items disclosed by a sample of large companies in their annual reports. It is based on a broad set
of disclosures, including general information; items from the income statement, balance sheet, and funds flow
statement; accounting standards; stock data; governance data; and special items.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e487a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e494" publication-type="other">
We obtain institutional ownership data from the FactSet Ownership database (LionShares) previously used, for
example, in Ferreira and Matos (2008), Ferreira, Massa, and Matos (2010), and Aggarwal et al. (2011).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e504a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e511" publication-type="other">
All firm-level data are obtained from Worldscope and Datastream, and the cross-listing data are from depositary
receipt lists from Bank of New York, J.P. Morgan, and Citigroup, CRSP files, and SEC filings.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e521a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e530" publication-type="other">
For robustness, we use a threshold measure of Insider control that equals one if a firm's Insider control is larger
than the sample median value of Insider Control, and zero otherwise. This alternative measure of Insider control
is negatively and significantly (/»-value &lt;0.01) associated with Voting for, confirming our findings. We also note
that while it may be interesting to compare our non-U.S. results with prior U.S. results, it is not possible to do
so directly because the managerial entrenchment measures, as well as other data, are different between our tests
and those conducted for U.S. firms' director voting patterns by Cai, Garner, and Walkling (2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e554a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e561" publication-type="other">
Because tests conducted by Aggarwal, Erel, Stulz, and Williamson (2010) imply that investors would be more
concerned with managerial entrenchment when country institutions are weak, while research by Bergman
and Nicolaievsky (2007) and Doidge et al. (2007) implies the opposite, in untabulated models we test the
interdependence between firm-level and country-level investor protection. For each country-level protection
variable, we estimate models with that variable, Insider control, and an interaction term between these variables,
along with the prior control variables. We find that the standalone coefficients retain significance but the
interaction term is generally insignificant, which suggests that the effect of firm-level managerial entrenchment
on shareholder votes cast in corporate elections is largely independent of country-level institutions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e590a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e597" publication-type="other">
While studies of whether shareholder voting patterns are linked to changes in executive compensation are also
informative, we do not analyze this topic because executive compensation packages are disclosed in relatively
few countries (Fernandes, Ferreira, Matos, and Murphy 2013) and compensation votes are rarely mandatory and
binding (Correa and Lei 2014). Evidence shows that shareholders in U.S. and U.K. firms provide less support
for equity compensation plans that are excessive or dilutive (see, e.g., Morgan, Poulsen, and Wolf 2006; Carter
and Zamora 2009; Ertimur, Ferri, and Muslu 2011; Armstrong, Gow, and Larcker 2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e620a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e629" publication-type="other">
See, for example, "Templeton backs Sun Pharmaceuticals in Taro Pharmaceuticals bid—Report," Dow Jones
International News, December 1, 2009; "Taro Pharmaceuticals Industries Ltd—Templeton Asset Management
executive chairman Mark Möbius sends letter to chairman of Taro Pharmaceuticals urging new management,"
Market News Publishing, December 23,2009; "Taro shareholders to Levitt and directors: Quit the board; minority
shareholders also reject indemnification proposals," PR Newswire, December 31, 2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e648a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e655" publication-type="other">
See, for example, "Shareholders reject Tokyo Electron, Yokogawa Electric's poison pills," Kyodo News, June
24, 2005; 'Tokyo Electron shareholders reject takeover defense step," Dow Jones International News, June 24,
2005; "Tokyo Electron, Yokogawa shareholders nix anti-takeover plans," Nikkei Report, June 25, 2005.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e668a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e675" publication-type="other">
Similarly, in June 2005, U.S. institutional investors were influential and pivotal for the rejection of "poison
pill" proposals in Yokogowa Electric Corp. and Fanuc Ltd. Sixty-four percent of Yokogawa's U.S. institutional
investors voted against the proposal, and less than 20% of U.S. funds voted in favor of management of Funac. In
both firms, according to reports, the two-thirds majority was again only missed by fractional margins, attributing
a crucial and pivotal role to these U.S. institutions that voted their shares against these proposals.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e694a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e701" publication-type="other">
See, for example, "BSkyB shareholders voice unease," Financial Times, September 24, 2003; "BSkyB to Face
Shareholder Ire over James Murdoch's Ascent," Wall Street Journal, November 12,2003; "BSkyB CEO rides out
criticism: James Murdoch is approved as director by 82% to 18%; father dismisses dissent," Wall Street Journal
Europe, November 17, 2003; "Board to be reorganised after review at BSkyB," Financial Times, May 14, 2004;
"BSkyB board reforms aid independence," Financial Times, June 15, 2004.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e721a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e728" publication-type="other">
See, for example, "Deutsche Boerse's management is criticized by big shareholders," Wall Street Journal,
February 22, 2005; "New blow to Deutsche's bid for LSE," The Times (London), February 25, 2005; "Merrill
Lynch opposes Deutsche Boerse bid for LSE", Dow Jones International News, February 25, 2005; "Moving the
market: Deutsche Boerse, in abrupt switch, drops proposed bid to buy LSE," Wall Street Journal, March 7,2005;
"Werner Seifert, longtime CEO of Deutsche Boerse, resigns amid shareholder squabble," Associated Press, May
9, 2005.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e751a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e758" publication-type="other">
In contrast to data on when directors leave the board, director hiring dates are often missing, so it is not possible
to compute the total number of board members. Thus, while we can compute a count measure of board turnover,
we cannot compute the percentage of directors turned over each year.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e771a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e778" publication-type="other">
The ISS Voting Analytics database provides a brief description for each agenda item, but it does not provide the
exact text including the director name. A potential concern is that when new directors are nominated there is more
likely to be dissent, perhaps because of poor firm performance, which could lead to a mechanical relation between
voting and turnover. However, prior findings by Cai, Garner, and Walkling (2009) show that new directors get
higher total shareholder support than incumbent directors, and Iliev and Lowry (2014) show that the same is
true when focusing on just institutional investor votes. Further, our models control for firm-level factors like past
performance that could lead to a change in directors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e804a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e811" publication-type="other">
While we explicitly control for firm performance, for robustness we also use the method employed in Cai, Garner,
and Walkling (2009). Specifically, we estimate a regression of Voting for directors on prior-year industry-adjusted
Profitability and Excess stock return, as well as industry, country, and year dummies. Using the residual from
this regression as measure of shareholder voting for directors confirms our results from Table 5 (not tabulated
for brevity).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e830a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e837" publication-type="other">
Yermack (2004) finds for U.S firms that a one-standard-deviation decrease in performance leads to about a 20%
increase in director turnover on a base of unconditional director turnover of 4.6% per year.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e847a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e856" publication-type="other">
Following Ai and Norton (2003), Norton, Wang, and Ai (2004), Greene (2010), and Karaca-Mandic, Norton, and
Dowd (2012), we define a model with an interaction term as E[y x,*2, Z] = F (ß x +ß2x2+ß2(x x X2)+S'Z),
where x (Voting for directors) and *2 (U.S. institutional ownership) are the variables of interest, Z is a set of
control variables, F(.) is a Poisson (exponential) transformation, and ß, ß2, and 8' are regression coefficients.
Letting v=ßx +ß2x2+ßl2(xl the marginal effect of Voting for directors Oq) on the conditional
expected value of Director turnover (y ) is calculated asdE[yx,X2,Z]/dx=dF/dvxdv/dx=dF/dvx(ß +
ß2xl)- In a nonlinear model dF/dv^ 1,and the marginal effect of Voting for directors (jcj ) is not a constant, but
instead depends on the values not only of x (Voting for directors) but also X2(U.S. institutional ownership), and
more generally, on all the other included control variables. Thus, relying on the coefficient estimates from the
regression output of this nonlinear model can be misleading for making inferences. In contrast, in a linear model
dF/dv= 1,and the marginal effect of x is ß +ß2X2- This expression varies linearly with X2 (U.S. institutional
ownership) but it is the same for any values of x (Voting for directors) and any other covariâtes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e899a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e906" publication-type="other">
More specifically, to correctly calculate the marginal effects of Voting for directors, we use the margins command
in Stata 11 and estimate the average marginal effects at different levels of U.S. institutional ownership as suggested
by Karaca-Mandic, Norton, and Dowd (2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e919a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e926" publication-type="other">
We use observations from the following countries: Australia, Austria, Belgium, Brazil, Bulgaria, Canada, Chile,
Denmark, Finland, France, Germany, Greece, Hong Kong, India, Indonesia, Ireland, Italy, Japan, Malaysia,
Netherlands, Norway, Portugal, South Africa, Spain, Sweden, and United Kingdom.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e939a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e946" publication-type="other">
As discussed in Section 1.1, it is difficult to verify that all acquirer votes that we observe in the dataset are indeed
mandatory and binding. However, while our research design intends to use only mandatory votes because these
represent the strongest test of whether the shareholder voting process works for non-U.S. firms, the possible
inclusion of some nonbinding votes may not matter given prior work showing that advisory-only votes can
impact firm outcomes (see, e.g., Cunat, Gine, and Guadalupe 2012; Ertimur, Ferri, and Muslu 2011; Ferri and
Maber 2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e969a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e976" publication-type="other">
Since our sample of target firms are public and we exclude tender-offer deals, we do not add the usual dummy
variables for private target firm and tender-offer deals. Further, for target firms, in unreported regressions, we
also control for the logarithm of the total deal value and confirm our results. We choose not to include this control
in our target-firm regressions because it is missing for about 26% of our observations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e992a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e999" publication-type="other">
For the acquirer firms, in terms of economic significance, the results of model 4 suggest that a one-standard-
deviation decrease in Voting for M&amp;A is associated with a 49.0% increase in the probability that a deal will not
be completed (calculated as -0.059 x 0.357 / 0.043).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623241e1012a1310">
            <label>34</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623241e1019" publication-type="other">
In contrast to our non-U.S.-firm results, for U.S. firms Daines, Gow, and Larcker (2010) do not find any relation
between shareholder voting patterns and a firm's RiskMetrics governance rating.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d623241e1038a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1042" publication-type="other">
Aggarwal, R., I. Erel, M. Ferreira, and R Matos. 2011. Does governance travel around the world? Evidence from
institutional investors. Journal of Financial Economics 100:154—81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1052a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1056" publication-type="other">
Aggarwal, R., I. Erel, R. Stulz, and R. Williamson. 2010. Differences in governance mechanisms between U.S.
and foreign firms: Measurements, causes and consequences. Review of Financial Studies 23:3131-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1066a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1070" publication-type="other">
Ai, C., and E. Norton. 2003. Interaction terms in logit and probit models. Economics Letters 80:123-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1077a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1081" publication-type="other">
Alexander, C., M. Chen, D. Seppi, and C. Spatt. 2010. Interim news and the role of proxy voting advice. Review
of Financial Studies 23:4419-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1092a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1096" publication-type="other">
Armstrong, C., I. Gow, and D. Larcker. 2013. The efficacy of shareholder voting: Evidence from equity
compensation plans, Journal of Accounting Research 51:909-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1106a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1110" publication-type="other">
Back, K., T. Li, and A. Ljungqvist. 2013. Liquidity and governance. Working Paper no. wl9669, NBER.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1117a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1121" publication-type="other">
Becht, M., J. Franks, C. Mayer, and S. Rossi. 2009. Returns to shareholder activism: Evidence from a clinical
study of the Hermes UK Focus Fund. Review of Financial Studies 22:3093-3129.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1131a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1135" publication-type="other">
Bergman, N., and D. Nicolaievsky. 2007. Investor protection and the Coasian view. Journal of Financial
Economics 84:738-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1145a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1149" publication-type="other">
Brav, A., W. Jiang, F. Partnoy, and R. Thomas. 2008. Hedge fund activism, corporate governance, and firm
performance. Journal of Finance 63:1729-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1159a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1163" publication-type="other">
Bris, A., and C. Cabolis. 2008. The value of investor protection: Firm evidence from cross-border mergers.
Review of Financial Studies 21:605-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1174a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1178" publication-type="other">
Buchanan, B., J. Netter, and T. Yang. 2010. Are shareholder proposals an important corporate governance device?
Evidence from US and UK shareholder proposals. Working Paper, University of Georgia.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1188a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1192" publication-type="other">
Bushman, R., J. Piotroski, and A. Smith. 2004. What determines corporate transparency? Journal of Accounting
Research 42:207-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1202a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1206" publication-type="other">
Cai, J., J. Garner, and R. Walkling. 2009. Electing directors. Journal of Finance 64:2389-2421.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1213a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1217" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. 1996. Understanding risk and return. Journal of Political Economy 104:298-345.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1224a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1228" publication-type="other">
Carter, M., and V. Zamora. 2009. Shareholder remuneration votes and CEO compensation design. Working Paper,
Boston College.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1238a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1242" publication-type="other">
Chen, X., J. Hartford, and K. Li. 2007. Monitoring: Which institutions matter? Journal of Financial Economics
86:279-305.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1253a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1257" publication-type="other">
Correa, R., and U. Lei. 2014. Say on pay laws, executive compensation, pay slice, and firm value around the
world. Working Paper, FRB International Finance Discussion Paper 1084.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1267a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1271" publication-type="other">
Cunat, V., M. Gine, and M. Guadalupe. 2012. The vote is cast: The effect of corporate governance on shareholder
value. Journal of Finance 67:1943-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1281a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1285" publication-type="other">
Daines, R., I. Gow, and D. Larcker. 2010. Rating the ratings: How good are commercial governance ratings?
Journal of Financial Economics 98:439-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1295a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1299" publication-type="other">
Djankov, S., R. La Porta, F. Lopez-de-Silanes, and A. Shleifer. 2008. The law and economics of self-dealing.
Journal of Financial Economics 88:430-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1309a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1313" publication-type="other">
Doidge, C., A. Karolyi, K. Lins, D. Miller, and R. Stulz. 2009. Private benefits of control, ownership, and the
cross-listing decision. Journal of Finance 64:425-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1323a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1327" publication-type="other">
Doidge, C., A. Karolyi, and R. Stulz. 2007. Why do countries matter so much for corporate governance? Journal
of Financial Economics 86:1-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1338a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1342" publication-type="other">
Durnev, A., and E. Kim. 2005. To steal or not to steal: Firm attributes, legal environment, and valuation. Journal
of Finance 60:1461-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1352a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1356" publication-type="other">
Ertimur, Y., F. Fern, and V. Muslu. 2011. Shareholder activism and CEO pay. Review of Financial Studies
24:535-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1366a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1370" publication-type="other">
Fan, J., and T. Wong. 2002. Corporate ownership structure and the informativeness of accounting earnings in
East Asia. Journal of Accounting and Economics 33:401-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1380a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1384" publication-type="other">
Fernandes, N., M. Ferreira, P. Matos, and K. Murphy. 2013. Are U.S. CEOs paid more? New international
evidence. Review of Financial Studies 26:323-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1394a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1398" publication-type="other">
Ferreira, M., M. Massa, and P. Matos. 2010. Shareholders at the gate? Institutional investors and cross border
mergers and acquisitions. Review of Financial Studies 23:601-44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1408a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1412" publication-type="other">
Ferreira, M., and P. Matos. 2008. The color of investors' money: The role of institutional investors around the
world. Journal of Financial Economics 88:495-533.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1423a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1427" publication-type="other">
Ferri, F., and D. Maber. 2013. Say on pay votes and CEO compensation: Evidence from the UK. Review of
Finance 17:527-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1437a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1441" publication-type="other">
Fischer, P., J. Grämlich, B. Miller, and H. White. 2009. Investor perceptions of board performance: Evidence
from uncontested director elections. Journal of Accounting Economics 48:172-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1451a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1455" publication-type="other">
Gillan, S., and L. Starks. 2000. Corporate governance proposals and shareholder activism: The role of institutional
investors. Journal of Financial Economics 57:275-305.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1465a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1469" publication-type="other">
Greene, W. 2010. Testing hypotheses about interaction terms in nonlinear models. Economic Letters 107:291-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1476a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1480" publication-type="other">
Gruener, D. 2006. Chilled to the pill: The Japanese judiciary's cool reception of the poison pill and potential
repercussions. University of Pittsburgh Law Review 67:871-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1490a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1494" publication-type="other">
Hermalin, B., and M. Weisbach. 1988. The determinants of board composition. RAND Journal of Economics
19:589-606.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1505a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1509" publication-type="other">
Hsieh, J., and Q. Wang. 2008. Shareholder voting rights in mergers and acquisitions. Working Paper, George
Mason University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1519a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1523" publication-type="other">
Iliev, P., and M. Lowry. 2014. Are mutual funds active voters? Review of Financial Studies 28:446-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1530a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1534" publication-type="other">
Jacobsen, S. 2014. The death of the deal: Are withdrawn acquisition deals informative of CEO quality? Journal
of Financial Economics 114:54—83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1544a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1548" publication-type="other">
Karaca-Mandic, P., E. Norton, and B. Dowd. 2012. Interaction terms in nonlinear models. Health Services
Research 47:255-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1558a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1562" publication-type="other">
Kau, J., J. Linck, and P. Rubin. 2008. Do managers listen to the market? Journal of Corporate Finance 14:347-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1569a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1573" publication-type="other">
Klein, A., and E. Zur. 2009. Entrepreneurial shareholder activism: Hedge funds and other private investors.
Journal of Finance 64:187-229.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1584a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1588" publication-type="other">
La Porta, R., F. Lopez-de-Silanes, and A. Shleifer. 1999. Corporate ownership around the world. Journal of
Finance 54:471-517.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1598a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1602" publication-type="other">
La Porta, R., F. Lopez-de-Silanes, A. Shleifer, and R. Vishny. 1998. Law and finance. Journal of Political
Economy 106:1113-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1612a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1616" publication-type="other">
Lei, U., and D. Miller. 2008. International cross-listing, firm performance, and top management turnover: A test
of the bonding hypothesis. Journal of Finance 63:1897-1937.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1626a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1630" publication-type="other">
Leuz, C., K. Lins, and F. Warnock. 2009. Do foreigners invest less in poorly governed firms? Review of Financial
Studies 22:3245-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1640a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1644" publication-type="other">
Leuz, C., D. Nanda, and P. Wysocki. 2003. Earnings management and investor protection: An international
comparison. Journal of Financial Economics 69:505-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1654a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1658" publication-type="other">
Luo, Y. 2005. Do insiders learn from outsiders? Evidence from mergers and acquisitions. Journal of Finance
60:1951-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1669a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1673" publication-type="other">
McCahery, J., Z. Sautner, and L. Starks. 2010. Behind the scenes: The corporate governance preferences of
institutional investors. Working Paper, University of Texas at Austin.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1683a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1687" publication-type="other">
Morgan, A., A. Poulsen, and J. Wolf. 2006. The evolution of shareholder voting for executive compensation
schemes. Journal of Corporate Finance 12:715-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1697a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1701" publication-type="other">
Nenova, T. 2003. The value of corporate voting rights and control: Across-country analysis. Journal of Financial
Economics 68:325-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1711a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1715" publication-type="other">
Norton, E., H. Wang, and C. Ai. 2004. Computing interaction effects and standard errors in logit and probit
models. Stata Journal 4:154-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1725a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1729" publication-type="other">
Parrino, R., R. Sias, and L. Starks. 2003. Voting with their feet: Institutional ownership changes around forced
CEO turnover. Journal of Financial Economics 68:3^46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1739a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1743" publication-type="other">
Rossi, S., and P. Volpin. 2004. Cross-country determinants of mergers and acquisitions. Journal of Financial
Economics 74:277-304.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1754a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1758" publication-type="other">
Weisbach, M. 1988. Outside directors and CEO turnover. Journal of Financial Economics 20:431-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1765a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1769" publication-type="other">
Yermack, D. 2004. Remuneration, retention, and reputation incentives for outside directors. Journal of Finance
59:2281-2308.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623241e1779a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623241e1783" publication-type="other">
Yermack, D. 2010. Shareholder voting and corporate governance. Annual Review of Financial Economics
2:103-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


