<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">21</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i30219106</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">30219109</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="pub-doi">10.1007/s10590-008-9034-5</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Methods for Extracting and Classifying Pairs of Cognates and False Friends</article-title>
          </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ruslan</given-names>
                  <surname>Mitkov</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Viktor</given-names>
                  <surname>Pekar</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Dimitar</given-names>
                  <surname>Blagoev</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Andrea</given-names>
                  <surname>Mulloni</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
          </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2007</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>29</fpage>
         <lpage>53</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2008 Springer Science Business Media B.V.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/30219109"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>The identification of cognates has attracted the attention of researchers working in the area of Natural Language Processing, but the identification of false friends is still an under-researched area. This paper proposes novel methods for the automatic identification of both cognates and false friends from comparable bilingual corpora. The methods are not dependent on the existence of parallel texts, and make use of only monolingual corpora and a bilingual dictionary necessary for the mapping of co-occurrence data across languages. In addition, the methods do not require that the newly discovered cognates or false friends are present in the dictionary and hence are capable of operating on out-of-vocabulary expressions. These methods are evaluated on English, French, German and Spanish corpora in order to identify English-French, English-German, English-Spanish and French-Spanish pairs of cognates or false friends. The experiments were performed in two settings: (i) assuming 'ideal' extraction of cognates and false friends from plain-text corpora, i.e. when the evaluation data contains only cognates and false friends, and (ii) a real-world extraction scenario where cognates and false friends have to first be identified among words found in two comparable corpora in different languages. The evaluation results show that the developed methods identify cognates and false friends with very satisfactory results for both recall and precision, with methods that incorporate background semantic knowledge, in addition to co-occurrence data obtained from the corpora, delivering the best results.</p>
          </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>Cognates</kwd>
            <kwd>Faux amis</kwd>
            <kwd>Orthographic similarity</kwd>
            <kwd>Distributonal similarity</kwd>
            <kwd>Semantic similarity</kwd>
            <kwd>Translational equivalence</kwd>
          </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
              <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
              <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
          </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
        
         <fn-group>
            <title>[Footnotes]</title>
            <fn id="d1548345e287a1310">
               <label>1</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e294" publication-type="other">
http://rali.iro.umontreal.ca/Traduction/TransCheck.en.html</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="d1548345e301a1310">
               <label>2</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e308" publication-type="other">
Inkpen et al. (2005)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="d1548345e315a1310">
               <label>3</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e322" publication-type="other">
Oakes 1998</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      
        
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d1548345e338a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e342" publication-type="other">
Barker G, Sutcliffe R (2000) An experiment in the semi-automatic identification of false-cognates between
English and Polish. In: Proceedings of the 1 Ith Irish conference on artificial intelligence and cognitive
science. Galway, Ireland, pp 597-606</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e355a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e359" publication-type="other">
Bergsma S, Kondrak G (2007a) Multilingual cognate identification using integer linear programming.
In: Proceedings of the international workshop on acquisition and management of multilingual lexicons.
Borovets, Bulgaria, pp 11-18</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e372a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e376" publication-type="other">
Bergsma S, Kondrak G (2007b) Alignment-based discriminative string similarity. In: Proceedings of
the 45th annual meeting of the association for computational linguistics. Prague, Czech Republic,
pp 656-663</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e389a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e393" publication-type="other">
Brew C, McKelvie D (1996) Word-pair extraction for lexicography. In: Proceedings of the second interna-
tional conference on new methods in language processing. Ankara, Turkey, pp 45-55</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e404a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e408" publication-type="other">
Budanitsky A, Hirst G (2001) Semantic distance in WordNet: an experimental, application-oriented eval-
uation of five measures. In: Proceedings of the workshop on WordNet and other lexical resources
second meeting of the North American chapter of the association for computational linguistics
(NAACL-2001). Pittsburgh, PA, pp 29-34</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e424a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e428" publication-type="other">
Danielsson P, Muehlenbock K (2000) Small but efficient: the misconception of high-frequency words in
Scandinavian translation. In: Envisioning machine translation in the information future, 4th conference
of the association for machine translation in the Americas (AMTA 2000), LNCS vol 1934. Springer
Verlag, Berlin, pp 158-168</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e444a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e448" publication-type="other">
Frunza O, Inkpen D (2006) Semi-supervised learning of partial cognates using bilingual bootstrapping. In:
Proceedings of the 21st international conference on computational linguistics and 44th annual meeting
of the association for computational linguistics. Sydney, Australia, pp 441-448</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e461a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e465" publication-type="other">
Fung P (1998) Statistical view on bilingual lexicon extraction: from parallel corpora to non-parallel corpora.
In: Machine translation and the information soup, third conference of the association for machine
translation in the Americas, LNCS vol 1529. Springer Verlag, Berlin, pp 1-17</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e478a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e482" publication-type="other">
Fung P, McKeown K (1997) Finding terminology translation from non-parallel corpora. In: Proceedings of
the 5th annual workshop on very large corpora. Hong Kong, August 1997, pp 192-202</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e492a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e496" publication-type="other">
Gale WA, Church KW, Yarowsky D (1992) A method for disambiguating word senses in a large corpus.
Comput Human 26:415-439</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e507a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e511" publication-type="other">
Gaussier E, Renders J-M, Matveeva I, Goutte C, D6jean H (2004) A geometric view on bilingual lexi-
con extraction from comparable corpora. In: ACL-04: 42nd annual meeting of the association for
computational linguistics, proceedings. Barcelona, Spain, pp 526-533</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e524a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e528" publication-type="other">
Grefenstette G (1996) Evaluation techniques for automatic semantic extraction: comparing syntactic and
window based approaches. In: Boguarev B, Pustejovsky J (eds) Corpus processing for lexical acqui-
sition. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA, pp 205-216</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e541a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e545" publication-type="other">
Guy J (1994) An algorithm for identifying cognates in bilingual wordlists and its applicability to machine
translation. J Quant Linguist 1(1):35-42</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e555a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e559" publication-type="other">
Inkpen D, Frunza O, Kondrak G (2005) Automatic identification of cognates and false friends in French
and English. In: Proceedings of the international conference on recent advances in natural language
processing (RANLP' 05). Borovets, Bulgaria, pp 251-257</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e572a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e576" publication-type="other">
Knight K, Graehl J (1998) Machine transliteration. Comput Linguist 24(4):599-612</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e583a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e587" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Knight K (2002) Estimating word translation probabilities from unrelated monolingual corpora
using the EM algorithm. In: Proceedings of the 17th national conference on artificial intelligence
(AAAI). Austin, TX, pp 711-715</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e601a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e605" publication-type="other">
Kondrak G (2000) A new algorithm for the alignment of phonetic sequences. In: Proceedings of
NAACL/ANLP 2000: 1st conference of the North American chapter of the association for com-
putational linguistics and 6th conference on applied natural language processing. Seattle, WA, pp
288-295</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e621a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e625" publication-type="other">
Kondrak G (2001) Identifying cognates by phonetic and semantic similarity. In: Proceedings of the sec-
ond meeting of the North American chapter of the association for computational linguistics (NAACL
2001). Pittsburgh, PA, pp 103-110</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e638a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e642" publication-type="other">
Kondrak G, Dorr B (2004) Identification of confusable drug names: a new approach and evaluation meth-
odology. In: Coling: 20th international conference on computational linguistics, proceedings. Geneva.
Switzerland, pp 952-958</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e655a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e659" publication-type="other">
Leacock C, Chodorow M (1998) Combining local context and WordNet similarity for word sense identifi-
cation. In: Fellbaum C (ed) WordNet: an electronic lexical database. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA, pp
265-283</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e672a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e676" publication-type="other">
Lee L (1999) Measures of distributional similarity. 37th Annual meeting of the association for computational
linguistics, College Park, MD, 25-32</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e686a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e690" publication-type="other">
Levenshtein N (1965) Binary codes capable of correcting deletions, insertions and reversals. Doklady
Akademii Nauk SSSR 163(4):845-848</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e701a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e705" publication-type="other">
Mann G, Yarowsky D (2001) Multipath translation lexicon induction via bridge languages. In: Proceedings
of the second meeting of the North American chapter of the association for computational linguistics
(NAACL 2001). Pittsburgh, PA, pp 151-158</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e718a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e722" publication-type="other">
Manning C, Schiitze H (1999) Foundations of statistical natural language processing. MIT Press. Cam-
bridge, MA</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e732a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e736" publication-type="other">
Melamed D (1999) Bitext maps and alignment via pattern recognition. Comput Linguist 25(1):107-130</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e743a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e747" publication-type="other">
Mulloni A, Pekar V (2006) Automatic detection of orthographic cues for cognate recognition. In: Proceed-
ings of the 5th international conference on language resources and evaluation (LREC-06). Genoa,
Italy, pp 2387-2390</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e760a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e764" publication-type="other">
Mulloni A, Pekar V, Mitkov R, Blagoev D (2007) Semantic evidence for automatic identification of cog-
nates. In: Proceedings of the I st international workshop on acquisition and management of multilingual
lexicons. Borovets, Bulgaria, pp 49-54</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e777a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e781" publication-type="other">
Nakov S, Nakov P, Paskaleva E (2007) Cognate or false friend? Ask the web! In: Proceedings of the 1st
international workshop on acquisition and management of multilingual lexicons. Borovets, Bulgaria,
pp 55-62</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e795a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e799" publication-type="other">
Nerbonne J, Heeringa W (1997) Measuring dialect distance phonetically. In: Proceedings of the third
workshop on computational phonology, special interest group of the association for computational
linguistics (SIGPHON-97). Madrid, Spain, pp 11-18</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e812a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e816" publication-type="other">
Oakes MP (1998) Statistics for corpus linguistics. Edinburgh University Press, Edinburgh, UK</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e823a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e827" publication-type="other">
Pereira F, Tishby N, Lee L (1993) Distributional clustering of English words. 31st Annual meeting of the
association for computational linguistics, Columbus, OH, pp 183-190</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e837a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e841" publication-type="other">
Rapp R (1999) Automatic identification of word translations from unrelated English and German corpora.
37th Annual meeting of the association for computational linguistics. College Park, MD, pp 519-526</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e851a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e855" publication-type="other">
Resnik P (1999) Semantic similarity in a taxonomy: an information-based measure and its application to
problems of ambiguity in natural language. J Artif Intel Res (11):95-130</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e865a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e869" publication-type="other">
Schulz S, Marko K, Sbrissia E. Nohama P. Hahn U (2004) Cognate mapping-a heuristic strategy for
the semi-supervised acquisition of a Spanish lexicon from a Portuguese seed lexicon. Coling: 20th
international conference on computational linguistics, proceedings Geneva, Switzerland, pp 813-819</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e883a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e887" publication-type="other">
Simard M, Foster G, Isabelle P (1992) Using cognates to align sentences in bilingual corpora. In: Fourth
international conference on theoretical and methodological issues in machine translation, empiricist
vs. rationalist methods in MT, TMI-92, Proceedings, Montreal, Canada, pp 67-81</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e900a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e904" publication-type="other">
Tanaka K, Iwasaki H (1996) Extraction of lexical translations from non-aligned corpora. In: Proceedings of
COLING 96: the 16th international conference on computational linguistics. Copenhagen, Denmark,
pp 580-585</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e917a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e921" publication-type="other">
Tapanainen P, Jdirvinen T (1997) A non-projective dependency parser. In: Proceedings of the 5th conference
on applied natural language processing. Washington D.C., Association of Computational Linguistics,
pp 64-71</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e934a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e938" publication-type="other">
Versley Y (2005) Parser evaluation across text types. In: Proceedings of the 4th workshop on treebanks and
linguistic theories (TLT 2005). Barcelona, Spain, pp 209-220</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e948a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e952" publication-type="other">
Vossen P. Bloksma L, Boersma P, Verdejo F, Gonzalo J, Rodriquez H, Rigau G, Calzolari N, Peters C,
Picchi E, Montemagni S, Peters W (1998) EuroWordNet Tools and resources report. Technical report
LE-4003, University of Amsterdam, The Netherlands (http://dare.uva.nl/record/157403)</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1548345e965a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1548345e969" publication-type="other">
Wu Z, Palmer M (1994) Verb semantics and lexical selection. 32nd Annual meeting of the association for
computational linguistics. Las Cruces, NM, pp 133-138</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      </back>
</article>
