<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26142248</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Are Stocks Real Assets? Sticky Discount Rates in Stock Markets</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
                  <surname>Katz</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Hanno</given-names>
                  <surname>Lustig</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Lars</given-names>
                  <surname>Nielsen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>2017</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">30</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i26142242</issue-id>
         <fpage>539</fpage>
         <lpage>587</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/26142248"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Local stock markets adjust sluggishly to changes in local inflation. When the local rate of inflation increases, local investors subsequently earn lower real returns on local stocks, but not on local bonds or foreign stocks, suggesting that local stock market investors use sticky long-run nominal discount rates that are too low when inflation increases because they are slow to update the inflation expectations in discount rates. Small amounts of stickiness in inflation expectations suffice to match the real stock return predictability induced by inflation in the data. We also consider other explanations, such as nominal cash flow extrapolation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1125e311a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e318" publication-type="other">
Our cross-country findings are the cross-sectional analogue of the well-known Fama and Schwert (1977) time-
series results for the United States.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e328a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e335" publication-type="other">
Others have argued that investors may choose to be rationally inattentive in some settings: In a model with
information constraints, Kacperczyk, Van Nieuwerburgh, and Veldkamp (2013) argue that mutual fund managers
rationally reallocate their attention to idiosyncratic instead of aggregate shocks during expansions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e348a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e355" publication-type="other">
In addition, career concerns give bond managers a strong incentive to spend some bandwidth on monitoring
inflation, because inflation forecast errors would differentially effect bond portfolios. Not so for stock portfolios.
Our evidence is also consistent with the findings of other researchers who study the effect of macroeconomic
announcements on asset prices: Rigobon and Sack (2006) document large, instantaneous effects of monetary
policy innovations on yields in bond markets, and smaller, muted effects on valuations in stock markets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e374a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e381" publication-type="other">
While sticky prices in product markets can explain incomplete pass-through of surprise inflation to nominal
stock returns (see Gorodnichenko and Weber [2013] for evidence on the effects of sticky prices in stock markets
around Fed announcements), they cannot account for incomplete pass-through of expected inflation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e395a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e402" publication-type="other">
This is a cross-sectional version of Fama ( 1981 )*s proxy hypothesis; inflation proxies other macro-economic
variables that affect how investors discount cash flows. Geske and Roll (1983) develop a fiscal version of this
argument.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e415a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e422" publication-type="other">
Campbell, Pflueger, and Viceira (2013) and David and Veronesi (2014) develop explanations for the time variation
in the stock-bond correlation. Song (2014) reconciles the upward sloping nominal yield curve with a negative
stock-bond correlation in a regime switching model.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e435a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e442" publication-type="other">
Where no 10-year bond was available, the bond closest to a 10-year bond was used. For each country, GFD
provides detailed information on the construction of the bond. The Online Appendix provides a list of country
codes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e455a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e462" publication-type="other">
Non-linear cross-sectional regressions do indeed produce similar results to the portfolio sorts, but only if we
allow the coefficients to vary over time. We do not need to estimate the country-specific average inflation rate.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e472a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e479" publication-type="other">
Online Appendix F reports results for sorts of countries by nominal interest rates.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e486a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e495" publication-type="other">
in their survey paper, Bekaert and Wang (2010), who build a large panel of countries to investigate the usefulness
of stocks in hedging inflation risk, report negative slope coefficients on inflation innovations and expected
inflation. When Bekaert and Wang (2010) control for industrial production growth in a multivariate regression
of stock returns on inflation innovations and output growth, some of these inflation betas of stocks switch signs
and become positive.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e515a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e522" publication-type="other">
Detailed results in Online Table 12.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e529a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e536" publication-type="other">
It follows that lagged inflation may no longer be a good measure of expected inflation over this sample. In
Online Appendix H, we use survey measures of 1 -year expected inflation instead of lagged inflation, and we find
that even in the last 15 years, real stocks returns are significantly lower in countries with higher-than-average
expected inflation, but real bond returns are not.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e552a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e559" publication-type="other">
We report similar evidence for the larger sample of countries in Online Table A26.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e566a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e573" publication-type="other">
Investors cannot simply use nominal yields plus an equity risk adjustment to price the nominal cash flows,
because these nominal yields include an inflation risk premium that does not apply if the stock's dividends are
indexed to inflation; investors need expected inflation under P, not Q.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e586a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e595" publication-type="other">
Aggregated across all firms i, these nominal cash flow projections naturally imply an expected future path for
aggregate inflation when combined with real cash flow projections. However, most investors do not attack this
macro-forecasting-problem for each firm. Instead, they focus on the micro version, involving only a few firms,
because of limited capacity to process information.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e611a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e618" publication-type="other">
Duffee (2014) computes that news about expected inflation over the life of the bond only account for 10% to 20%
of the shocks to Treasury yields, leaving stocks to real rates and term premiums to account for the rest. Surely, for
stocks, this fraction is an order of magnitude smaller, because stocks are claims to real cash flows. In addition,
recomputing the appropriate nominal discount rates when expected inflation changes to reprice the nominal cash
flows of stocks is not an easy task. Simply computing the actual duration of stocks is hard. Repricing nominal
bonds when expected inflation changes is simple by comparison. As a result, a fraction of stock market investors
may rationally decide not to continuously reprice stocks, given a limited capacity to process information, simply
because inflation innovations account for a small fraction of total stock return variation, but they account for a
much larger fraction of bond return variation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e651a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e658" publication-type="other">
Provided that stock dividend payments do not covary with the price-dividend ratio, the time variation in the
market log price-dividend ratio equals the time variation of the average log price-dividend ratio.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e668a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e675" publication-type="other">
However, looking at the U.S. experience, Milani (2007) concludes that agents who use adaptive learning would
have underestimated inflation persistence until the early 1980s. The perceived degree of persistence then declines
again, only to increase in the 1990s. In the baseline panel, the stock return spread between the lowest and the
highest quintile is smallest or even switches signs in the 1980s, consistent with the notion that persistence cpr
was too low around the world in the 1950s and 1960s, and finally was about right in the 1980s.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e694a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e701" publication-type="other">
This evidence is not shown in Table 8.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e708a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e715" publication-type="other">
Recall that in sticky discount rate models, the instantaneous positive effect on stock valuations of an inflation
surprise is immediately offset by subsequent decreases in the valuation, as agents update inflation expectations.
That is not the case when investors have rational inflation expectations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e728a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e735" publication-type="other">
Piazzesi and Schneider (2006) show that a negative correlation between expected inflation and future real
consumption growth, a feature of the U.S. data, delivers upward sloping nominal yield curves in a standard
representative agent dynamic equilibrium model. Bansal and Shaliastovich (2013) extend a version of this model
to match moments of bond, stock and currency returns by introducing uncertainty about inflation as an additional
state variable. Nakamura et al. (2013) find evidence of inflation spikes during consumption disasters. There is an
older literature on this topic. Fama (1981) originally proposed a proxy explanation of the negative correlation
between expected inflation and stock returns in the U.S. time series. Fama conjectures that there is a negative
relation between the future growth of real activity and the level of expected inflation, as well as a positive
correlation between the future growth and expected real stock returns, thus giving rise to a negative correlation
between inflation expectations and expected real returns. Geske and Roll (1983) developed a reverse causation
version of this argument.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e773a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e780" publication-type="other">
A central tenet of modern asset pricing is that the price of risk is counter-cyclical (see Campbell and Cochrane
1999). There is plenty of empirical evidence to support this notion (see Lettau and Ludvigson 2002, Lustig
and Verdelhan 2012). In this class of models, expected returns on stocks invariably increase in bad times, when
marginal utility growth is high. That delivers a negative covariance between realized stock returns and the pricing
kernel, the key to a positive equity premium.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e800a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e809" publication-type="other">
In a related strand of the literature, Alvarez, Atkeson, and Kehoe (2002,2009) develop a Baumol-Tobin model with
endogenously segmented markets. Investors incur a fixed costs when participating in asset markets. An increase
in expected inflation increases the benefit of participation in asset markets and hence lowers risk premiums. If
inflation is sufficiently high, the neutrality of inflation is restored, in line with our findings for high inflation
countries. However, this Baumol-Tobin mechanism cannot explain the asymmetric effect of inflation on equity
and bond risk premiums.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1125e832a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1125e839" publication-type="other">
Several authors have found additional evidence in support of the money illusion hypothesis. Campbell and
Vuolteenaho (2004) find that the level of inflation explains a large share of mispricing of the U.S. stock market,
consistent with the Modigliani-Cohn hypothesis. In the cross-section of U.S. stocks, Cohen, Polk and Vuolteenaho
(2005) also find evidence that stock market investors are subject to money illusion, while Brunnermeier and
Julliard (2008) report similar evidence from U.S. housing markets. Piazzesi and Schneider (2008) develop an
equilibrium model in which real rate disagreement is driven by money illusion. Using survey data for earnings
forecasts and expected inflation, Sharpe (2002) attributes the negative correlation between equity valuations and
expected inflation to an increase in the required real return on stocks and a decrease in expected earnings growth
that coincide with a rise in expected inflation. In recent work, Bekaert and Engstrom (2010) attribute this U.S.
correlation to heightened uncertainty during times of higher expected inflation in the United States.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d1125e883a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e887" publication-type="other">
Alvarez, F., A. Atkeson, and P. J. Kehoe. 2002. Money, interest rates, and exchange rates with endogenously
segmented markets. Journal of Political Economy 110:73-112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e897a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e901" publication-type="other">
. 2009. Time-varying risk, interest rates, and exchange rates in general equilibrium. Review of Economic
Studies 76:851-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e911a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e915" publication-type="other">
Asness, C. S. 2000. Stocks versus bonds: Explaining the equity risk premium. Financial Analysts Journal
56:96-113.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e925a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e929" publication-type="other">
Bacchetta, P., E. Mertens, and E. van Wincoop. 2009. Predictability in financial markets: What do survey
expectations tell us? Journal of International Money and Finance 28:406-426.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e940a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e944" publication-type="other">
Baele, L., G. Bekaert, and K. Inghelbrecht. 2010. The determinants of stock and bond return comovements.
Review of Financial Studies 23: 2374^-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e954a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e958" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., and M. Dahlquist. 2000. The forward premium puzzle: Different tales from developed and emerging
economies. Journal of International Economics 51:115-44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e968a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e972" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., and I. Shaliastovich. 2013. A long-run risks explanation of predictability puzzles in bond and currency
markets. Review of Financial Studies 26:1-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e982a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e986" publication-type="other">
Barberis, N., A. Shleifer, and R. W. Vishny. 1998. A model of investor sentiment. Journal of Financial Economics
49:307-43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e996a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1000" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, G., and E. Engstrom. 2010. Inflation and the stock market: Understanding the "Fed Model." Journal of
Monetary Economics 57:278-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1010a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1014" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, G., and X. Wang. 2010. Inflation risk and the inflation risk premium. Economic Policy 25:755-806.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1022a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1026" publication-type="other">
Boudoukh, J., and M. Richardson. 1993. Stock returns and inflation: A long-horizon perspective. American
Economic Review 83:1346-55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1036a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1040" publication-type="other">
Brunnermeier, M., and C. Julliard. 2008. Money illusion and housing frenzies. Review of Financial Studies
21:135-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1050a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1054" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y. and J. H. Cochrane. 1999. By force of habit: A consumption-based explanation of aggregate
stock market behavior. Journal of Political Economy 107:205-51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1064a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1068" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., C. Pflueger, and L. M. Viceira. 2013. Monetary policy drivers of bond and equity risks. Working
Paper, Harvard Business School.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1078a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1082" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., and R. J. Shiller. 1988. Stock prices, earnings and expected dividends. Journal of Finance
43:661-76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1092a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1096" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., A. Sunderam, and L. M. Viceira. 2013. Inflation bets or deflation hedges? the changing risks of
nominal bonds. Working Paper, Harvard Business School.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1107a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1111" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., and T. Vuolteenaho. 2004. Inflation illusion and stock prices. The American Economic Review
94:19-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1121a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1125" publication-type="other">
Cohen, R. B., C. Polk, and T. Vuolteenaho. 2005. Money illusion in the stock market: The Modigliani-Cohn
hypothesis. Quarterly Journal of Economics 120:639-68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1135a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1139" publication-type="other">
Coibion, O., and Y. Gorodnichenko. 2015. Information rigidity and the expectations formation process: A simple
framework and new facts. American Economic Review 105:2644-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1149a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1153" publication-type="other">
David, A., and P. Veronesi. 2014. What ties return volatilities to price valuations and fundamentals. Journal of
Political Economy 121:682-746.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1163a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1167" publication-type="other">
Duffee, G R. 2014. Expected inflation and other determinants of Treasury yields. Working Paper, Johns Hopkins
University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1177a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1181" publication-type="other">
Erb, C. B., C. R. Harvey, and T. E. Viskanta. 1995. Inflation and world equity selection. Financial Analysts
Journal 51:28^-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1192a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1196" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F. 1981. Stock returns, real activity, inflation, and money. American Economic Review 71:545-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1203a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1207" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and G. W. Schwert. 1977. Asset returns and inflation. Journal of Financial Economics 5:115-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1214a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1218" publication-type="other">
Fuster, A., B. Hebert, and D. Laibson. 2011. Natural expectations, macroeconomic dynamics, and asset pricing.
NBER Macroeconomics Annual 26:1-48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1228a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1232" publication-type="other">
Geske, R., and R. Roll. 1983. The fiscal and monetary linkage between stock returns and inflation. Journal of
Finance 38:1-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1242a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1246" publication-type="other">
Gomes, J., U. Jermann, and L. Schmid. 2014. Sticky leverage. Working paper, Wharton School.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1253a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1257" publication-type="other">
Gorodnichenko, Y., and M. Weber. 2013. Are sticky prices costly? Evidence from the stock market. Working
Paper, UC Berkeley.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1268a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1272" publication-type="other">
Hansen, L. P., and R. J. Hodrick. 1980. Forward exchange rates as optimal predictors of future spot rates: An
econometric analysis. Journal of Political Economy 88:829-53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1282a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1286" publication-type="other">
Henriksen, E., F. E. Kydland, and R. Mustek. 2013. Globally correlated nominal fluctuations. Journal of Monetary
Economics 60:613-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1296a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1300" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, D. A., and J. Yu. 2013. Asset pricing in production economies with extrapolative expectations.
Working Paper, UC Irvine.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1310a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1314" publication-type="other">
Jaffe, J. F., and G. Mandelker. 1976. The "Fisher effect" for risky assets: An empirical investigation. Journal of
Finance 31:447-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1324a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1328" publication-type="other">
Kacperczyk, M., S. Van Nieuwerburgh, and L. Veldkamp. 2013. Time-varying fund manager skill. Journal of
Finance 69:1455-84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1338a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1342" publication-type="other">
Kang, J., and C. E. Pflueger. 2014. Inflation risk in corporate bonds. Journal of Finance 70: 115-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1350a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1354" publication-type="other">
Lettau, M., and S. C. Ludvigson. 2002. Measuring and modeling variation in the risk-return tradeoff. 1: 617-90.
In: Handbook of financial econometrics, ed. Y. Ait Sahalia, and L. P. Hansen. Amsterdam: North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1364a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1368" publication-type="other">
Lettau, M., and J. A. Wächter. 2007. Why is long-horizon equity less risky? A duration-based explanation of the
value premium. Journal of Finance 62:55-92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1378a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1382" publication-type="other">
Liew, J. 1995. Stock Returns, Inflation and the Volatility of Growth in the Money Supply: Evidence from Emerging
Markets. PhD thesis, University of Chicago Graduate School of Business.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1392a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1396" publication-type="other">
Lintner, J. 1975. Inflation and security returns. Journal of Finance 30:259-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1403a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1407" publication-type="other">
Lustig, H., and A. Verdelhan. 2012. Business cycle variation in the risk-return trade-off. Journal of Monetary
Economics, 59:S35-S49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1417a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1421" publication-type="other">
Madkowiak, B., E. Moench, and M. Wiederholt. 2009. Sectoral price data and models of price setting. Journal
of Monetary Economics 56:S78-S99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1432a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1436" publication-type="other">
Mackowiak, B., and M. Wiederholt. 2009. Optimal sticky prices under rational inattention. American Economic
Review 99:769-803.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1446a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1450" publication-type="other">
Malmendier, U., and S. Nagel. 2015. Learning from inflation experiences. Quarterly Journal of Economics
131:53-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1460a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1464" publication-type="other">
Mankiw, N. G, and R. Reis. 2002. Sticky information versus sticky prices: A proposal to replace the new keynesian
phillips curve. Quarterly Journal of Economics 117:1295-328.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1474a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1478" publication-type="other">
Milani, F. 2007. Expectations, learning and macroeconomic persistence. Journal of Monetary Economics
54:2065-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1488a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1492" publication-type="other">
Modigliani, F., and R. Cohn. 1979. Inflation, rational valuation and the market. Financial Analysts Journal
35:24-44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1502a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1506" publication-type="other">
Nakamura, E., J. Steinsson, R. Barro, and J. Ursua. 2013. Crises and recoveries in an empirical model of
consumption disasters. American Economic Journal: Macroeconomics 5:35-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1517a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1521" publication-type="other">
Newey, W. K., and K. D. West. 1987. A simple, positive semidefinite, heteroskedasticity and autocorrelation
consistent covariance matrix. Econometrica 55:703-708.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1531a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1535" publication-type="other">
Piazzesi, M., and M. Schneider. 2006. Equilibrium yield curves. National Bureau of Economic Analysis
Macroeconomics Annual. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1545a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1549" publication-type="other">
. 2008. Inflation Illusion, Credit, and Asset Prices, pages 147-89. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1556a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1560" publication-type="other">
Piazzesi, M., and M. Schneider. 2009a. Inflation and the price of real assets. Working Paper, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1567a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1571" publication-type="other">
. 2009b. Trend and cycle in bond premia. Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis, Research Department.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1578a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1582" publication-type="other">
Reis, R. 2006. Inattentive consumers. Journal of Monetary Economics 53:1761-800.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1590a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1594" publication-type="other">
Rigobon, R., and B. Sack. 2006. Noisy macroeconomic announcements, monetary policy, and asset prices. In
Campbell, J. Y., ed. 335-70, Asset Prices and Monetary Policy, Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1604a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1608" publication-type="other">
Sargent, T. J. 2002. The conquest of American inflation. Princeton: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1615a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1619" publication-type="other">
Sharpe, S. A. 2002. Reexamining stock valuation and inflation: The implications of analysts' earnings forecasts.
Review of Economics and Statistics 84:632-48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1629a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1633" publication-type="other">
Sims, C. 2003. Implications of rational inattention. Journal of Monetary Economics 50:665-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1640a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1644" publication-type="other">
Solnik, B. 1983. The relation between stock prices and inflationary expectations: The international evidence.
Journal of Finance 38:35-48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1654a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1658" publication-type="other">
Song, D. 2014. Bond market exposures to macroeconomic and monetary policy risks. PIER Working Paper
Archive 14-017, Penn Institute for Economic Research, Department of Economics, University of Pennsylvania.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1669a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1673" publication-type="other">
Verdelhan, A. 2010. A habit-based explanation of the exchange rate risk premium. Journal of Finance 65:123-45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1125e1680a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1125e1684" publication-type="other">
Wright, J. H. 2011. Term premia and inflation uncertainty: Empirical evidence from an international panel dataset.
American Economic Review 101:1514-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
