<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26296336</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PROFESSIONAL FEATURE</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Connecting the Dots Learning from Multiple Wargames</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Rubel</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert C. (Barney)</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Captain Rubel is retired and living in Monticello, Illinois. From May 2006 to August 2014 he was Dean of the Center for Naval Warfare Studies (CNWS) at the US Naval War College. Prior to assuming this position, he was Chair of the Wargaming Department. A 30-year Navy veteran, he was a light attack naval aviator, flying the A-7 Corsair II and later the F/A-18 Hornet. He commanded Strike Fighter Squadron 131 and served as the Inspector General at US Southern Command.</p> 
                  <p>Captain Rubel’s shore assignments were principally involved with professional military education. He is a graduate of the Spanish Naval War College in Madrid and the US Naval War College in Newport, RI. He completed three separate faculty tours at the US Naval War College as a joint military operations instructor and ultimately as the Deputy Dean of the Center for Naval Warfare Studies. During these tours he served as the William F. Halsey Chair of Air Strike Warfare and later the Colin Powell Chair of Joint Warfare.</p> 
                  <p>As Dean of CNWS, Professor Rubel designed and directed an eight-month effort that provided the logic and concepts that underpinned the 2007 US national maritime strategy “A Cooperative Strategy for 21st Century Seapower.” Professor Rubel increased student advanced research and developed new lines of inquiry including strategic cyberspace, unmanned systems, naval logistics, and command via challenged networks. He also redirected the vector of the International Law Department from teaching maritime law to research on cutting edge law of war issues. He has published over thirty articles and book chapters on a number of subjects related to naval operational warfighting and strategy.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>December 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>49</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26296325</issue-id>
         <fpage>30</fpage>
         <lpage>37</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2016, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26296336"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Britten, N., Campbell, R., Pope, C., Donovan, J., Morgan, M., and Pill, R. 2002. “Using Meta Ethnography to Synthesize Qualitative Research: A Worked Example”, Journal of Health Services Research &amp; Policy, Vol 7 No 4, 209–215; http://betterevaluation.org/sites/default/files/Using-meta-ethnography-to-synthesise-qualitatie-research.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Culora, T. J. 2016. “A Wargaming Renaissance”, Proceedings Magazine, Vol 142/5/1,359; www.usni.org/magazines/proceedings/2016-05/war-gaming-renaissance.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Downes-Martin, S. 2013. “The Diabolus in Machina of War Gaming”, Naval War College Review, Summer, 67–80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanley, J. T. 1991. “On Wargaming”, PhD dissertation, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hay, B., and Gile, B. 1993. “Global Wargame, The First Five Years”, Newport Paper #4. Naval War College Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Perla, P. 1990. The Art of Wargaming. US Naval Institute Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rubel, R. C. 2003. Using Wargames for Command and Control Experimentation, a paper submitted to the 8th International Command and Control Research and Technology Symposium; www.dtic.mil/dtic/tr/fulltext/u2/a466408.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rubel, R. C. 2006. “The Epistemology of War Gaming”, Naval War College Review, Spring, 108–128; www.usnwc.edu/getattachment/5fce9410-594b-47bf-af57-4cf5e406e634/Epistemology-of-War-Gaming,-The---Rubel,-Robert-C-.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weed, M. 2005. “‘Meta Interpretation’: A Method for the Interpretive Synthesis of Qualitative Research”, Forum Qualitative Sozialforschung/Forum: Qualitative Social Research, Vol 6, No 1, Article 37; http://nbn-resolving.de/urn:nbn:de:0114-fqs0501375.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Work, R., and Selva, P. 2015. Revitalizing Wargaming is Necessary to be Prepared for Future Wars, War on the Rocks (December 8); http://warontherocks.com/2015/12/revitalizing-wargaming-is-necessary-to-be-prepared-for-future-wars.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
