<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26272337</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Closed-Loop Combustion Control of a HCCI Engine with Re-Breathing EGR System</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nakamura</surname>
                  <given-names>Yusuke</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jung</surname>
                  <given-names>Dong-Won</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Iida</surname>
                  <given-names>Norimasa</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Keio Univ.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>December 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26272316</issue-id>
         <fpage>2110</fpage>
         <lpage>2121</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright @2013 SAE Japan and Copyright @ 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26272337"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This study experimentally investigates the control system and the algorithm after constructing a HCCI combustion control system for the development of a small HCCI engine fuelled with Dimethyl Ether (DME). This system can control four throttles for the mixing ratio of three gases of in-cylinder (stoichiometric pre-mixture, hot EGR gas and cold EGR gas). At first, the combustion behavior for combustion phasing retarded operation with cold and hot EGR was examined. Then, the potential of model-based and feed back control for HCCI combustion with change of the demand of IMEP was investigated. In the end, the limit of combustion-phasing retard for IMEP and PRR was explored. Results shows that to get high IMEP with acceptable PRR and low coefficient of variation of IMEP, crank angle of 50% heat release (CA50) should be controlled at constant phasing in the expansion stroke. CA50 can be controlled by changing the ratio of pre-mixture, hot EGR gas and cold EGR gas with throttles. Due to the cycle-to-cycle variation, the change of total mass of fuel in cylinder has a big effect on IMEP. After misfire, unburned fuel and intermediates remain in exhaust gas, which is re-breathed as hot EGR gas, and unburned fuel and intermediates are supplied to next cycle. This leads to the total mass of fuel changes cycle-to-cycle. As a result of feedback control, transient performance is realized but high sensitivity of response cannot be achieved under the constant engine speed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fuquan, Z. Thomas, W.A. Dennis, N. A. John, E.D. James, A.E. Paul, M.N. Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Engines: Key Research and Development Issues, Society of Automotive Engineering, Warrendale, PA 15096-0001-USA, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg M., Dec, J.E. Babajimopoulos, A. Assanis, D. Comparing Enhanced Natural Thermal Stratification Against Retarded Combustion Phasing for Smoothing of HCCI Heat-Release Rates, SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2994, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg M., Dec, J.E. Comparing late-cycle autoignition stability for single- and two-stage ignition fuels in HCCI engines, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 31(2):2895-2902, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg M., Dec, J.E. Cernansky, N.P. Potential of Thermal Stratification and Combustion Retard for Reducing Pressure-Rise Rates in HCCI Engines, Based on Multi-Zone Modeling and Experiments, SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0113, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg M., Hwang, W.T. Dec, J.E. An Investigation of Thermal Stratification in HCCI Engines Using Chemiluminescence Imaging, SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1518, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haraldsson, G. Tunestål P., Johansson, B. Hyvönen J., HCCI Combustion Phasing in a Multi Cylinder Engine Using Variable Compression Ratio, SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2858, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Agrell, F. Ångström H.E., Eriksson, B. Wikander, J. Linderyd, J. Integrated Simulation and Engine Test of Closed Loop HCCI Control by Aid of Variable Valve Timings, SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0748, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg M., Dec, J.E. Combined Effects of Fuel-type and Engine Speed on Intake Temperature Requirements and Completeness of Bulk Gas Reactions in an HCCI Engine, SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3173, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg M., Dec, J.E. EGR and Intake Boost for Managing HCCI Low- Temperature Heat Release over Wide Ranges of Engine Speed, SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0051, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg M., Dec, J.E. Hwang, W.T. Thermodynamic and Chemical Effects of EGR and Its Constituents on HCCI Autoignition, SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0207, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg M., Dec, J.E. Isolating the Effects of Fuel Chemistry on Combustion Phasing in an HCCI Engine and the Potential of Fuel Stratification for Ignition Control, SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0557, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J.O. Tunestål P., Johansson, B. Fiveland, S. Agama, J.R. Assanis, D.N. Compression Ratio Influence on Maximum Load of a Natural Gas-Fueled HCCI Engine, SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0111, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haraldsson, G. Tunestål P., Johansson, B. Hyvönen J., HCCI Closed- Loop Combustion Control Using Fast Thermal Management, SAE Paper Technical 2004-01-0943, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haraldsson, G. Tunestål P., Johansson, B. Hyvönen J., HCCI Combustion Phasing With Closed-Loop Combustion Control Using Variable Compression Ratio in a Multi-Cylinder Engine, SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1830, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Agrell, F. Ångström H.E., Eriksson, B. Wikander, J. Linderyd, J. Integrated Simulation and Engine Test of Closed Loop HCCI Control by Aid of Variable Valve Timings, SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0748, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Acroumanis, C. Bae, C.S. Crookes, R. Kimoshita, E. The potential of dimethyl ether (DME) as an alternative fuel for compression-ignition engines: A review, FUEL, Vol. 87, No. 7, pp. 1014-1030, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bengtsson, J. Strandh, P. Johansson, R. Tunestal, P. Johansson, B. Closed-loop combustion control of homogeneous charge compression ignition (HCCI) engine dynamics, International Journal of Adaptive Control and Signal Processing, Vol. 18, Issue 2, pp. 167-179, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bengtsson, J. Strandh, P. Johansson, R. Tunestal, P. Johansson, B. Hybrid control of homogeneous charge compression ignition (HCCI) engine dynamics, International Journal of Control, Vol. 79, Issue 5, pp. 422-448, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakamura, Y. Yamasita, K. Jung, D. W. Iida, N. Combustion Variation for HCCI Engines Equipped with Re-breathing System- Influence of In- Cylinder Gas Temperature and Composition at Compression Start on Combustion Phasing -, 2012 Annual Congress-Autumn, Osaka, Japan, October 3-5, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw- Hill, New York, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
