<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939373</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Property Taxes and Local Debt</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Local Origins and Implications of the 1930s Urban Debt Crisis</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gunter</surname>
                  <given-names>Samara</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Siodla</surname>
                  <given-names>James</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>43</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939373"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Rising incomes and automobile ownership encouraged widespread suburbanization and urban growth during the 1920s. These developments were facilitated by debt-financed infrastructure spending on the part of local governments. When the Great Depression struck, it brought a crisis in which cities were forced to reschedule debt, were at risk of default, and were weakly positioned to respond to local economic crisis. This paper seeks to identify the factors that led to high city debt loads in 1929 and the implications for urban communities in the downturn. We find that cities constrained by strict government debt limits and a supermajority popular-vote requirement for borrowing were significantly less indebted in 1929, while cities facing strict tax limits were more indebted. Cities carrying high debt loads into the Depression made bigger spending cuts in critical areas between 1931 and 1933. These results shed light not only on the urban experience during the downturn, but also the effectiveness of institutional constraints on local government borrowing during the early twentieth century.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Bernanke, B., 1983. Nonmonetary effects of the financial crisis in the propagation of the great depression. American Economic Review 73 (3), 257-276.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Bird, F. L., 1935. The municipal debt load in 1935: Cities of over 50,000 population. Report, New York City.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Bird, F. L., 1936. Cities and their debt burdens. National Municipal Review January.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Chernick, H., Langley, A., Reschovsky, A., 2011. The impact of the great recession and the housing crisis on the financing of america's largest cities. Regional Science and Urban Economics 41 (4), 372-381.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Coate, S., Knight, B., 2011. Government form and public pending: Theory and evidence from us municipalities. American Economic Journal: Economic Policy 3 (3), 82-112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Coen-Pirani, D., Wooley, M., 2018. Fiscal centralization: Theory and evidence from the great depression. American Economic Journal: Economic Policy 10 (2), 39-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Cromwell, E., Ihlanfeldt, K., 2015. Local government responses to exogenous shocks in revenue sources: Evidence from orida. National Tax Journal 68 (2), 339-376.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Dykstra, C. A., 1934. New tasks for public administrators. In: Ridley, C. E., Nolting, O. F. (Eds.), The Municipal Year Book 1934. International City Managers' Association, Chicago, pp. 19-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Field, A. J., 1992. Uncontrolled land development and the duration of the depression in the united states. Journal of Economic History 52 (4), 785-805.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Fishback, P. V., Johnson, R. S., Kantor, S., 2010. Striking at the roots of crime: The impact of welfare spending on crime during the great depression. Journal of Law and Economics 53, 715-740.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Fishback, P. V., Kantor, S., Wallis, J. J., 2003. Can the three r's be rehabilitated? a comprehensive analysis, program by program, county by county. Explorations in Economic History 40 (3), 278-307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Fuchs, E. R., 1992. Mayors and Money: Fiscal Policy in New York and Chicago. University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Gelfand, M. I., 1975. A Nation of Cities: The Federal Government and Urban America, 1933-1965. New York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Haines, M. R., ICPSR, 2010. Historical, demographic, economic, and social data: The united states, 1790-2002. Ann Arbor, MI: Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Hillhouse, A. M., 1936. Municipal bonds: A century of experience. New York: Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Hirschboeck, H. C., 1935. Municipal current expenses and the debt limit. Marquette Law Review 19 (2), 59-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Joe, M. D., 2013. Drivers of municipal bond defaults during the great depression. Master's thesis.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Martin, R. F., 1939. National income and its distribution, 1919-1938. Tech. rep., The Con- ference Economic Record.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Michigan Planning Commission, 1939. A study of subdivision development in the detroit metropolitan area. Commission report, Lansing, Michigan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">National Housing Agency, 1945. Land assembly for urban redevelopment. Report, Washing- ton, D.C.: GPO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Paquin, B. P., 2015. Chronicle of the 161-year history of state-imposed property tax limita- tions. Lincoln Institute of Land Policy Working Paper WP15BP1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Ridley, C. E., Noltino, O. F. (Eds.), 1936. The Municipal Year Book 1936. Chicago: The International City Managers' Association.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Rothbard, M. N., 2000. America's Great Depression. The Ludwig von Mises Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Skidmore, M., Scorsone, E., 2011. Causes and consequences of fiscal stress in michigan cities. Regional Science and Urban Economics 41, 360-371.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Thomasson, M. A., Fishback, P. V., 2014. Hard times in the land of plenty: The e ect on income and disability later in life for people born during the great depression. Explorations in Economic History 54, 64-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Thompson, P. N., 2016. School district and housing price responses to fiscal stress labels: Evidence from ohio. Journal of Urban Economics 94, 54-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Thompson, P. N., 2017. E ects of fiscal stress labels on municipal government finances, housing prices, and the quality of public services: Evidence from ohio. Regional Science and Urban Economics 64, 98-116.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Tyer, C., Willand, J., 1997. Public budgeting in america: A twentieth century retrospective. Journal of Public Budgeting, Accounting and Financial Management 9 (2), 189-219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">U.S. Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations, 1973. A commission report: City financial emergencies, the intergovernmental division. Commission report, Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">U.S. Census Bureau, 1915. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1916.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">U.S. Census Bureau, 1916. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1917.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">U.S. Census Bureau, 1917. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1918.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">U.S. Census Bureau, 1918. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1919.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">U.S. Census Bureau, 1919. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1921.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">U.S. Census Bureau, 1923. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1925.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">U.S. Census Bureau, 1924. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1926.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">U.S. Census Bureau, 1925. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1927.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">U.S. Census Bureau, 1926. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1928.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">U.S. Census Bureau, 1927. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1929.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">U.S. Census Bureau, 1928. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">U.S. Census Bureau, 1929. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1932.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">U.S. Census Bureau, 1930. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1932.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">U.S. Census Bureau, 1931. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 30,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1934.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">U.S. Census Bureau, 1932. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 100,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1934.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">U.S. Census Bureau, 1933. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 100,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1935.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">U.S. Census Bureau, 1934. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 100,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1936.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">U.S. Census Bureau, 1935. Financial statistics of cities having a population of over 100,000. Annual report, Washington, D.C.: 1937.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">U.S. Census Bureau, 1975. Historical statistics of the united states: Colonial times to 1970. Report, Washington, D.C.: GPO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Wallis, J. J., 1984. The birth of the old federalism: Financing the new deal, 1932-1940. Journal of Economic History 44 (1), 139-159.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Wallis, J. J., 2001. A history of the property tax in america. In: Oates, W. E. (Ed.), Property Taxation and Local Government Finance. Lincoln Institute of Land Policy, Cambridge, pp. 123-147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Total Debt, 1915–1935 (89-City Balanced Panel)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Total Debt by Type, 1915–1935 (89-City Balanced Panel)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>The Role of Suburbanization, 1915–1935 Breakdown of Funded, Floating and Special Assessment Debt (88-City Balanced Panel)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Variation in Real Per-Capita Debt Levels in 1929</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Change in Real Per-Capita Debt, 1923-1929</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Determinants of 1929 Debt Loads</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Debt Determinants and 1929 Municipal Debt, Spending, and Revenue</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Debt Determinants and 1929 Spending (4 Categories)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Debt Determinants and 1929 Spending (9 Categories)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Indebtedness and City Policy Actions (OLS)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Indebtedness and City Spending</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Indebtedness and City Spending in General Departments</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
