<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275479</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investigations on Pre-Ignition in Highly Supercharged SI Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dahnz</surname>
                  <given-names>Christoph</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT), Institut fuer Kolbenmaschinen</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Han</surname>
                  <given-names>Kyung-Man</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT), Institut fuer Kolbenmaschinen</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Spicher</surname>
                  <given-names>Ulrich</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT), Institut fuer Kolbenmaschinen</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Magar</surname>
                  <given-names>Max</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT), Institut fuer Technische Thermodynamik</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schießl</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT), Institut fuer Technische Thermodynamik</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Maas</surname>
                  <given-names>Ulrich</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT), Institut fuer Technische Thermodynamik</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>214</fpage>
         <lpage>224</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275479"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper presents the results of a study on reasons for the occurrence of pre-ignition in highly supercharged spark ignition engines. During the study, the phenomena to be taken into account were foremost structured into a decision tree according to their physical working principles. Using this decision tree all conceivable single mechanisms to be considered as reasons for pre-ignition could be derived. In order to judge each of them with respect to their ability to promote pre-ignition in a test engine, experimental investigations as well as numerical simulations were carried out.</p>
            <p>The interdependence between engine operating conditions and pre-ignition frequency was examined experimentally by varying specific parameters. Additionally, optical measurements using an UV sensitive high-speed camera system were performed to obtain information about the spatial distribution of pre-ignition origins and their progress.</p>
            <p>The numerical simulations included the analysis of the general auto-ignition behavior of air/fuel mixtures depending on the thermodynamic conditions, mixture composition and other factors by taking into account detailed reaction kinetics. Furthermore, 3D CFD simulations were conducted in order to determine the predominant conditions within the combustion chamber.</p>
            <p>By combining the results of the experimental and numerical investigations, many of the identified mechanisms could be ruled out. Others were classified to be very improbable. The release of lubricant oil droplets from the cylinder liner turned out to be the most probable explanation for the occurrence of pre-ignition. As a main factor influencing the amount of droplets released and hence the pre-ignition frequency, oil dilution caused by spray impingement due to the lateral injector position was identified.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Willand, J., Daniel, M., Montefrancesco, E., Geringer, B., Hofmann, P., and Kieberger, M., “Grenzen des Downsizing bei Ottomotoren durch Vorentflammung”, MTZ - Motortechnische Zeitschrift 70(5):422-428, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Esser, C., Maas, U., and Warnatz, J., “Chemistry of the Auto-Ignition in Hydrocarbon Air Mixtures up to Octane and its Relation to Engine Knock”, presented at the International Symposium on Diagnostics and Modeling of Combustion in Reciprocating Engines, JSME, 1985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maas, U., Warnatz, J.,“Ignition Processes in Hydrogen- Oxygen Mixtures,” Combustion and Flame 74(1):53-69, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrae, J. C. G., Björnbom, P., Cracknell, R. F., and Kalghatgi, G. T., “Autoignition of Toluene Reference Fuels at High Pressures Modeled with Detailed Chemical Kinetics”, Combustion and Flame 149(1-2): 2-24, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, H. J., Gaffuri, P., Pitz, W. J., and Westbrook, C. K., “A Comprehensive Modeling Study of n-Heptane Oxidation”, Combustion and Flame 114(1-2):149-177, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, H. J., Gaffuri, P., Pitz, W. J., and Westbrook, C. K., “A Comprehensive Modeling Study of iso-Octane Oxidation”, Combustion and Flame 129(3):253-280, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrae, J. C. G. and Head, R. A.: “HCCI Experiments with Gasoline Surrogate Fuels Modeled by a Semidetailed Chemical Kinetic Model”, Combustion and Flame 156(4): 842-851, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Štěpina, V. and Veselý, V.: Lubricants and Special Fluids. Tribology Series (23), Elsevier, Amsterdam, ISBN 9780444986740:67, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rangert, B., “Hydrodynamic Piston Ring Lubrication with Reference to Lubrication Oil Consumption”, Ph.D. thesis, Chalmers University of Technology, Göteborg, 1974.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yilmaz, E., Tian, T, Wong, V.W., and Heywood, J.B., “The Contribution of Different Oil Consumption Sources to Total Oil Consumption in a Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2909, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
