<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica, Centre for Financial Assistance to African Countries</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">23024757</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>ON FINANCIAL SECTOR REFORM AND DEVELOPMENT: A CASE STUDY OF GHANA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>V.V.</given-names>
                  <surname>Bhatt</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1993</year>
         </pub-date>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i23024723</issue-id>
         <fpage>5</fpage>
         <lpage>26</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23024757"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Because of inappropriate macroeconomic policies and adverse external environment, the Sub-Saharan Africa experienced economic decline and a fall in the living standards in the early eighties. To reverse this trend, many countries have adopted structural adjustment measures since 1983-84 to correct economic imbalances and create a favorable environment for growth and development; so far 19 countries have made strong overall reform effort, while another 13 have taken some measures to correct economic imbalances. Of all these countries, the experience of Ghana is much more interesting for several reasons. Firstly, Ghana experienced the sharpest economic decline and fall in living standards during 1978-83 — with the exception of Chad, Madagascar and Uganda — a decline which considerably weakened the financial system. Secondly, Ghana has realized that structural adjustment measures cannot succeed without strengthening and developing the financial sector with a view to raising the rate of financial saving and allocating it on the basis of sound criteria with the objectives of improving investment and productive efficiency and export performance; as a result, it is the first country which formulated a program for financial sector reform and development in 1988 with the assistance of the World Bank and the IMF. Thirdly, Ghana has not only reversed the earlier trend of economic decline, but has also experienced an annual average growth rate of GDP of 5-6 percent during the period 1984 to 1990, which, with the exception of Mauritius, is the highest growth rate among the Sub-Saharan countries; and at the same time, it has adopted an institutional and policy framework appropriate for strengthening and development of the financial sector. Ghana's experience since 1983 thus may prove instructive and enlightening to Sub-Saharan countries as well as other developing countries in indicating the main contours of institutional and policy framework essential for financial sector reform and development, without which other measures of structural adjustment cannot be effective in attaining the required growth in GDP and living standards. It is the objective of this paper to indicate the institutional and policy framework adopted by Ghana, analyze its impact on the financial system, pinpoint the problems that still persist and try to draw some lessons from its experience that may be relevant for other countries, facing similar problems.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d22e117a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e124" publication-type="other">
V.V. Bhatt, Structure of
Financial Institutions (Bombay, Vora &amp; Co., 1972, Chapter 2)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e134a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e141" publication-type="other">
V.V. Bhatt, On Financial Innovations and Credit Market Evolu-
tion, (World Bank, Economic Development Institute Seminar Paper, 1988)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e150" publication-type="other">
V.V. Bhatt, "Entrepreneurship De-
velopment: India Experience" Finance and Development (World Bank and IMF, Washington, D.C., March 1986)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e159" publication-type="other">
V.V. Bhatt Financial Institutions and Technical Consultancy Services (Washington, D.C., World Bank, EDI
Seminar Paper No. 24,1981)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e169" publication-type="other">
V.V. Bhatt, Development Banks as Catalysts for Industrial Development
(Washington, D.C., World Bank, EDI Seminar Paper, 1989)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e179a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e186" publication-type="other">
World Bank, World Development Report, 1989, pp. 60-61 and V.V. Bhatt, Development Perspectives
(Oxford, Programers Press, 1980) Chapter 13</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e195" publication-type="other">
V.V. Bhatt, "Industrial Projects: Appraisal Criteria" in
Some Aspects of Development Strategy and Policies, (World Bank, EDI Seminar Paper, 1982)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
   </back>
</article>
