<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278050</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Model for Prediction of Knock in the Cycle Simulation by Detail Characterization of Fuel and Temperature Stratification</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kozarac</surname>
                  <given-names>Darko</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Zagreb</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tomic</surname>
                  <given-names>Rudolf</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Zagreb</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Taritas</surname>
                  <given-names>Ivan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Zagreb</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chen</surname>
                  <given-names>Jyh-Yuan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of California</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dibble</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert W.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of California</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>September 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278043</issue-id>
         <fpage>1520</fpage>
         <lpage>1534</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278050"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Development of SI engines to further increase engine efficiency is strongly affected by the occurrence of engine knock. Engine knock has been widely investigated over the years and the main promoting parameters have been identified as load (temperature and pressure), mixture composition, engine speed, characteristic of the fuel, combustion chamber design, and etc. In this paper a new model for predicting engine knock in 0-D environment is presented. The model is based on the well-known approach of using a Livengood and Wu knock integral. Ignition delay data that are supplied to the knock integral are for specific fuel calculated by detail chemical kinetics and are comprised of low temperature heat release ignition delay and high temperature heat release ignition delay. Next, the cycle to cycle variations of engine and temperature stratification of the end gas have to be taken into account. For temperature stratification a new model is developed which is based on the detail analysis of specific CFD results of several engines at different operating conditions. The validation of the knock prediction model was made by comparisons of the simulation results with the experimental data, for two different fuels (n-heptane and gasoline), showing promising ability of the model to predict the tendency of knocking. The results also showed that the cyclic variability of the knock occurrence and intensity in SI combustion is not only caused by the differences in pressure profile caused by cycle to cycle variations, but also by some other factors.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjeric, M., Kozarac, D., and Taritas, I., “Experimentally Supported Modeling of Cycle-to-Cycle Variations of SI Engine Using Cycle- Simulation Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1069, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1069.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vitek, O., Macek, J., Poetsch, C., and Tatschl, R., “Modeling Cycle-to- Cycle Variations in 0-D/1-D Simulation by Means of Combustion Model Parameter Perturbations based on Statistics of Cycle-Resolved Data,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):1075-1098, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1314.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontana, G., Bozza, F., Galloni, E., and Siano, D., “Experimental and Numerical Analyses for the Characterization of the Cyclic Dispersion and Knock Occurrence in a Small-Size SI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-32-0069, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-32-0069.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, F., Rolando, L., Pautasso, E., and Servetto, E., “A Methodology to Mimic Cycle to Cycle Variations and to Predict Knock Occurrence through Numerical Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1070, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1070.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B. “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals,” McGraw- Hill Inc., New York, ISBN 0-07-28637-X, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hajireza, S., Mauss, F., Sunden, B., “Two-Zone Model of Gas Thermodynamic State in SI Engines with Relevance for Knock,” presented at the international symposium on diagnostics and modeling of combustion in internal combustion engines COMODIA90, Japan, September 3-5, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karim, G. and Gao, J., “A Predictive Model for Knock in Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 922366, 1992, doi:10.4271/922366.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moses, E., Yarin, A.L., and Bar-Yoseph, P. “On knocking prediction in spark ignition engines,” Combustion and Flame 101(3): 239-261, 1995, doi:10.1016/0010-2180(94)00202-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gogan, A., Sundén, B., Montorsi, L., Ahmedand, S. et al., “Knock Modeling: an Integrated Tool for Detailed Chemistry and Engine Cycle Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3122, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noda, T., Hasegawa, K., Kubo, M., and Itoh, T., “Development of Transient Knock Prediction Technique by Using a Zero-Dimensional Knocking Simulation with Chemical Kinetics,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0618, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0618.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D'Errico, G., Lucchini, T., Onorati, A., Mehl, M. et al., “Development and Experimental Validation of a Combustion Model with Detailed Chemistry for Knock Predictions,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0938, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0938.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leppard, F.R., “A Detailed Chemical Kinetics Simulation of Engine Knock,” Combustion Science and Technology 43(1-2): 1-20, 1985, doi:10.1080/00102208508946993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Halstead, M.P., Kirsch, L.J., Prothero, A., and Quinn, C.P., “A Mathematical Model for Hydrocarbon Autoignition at High Pressures,” Proceedings of the Royal Society of London. Series A, Mathematical and Physical Sciences, 346(1647): 515-538, 1975, doi:10.1098/rspa.1975.0189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cox, R., Myhill, R., and Sweetenham, W., “Knock prediction in spark ignition engines,” Numerical Combustion, Lecture Notes in Physics, 351: 211-222, 1989, doi:10.1007/3-540-51968-8_85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kikusato, A., Jin, K., and Daisho, Y., “A Numerical Simulation Study on Improving the Thermal Efficiency of a Spark Ignited Engine - Part 1: Modeling of a Spark Ignited Engine Combustion to Predict Engine Performance Considering Flame Propagation, Knock, and Combustion Chamber Wall -,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(1):96-105, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1073.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">By, A., Kempinski, B., and Rife, J., “Knock in Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 810147, 1981, doi:10.4271/810147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Belli, M., Bova, S., and Fragiacomo, P., “Model Predictions and Experimental Evidence of Detonation Characteristics in a Spark Ignition I.C.E.,” presented at the international symposium on diagnostics and modeling of combustion in internal combustion engines COMODIA90, Japan, September 3-5, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Soylu, S., “Prediction of knock limited operating conditions of a natural gas engine,” Energy Conversion and Management 46(1): 121-138, 2005, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2004.02.014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Worret, R., Bernhardt, S., Schwarz, F., and Spicher, U., “Application of Different Cylinder Pressure Based Knock Detection Methods in Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1668, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1668.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kozarac, D., Schuemie, A., Ofner, H., and Tatschl, R. “Modeling of natural gas engine with the emphasis on prediction of knock” presented at 6th European Congress on Computational Methods in Applied Sciences and Engineering (ECCOMAS 2012), Austria September 10-14, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steurs, K., Blomberg, C., and Boulouchos, K., “Knock in an Ethanol Fueled Spark Ignition Engine: Detection Methods with Cycle-Statistical Analysis and Predictions Using Different Auto-Ignition Models,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):568-583, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Livengood, J.C., Wu, P.C., “Correlation of Auto-ignition Phenomena in Internal Combustion Engines and Rapid Compression Machines,” Symposium (International) on Combustion 5(1): 347-356, 1955, doi:10.1016/S0082-0784(55)80047-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heiss, M., Lauer, T., Geringer, B., “A detailed analysis of engine knock initiation by means of a stochastic reactor model,” presented at 6th European Congress on Computational Methods in Applied Sciences and Engineering (ECCOMAS 2012), Austria September 10-14, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smith, G.P., Golden, D.M., Frenklach, M., Moriarty, N.W., Eiteneer, B., Goldenberg, M., Bowman, C.T., Hanson, R.K., Song, S., Gardiner, W.C., Jr. Lissianski, V.V., Qin, Z., available at http://www.me.berkeley.edu/gri_mech/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ban, M., and Duic, N., “Adaptation Of N-Heptane Auto-ignition Tabulation For Complex Chemistry Mechanisms,” Thermal Science 15:135-144, 2011, doi:10.2298/TSCI100514077B.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Richard, S., Bougrine, S., Font, G., Lafossas, F.-A. et al., “On the Reduction of a 3D CFD Combustion Model to Build a Physical 0D Model for Simulating Heat Releas, Knock and Pollutants in SI Engines,” Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology - 64(3):223-242, 2009, doi:10.2516/ogst/2008055.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brecq, G., Bellettre, J., and Tazerout, M., “A new indicator for knock detection in gas SI engines,” International Journal of Thermal Sciences, 42(5): 523-532, 2003, doi:10.1016/S1290-0729(02)00052-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, H.J., Gaffuri, P., Pitz, W.J., and Westbrook, C.K., “A Comprehensive Modeling Study of n-Heptane Oxidation,” Combustion and Flame 114(1-2): 149-177, 1998, doi:10.1016/S0010-2180(97)00282-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrae, J., Johansson, D., Björnbom, P., Risberg, P. et al., “Cooxidation in the auto-ignition of primary reference fuels and nheptane/toluene blends,” Combustion and Flame 140(4): 267-286, 2005, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2004.11.009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
