<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278325</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Numerical Comparison of Rolling Road Systems</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hennig</surname>
                  <given-names>Alexander</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Widdecke</surname>
                  <given-names>Nils</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kuthada</surname>
                  <given-names>Timo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wiedemann</surname>
                  <given-names>Jochen</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>IVK / FKFS Univ. Stuttgart</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278288</issue-id>
         <fpage>2659</fpage>
         <lpage>2670</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278325"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The entire automotive industry is moving towards lower CO₂ emissions and higher energy efficiency. Especially for higher driving speeds this can be achieved by minimizing aerodynamic drag. Additionally, aerodynamic downforce is essential to maintain or even improve the handling performance of a vehicle. In order to optimize the vehicle's aerodynamic efficiency in wind tunnel tests, the boundary conditions of a vehicle driving on a road must be simulated properly. Particularly for optimizing the underbody region of a vehicle, ground simulation is an important issue in every wind tunnel. Today rolling road systems featuring one or more moving belts on the wind tunnel floor are a standard tool to simulate the complex boundary condition of a vehicle driving on the road. But generally the technical effort to measure aerodynamic forces accurately increases with improvement of the aerodynamic ground simulation.</p>
            <p>This paper presents an attempt to evaluate the influence of different rolling road systems. The use of CFD makes it possible to investigate their influence on different types of vehicles excluding wind tunnel interference effects and independent of force measurement techniques. A numerical study with a standard passenger car and generic racing cars is presented. This study includes rolling road systems like a 5-belt, a T-belt and a single belt system as well as a new 3-belt rolling road layout.</p>
            <p>An investigation of surface pressures, force development graphs and integral values is shown to analyze the influences of different rolling road systems. It can be concluded that, particularly concerning aerodynamic developments for the vehicle underbody, single belt systems or at least multiple partial belt systems of similar dimensions are essential to guarantee an optimal and reliable ground simulation in automotive wind tunnels.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cooper, K.R., Fediw, A.A., Garry, K.P. Wlodarski, S., “Development of a Moving Ground System for the Study of Vehicle Aerodynamics,” 2-Day Conference, The Royal Aeronautical Society, Loughborough University UK, 1994</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carr, G.W. and Eckert, W., “A Further Evaluation of Ground-Plane Suction Method for Ground Simulation in Automotive Wind Tunnels,” SAE Technical Paper 940418, 1994, doi: 10.4271/940418.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuthada, T. and Wiedemann, J., “Investigations in a Cooling Air Flow System under the Influence of Road Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0796, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-0796.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duncan, B.D., Kandasamy, S., Sbeih, K., Lounsberry, T.H. et al., “Further CFD Studies for Detailed Tires using Aerodynamics Simulation with Rolling Road Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0756, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0756.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duncan, B.D. and Golsch, K., “Characterization of Separated Turbulent Flow Regions in CFD Results for a Pontiac NASCAR Race Car,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-3556, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-3556.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wäschle, A., “The Influence of Rotating Wheels on Vehicle Aerodynamics - Numerical and Experimental Investigations,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0107, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duell, E., Kharazi, A., Muller, S., Ebeling, W. et al., “The BMW AVZ Wind Tunnel Center,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0118, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0118.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koremoto, K., Kawamura, N., Kuratani, N., Nakamura, S., Arai, T., Galanga, F., Walter, J., Martindale, B., Duell, E., Muller, S., “The Characteristics of the Honda Full Scale Aero-acoustic Wind Tunnel equipped with a Rolling Road System,” 8th MIRA International Vehicle Aerodynamics Conference, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wiedemann, J. and Potthoff, J., “The New 5-Belt Road Simulation System of the IVK Wind Tunnels - Design and First Results,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0429, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0429.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borello, G., Beccio, S., Gollo, G., and Quagliotti, F.B., “Rolling Road Technology for Automotive High Speed Testing,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0353, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-0353.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cogotti, A., “The New Moving Ground System of the Pininfarina Wind Tunnel,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1044, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1044.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lietz, R., Mallick, S., Kandasamy, S., and Chen, H., “Exterior Airflow Simulations Using a Lattice Boltzmann Approach,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0596, 2002, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-0596.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bartelheimer, W. “Berechnung der Fahrzeugströmungbei BMW: Validierung und Einsatz bei Exa PowerFLOW,” Tagung “Fahrzeug-Aerodynamik”, Haus der Technik, München, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parpais, S., Farce, J., Baily, O., Genty, H., “A Comparison of Experimental Investigations and Numerical Simulations around Two-box form Models,” MIRA, 4th Int. Conference of Vehicle Aerodynamics, Warwick, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mallick, S., Remondi, S., Chen, H., Pervaiz, M., “Developing CFD through Validation of Turbulence Models,” MIRA, 3rd Int. Conference of Vehicle Aerodynamics, Warwick, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fischer, O., Kuthada, T., Mercker, E., Wiedemann, J. et al., “CFD Approach to Evaluate Wind-Tunnel and Model Setup Effects on Aerodynamic Drag and Lift for Detailed Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0760, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0760.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mercker, E. and Cooper, K.R., “A Two-Measurement Correction for the Effects of a Pressure Gradient on Automotive, Open-Jet, Wind Tunnel Measurements,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0568, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0568.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fischer, O., Kuthada, T., Wiedemann, J., Dethioux, P. et al., “CFD Validation Study for a Sedan Scale Model in an Open Jet Wind Tunnel,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0325, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
