<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285111</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Study of Low Soot or Soot-Free Leaner Lifted Flame Combustion in a Light Duty Optical Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Malbec</surname>
                  <given-names>Louis-Marie</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kashdan</surname>
                  <given-names>Julian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>IFP Energies nouvelles; Institut Carnot IFPEN TE</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>June 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285080</issue-id>
         <fpage>1064</fpage>
         <lpage>1079</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285111"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Previous experimental data obtained in constant volume combustion vessels have shown that soot-free diffusive flames can be achieved in a Diesel spray if the equivalence ratio at the flame lift-off location is below 2. The so-called Leaner Lifted-Flame Combustion (LLFC) strategy is a promising approach to limit the levels of in-cylinder soot produced in Diesel engines. However, implementing such strategies in light-duty engines is not straightforward due to the effects of charge confinement , non-steady boundary conditions and spray-spray interactions compared to the simplified configuration of a free-jet in a constant-volume combustion vessel. The present study aims at trying to gain a better understanding of the requirements in terms of injector and engine settings in order to reach the LLFC regime in a light-duty engine.</p>
            <p>Experiments were performed on a 0.5L single-cylinder optical engine. Various injector nozzle geometries were investigated, offering variations in the number of holes (7 to 14), in hole diameter (63μm to 123μm) and in nozzle mass flow rate (240ml/min to 672ml/min). The impact of variations in engine operating conditions was also studied, in terms of EGR rate (0% to 65%), injection pressure (800bar to 1600bar), swirl (1 and 1.5), and boost pressure (1bar to 2.2bar). Engine-out soot emissions were measured with a smoke meter. The combustion process was characterized using a high-speed camera which collected the broadband emission of incandescent soot. An intensified camera recorded once per cycle OH* chemiluminescence at 310nm.</p>
            <p>The results shows how in-cylinder soot formation is affected by the parametric variations. In particular, for low levels of EGR, the rate of soot formation is very high and mainly driven by in-cylinder thermodynamic conditions. For high EGR levels(e.g. &gt; 65%) the reaction rates are too low to enable soot formation, even if the thermodynamic conditions are favorable.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Plee, S.L., Ahmad, T., and Myers, J.P., "Flame Temperature Correlation for the Effects of Exhaust Gas Recirculation on Diesel Particulate and NO x Emissions," 1981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R.D., and Duraisamy, G., "Review of high efficiency and clean reactivity controlled compression ignition (RCCI) combustion in internal combustion engines," Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 46:12–71, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.pecs.2014.05.003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Kitahara, Y., and Aiyoshizawa, E., "Ultra-Clean Combustion Technology Combining a Low-Temperature and Premixed Combustion Concept for Meeting Future Emission Standards," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0200, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Ogawa, H., Muranaka, S., , "New Combustion Concept for Ultra-Clean and High-Efficiency Small DI Diesel Engines," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3681, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3681.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shimazaki, N., Tsurushima, T., and Nishimura, T., "Dual Mode Combustion Concept With Premixed Diesel Combustion by Direct Injection Near Top Dead Center," SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0742, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0742.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kanda, T. Hakozaki, T. Uchimoto, T. Hatano, J., "PCCI Operation with Early Injection of Conventional Diesel Fuel," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0378, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0378.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Minato, A. Tanaka, T., and Nishimura, T., "Investigation of Premixed Lean Diesel Combustion with Ultra High Pressure Injection," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0914, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0914.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Polonowski, C. Mueller, C. Gehrke, C. Bazyn, T., "An Experimental Investigation of Low-Soot and Soot-Free Combustion Strategies in a Heavy-Duty, Single-Cylinder, Direct-Injection, Optical Diesel Engine," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):51–77, 2012, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D. and Higgins, B., "Flame Lift-Off on Direct-Injection Diesel Sprays Under Quiescent Conditions," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01- 0530, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0530.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D. Higgins, B. and Pickett, L., "Flame Lift-Off on Direct- Injection Diesel Fuel Jets: Oxygen Concentration Effects," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0890, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M. and Siebers, D.L., "An Investigation of Diesel Soot Formation Processes Using Micro-Orifices," Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 29:655–662, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. and Siebers, D., "Non-Sooting, Low Flame Temperature Mixing-Controlled DI Diesel Combustion," SAE Technical Paper 2004- 01-1399, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M. and Siebers, D.L., "Soot in Diesel fuel jets: effects of ambient temperature, ambient density, and injection pressure," Combustion and Flame 138:114–135, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Siebers, D. and Idicheria, C., "Relationship Between Ignition Processes and the Lift-Off Length of Diesel Fuel Jets," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3843, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chartier, C., Aronsson, U., Andersson, Ö., Egnell, R. , "Analysis of Smokeless Spray Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine by Combined Simultaneous Optical Diagnostics," SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1353, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1353.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aronsson, U., Chartier, C., Andersson, Ö., Egnell, R. , "Analysis of the Correlation Between Engine-Out Particulates and Local Φ in the Lift- Off Region of a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Using Raman Spectroscopy," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1):645–660, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kashdan, J. and Thirouard, B., "A Comparison of Combustion and Emissions Behaviour in Optical and Metal Single-Cylinder Diesel Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1857–1872, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B. and Siebers, D., "Measurement of the Flame Lift-Off Location on DI Diesel Sprays Using OH Chemiluminescence," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0918, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0918.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaydon, A.G., "The Spectroscopy of Flames," Chapman and Hall Ltd., London, ISBN 978-94-009-5722-0, 1974.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">"4th ECN workshop, 5-6 Sept. 2015, Kyoto, Japan, https://ecn.sandia. gov/ecn-workshop/ecn4-workshop/," 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., "Scaling Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays Based on Mixing-Limited Vaporization," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01- 0528, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0528.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M. and Kattke, K., "Entrainment Waves in Diesel Jets," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1170–1193, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Manin, J., Genzale, C., Siebers, D. , "Relationship Between Diesel Fuel Spray Vapor Penetration/Dispersion and Local Fuel Mixture Fraction," SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):764–799, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0686.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malbec, L. and Bruneaux, G., "Study of Air Entrainment of Multi-hole Diesel Injection by Particle Image Velocimetry - Effect of Neighboring Jets Interaction and Transient Behavior After End of Injection.," SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):107–123, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0342.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malbec, L., Egúsquiza, J., Bruneaux, G., and Meijer, M., "Characterization of a Set of ECN Spray A Injectors: Nozzle to Nozzle Variations and Effect on Spray Characteristics," SAE Int. J. Engines 6(3):1642–1660, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0037.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., "A Conceptual Model of DI Diesel Combustion Based on Laser-Sheet Imaging," SAE Technical Paper 970873, 1997, doi:10.4271/970873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., "Combustion structure of free and wall-impinging diesel jets by simultaneous laser-induced fluorescence of formaldehyde, poly-aromatic hydrocarbons, and hydroxides," International Journal of Engine Research 9:249–265, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">2003-01-0074Musculus, M., "Effects of the In-Cylinder Environment on Diffusion Flame Lift-Off in a DI Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0074, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0074.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Donkerbroek, A.J., Boot, M.D., Luijten, C C M, Dam, N.J., "Flame lift-off length and soot production of oxygenated fuels in relation with ignition delay in a DI heavy-duty diesel engine," Combustion and Flame 158(3):525–538, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eagle, W.E., Musculus, Mark P B, Malbec, L.-M., and Bruneaux, G., "Measuring transient entrainment rates of a confined vaporizing diesel jet," ILASS Americas, 26th Annual Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
