<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Research Center on International Cooperation of the University of Bergamo</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90002019</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>MANAGERIAL PSYCHOLOGY AND CORPORATE INVESTMENT RATIONALITY</article-title>
            <subtitle>EVIDENCE FROM TUNISIAN LISTED FIRMS</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Baccar</surname>
                  <given-names>Amel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ezzeddine</surname>
                  <given-names>Ben Mohamed</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Bouri</surname>
                  <given-names>Abdelfettah</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>3</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>1, 2 and 3</sup>Faculty of Economics and Management, FSEG Sfax, Tunisia.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>40</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e90002016</issue-id>
         <fpage>51</fpage>
         <lpage>73</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90002019"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>In this paper, we present an original essay that aims to explore the effect of some psychological biases on corporate investment decision’s rationality. Departing from a sample of traded Tunisian firms and the annual reports of those firms, we construct proxies for the optimism, overconfidence and others behavioral biases.We find that these biases affect corporate investment rationality and our results are robust with numerous control variables attached to the firms and the CEOs characteristics. The paper contributes to the behavioral corporate finance literature since we investigate the effect of a pool of psychological biases that are still unexplored such as the disposition effect, loss aversion and the prospect theory bias on corporate investment rationality index.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Key words:</label>
            <kwd>Managerial Psychology</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Investment Decision rationality</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Corporate Governance</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>behavioral biases</kwd>
            <x>.</x>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barber B. and T. Odean, 2000, “Trading is Hazardous to your Wealth: The Common Stock Investment Performance of Individual Investors”, Journal of Finance, Vol. 55, No. 2, pp. 773-806.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ben Fatma E., E. Ben Mohamed and S. Boudabbous, 2015, “Does Entrepreneur Dispositional Optimism Bias affect Small Firms Technical Efficiency?”, International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Small Business, Vol. 24, No. 3, pp. 302-321.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ben Mohamed E., R. Fairchild, A. Baccar and A. Bouri, 2012, “Does Corporate Governance Affect Managerial Optimism: New Evidence from Nyse Panel Data Firms”, International Journal of Euro-Mediterranean Studies, Vol. 5, No. 1, pp. 41-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ben Mohamed E., R. Fairchild, and A. Bouri, 2014a, “Investment Cash Flow Sensitivity under Managerial Optimism: New Evidence from NYSE Panel Data Firms”, Journal of Economics, Finance and Administrative Sciences, Vol. 19, No. 36, pp. 11-18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ben Mohamed E., S. Naceur, A. Baccar and A. Bouri, 2014b, “CEO’s Personal Characteristics, Ownership and Investment Cash Flow Sensitivity: Evidence from NYSE Panel Data firms”, Journal of Economics, Finance and Administrative Sciences, Vol. 19, No. 37, pp. 98-103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bishop R. and T. Heberlein, 1979, “Measuring Values of Extra-Market Goods: Are Indirect Measures Biased?”, American Journal of Agriculture Economics, Vol. 61, No. 5, pp. 926-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Campbell C., S. Johnson, J. Rutherford and B. Stanley, 2011, “CEO Confidence and Forced Turnover”, Journal of Financial Economics, Vol. 101, No. 3, pp. 695-712.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fairchild R., 2005, “Behavioral Finance in a Principal Agent Model of Capital Budgeting”, ICFAI Journal of Behavioral Finance, Vol. 2, No. 1, pp. 34-44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fama E., 1980, “Agency Problem and the Theory of the Firm”, Journal of Political Economy, Vol. 88, No. 2, pp. 288-307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gervais S., J.B. Heaton and T. Odean, 2003, “Overconfidence, Investment Policy, and Executive Stock Option”, Working Paper, Duke University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gleitman H., A.J. Fridlund and D. Reisberg, 2000, Basic Psychology, 5th ed., Norton &amp; Co.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hackbarth D., 2008, “Managerial Traits and Capital Structure Decisions”, Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis, Vol. 43, No. 4, pp. 843-881.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hasite R and R.M. Dawes, 2000, “Rational Choice in an Uncertain Word: The Psychology of Judgment and Decision Making”, Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heaton J.B., 2002, “Managerial Optimism and Corporate Finance”, Financial Management, Vol. 32, No. 2, pp. 33-45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hirshleifer D., 2001, “Investor Psychology and Asset Pricing”, Journal of Finance, Vol. 56, No. 4, pp. 1533-1597.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang W., F. Jiang, Z. Liu and M. Zhang, 2011, “Agency Cost, Top Executives’ Overconfidence, and Investment-Cash Flow Sensitivity: Evidence from Listed Companies in China”, Pacific-Basin Finance Journal, Vol. 19, No. 3, pp. 261-277.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jensen M.C, 1993, “The Modern Industrial Revolution, Exit, and the Failure of Internal Control Systems”, Journal of Finance, Vol. 48, No. 3, pp. 831-880</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kahneman D. and D. Lovallo, 1993, “Timid Choices and Bold Forecasts: A Cognitive Perspective on Risk Taking”, Management Sciences, Vol. 39, No. 1, pp. 17-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knetsch J.L and J.A Sinden, 1984, “Willingness to Pay and Compensation Demanded: Experimental Evidence of an Unexpected Disparity in Measures of Value”, Quarterly Journal of Economics, Vol. 99, No. 3, pp. 507- 521.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin Y.H, S.Y. Hu and M.S. Chen, 2008, “Testing Pecking Order Prediction from the Viewpoint of Managerial Optimism: Some Empirical Evidence from Taiwan”, Pacific-Basin Finance Journal, Vol. 16, No. 2, pp. 160-181.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin Y.H., S.Y. Hu and M.S. Chen, 2005, “Managerial Optimism and Corporate Investment: Some Empirical Evidence from Taiwan”, Pacific-Basin Finance Journal, Vol. 13, No. 5, pp. 523-546.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malmendier U. and G. Tate, 2005a, “CEO Overconfidence and Corporate Investment”, Journal of Finance, Vol. 60, No. 6, pp. 2661-2700.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malmendier U. and G. Tate, 2005b, “Does Overconfidence Affect Corporate Investment? CEO Overconfidence Measures Revisited”, European Financial Management, Vol. 11, No. 5, pp. 649-659.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malmendier U. and G. Tate, 2008, “Who Makes Acquisitions? CEO Overconfidence and the Market’s Reaction”, Journal of Financial Economics, Vol. 89, No. 1, pp. 20-43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Odean T., 1998, “Are Investors Reluctant to Realize their Losses?”, Journal of Finance, Vol. 53, No. 5, pp. 1775-1798</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Odean T., 1999, “Do Investors Trade Too Much?”, American Economic Review, Vol. 89, No. 5, pp. 1279-1298.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oliveira A., 2007, “A Discuss of Rational and Psychological Decision-Making Theories and Models: The Search for a Cultural-Ethical Decision-Making Model”, Electronic Journal of Business Ethics and Organization Studies, Vol. 12, No. 2, pp. 12-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pawlina G. and D.R. Renneboog, 2005, “Is Investment-Cash Flow Sensitivity Caused by Agency Costs or Asymmetric Information? Evidence from the UK”, European Financial Management, Vol. 11, No. 4, pp. 483-513.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roll R., 1986, “The Hubris Hypothesis of Corporate Takeovers”, The Journal of Business, Vol. 59, No. 2, pp. 197-216.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rubinstein A., 1988, “Instinctive and Cognitive Reasoning: A Study of Response Times”, The Economic Journal, Vol. 117, No. 523, pp. 1243-1259.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shefrin H., 1999, “Behavioral Corporate Finance”, Journal of Applied Corporate Finance, Vol. 14, No. 3, pp. 113-124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Statman M., S. Thorley and K. Vorkink, 2005, “Investor Overconfidence and Trading”, Working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tversky A. and D. Kahneman, 1981, “The Framing of Decisions and the Rationality of Choice”, Science, Vol. 211, No. 1, pp. 453-458.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weinstein N., 1980, “Unrealistic Optimism about Future Life Events”, Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, Vol. 39, No. 5, pp. 806-820.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yermack D., 1996, “Higher Market Valuation of Companies with a Small Board of Directors”, Journal of Financial Economics, Vol. 10, No. 2, pp. 185-211.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
