<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">15</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830266</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830270</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>AN EMPIRICAL INVESTIGATION OF THE CONCENTRATION - PROFITABILITY RELATIONSHIP IN THE JORDANIAN BANKING SYSTEM / ETUDE D'INVESTIGATION EMPIRIQUE SUR LES RELATIONS ENTRE CONCENTRATION ET RENTABILITE DANS LE SYSTEME BANCAIRE JORDANIEN</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Mehmet A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Civelek</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Mohamed W.</given-names>
                  <surname>Al-Alami</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1991</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>247</fpage>
         <lpage>260</lpage>
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830270"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The aim of this study is to test empirically the structure-performance (S-P) hypothesis within the institutional context of the Jordanian commercial banking system. The study utilizes cross-sectional data collected from the whole sample of 16 commercial banks in Jordan over the five consecutive years from 1984-1988. To fulfil its aim, a bank profitability model is formulated under the methodological guidelines of the existing studies in the empirical literature. Even though the study presents some empirical evidence in support of the S-P hypothesis within the Jordanian commercial banking system, the role of the market concentration variable in the determination of bank profitability cannot be emphasized. The main reasons for this are the appearance of the market growth variable as a potentially influential factor in the bank profitability relation and the empirical ambiguity introduced into the equation by the risk variable. Consequently, it should be underlined that the empirical findings of the present study cannot be extended to make strong policy suggestions in the direction of more restrictive (or lenient) banking regulation. Le but de cette étude est d'examiner empiriquement la performance structurelle (P-S) des hypothèses du contenu institutionnel du système bancaire commercial Jordanien. L'étude a utilisé des données (cross - sectionnelles) prises des (16) banques commerciales existantes en Jordanie et pour une période de cinq ans successives (1984-1988). Afin de compléter cet objectif, un modèle de la rentabilité bancaire a été formé d'après des indicateurs méthodologiques des études existantes dans la literature empirique. En fait, cette étude presente quelques evidences empiriques qui appuient les hypothèses du (P-S), du système bancaire commercial Jordanien, mais le rôle variable de la concentration du marché dans la determination de la rentabilité bancaire ne peut être generalisé. Et dont les raisons principales, reviennent à l'apparence du développement variable du marché comme un facteur potentiel d'influence sur la relation entre la rentabilité bancaire et l'ambiguïté empirique introduite dans l'equation par le changement du risque. En conséquence, il faut souligner que les résultats empiriques de cette étude ne peuvent s'étendre pour présenter des propositions d'une forte politique qui s'étend vers la modification des règlements bancaires actuels.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d8e147a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e154" publication-type="other">
Goodfriend and King (1988).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e161a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e168" publication-type="other">
Dennis (1981, pp. 21-22).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e175a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e182" publication-type="other">
Rhoades and Rutz (1986,
p. 73).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e192a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e199" publication-type="other">
Baumol and Willig (1986)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e207a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e214" publication-type="other">
Rhoades and Rutz (1982, p. 79)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e221a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e228" publication-type="other">
Adelman (1965).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e235a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e242" publication-type="other">
Gibson (1985, p. 633).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d8e258a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e262" publication-type="other">
Adelman, M.A. Comment on the "H" Concentration Measure as a Number-Equivalent, Review of Economics
and Statistics, 1969, 51(1), 99-101.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e272a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e276" publication-type="other">
Ahmed, N.N. Studies in the Banking Culture, first edition, Amman, 1984 (in Arabic).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e283a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e287" publication-type="other">
Bain, J.S. Workable Competition in Oligopoly, American Economic Review, 1950, 40(2), 35-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e294a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e298" publication-type="other">
_ Relation of Profit Rate to Industry Concentration: American Manufacturing, 1936 to 1940, Quarterly
Journal of Economics, 1951, 65(3), 293-324.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e309a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e313" publication-type="other">
Baumol, W.J., Panzar, J.C. and Willig, R. Contestable Markets and the Theory of Industry Structure, New York:
Harcourt, Brace and Javanovich, 1982.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e323a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e327" publication-type="other">
_ and Willig, R.D., Contestability: Since the Book, Oxford Economic Papers, 1986, 38(Supplement),
9-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e337a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e341" publication-type="other">
Brozen, Y. Concentration, Mergers, and Public Policy, New York: Macmillan Publishing Company, Inc., 1982.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e348a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e352" publication-type="other">
Clark, J.A. Single-Equation, Multiple Regression Methodology: Is It an Appropriate Methodology for the Structure-
Performance Relationship in Banking? Journal of Monetary Economics, 1986, 18(3), 259-312.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e362a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e366" publication-type="other">
Demsetz, H. Industry Structure, Market Rivalry and Public Policy, Journal of Law and Economics, 1973,16(1), 1-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e373a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e377" publication-type="other">
Dennis, G.E. Monetary Economics, London: Longman Group Limited, 1981.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e385a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e389" publication-type="other">
Edwards, F. Managerial Objectives in Regulated Industries: Expense-Preference Behavior in Banking, Journal
of Political Economy, 1977, 85(2), 147-162.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e399a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e403" publication-type="other">
Fanik, F. Jordan Banks Profitability, A Financial Analytical Study for the Profitability of the Licensed Banks, Am-
man, 1981 (in Arabic).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e413a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e417" publication-type="other">
Gilbert, R.A. Bank Market Structure and Competition: A Survey, Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking, 1984,
16(4), 617-645.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e427a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e431" publication-type="other">
Glassman, CA. and Rhoades S.A.; Owner Vs. Manager; Control Effects on Bank Performance, Review of
Economics and Statistics, 1980, 62(2), 263-270.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e441a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e445" publication-type="other">
Goodfriend, M. and King, R.G. Financial Deregulation, Monetary Policy, and Central Banking, Economic Review,
Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond, 1988, 2, 3-20.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e455a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e459" publication-type="other">
Heggested, A.J. Market Structure, Risk and Profitability in Commercial Banking, Journal of Finance, 1977, 32(4),
1207-1216.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e470a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e474" publication-type="other">
_ Market Structure, Competition, and Performance in Financial Industries: A Survey of Banking Studies,
in Issues in Financial Regulation, Edited by Franklen R.E., New York: McGraw-Hill, 1979, 449-490.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e484a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e488" publication-type="other">
_ and Mingo, J. J. Prices, Nonprices, and Competition in Commercial Banking, Journal of Money,
Credit and Banking, 1976, 8 (2), 107-117.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e498a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e502" publication-type="other">
Peltzman, S. The Gains and Losses from Industrial Concentration, Journal of Law and Economics, 1977, 20(3),
229-263.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e512a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e516" publication-type="other">
Rhoades, S.A. and Rutz, R.D. Market Power and Firm Risk: A Test for "Quiet Life" Hypothesis, Journal of
Monetary Economics, 1982, 9(1), 73-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e526a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e530" publication-type="other">
Rose, S. and Fraser, D.R. The Relationships between Stability and Change Market Structure: An Analysis of
Bank Prices, Journal of Industrial Economics, 1976, 24(2), 251-266.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e540a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e544" publication-type="other">
Scherer, F.M. Industrial Market Structure and Economic Performance, Chicago: Rand McNally College Publishing
Company 1970.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e555a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e559" publication-type="other">
Schweiger, I. and McGee, J.S. Chicago Banking; The Structure and Performance of Banks and Related Finan-
cial Institutions in Chicago and Other Areas, Journal of Business, 1961, 34(2), 203-366.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e569a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e573" publication-type="other">
Smirlock, M. Evidence on the (Non)Relationship Between Concentration and Profitability in Banking, Journal
of Money Credit and Banking, 1985, 17(1), 69-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e583a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e587" publication-type="other">
Ziad, R. Banking Management, A Practical Study in Jordan, Third edition, Amman, 1982 (in Arabic).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


