<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">7</issue>
         <issue-id>i40035312</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40782962</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Temporary versus Permanent Shocks: Explaining Corporate Financial Policies</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alexander S.</given-names>
                  <surname>Gorbenko</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ilya A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Strebulaev</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2010</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2591</fpage>
         <lpage>2647</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2010 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40782962"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We investigate corporate financial policies in the presence of both temporary and permanent shocks to firms' cash flows. In our framework, cash flows can be negative and are imperfectly correlated with firm value, and earnings volatility differs from asset volatility. These results are consistent with empirical stylized facts. They are also contrary to the implications of existing dynamic capital structure models that allow only for permanent shocks to cash flows. Temporary shocks increase the importance of financial flexibility and may provide an intuitively simple and realistic explanation of empirically observed financial conservatism and low leverage phenomena. The theoretical framework developed in this article general enough to be used in various corporate finance applications.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d8e290a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e297" publication-type="other">
Washington Post, September 20 2006, p. D01 .</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e304a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e311" publication-type="other">
Givoly and Hayn (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e318a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e325" publication-type="other">
Schaefer and Strebulaev (2008)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e332a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e339" publication-type="other">
Dixit
and Pindyck 1994</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e350a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e357" publication-type="other">
Hackbarth, Miao, and Morellec (2006)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e363" publication-type="other">
Bhamra, Kühn, and Strebulaev
(2010a)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e373a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e380" publication-type="other">
Goldstein, Ju, and Leland 2001</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e386" publication-type="other">
Strebulaev (2007)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>&lt;bold&gt;References&lt;/bold&gt;</title>
        <ref id="d8e402a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e406" publication-type="other">
Almeida, H., and T. Philippon. 2007. The Risk-Adjusted Cost of Financial Distress. Journal of Finance
62:2557-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e416a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e420" publication-type="other">
Altman, E. I. 1984. A Further Empirical Investigation of the Bankruptcy Cost Question. Journal of Finance
39:1067-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e430a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e434" publication-type="other">
Andrade, G., and S. N. Kaplan. 1998. How Costly Is Financial (Not Economic) Distress? Evidence from Highly
Leveraged Transactions That Became Distressed. Journal of Finance 53:1443-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e444a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e448" publication-type="other">
Asquith, P., R. Gertner, and D. Scharfstein. 1994. Anatomy of Financial Distress: An Examination of Junk Bond
Issuers. Quarterly Journal of Economics 109:625-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e459a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e463" publication-type="other">
Berndt, Α., R. Douglas, D. Duffie, M. Ferguson, and D. Schranz. 2005. Measuring Default Risk Premia from
Default Swap Rates and EDFs. Working Paper, Stanford GSB.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e473a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e477" publication-type="other">
Bhamra, H, L. Kühn, and I. A. Strebulaev. 2010a. The Levered Equity Risk Premium and Credit Spreads: A
Unified Framework. Review of Financial Studies 23:645-703.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e487a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e491" publication-type="other">
Bhamra, H., L. Kühn, and I. A. Strebulaev. 2010b (forthcoming). The Aggregate Dynamics of Capital Structure
and Macroeconomic Risk. Review of Financial Studies.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e501a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e505" publication-type="other">
Coles, J., M. Lemmon, and F. Meschke. 2007. Structural Models and Endogeneity in Corporate Finance.
Working Paper, University of Utah.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e515a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e519" publication-type="other">
Corwin, S. A. 2003. The Determinants of Underpricing for Seasoned Equity Offers, Journal of Finance
58:2249-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e529a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e533" publication-type="other">
Dao, B., and M. Jeanblanc. 2006. Double Exponential Jump Diffusion Process: A Structural Model of Endoge-
nous Default Barrier with Roll-Over Debt Structure. Working Paper, University Paris Dauphine.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e544a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e548" publication-type="other">
Davydenko, S. 2007. When Do Firms Default? A Study of the Default Boundary. Working Paper, University of
Toronto.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e558a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e562" publication-type="other">
Dixit, A. K., and R. S. Pindyck. 1994. Investment under Uncertainty. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e569a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e573" publication-type="other">
Fan, Η., and S. M. Sundaresan. 2000. Debt Valuation, Renegotiation, and Optimal Dividend Policy. Review of
Financial Studies 13:1057-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e583a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e587" publication-type="other">
Faulkender, M, and M. A. Petersen. 2006. Does the Source of Capital Affect Capital Structure? Review of
Financial Studies 19:45-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e597a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e601" publication-type="other">
Fischer, E. O., R. Heinkel, and J. Zechner. 1989. Optimal Dynamic Capital Structure Choice: Theory and Tests.
Journal of Finance 44: 19-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e611a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e615" publication-type="other">
Gamba, Α., and A. Triantis. 2008a. The Value of Financial Flexibility. Journal of Finance 63:2263-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e623a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e627" publication-type="other">
Gamba, Α., and A. Triantis. 2008b. Valuing Corporate Financing Strategies. Working Paper, University of
Maryland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e637a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e641" publication-type="other">
Givoly, D., and C. Hayn. 2000. The Changing Time-Series Properties of Earnings, Cash Flows and Accruals:
Has Financial Reporting Become More Conservative? Journal of Accounting and Economics 29:287-320.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e651a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e655" publication-type="other">
Goldstein, R., N. Ju, and Η. Ε. Leland. 2001. An EBIT-Based Model of Dynamic Capital Structure. Journal of
Business 74:483-512.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e665a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e669" publication-type="other">
Graham, J. R. 1999. Do Personal Taxes Affect Corporate Financing Decisions? Journal of Public Economics
73:147-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e679a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e683" publication-type="other">
Graham, J. R. 2000. How Big Are the Tax Benefits of Debt? Journal of Finance 55: 1 901-4 1 .</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e690a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e694" publication-type="other">
Graham, J. R. 2003. Taxes and Corporate Finance: A Review. Review of Financial Studies 16:1075-129.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e702a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e706" publication-type="other">
Graham, J. R., and C. R. Harvey. 2001. The Theory and Practice of Corporate Finance: Evidence from the Field.
Journal of Financial Economics 60: 1 87-243.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e716a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e720" publication-type="other">
Hackbarth, D., C. A. Hennessy, and H. E. Leland. 2007. Can the Trade-Off Theory Explain Debt Structure?
Review of Financial Studies 20:1389-428.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e730a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e734" publication-type="other">
Hackbarth, D., J. Miao, and E. Morellec. 2006. Capital Structure, Credit Risk, and Macroeconomic Conditions.
Journal of Financial Economics 82:519-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e744a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e748" publication-type="other">
Hackbarth, D., and Ε. Morellec. 2008. Stock Returns in Mergers and Acquisitions. Journal of Finance
63:1213-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e758a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e762" publication-type="other">
Hansen, R. S. 2001. Do Investment Banks Compete in IPOs?: The Advent of the "7% Plus Contract." Journal
of Financial Economics 59:313-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e772a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e776" publication-type="other">
Hennessy, C. Α., and Τ. Μ. Whited. 2005. Debt Dynamics. Journal of Finance 60:1 129-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e784a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e788" publication-type="other">
Hennessy, C. Α., and Τ. Μ. Whited. 2007. How Costly Is External Financing? Evidence from a Structural
Estimation. Journal of Finance 62: 1705-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e798a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e802" publication-type="other">
Ju, N., R. Parrino, A. M. Poteshman, and M. S. Weisbach. 2005. Horse and Rabbits? Optimal Dynamic
Capital Structure from Shareholder and Manager Perspectives. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis
40:259-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e815a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e819" publication-type="other">
Kim, E. H. 1989. Optimal Capital Structure in Miller's Equilibrium. In S. Bhattacharya and G. Constantinides
(eds.), Financial Markets and Incomplete Information: Frontiers of Financial Theory, vol. 2, pp. 36-48. Totowa,
NJ: Rowman and Littlefield.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e832a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e836" publication-type="other">
Kou, S. G. 2002. A Jump-Diffusion Model for Option Pricing. Management Science 48:1086-101.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e843a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e847" publication-type="other">
Kou, S. G., and H. Wang. 2004. Option Pricing under a Double Exponential Jump Diffusion Model. Management
Science 50:1 178-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e857a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e861" publication-type="other">
Kurshev, Α., and I. A. Strebulaev. 2007. Firm Size and Capital Structure. Working Paper, Stanford Graduate
School of Business.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e872a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e876" publication-type="other">
Leland, Η. Ε. 1994. Corporate Debt Value, Bond Covenants, and Optimal Capital Structure. Journal of Finance
49:1213-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e886a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e890" publication-type="other">
Leland, H. E. 1998. Agency Costs, Risk Management, and Capital Structure. Journal of Finance 53:1213-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e897a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e901" publication-type="other">
Mauer, D. C, and A. J. Triantis. 1994. Interactions of Corporate Financing and Investment Decisions: A
Dynamic Framework. Journal of Finance 49: 1253-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e911a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e915" publication-type="other">
Merton, R. C. 1976. Option Pricing When Underlying Stock Returns Are Discontinuous. Journal of Financial
Economics 3:125-44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e925a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e929" publication-type="other">
Morellec, E. 2001. Asset Liquidity, Capital Structure, and Secured Debt. Journal of Financial Economics
61:173-206.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e939a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e943" publication-type="other">
Morellec, E. 2004. Can Managerial Discretion Explain Observed Leverage Ratios? Review of Financial Studies
Π -.251-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e954a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e958" publication-type="other">
Neider, J. Α., and R. Mead. 1967. A Simplex Method for Function Minimization. Computer Journal 7:308-13.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e965a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e969" publication-type="other">
Pulvino, T. C. 1998. Do Asset Fire Sales Exist? An Empirical Investigation of Commercial Aircraft Transactions.
Journal of Finance 53:939-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e979a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e983" publication-type="other">
Rajan, R. G., and L. Zingales. 1995. What Do We Know about Capital Structure? Some Evidence from
International Data. Journal of Finance 50:1421-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e993a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e997" publication-type="other">
Sarkar, S., and F. Zapatero. 2003. The Trade-Off Model with Mean Reverting Earnings: Theory and Empirical
Tests. Economic Journal 1 13:834-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1007a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1011" publication-type="other">
Schaefer, S. M., and I. A. Strebulaev. 2008. Structural Models of Credit Risk Are Useful: Evidence from Hedge
Ratios on Corporate Bonds. Journal of Financial Economics 90: 1-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1021a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1025" publication-type="other">
Scholes, M., and M. Wolfson. 1992. Taxes and Business Strategy: A Planning Approach. Englewood Cliffs, NJ:
Prentice-Hall.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1036a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1040" publication-type="other">
Shreve, S. E. 2004. Stochastic Calculus for Finance II: Continuous-rime Models. New York: Springer Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1047a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1051" publication-type="other">
Strebulaev, I. A. 2007. Do Tests of Capital Structure Theory Mean What They Say? Journal of Finance
62:1747-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1061a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1065" publication-type="other">
Subramanian, A. 2008. Managerial Flexibility, Agency Costs and Optimal Capital Structure. Working Paper,
Georgia State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1075a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1079" publication-type="other">
Sundaresan, S. M., and N. Wang. 2007. Investment under Uncertainty with Strategic Debt Service. American
Economic Review 97:256-61 .</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1089a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1093" publication-type="other">
Weiss, L. A. 1990. Bankruptcy Resolution Direct Costs and Violations of Priority of Claims. Journal of
Financial Economics 27:285-314.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1103a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1107" publication-type="other">
Whited, Τ. Μ. 2006. External Finance Constraints and the Intertemporal Pattern of Intermittent Investment.
Journal of Financial Economics 81 :467-502.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1118a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1122" publication-type="other">
Zhdanov, A. 2008. Optimal Capital Structure in a Duopoly. Working Paper, Rochester University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


