<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000452</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40008417</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Automatic Acquisition of Semantic Collocation from Corpora</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Satoshi</given-names>
                  <surname>Sekine</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Jun-Ichi</given-names>
                  <surname>Tsujii</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1995</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>219</fpage>
         <lpage>258</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1995 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40008417"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>The real difficulty in developing practical NLP systems is due to the fact that we do not know in advance what actual "instances of knowledge" should be used in the application system, even though we know in advance what "types of knowledge" are required. An effective method for extracting linquistic knowledge from corpora is needed. We propose automatic linguistic knowledge acquisition from sublanguage corpora. The system combines existing linquistic knowledge and human intervention with corpus based techniques. The algorithm involves a "Gradual Approximation", which works to converge linguistic knowledge gradually towards desirable results. We conducted three experiments. The first experiment revealed the characteristic of this algorithm and the others proved the effectiveness of this algorithm for a real corpus. The results show the algorithm is promising, though there are some problems; the practical problem of the parameters, the formalism problems to include more linguistic features and the combination with other linguistic clues for more development. We would like to continue the research to perform further experiments and to improve the algorithm.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>knowledge acquisition</kwd>
            <kwd>linguistic knowledge</kwd>
            <kwd>corpus linguistic</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d2102684e138a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e142" publication-type="other">
M. R. Brent: Semantic Classification of Verbs from their Syntactic Contexts: An Implemented Clas-
sifier for stativity. Proceedings of the fifth conference of the European chapter of the Association
for Computational Linguistics, Berlin, 9-11 April 1991, pp. 222-226 (1991).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e155a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e159" publication-type="other">
M. R. Brent: Automatic acquisition of subcategorization frames from untagged text. 20th Conference
of ACL (1991).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e169a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e173" publication-type="other">
P. Brown, J. Cocke, S. Della Pietra, V. Della Pietra, F. Jelinek, R. Mercer, and P. Roossin: A statistical
approach to language translation. Proceedings of COLING, Budapest, 1988, pp. 71-76 (1988).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e183a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e187" publication-type="other">
Peter F. Brown, Stephen A. Dolla Pietra, Vincent J. Della Pietra, and Robert L. Mercer: A statistical
approach to machine translation. Computer Linguistics, 16(2) pp. 79-85 (1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e198a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e202" publication-type="other">
N. Calzolari: Lexical Database and a Lexical Knowledge Base. 1st International lexical Acquisition
Workshop, Detroit, Michigan (1989).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e212a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e216" publication-type="other">
N. Calzolari and R. Bindi: Acquisition of lexical information from a large textual Italian corpus.
Proceedings of the 13th International Conference on Computational Linguistics. Helsinki 1990,
vol. 3, pp. 54-59 (1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e229a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e233" publication-type="other">
K. Church: A stochastic parts programme and noun phrase parser for unrestricted text. Proceedings
of the second conference on applied natural language processing. Austin Texas, 9-7 February
1988, pp. 136-143 (1988).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e246a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e250" publication-type="other">
K. Church and P. Hanks: Word association norms, mutual information and lexicography. Proceedings
of the 27th annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics. Vancouver, 26-29
June, 1989, pp. 76-83 (1989). Computational Linguistics, 1989 vol. 16.1 (1989).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e263a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e267" publication-type="other">
K. Church, W. Gale, P. Hanks, and D. Hindle: Using statistics in Lexical Analysis. Lexical Acquisition
(edited by Uri Zernik) (1991).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e277a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e281" publication-type="other">
I. Dagan and I. Alon: Automatic processing of large corpora for resolution of anaphora reference.
Proceedings of the 13th International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Helsinki 1990,
vol. 3, pp. 330-332 (1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e295a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e299" publication-type="other">
I. Dagan, A. Itai and U. Schwall: Two languages are more informative than one. 29th ACL, Berkely,
pp. 130-137 (1991).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e309a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e313" publication-type="other">
L. Frazier: On comprehending sentences: Syntactic parsing strategies. PH.D. dissertation, University
of Connecticut (1978).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e323a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e327" publication-type="other">
S. J. DeRose: Grammatical Disambiguation by Statical Optimization. Computational Linguistics,
Vol. 14, No. 1 (1988).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e337a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e341" publication-type="other">
R. Gnanadesikan: Methods for statistical Data Analysis of Multivariate Observations (1977).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e348a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e352" publication-type="other">
R. Grishman, N. T. Nhan, and E. Marsh: Turning Natural Language Grammars for New Domains.
Conference on Intelligent Systems and machines, Rochester, Minnesota, pp. 342-346 (1984).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e362a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e366" publication-type="other">
Ralph Grishman, L. Hirschman, and N. T. Nhan: Discover Procedures for Sublanguage Selectional
Patterns: Initial Experiments, Comp. Linguistics Vol. 12, No. 3 (1986).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e377a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e381" publication-type="other">
M. Chitrao and R. Grishman: Statistical Parsing of Message. Proceedings of the June DARPA Speech
and Natural Language workshop. Hidden Valley, Pennsylvania (1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e391a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e395" publication-type="other">
D. Hindle: Acquiring disambiguation rules from text. Proceedings of the 27th annual meeting of the
Association for Computational Linguistics. Vancouver, 26-29 June 1989, pp. 118-125 (1989).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e405a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e409" publication-type="other">
D. Hindle: Structural Ambiguity and Lexical Relations. Proceedings of the June DARPA Speech and
Natural Language workshop. Hidden Valley, Pennsylvania (1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e419a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e423" publication-type="other">
D. Hindle and M. Rooth: Noun classification from predicative argument structures. 28th Conference
of the A.C.L. pp. 268-275 (1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e433a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e437" publication-type="other">
D. Hindle and M. Rooth: Structural Ambiguity and Lexical Relations. 29th Conference of the A.C.L.
(1991).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e447a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e451" publication-type="other">
J. Kimball: Seven principles of surface structure parsing in natural language, Cognition 2 (1973).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e459a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e463" publication-type="other">
R. Kittredge and L. Hirschman: Sublanguage: Studies of Language in Restricted Semantic domains.
Series of Foundations of Communications, Walter de Gruyter, Berlin (1983).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e473a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e477" publication-type="other">
C. Leech, R. Garside, and E. Atwell: The Automatic Grammatical Tagging of the LOB Corpus.
ICAME News 7, pp. 13-33 (1983).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e487a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e491" publication-type="other">
G. Leech, R. Garside and G. Sampson: The computational analysis of English; A corpus based
approach. London, Longman (1987).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e501a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e505" publication-type="other">
M. Marcus: Tutorial on Tagging and Processing Large Textual Corpora. Presented 28th annual
meeting of the ACL (1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e515a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e519" publication-type="other">
E. Brill, D. Magerman, M. Marcus and B. Santorini: Deducting Linguistic Structure from the statistics
of Large Corpora. Proceedings of the June DARPA Speech and Natural Language workshop.
Hidden Valley, Pennsylvania (1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e532a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e536" publication-type="other">
David M. Margerman and Mitchell P. Marcus: Pearl: A Probabilistic Chart Parser. 5th Conference of
the E.A.C.L. (1991).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e547a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e551" publication-type="other">
S. Sekine, J. J. Carroll, S. Ananiadou and J. Tsujii: Automatic Learning for Semantic Collocation.
3rd Conference on Applied Natural Language Processing (1992).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e561a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e565" publication-type="other">
S. Sekine, S. Ananiadou, J. J. Carroll and J. Tsujii: Linguistic Knowledge Generator. Proceedings of
the 14th COLING, Nante, July 1992 (1992).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e575a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e579" publication-type="other">
F. Smadja: Lexical Co-occurrence, The missing Link in Language Acquisition. Program and abstracts
of the 15th International ALLC, conference of the Association for Literary and Linguistic com-
puting, Jerusalem, Israel (1988).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e592a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e596" publication-type="other">
F. Smadja and K. McKeown: Automatically Extracting and Representing Collocations for language
generation. 28th Conference of the A.C.L. (1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e606a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e610" publication-type="other">
F. Smadja: From N-Grams to Collocations an Evaluation of XTRACT. 29th Conference of the A.C.L.
(1991).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e620a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e624" publication-type="other">
F. Smadja: Marcro coding the lexicon with co-occurrence knowledge. Lexical Acquisition (edited by
Uri Zernik) (1991).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e635a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e639" publication-type="other">
J. Tsujii, J. Carroll and S. Ananiadou: Methodologies for Development of Sublanguage MT System.
CCL/UMIST Report, No. 90/10 (1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e649a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e653" publication-type="other">
J. Tsujii, S. Ananiadou, J. Carroll and S. Sekine: Methodologies for Development of Sublanguage
MT System II. CCL/UMIST Report, No. 91/11 (1991).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e663a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e667" publication-type="other">
J. Tsujii, S. Ananiadou, I. Arad and S. Sekine: Linguistic Knowledge Acquisition from Corpora.
International workshop on Fundamental research for the Future Generation of natural Language
Processing (UMIST) (1992).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e680a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e684" publication-type="other">
T. Utsuro, Y. Matsumota and M. Nagao: Lexical Knowledge Acquisition from Bilingual Corpora.
COLING-92 (1992).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e694a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e698" publication-type="other">
Uri Zernik: Paradigms in lexical acquisition. First International Lexical Acquisition Workshop,
Detroit, Michigan (1989).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e708a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e712" publication-type="other">
Uri Zernik: Lexical acquisition: Learning from corpus by capitalizing on lexical categories. Eleventh
International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, Detroit, Michigan (1989).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e723a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e727" publication-type="other">
Uri Zernik and Paul Jacobs: Tagging for Learning: Collecting Thematic Relations from Corpus. 13th
COLING-90 (1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e737a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e741" publication-type="other">
Uri Zernik (ed.): Introduction and Tagging Word Sense In Corpus, lexical Acquisition: Using on-line
resources to build a lexicon. Lawrence Erlbaum (1991).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e751a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e755" publication-type="other">
Yorick Wilks, Right Attachment and Preference Semantics. 2nd Conference of the European Chapter
of the A.C.L. (1985).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e765a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e769" publication-type="other">
A. Zampolli: Reusable Linguistic Resources (Invited paper). 5th Conference of the E.A.C.L. (1991).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e776a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e780" publication-type="other">
G. Zipf: Human behaviour and the principle of least effort. Addison-Wesley (1949).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102684e787a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102684e791" publication-type="other">
G. Ziph: The psycho-biology of language: An introduction to dynamic philology. MIT Press (1965).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
