<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i25829915</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25829919</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>LE ROLE DU FMI EN AFRIQUE / THE ROLE OF THE IMF IN AFRICA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Omrana</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1985</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>143</fpage>
         <lpage>173</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25829919"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Economic and social disequilibria together with the crisis experienced by most African countries have been partly caused by economic policy mistakes and structural rigidities compounded by natural disasters. But, the author has particularly emphasized external factors as the main causes of the economic and financial problems of African countries. These problems have been mostly transmitted through foreign demand for exports which has been particularly affected by the drastic drop in the growth of GDP and world trade, by the record levels of inflation, by the collaps of the fixed exchange rate system and by the oil shocks. In this international context, African countries have been particularly affected by the following four major problems analyzed in the paper: (i) deterioration in the terms of trade; (ii) exchange rate fluctuations; (iii) deterioration in foreign payments; and (iv) higher external debt. In fact, it is due to their debt level (in relation to GDP and exports) and structure that African countries were compelled to adopt adjustment measures and have come to perceive funding as part of the adjustment process. Hence the role played by the IMF as a supplier of financial resources to support policies designed and applied within adequate adjustment programmes. It appears that easy foreign financing tends to hide actual economic problems while disequilibria are worsening, thus delaying adjustment measures which become more difficult to apply. The IMF intervenes in a situation which is mostly characterized by the following economic policies: (a) price controls; (b) administrative control of imported goods; (c) subsidization of basic commodity consumption; (d) non remunerative producer prices; (e) overvalued exchange rates; and (f) unbearable budget, public sector and external account deficits. The objectives of IMF programmes in Africa have been clearly presented. They mostly relate to achieving reasonable growth raies, to curbing inflation and to restoring equilibria. The means of action are to be found on both the demand side (financial and monetary measures) and the supply side (exchange rate, interest rate, pricing policy, etc...). IMF programmes have yielded mixed results and the explanations supplied by the Fund in this respect have met reservation from African countries which have emphasized other factors, i.e.: (1) exogenous factors, (2) conditionality, (3) insufficient mobilized resources and inadequacy between loan maturities and terms, and (4) analytical and policy approach underlying the adjustment programme and which underestimates socio-economic conditions in the African environment. A confrontation of arguments generally made by recipient countries and those by IMF officials reveals that economic and social situations are not similar and that any generalization would be misleading. Furthermore, it should be noted that opposition to Fund policies actually means opposition to change, as the latter concerns the basis of African countries' policies and, as such, is perceived as interference with their freedom (and sovereignty). In the light of mounting difficulties and lack of short-terms alternatives, African countries are becoming increasingly sensitive to the Fund's arguments but they consider that the adjustment cost will be all the more reduced since the Fund is more generous in extending its assistance and since it agrees to regard African countries as a specific case. The Fund's recognition of specific African economic problems and the increase in the size of its financial assistance raise the difficult issue of the reform of the international monetary system, of which the IMF is both the tool and expression. Admitting that African countries have specific problems is tantamount to accenting integrate the reform of the system into a reform of international trade and financial relations. It also means acknowledging that there are real problems in the size and distribution of international liquidity. And, it finally means realizing that control of the institution and voting power are questions that cannot be avoided forever in the operation of the Fund.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>fre</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1e254a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e261" publication-type="other">
Rapport sur le septieme congres mondial de I'Association economique internationale, p. 5, document
CAEM.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e271a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e278" publication-type="other">
document UNCTAD/CA/288, juin 1983 prepare a I'intention de la Huitieme Reunion Ordinaire de I'AB-
CA, en particulier pp. IV-VI, 15-22.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e288a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e297" publication-type="other">
Document N. 9.343.07 (a) CEA, Addis-Abeba.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e304a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e311" publication-type="other">
* Adjustment Programme in Africa: the recent experience, 1980-1981 ». DM 83, prepared by J.B. Zulu and
S.M. Nsouli.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e322a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e329" publication-type="other">
Bahram Nowzad, « The IMF and its critics », article publie dans la collection « Essays in International
Finance », n. 146, revue de I'Universite de Princeton.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e339a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e346" publication-type="other">
« The Fund in Africa », par Paul A. Acquah, FMI, Seminaire organise conjointement par le FMI et la Banque
Centrale du Kenya sur le theme: « Le FMI et les pays en voie de developpement», Mars 1982.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e356a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e363" publication-type="other">
« The changing role of the Fund in the IMS », par Azizali F. Mohammed, FMI, Seminaire, Mars 1982.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e370a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e377" publication-type="other">
« Fund Programs and Economic Adjustment » par S. Kanesa-Thesan, ibid., S6minaire, Mars 1982.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e384a1310">
            <label>12- bis</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e391" publication-type="other">
« The balance of payments adjustment in developing countries », par Sidney Dell et Roger Lawrence,
Pergamon Press.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
  </back>
</article>


