<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440295</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Building Trust? Conditional Cash Transfer Programmes and Social Capital</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Orazio</given-names>
                  <surname>Attanasio</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Luca</given-names>
                  <surname>Pellerano</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Sandra Polanía</given-names>
                  <surname>Reyes</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">30</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440093</issue-id>
         <fpage>139</fpage>
         <lpage>177</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2009</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440295"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>In this paper, we propose a measure of social capital based on behaviour in a public goods game. We conducted a public goods game within 28 groups in two similar neighbourhoods in Cartagena, Colombia, one of which had been targeted for over two years by a conditional cash transfer programme that has an important social component. The level of cooperation we observe in the 'treatment' community is considerably higher than that in the 'control' community. The two neighbourhoods, however, although similar in many dimensions, turn out to be significantly different in other observable variables. The result we obtain in terms of cooperation, however, is robust to controls for these observable differences. We also compare our measure of social capital with other more traditional measures that have been used in the literature.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d8e266a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e273" publication-type="other">
Submitted March 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e280a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e287" publication-type="other">
See Rawlings and Rubio (2003) and Fiszbein and Schady (2009) for a comprehensive review.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e294a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e301" publication-type="other">
However, several studies have identified useful proxies for social capital, using different types and
combinations of qualitative, comparative and quantitative research methodologies (see Woolcock and
Narayan (2000)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e314a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e321" publication-type="other">
For instance, in the case of PROGRESA, see Adato (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e329a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e336" publication-type="other">
Although Pellerano (2009) looks at evidence from Colombia on the impact of CCT programmes on
social participation and membership of civic organisations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e346a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e353" publication-type="other">
See, for instance, Karlan (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e360a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e367" publication-type="other">
See, for instance, Durlauf and Fafchamps (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e374a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e381" publication-type="other">
Specifically, the World Bank promotes the Social Capital Assessment Tool (SOCAT) and the Social
Capital Integrated Questionnaire (SC-IQ). Information on these instruments can be found at
http://web.worldbank.org/WBSITE/EXTERNAL/TOPICS/EXTSOCIALDEVELOPMENT/EXTTSOCIA
LCAPITAL/0„contentMDK:20193059~menuPK:418220-pagePK: 148956~piPK:216618~theSitePK:401
015,00.html.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e400a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e407" publication-type="other">
See Cardenas and Jaramillo (2007) and Inter-American Development Bank (2007).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e414a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e423" publication-type="other">
Some of these initiatives have been performed by the Centre for the Evaluation of Development
Policies (EDePo) and its Colombian partners in collaboration with Abigail Barr from the University of
Oxford and Juan Camilo Cardenas from the Universidad de los Andes in Bogota. Their help and support
have been invaluable. We have experimented with risk-pooling games, trust games and public goods
games, and we have combined the information from these games with information collected in detailed
surveys.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e447a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e454" publication-type="other">
Many of the VCMs reported in the literature afford the possibility of investing a fraction of the initial
endowment, while our game forces a 0/1 choice, making the explanation much simpler. In the literature,
average contributions to the public good are in a range of 40 to 60 per cent of the group optimum
(Ledyard, 1995; Camerer and Fehr, 2003; Cardenas and Carpenter, 2008). For a detailed survey of these
results, see in addition Croson (2007).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e473a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e480" publication-type="other">
Defined by Carpenter and Matthews (2004) as 'the act of demonstrating one's disapproval, at some
personal cost, for the violation of widely-held norms (e.g., don't free ride)'. Cardenas and Jaramillo
(2007) defined it as 'a predisposition of the network members to cooperate and to punish those who don't,
even at a personal cost' or 'the trust endowment of the social network'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e496a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e503" publication-type="other">
See Attanasio et al. (in progress).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e510a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e517" publication-type="other">
In Colombia, most welfare programmes are targeted using the so-called Sisben score, a poverty
indicator which is updated periodically. On the basis of this score, households are assigned to one of six
categories. Familias enAcciôn targets level 1 of Sisben, which is the poorest category.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e530a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e537" publication-type="other">
For additional information on the Encuentros de Cuidado, see Acciôn Social (2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e544a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e551" publication-type="other">
For additional information about the instruments, see the online appendix published at http://
www.ifs.org.uk/docs/app_vcm_intstruments.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e562a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e569" publication-type="other">
See Cardenas and Carpenter (2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e576a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e583" publication-type="other">
Unfortunately, we did not have this number of players in 14 sessions because some subjects failed to
show up. However, the average session size was 24 people and there was no significant difference in
session size between the control and target neighbourhoods.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e596a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e603" publication-type="other">
Units in thousands; thus $5 means COL$5,000 (US$2.56, according to the official exchange rate at
that date TRM: US$l=COL$ 1,951.84 (monthly mean average for July 2007, http://www.banrep.gov.co)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e613a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e620" publication-type="other">
According to administrative data, about 50 per cent of mothers do not attend the Encuentros de
Cuidado. This pattern could be explained by the fact that the programme's officials helped us in the
recruitment process and mothers might have been afraid of the consequences of saying in the survey that
they do not attend.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e636a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e643" publication-type="other">
20A referee suggested asking the subjects about their acquaintances' trustworthiness. This information
would have given us a more accurate measure of social capital. There were two reasons we only obtained
a measure for connectivity. First, we replicated the same experimental and survey design that was
conducted in the FA's first and second follow-up evaluations in rural areas. Second, we were constrained
by time logistics. Flowever, we will consider collecting a trustworthiness measure in future studies.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e662a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e669" publication-type="other">
Cârdenas and Jaramillo (2007) applied a similar design with larger groups and found evidence that
the players infer from their immediate neighbourhood information about the global features of the
network.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e683a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e692" publication-type="other">
As mentioned in footnote 10, a direct comparison with many of the games reported in the literature is
problematic, as in most of them participants are allowed to contribute a fraction of their endowment to the
public good while we impose an all-or-nothing choice. However, reported average contributions range
from 23 per cent of endowment in Peru (Henrich and Smith, 2004) to 37 per cent in the US (Harrison and
List, 2004), 52 per cent in Russia (Gächter, Herrmann and Thöni, 2004), 53 per cent in Zimbabwe (Barr
and Kinsey, 2002) and 58 per cent in Kenya (Ensminger, 2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e715a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e722" publication-type="other">
This result may be due to the fact that in El Pozon, it is easier to contact displaced people through FA
operational networks, as they are beneficiaries of the programme. In Ciénaga, this population may be
more difficult to recruit because they are usually socially isolated.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e735a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e742" publication-type="other">
Specifically, in order to control for contiguous sessions correlation, we include in specification 3 a
dummy for the first session each day and a variable capturing the mean of the previous two sessions'
deviations from the neighbourhood average contribution to the public account in Round 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e755a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e762" publication-type="other">
However, we report that experimenter 3 was the only man in the team and he only conducted
sessions in El Pozön. The other two experimenters performed experiments in both El Pozön and Ciénaga.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e772a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e779" publication-type="other">
We represent group heterogeneity by the standard deviations of selected characteristics in each
session. In addition to these variables that reflect heterogeneity, we also control for the average level of
education in the session.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e792a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e799" publication-type="other">
We also include the average level of cooperation in the first round. While players do not know how
many players contributed to the public good in the first round, they may learn about others' behaviour
during the time for communication. As it turns out, this variable is not significantly different from zero
and its exclusion does not change the results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e816a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e823" publication-type="other">
A worrying feature of our data is that our subjects are more likely to be interacting in the same
session with their relatives in Ciénaga than in El Pozon. It is difficult to imagine that the programme
directly affects this indicator. Hence one hypothesis here is that the game recruitment process in Ciénaga
exploited to a greater extent existing family networks. Of course, the presence of relatives can determine
the individual's behaviour in the VCM game. Given the very small number of relatives in our sample, our
results do not change if we add this variable to the list of session control variables that we used for the
models presented in Section V.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e849a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e856" publication-type="other">
Although these differences are not significant in levels, they become so after conditioning for
participation in at least one organisation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e866a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e873" publication-type="other">
See Pellerano (2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e880a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e887" publication-type="other">
For these indicators, we ask the subjects: 'Do you attend the meetings? Do you participate in the
decision processes? Are you one of the leaders in the group? 'Do you support the group with money or
voluntary work? And usually, how many hours per month do you spend attending this group?'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e900a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e907" publication-type="other">
We asked about the last local elections in Cartagena (Gobernador, mayor, members of the Asambleas
Departamentales, Concejos Municipales and Juntas Administradoras Locales). They were held 7 months
after the start of the programme and 4 months before the beginning of the programme in El Pozôn. We
also asked about the presidential elections, which were held 11 months after the beginning of the
programme in El Pozön.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e926a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e933" publication-type="other">
The same controls as those in specification 3 in Table 3 and in specification 6 in Table 4 are used
respectively for Round 1 and for Round 2.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e944a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e951" publication-type="other">
0n average, the index has a value of 0.38, which means that 38 per cent of the one-to-one
relationships in the group happen between relatives, friends or acquaintances.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d8e970a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e974" publication-type="other">
Acciön Social (2003), Los Encuentros de Cuidado: Promotion de la Education y la Salud
Familiar (Childcare meetings: promotion of education and family health), Presidencia de
la Repüblica, Fondo de Inversion para la Paz (FIP), Programa de Familias en Acciôn,
Bogota DC, http://www.accionsocial.gov.co/documentos/l 69_Encuentros_de_cuidado.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e990a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e994" publication-type="other">
Adato, M. (2000), The Impact of PROGRESA on Community Social Relationships,
Washington, DC: International Food Policy Research Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1004a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1008" publication-type="other">
Anderson, L., Mellor, J. and Milyo, J. (2004), 'Social capital and contributions in a public-
goods experiment', American Economic Review Papers and Proceedings, vol. 94, pp.
373-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1021a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1025" publication-type="other">
Andreoni, J. (1988), 'Why free ride? Strategies and learning in public goods experiments',
Journal of Public Economics, vol. 37, pp. 291-304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1036a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1040" publication-type="other">
— (1995), 'Cooperation in public-goods experiments: kindness or confusion?', American
Economic Review, vol. 85, pp. 891-904.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1050a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1054" publication-type="other">
Attanasio, O., Battistin, E., Fitzsimons, E., Mesnard, A. and Vera-Hernândez, M. (2005), How
Effective Are Conditional Cash Transfers? Evidence from Colombia, IFS Briefing Note
no. 54 (http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/3214).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1067a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1071" publication-type="other">
—, Choi, S., Pellerano, L. and Polania Reyes, S. (in progress), 'Social capital as coordination
in a multiple equilibria setting: evidence from a field experiment in Colombia', Institute
for Fiscal Studies and University College London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1084a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1088" publication-type="other">
— and Phillips, D. (in progress), 'Playing fair? Using experimental games to investigate
social capital in rural Colombia', Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1098a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1102" publication-type="other">
Barr, A. and Kinsey, B. (2002), 'Do men really have no shame?', Center for the Study of
African Economies, Working Paper no. 164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1112a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1116" publication-type="other">
Bochet, O., Page, T. and Putterman, L. (2006), 'Communication and punishment in voluntary
contribution experiments', Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization, vol. 60, pp.
11-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1130a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1134" publication-type="other">
Bowles, S. and Gintis, H. (2004), 'The evolution of strong reciprocity: cooperation in
heterogeneous groups', Theoretical Population Biology, vol. 65, pp. 17-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1144a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1148" publication-type="other">
Camerer, C. and Fehr, E. (2003), 'Measuring social norms and preferences using experimental
games: a guide for social scientists', Institute for Empirical Research in Economics
(IEW), Working Paper no. 97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1161a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1165" publication-type="other">
Cardenas, J. C. (2003), 'Real wealth and experimental cooperation: experiments in the field
lab', Journal of Development Economics, vol. 70, pp. 263-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1175a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1179" publication-type="other">
— and Carpenter, J. (2008), 'Behavioural development economics: lessons from field labs in
the developing world', Journal of Development Studies, vol. 44, pp. 311-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1189a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1193" publication-type="other">
— and Jaramillo, C. (2007), 'Cooperation in large networks: an experimental approach",
Universidad de los Andes, Documentos CEDE no. 2007-06.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1203a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1207" publication-type="other">
— and Ostrom, E. (2004), 'What do people bring into the game? Experiments in the field
about cooperation in the commons', Agricultural Systems, vol. 82, pp. 307-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1218a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1222" publication-type="other">
Carpenter, J. and Matthews, P. (2004), 'Social reciprocity', Institute for the Study of Labor
(IZA), Discussion Paper no. 1347.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1232a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1236" publication-type="other">
Croson, R. (2007), 'Theories of commitment, altruism and reciprocity: evidence from linear
public goods games', Economic Inquiry, vol. 45, pp. 199-216.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1246a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1250" publication-type="other">
Durlauf, S. and Fafchamps, M. (2005), 'Social capital', in P. Aghion and S. N. Durlauf (eds),
Handbook of Economic Growth, vol. 1B, Amsterdam: Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1260a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1264" publication-type="other">
Ensminger, J. (2000), 'Experimental economics in the bush: why institutions matter', in C.
Menard (ed.), Institutions, Contracts, and Organizations: Perspectives from New
Institutional Economics, London: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1277a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1281" publication-type="other">
Fischbacher, U. and Gächter, S. (2009), 'Social preferences, beliefs, and the dynamics of free
riding in public good experiments', Centre for Decision Research and Experimental
Economics (CeDEx), Discussion Paper no. 2009-04.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1294a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1298" publication-type="other">
—, — and Fehr, E. (2001), 'Are people conditionally cooperative? Evidence from a public
goods experiment', Economics Letters, vol. 71, pp. 397 404.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1309a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1313" publication-type="other">
Fiszbein, A. and Schady, N. (2009), Conditional Cash Transfers: Reducing Present and
Future Poverty, Washington, DC: World Bank.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1323a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1327" publication-type="other">
Gächter, S., Herrmann, B. and Thöni, C. (2004), 'Trust, voluntary cooperation, and socio-
economic background: survey and experimental evidence', Journal of Economic Behavior
&amp; Organization, vol. 55, pp. 505-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1340a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1344" publication-type="other">
Glaeser, E. L., Laibson, D. I., Scheinkman, J. A. and Soutter, C. L. (2000), 'Measuring trust',
Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 115, pp. 81 \-A6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1354a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1358" publication-type="other">
Gunnthorsdottir, A., Houser, D. and McCabe, K. (2007), 'Disposition, history and
contributions in public goods experiments', Journal of Economic Behavior &amp;
Organization, vol. 62, pp. 304-15.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1371a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1375" publication-type="other">
Harrison, G. and List, J. (2004), 'Field experiments', Journal of Economic Literature, vol. 42,
pp. 1009-55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1385a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1389" publication-type="other">
Henrich, J. and Smith, N. (2004), 'Comparative experimental evidence from Machiguenga,
Mapuche, Huinca and American populations', in J. Henrich, R. Boyd, S. Bowles, C.
Camerer, E. Fehr and H. Gintis (eds), Foundations of Human Sociality: Economic
Experiments and Ethnographic Evidence from Fifteen Small-Scale Societies, Oxford:
Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1409a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1413" publication-type="other">
Inter-American Development Bank (2007), Outsiders? The Changing Patterns of Exclusion in
Latin America and the Caribbean, G. Marquez, A. Chong, S. Duryea, J. Mazza and H.
Nopo (coordinators), Washington, DC: IADB.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1426a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1430" publication-type="other">
Isaac, M. and Walker, J. (1988a), 'Communication and free-riding behavior: the voluntary
contribution mechanism', Economic Inquiry, vol. 26, pp. 585-608.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1440a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1444" publication-type="other">
— and — (1988b), 'Group size effects in public goods provision: the voluntary contributions
mechanism', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 103, pp. 179-99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1454a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1458" publication-type="other">
Karlan, D. (2005), 'Using experimental economics to measure social capital and predict
financial decisions', American Economic Review, vol. 95, pp. 1688-99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1468a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1472" publication-type="other">
Kurzban, R., McCabe, K., Smith, V. and Wilson, B. (2001), 'Incremental commitment and
reciprocity in a real time public goods game', Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin,
vol. 27, pp. 1662-73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1485a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1489" publication-type="other">
Ledyard, J. (1995), 'Public goods: a survey of experimental research', in J. H. Kagel and A.
E. Roth (eds), The Handbook of Experimental Economics, Princeton, NJ: Princeton
University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1503a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1507" publication-type="other">
Marwell, G. and Ames, R. (1979), 'Experiments on the provision of public goods I: resources,
interest, group size, and the free rider problem', American Journal of Sociology, vol. 84,
pp. 1335-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1520a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1524" publication-type="other">
Messick, D. M. and Brewer, M. B. (1983), 'Solving social dilemmas', in L. Wheeler and P. R.
Shaver (eds), Review of Personality and Social Psychology, vol. 4, pp. 11^14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1534a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1538" publication-type="other">
Pellerano, L. (2009), 'Assessing the impact of conditional cash transfer programmes on social
participation: evidence from Colombia', Institute for Fiscal Studies, Working Paper,
forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1551a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1555" publication-type="other">
Putnam, R. D., Leonardi, R. and Nanetti, R. Y. (1993), Making Democracy Work, Princeton,
NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1565a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1569" publication-type="other">
Rabin, M. (1993), 'Incorporating fairness into game theory and economics', American
Economic Review, vol. 83, pp. 1281-302.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1579a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1583" publication-type="other">
Rawlings, L. and Rubio, G. (2003), 'Evaluating the impact of conditional cash transfer
programs: lessons from Latin America', World Bank, Policy Research Working Paper no.
3119.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1597a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1601" publication-type="other">
Robison, L. and Siles, M. (2002), 'The use of social capital for development and poverty
reduction', Social Development Strategy, World Bank.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1611a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1615" publication-type="other">
Skoufias, E. (2005), PROGRESA and Its Impacts on the Welfare of Rural Households in
Mexico, IFPRI Research Report no. 139, Washington, DC: International Food Policy
Research Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1628a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1632" publication-type="other">
Woolcock, M. and Narayan, D. (2000), 'Social capital: implications for development theory,
research, and policy', World Bank Research Observer, vol. 15, pp. 225—49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
