<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308407</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Fast Oxygen Based Transient Diesel Engine Operation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Alberer</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>del Re</surname>
                  <given-names>Luigi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Institute for Design and Control of Mechatronical Systems, Johannes Kepler University Linz</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>405</fpage>
         <lpage>413</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308407"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Due to the advancements in passenger car Diesel engine design, the contribution of transient emission spikes has become an important fraction of the total emissions during the standardized test cycles, hence the interest of this work on dynamical engine operation, in particular on the improvement of NOₓ and PM emissions. This paper proposes to use a UEGO sensor (universal exhaust gas oxygen sensor) in the upstream of the turbine in combination with a Kalman filter to estimate the target quantities, namely in-cylinder oxygen concentration before and after combustion. This information is used to define the fuel injection as well as the values of the air path actuators. Test bench measurements with a production Diesel engine are presented, where the oxygen based approach is compared to the standard calibration during a fast load increase. It is shown that the torque response could be maintained while NOₓ as well as PM emission peaks were reduced significantly.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Nieuwstadt, M.J., Kolmanovsky, I.V., Moraal, P.E., Stefanopoulou, A. and Jankovic, M. (2000). EGR-VGT control schemes: experimental comparison for a high-speed diesel engine. Control Systems Magazine IEEE, 20(3): p. 63-79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, S. Kevin and Yanakiev, Ognyan, Transient NOx Emission Reduction Using Exhaust Oxygen Concentration Based Control for a Diesel Engine. SAE World Congress, Detroit, MI, USA, 2005-01- 0372, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Langthaler, P. and del Re, L, Fast Predictive Oxygen Charge Control of a Diesel Engine. 2007 American Control Conference, New York City, USA, FrA06.1, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakayama, Shigeki, Fukuma, Takao, Matsunaga, Akio, Miyake, Teruhiko and Wakimoto, Toru, A New Dynamic Combustion Control Method Based on Charge Oxygen Concentration for Diesel Engines. SAE World Congress, Detroit, MI, USA, 2003-01- 3181, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakayama, S., Ibuki, T., Hosaki, H. and Tominaga, H., "An Application of Model Based Combustion Control to Transient Cycle-by-Cycle Diesel Combustion" SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):850-860, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amstutz, Alois and del Re, Luigi (1995). EGO sensor based robust output control of EGR in diesel engines. IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, 3(1): p. 39-48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chauvin, Jonathan, Moulin, Philippe, Corde, Gilles, Petit, Nicolas and Rouchon, Pierre, Real-Time nonlinear individual Cylinder Air Fuel Ratio Observer on a Diesel Engine Testbench. in IFAC World Congress. 2005. Prague, Czech Republic.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grizzle, J.W., Dobbins, K.L. and Cook, J.A. (1991). Individual cylinder air-fuel ratio control with a single EGO sensor. Vehicular Technology, IEEE Transactions on Control, 40(1 Part 2): p. 280-286.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cavina, Nicolò, Corti, Enrico and Moro, Davide, Closed-loop Individual Cylinder Air-Fuel Ratio Control via UEGO Signal Spectral Analysis. IFAC World Congress, Seoul, Korea, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Nieuwstadt, M J, Moraal, P. E, Kolmanovsky, I. V, Stefanopoulou, A, Wood, P. and Criddle, M Decentralized and Multivariable Designs for EGRVGT Control of a Diesel Engine. IFAC Workshop on Advances in Automotive Control, Mohican State Park, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stefanopoulou, Anna G. , Kolmanovsky, Ilya and Freudenberg, James S. (2000). Control of variable geometry turbocharged diesel engines for reduced emissions. IEEE-Transactions-on-Control-Systems- Technology, 8(4): p. 733-745.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jung, Merten, Mean-Value Modelling and Robust Control of the Airpath of a Turbocharged Diesel Engine. Department of Engineering, Cambridge, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ortner, Peter and del Re, Luigi (2007). Predictive Multivariable Control of a Diesel Engine Air Path. IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology (Control Applications in Automotive Engineering).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Langthaler, Peter, Model Predictive Control of a Diesel Engine Airpath. Institute for Design and Control of Mechatronical Systems, Linz, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alberer, Daniel, Ranzmaier, Martin, del Re, Luigi and Huschenbett, Matthias, MIMO Model Predictive Control for Integral Gas Engines under Switching Disturbances. 17th IEEE International Conference on Control Applications, San Antonio, Texas, USA, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alberer, Daniel, del Re, Luigi, Winkler, Stephan and Langthaler, Peter, Virtual Sensor Design of Particulate and Nitric Oxide Emissions in a DI Diesel Engine. ICE 2005, 7th International Conference on Engines for Automobile, Capri, Italy, 2005-24-063, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bertola, Andrea G., Technologies for Lowest NOx and Particulate Emissions in DI-Diesel Engine Combustion - Influence of Injection Parameters, EGR and Fuel Composition. 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schubiger, Raffael, Boulouchos, Konstantinos and Eberle, Meinrad K. (2002). Rußbildung und Oxidation bei der dieselmotorischen Verbrennung. MTZ, 63(5): p. 342-353.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gärtner, Uwe, Die Simulation der Stickoxid-Bildung in Nutzfahrzeug-Dieselmotoren. 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">del Re, Luigi, Langthaler, Peter, Furtmüller, Christian, Winkler, Stephan and Affenzeller, Michael (2005). NOx Virtual Sensor Based on Structure Identification and Global Optimization. SAE 2005 Transaction Journal of Engines.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Riegel, H. Neumann, H.-M. Wiedenmann (2002). Exhaust gas sensors for automotive emission control. Solid State Ionics, 152-153: p. 783-800.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bosch, Technical Customer Information LSU 4.2. 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bosch, Technical Product Information LSU 4.9. 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalman, R. E. (1960). A New Approach to Linear Filtering and Prediction Problems. Transactions of the ASME–Journal of Basic Engineering, 82 (Series D): p. 35-45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
