<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939433</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Infrastructure and Local Debt</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>TAX EXEMPTION OF STATE AND LOCAL DEBT</article-title>
            <subtitle>WHO BENEFITS?</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Riegel</surname>
                  <given-names>Konul Amrahova</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>38</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939433"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The longstanding “muni puzzle” is a controversial empirical finding that the tax exemption of interest income on debt issued by state and local governments beneats investors more than the issuers. In this study, I provide a new approach to measuring interest savings associated with issuing tax-exempt municipal bonds (munis) and present empirical evidence dismantling the puzzle. I show that the tax policy is effective and consistent with theory, after accounting for idiosyncratic issuer risk and investor preference. I match tax-exempt munis to near-identical taxable munis issued by the same government at the same time with the same security characteristics to identify the slope of and the trend in implied marginal tax rates. Results of the random coefficients model, which mitigates issuer- and issuance-level unobserved effects, predict the slope of the marginal tax rate to be consistent with asset pricing theory and the tax proale of the typical muni investor. Findings imply heterogeneity in implied marginal tax rates across issuers due to variations in idiosyncratic risks as well as cyclicality over time.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Alexander, G. J., A. K. Edwards, and M. G. Ferri (2000). The determinants of trading volume of high-yield corporate bonds. Journal of Financial Markets 3, 177{204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Ang, A., V. Bhansali, and Y. H. Xing (2010). Taxes on tax-exempt bonds. Journal of Finance 65 (2), 565{601.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Atwood, T. (2003). Implicit taxes: Evidence from taxable, amt, and tax-exempt state and local government bond yields. The Journal of the American Taxation Associa- tion 25 (1), 1{20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Auerbach, A. J. and M. A. King (1983). Taxation, portfolio choice and debt-equity ratios: A general equilibrium model. Quarterly Journal of Economics 98 (4), 588{609.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bakija, J. (2000). The e ect of taxes on portfolio choice: Evidence from panel data spanning the tax reform act of 1986. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Benson, E. (1979). The search for information by underwriters and its impact on municipal interest cost. The Journal of Finance 34 (4), 871{885.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Benson, E. and B. Marks (2007). Structural deacits and state borrowing costs. Public Budgeting and Finance (3), 1{19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Bergstresser, D. and R. Cohen (2015). Changing patterns in household ownership of municipal debt: Evidence from the 1989-2013 surveys of consumer anances. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Bhattacharya, U., A. Hackethal, S. Kaesler, B. Loos, and S. Meyer (2012). Is unbiased anancial advice to retail investors suacient? answers from a large aeld study. The Review of Financial Studies 25 (4), 975{1032.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Bolton, P., X. Freixas, and J. Shapiro (2012). The credit ratings game. Journal of Finance 67 (1), 85{111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Brien, S. T. and D. L. Sjoquist (2014). Do state-funded property tax exemptions actually provide tax relief? georgia's htrg program. Public Finance Review 42 (5), 608.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Butler, A. (2008). Distance still matters: Evidence from alexander w. butlermunicipal bond underwriting. Review of Financial Studies 21 (2), 763{784.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">CBO (2010). A series of issue summaries from the congressional budget oace. ascal stress faced by local governments. Congressional Budget Oace.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Cestau, Dario, G., R. C., and N. Sch&#x7f;urho (2013). Tax-subsidized underpricing: The market for build america bonds. Journal of Monetary Economics (60), 593{608.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Chalmers, J. (1998). Default risk cannot explain the muni puzzle: Evidence from municipal bonds that are secured by u.s. treasury obligations. The Review of Financial Studies 11 (2), 281{308.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Chalmers, J. (2006). Systematic risk and the muni puzzle. National Tax Journal LIX (4), 833{848.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Corwin, S. and P. Schultz (2005). The role of ipo underwriting syndicates: Pricing, information production, and underwriter competition. Journal of Finance 60 (1), 443{ 486.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Denison, D. V., M. Hackbart, and M. J. Moody (2009). When states discriminate: The non-uniform tax treatment of municipal bond interest. Public Administration Review 69 (3), 458{468.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Dougal, C., P. Gao, and C. Parsons (2016). What is in the (school) name. racial discrimination in higher education bond markets. 6th Miami Behavioral Finance Conference.Available at SSRN: http://ssrn.com/abstract=2727763 .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Downing, C. and F. Zhang (2004). Trading activity and price volatility in the municipal bond market. Journal of Finance 59 (2), 899{931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Galper, H., K. Reuben, R. Auxier, and A. Eng (2014). Municipal debt: What does it buy and who beneats? National Tax Journal 67 (4), 901{924.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Galper, H. and E. Toder (1981). Modeling revenue and allocation e ects of the use of tax-exempt bonds for private purposes. Eaciency in the Municipal Bond Market: The Use of Tax-Exempt Bonds for Private Purposes.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Gamkhar, S. and B. Zou (2014). To tax or not to tax: Lessons from the build america bond program about optimal federal tax policy for municipal bonds. Municipal Finance Journal 35 (3), 1 { 25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Gao, L. and D. V. Denison (2014). Indirect and direct subsidies for the cost of government capital: Comparing tax-exempt bonds and build america bonds. National Tax Journal 67 (3), 569.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Gao, P., C. Lee, and D. Murphy (2017). Municipal borrowing costs and state policies for distressed municipalities. Available at SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=2845515 or http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2845515 .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Garrett, D., A. O. J. Roberts, and J. C. S. Serrato (2017). Tax advantages and imperfect competition in auctions for municipal bonds. NBER Working Paper 23473 forthcom- ing(http://www.nber.org/papers/w23473).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Gordon, R. H. and G. E. Metcalf (1991). Do tax-exempt bonds really subsidize municipal capital? National Tax Journal 44 (4), 71{79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Green, R. (1993). A simple model of the taxable and tax-exempt yield curves. Journal of Finance 6 (2), 233{264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Green, R. C., D. Li, and N. Schurho (2010). Price discovery in illiquid markets: Do anancial asset prices rise faster than they fall? Journal of Finance 65 (5), 1669{1702.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Guzman, T. and T. Moldogaziev (2012). Which bonds are more expensive? the cost di erentials by debt issue purpose and the method of sale: An empirical analysis.Public Budgeting and Finance 32 (3), 79{101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Harris, L. E. and M. S. Piwowar (2006). Secondary trading costs in the municipal bond market. Journal of Finance 61 (3), 1361{1397.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Hildreth, W. B. and C. K. Zorn (2005). The evolution of the state and local government municipal debt market over the past quarter century. Public Budgeting and Finance 25 (4), 127{153.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Hotchkiss, E. S. and G. Jostov (2007). Determinants of corporate bond trading: A comprehensive analysis. ssrn.com.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Johnson, C. and K. Kriz (2005). Fiscal institutions, credit ratings, and borrowing costs.Public Budgeting and Finance (1), 84{104.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Joulfaian, D. and T. Matheson (2009). The supply elasticity of tax-exempt bonds. Pro- ceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association 102, 102nd Annual Conference on Taxation, 136{142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Kriz, K. (2003). Comparative costs of negotiated versus competitive bond sales: New evidence from state general obligation bonds. The Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance 43 (2), 191{211.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Kriz, K. A. and Y. Xiao (2017). The impact of rating recalibration on municipal bond yield spreads. Public Budgeting and Finance 37 (2), 83{101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Landoni, M. (Accessed on 02/20/2018). Tax distortions and bond issue pricing. SSRN working paper https://ssrn.com/abstract=2735812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Liu, G. and D. V. Denison (2014). Indirect and direct subsidies for the cost of government capital: Comparing tax-exempt bonds and build america bonds. National Tax Journal 67 (3), 569{594.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Longsta , F. A. (2011). Municipal debt and marginal tax rates: Is there a tax premium in asset prices? Journal of Finance 66 (3), 721{751.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Luby, M. and T. Moldogaziev (2013). An empirical examination of the determinants of municipal bond underwriting fees. Municipal Finance Journal 34 (02), 13{50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Luby, M. J. (2012). Federal intervention in the municipal bond market: The e ectiveness of the build america bond program and its implications on federal and subnational budgeting. Public Budgeting and Finance 32 (4), 46{70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Luby, M. J. and T. Moldogaziev (2014). Tax increment debt anance and the great recession. National Tax Journal 67 (3), 675.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Maguire, S. and J. M. Stupak (2015). Tax-exempt bonds: A description of state and local government debt. Congressional Research Service Report (7 5700).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Marlowe, J. (2015). Municipal bonds and infrastructure development - past, present, and future. A Policy Issue White Paper Prepared on behalf of the ICMA Governmental A airs and Policy Committee.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">McCue, M. J. and J. L. Stevens (1992). Market segmentation and the residual demand for tax-exempt bonds: Emprical evidence from the elimination of interest deductions.Journal of Business Finance and Accounting 19 (5), 777{788.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Moldogaziev, T., C. Johnson, and M. Luby (2018). Underwriting of municipal debt and placement risk premiums in broker-dealer market transaction prices. SSRN Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Moldogaziev, T., S. Kioko, and H. W. Bartley (2017). Impact of bankruptcy eligibility requirements and statutory liens on borrowing costs. Public Budgeting and Fi- nance 37 (4), 47{73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Moldogaziev, T. and M. Luby (2016). Too close for comfort: Does the intensity of municipal advisor and underwriter relationship impact borrowing costs? Public Budgeting and Finance 36 (3), 69{93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">MSRB (2014a). Municipal trading volume dips in third quarter 2014. Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board Press Release.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">MSRB (2014b). Report on secondary market trading in the municipal securities market, july (analysis by erik r. sirri). Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Nanda, V. and R. Singh (2004). Bond insurance: What is special about munis? Journal of Finance 59 (5), 2253{2279.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Park, Y., D. Matkin, and J. Marlowe (2016). Internal control deaciencies and municipal borrowing costs. Public Budgeting and Finance, 1{24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Peng, J. and P. Brucato (2003). Another look at the e ect of method of sale on the interest cost in the municipal bond market -a certiacation model. Public Budgeting and Finance, 73{95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Peng, J. and P. Brucato (2004). An empirical analysis of market and institutional mechanisms for alleviating information asymmetry in the municipal bond market. Journal of Economics and Finance 28 (2), 226{238.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Piketty, T., E. Saez, and G. Zucman (2018). Distributional national accounts: Methods and estimates for the united states. Quarterly journal of economics forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Pine, S. (2013). Municipal bond interest tax exemption at risk. Parks and Recre- ation 48 (9), 22 { 24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Pirinsky, C. A. and Q. Want (2011). Market segmentation and the cost of capital in domestic market: Evidence from municipal bonds. Financial Management 40, 455{ 481.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Poterba, J. (1989). Tax reform and market for tax-exempt debt. Regional Science and Urban Economics 19, 537{562.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Poterba, J. M. and A. A. Samwick (2003). Taxation and household portfolio composition: Evidence from tax reforms in the 1980s and 1990s. Journal of Public Economics 87 (1), 5{39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Poterba, J. M. and A. R. Verdugo (2011). Portfolio substitution and the revenue cost of the federal income tax exemption for state and local government bonds. National Tax Journal 20 (64), 591{614.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <mixed-citation id="c62">Raineri, L., M. Robbins, B. Simonsen, and K. Weaver (2012). Underwriting, brokerage, and risk in municipal bond sales. Municipal Finance Journal 33 (2), 87{103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Robbins, M. and B. Simonsen (2007). Competition and selection in municipal bond sales: Evidence from missouri. Public Budgeting and Finance 27 (2), 88{103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Robbins, M., B. Simonsen, and B. Jump (2000). Maturity structure and borrowing costs: The implications of level debt service. Municipal Finance Journal 21 (3), 40{66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r65">
            <mixed-citation id="c65">Ronen, T. and X. Zhou (2013). Trade and information in the corporate bond market.Journal of Financial Markets 16, 61{103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r66">
            <mixed-citation id="c66">Schultz, P. (2012). The market for new issues of municipal bonds: The roles of transparency and limited access to retail investors. Journal of Financial Economics 106, 492{512.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r67">
            <mixed-citation id="c67">Schwert, M. (2017). Municipal bond liquidity and default risk. The journal of a- nance forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r68">
            <mixed-citation id="c68">SEC (2012). Report on the municipal securities market. Securities and Exchange Com- mission, http://www.sec.gov/news/studies/2012/munireport073112.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r69">
            <mixed-citation id="c69">SIFMA (Accessed on 04/05/2017). Municipal market statistics. Securities Industry and Financial Markets Association, http://www.sifma.org/research/statistics.aspx .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r70">
            <mixed-citation id="c70">Simonsen, B. and M. Robbins (2002). Measuring municipal borrowing costs: How missing cost information biases interest rate calculations. Public Budgeting and Finance (1), 46{60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r71">
            <mixed-citation id="c71">Sorensen, E. (1979). Negotiated municipal bond underwritings: Implications for ea- ciency: A note. Journal of Money, Credit and Banking 11 (3), 366{370.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r72">
            <mixed-citation id="c72">The-Bond-Buyer (Accessed on 2/15/2016). Ohio state moves to shelf registration-style offering.The Bond Buyer Webiste, http://www.bondbuyer.com/news/regionalnews/ohio- state-moves-to-shelf-registration-style-o ering-1097812-1.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r73">
            <mixed-citation id="c73">Trzcinka, C. (1982). The pricing of tax-exempt bonds and the miller hypothesis. Journal of Finance 37 (4), 907{923.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r74">
            <mixed-citation id="c74">Viciera, L. M. and J. Y. Campbell (2012). Strategic asset allocation: Portfolio choice for long-term investors. Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r75">
            <mixed-citation id="c75">Wang, J., C. Wu, and F. X. Zhang (2008). Liquidity, default, taxes, and yields on municipal bonds. The journal of banking and anance 32 (6), 1133{1149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r76">
            <mixed-citation id="c76">Warga, A. (1992). Bond returns, liquidity, and missing data. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 27, 605{617.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r77">
            <mixed-citation id="c77">Weitzman, A. and K. Glazier (2016). How shrinking spreads are making the muni underwriting business unsustainable. The Bond Buyer (2), June 6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Variable Descriptions and Data Sources</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Sample Exclusion Criteria</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Excerpt from The Official Statement of The State of Georgia Debt Issuance (2015)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Matching Criteria for Tax-exempt and Taxable Muni Pairs</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Visual Representation of Matched Pairs</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Distribution of the Naive Implied Marginal Tax Rate, τ</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Distribution of Implied Marginal Tax Rate, τ, Post-match, by Issuer Type</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>RCM Results, DV = Exempt Yield</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Implied Marginal Tax Rate, τ, by Time to Maturity</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Evolution of the Implied Marginal Tax Rate, τ</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Matched Sample Summary Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Unmatched Exempt Sample Summary Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Unmatched Taxable Sample Summary Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Issuer Type Distribution</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>GLM Results, Dependent Variable = τ</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>GLM Results, DV = Exempt Offering Yield</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
