<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">finamana</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j100419</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Financial Management</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Financial Management Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00463892</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">1755053X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">3665263</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Presidential Address</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Teaching and Research in Finance: Perceptions, Conflicts, and the Future</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>George H.</given-names>
                  <surname>Hempel</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date>
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>1983</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i284550</issue-id>
         <fpage>5</fpage>
         <lpage>10</lpage>
         <page-range>5-10</page-range>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1983 Financial Management Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/3665263"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper examines perceptions of the academic finance community of and by the three major communities -- business people, students, and the university community -- that constitute the academic finance community's major constituencies. It then examines academic finance persons' perceptions of each other; important conflicts that arise from these differences in perceptions are disclosed. The author then discusses his ideas of what may happen in teaching and research in financial management in coming years because of these conflicts. He suggests that the evaluation of teaching in Finance needs to be improved, that teaching methodology will be more pluralistic in the future, and that doctoral programs need to be modified. "Quality" and "readability" by the three primary constituencies are emphasized in the discussion of research in the future. The article concludes with a discussion of programs, such as a course syllabus research center, encouragement of practitioner participation in annual meetings, an annual practitioner/academic forum on a current topic, and a corporate sponsorshiop membership designation, which the FMA might undertake to improve the future outlook for teaching and research in finance.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
