<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26272319</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Two-Color Diffused Back-Illumination Imaging as a Diagnostic for Time-Resolved Soot Measurements in Reacting Sprays</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Manin</surname>
                  <given-names>Julien</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pickett</surname>
                  <given-names>Lyle M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Skeen</surname>
                  <given-names>Scott A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>December 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26272316</issue-id>
         <fpage>1908</fpage>
         <lpage>1921</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26272319"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Despite ongoing research efforts directed at reducing engine-out emissions, diesel engines are known to be one of the largest sources of atmospheric particulate matter (i.e., soot). Quantitative measurements are of primary importance to address soot production during the combustion process in the cylinder of diesel engines. This study presents the capabilities of an extinction-based diagnostic developed to quantitatively measure the soot volume fraction in n-dodecane sprays injected in a high-pressure, high-temperature vessel. Coupled with high-speed imaging, the technique yields time-resolved measurements of the soot field by relying on a diffused back-illumination scheme to improve extinction quantification in the midst of intense beam steering. The experiments performed in this work used two wavelengths, which, when combined with the Rayleigh-Debye-Gans theory, provide information about the optical and physical properties of soot. For validation of the extinction imaging technique and comparison with prior work, the path-averaged soot volume fraction has been simultaneously measured using laser extinction.</p>
            <p>We found the sensitivity of this diagnostic to soot volume fraction to be below 1 ppm despite beam-steering influences in the time-resolved data, and we were able to quantify higher soot concentrations in engine-relevant spray flames than previous studies by our group that used laser-induced incandescence (LII) in conjunction with path-averaged laser extinction. This work demonstrated a preference for shorter visible wavelengths, as soot-generated extinction is higher while broadband flame emission is lower at these wavelengths. Consequently, shorter visible wavelengths resulted in a greater signal-to-noise ratio. Analysis of two-color extinction indicated that the refractive index and morphological properties of soot change during the formation and oxidation processes.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bond T. C., Doherty S. J., Fahey D. W., Forster P. M., Berntsen T., DeAngelo B. J., Flanner M. G., Ghan S., Karcher B., and Koch D.. et al. Bounding the role of black carbon in the climate system: a scientific assessment. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Puri R., Richardson T. F., Santoro R. J., and Dobbins R. A.. Aerosol dynamic processes of soot aggregates in a laminar ethene diffusion flame. Combustion and flame, 92(3):320-333, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Iuliis S., Cignoli F., and Zizak G.. Two-color laser-induced incandescence (2c-lii) technique for absolute soot volume fraction measurements in flames. Applied optics, 44(34):7414-7423, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sorensen C. M.. Light scattering by fractal aggregates: A review. Aerosol Science &amp; Technology, 35(2):648-687, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Crosland B. M., Johnson M. R., and Thomson K. A.. Analysis of uncertainties in instantaneous soot volume fraction measurements using two-dimensional, auto-compensating, laser-induced incandescence (2DAC- LII). Applied Physics B, 102(1): 173-183, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett L. M. and Siebers D. L.. Soot in diesel fuel jets: effects of ambient temperature, ambient density, and injection pressure. Combustion and Flame, 138(1-2): 114-135, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cenker, E., Bruneaux, G., Pickett, L., and Schulz, C., “Study of Soot Formation and Oxidation in the Engine Combustion Network (ECN), Spray A: Effects of Ambient Temperature and Oxygen Concentration,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):352-365, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0901.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöholm, J., Wellander, R., Bladh, H., Richter, M. et al., “Challenges for In-Cylinder High-Speed Two-Dimensional Laser-Induced Incandescence Measurements of Soot,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1): 1607-1622, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1280.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett L. M. and Siebers D. L.. Soot formation in diesel fuel jets near the lift-off length. International Journal of Engine Research, 7(2): 103-130, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greeves G. and Meehan J. O.. Measurement of instantaneous soot concentration in a diesel combustion chamber. IMechE, pages 73-82, 1975.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang Y. J., Kobayashi H., Matsuzawa K., and Kamimoto T.. A photographic study of soot formation and combustion in a diesel flame with a rapid compression machine. International Symposium COMODIA 1985, Tokyo, Japan, 1985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miyamoto, N., Ogawa, H., Goto, N., and Sasaki, H., “Analysis of Diesel Soot Formation under Varied Ignition Lag with a Laser Light Extinction Method,” SAE Technical Paper 900640, 1990, doi:10.4271/900640.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakakita, K., Nagaoka, M., Fujikawa, T., Ohsawa, K. et al., “Photographic and Three Dimensional Numerical Studies of Diesel Soot Formation Process,” SAE Technical Paper 902081, 1990, doi: 10.4271/902081.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greenberg P. S. and Ku J. C.. Soot volume fraction imaging. Applied optics, 36(22):5514-5522, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Snelling D. R., Thomson K. A., and Smallwood O. L., and Gulder G. J.. Two-dimensional imaging of soot volume fraction in laminar diffusion flames. Applied optics, 38(12):2478-2485, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thomson K. A., Johnson M. R., Snelling D. R., and Smallwood G. J.. Diffuse-light two-dimensional line-of-sight attenuation for soot concentration measurements. Applied optics, 47(5):694-703, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu Y. and Lee C. F.. Forward-illuminated light-extinction technique for soot measurements. Applied Optics, 45:2046-2057, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dobbins R. A. and Megaridis C. M.. Absorption and scattering of light by poly disperse aggregates. Applied Optics, 30(33):4747-4754, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S. and Pickett, L., “Soot Volume Fraction and Morphology of Conventional, Fischer-Tropsch, Coal-Derived, and Surrogate Fuel at Diesel Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(2):647-664, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0678.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aizawa, T., Nishigai, H., Kondo, K., Yamaguchi, T. et al., “Transmission Electron Microscopy of Soot Particles Directly Sampled in Diesel Spray Flame - A Comparison between US#2 and Biodiesel Soot,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(2):665-673, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0695.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koylu U. O. and Faeth G. M.. Optical properties of overfire soot in buoyant turbulent diffusion flames at long residence times. Journal of heat transfer, 116(1):152-159, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shaddix C. R., Palotas A. B., Megaridis C. M, Choi M. Y., and Yang N. Y. C.. Soot graphitic order in laminar diffusion flames and a large-scale jp-8 pool fire. International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer, 48(17): 3604-3614, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skeen S. A., Manin J., Dalen K., and Pickett L. M.. Extinction-based imaging of soot processes over a range of diesel operating conditions. To be submitted to Combustion &amp; Flame, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., “Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 980809, 1998, doi:10.4271/980809.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manin J., Bardi M., and Pickett L. M.. Evaluation of the liquid length via diffused back-illumination imaging in vaporizing diesel sprays. International Symposium COMODIA 2012, Fukuoka, Japan, SP2-4:665-673, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ghandhi J. B. and Heim D. M.. An optimized optical system for backlit imaging. Review of Scientific Instruments, 80:056105, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koylu U. O., McEnally C. S., Rosner D. E., and Pfefferle L. D.. Simultaneous measurements of soot volume fraction and particle size/microstructure in flames using a thermophoretic sampling technique. Combustion and Flame, 110(4):494-507, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yon J., Lemaire R., Therssen E., Desgroux P., Coppalle A., and Ren K. F.. Examination of wavelength dependent soot optical properties of diesel and diesel/rapeseed methyl ester mixture by extinction spectra analysis and lii measurements. Applied Physics B, 104(2):253-271, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Williams T. C., Shaddix C. R., Jensen K. A., and Suo-Anttila J. M.. Measurement of the dimensionless extinction coefficient of soot within laminar diffusion flames. International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer, 50(7):1616-1630, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lopez J. J. and Pickett L. M.. Jet/wall interaction effects on soot formation in a diesel fuel jet. International Symposium COMODIA 2004, Yokohama, Japan, pages 387-394, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus M. P. B. and Pickett L. M.. Diagnostic considerations for optical laser-extinction measurements of soot in high-pressure transient combustion environments. Combustion and flame, 141(4):371-391, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schnaiter M., Horvath H., Mohler O., Naumann K.-H., Saathoff H., and Schock O. W.. UV-VIS-NIR spectral optical properties of soot and sootcontaining aerosols. Journal of Aerosol Science, 34(10):1421-1444, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moffat R. J.. Describing the uncertainties in experimental results. Experimental thermal and fluid science, 1(1):3-17, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maria-Frances Candela. Scattering of Light from Soot Particles. PhD thesis, Lund Institute of Technology, Lund, Sweden, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu F. and Smallwood G. J.. The effect of particle aggregation on the absorption and emission properties of mono-and polydisperse soot aggregates. Applied Physics B, 104(2):343-355, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dalzell W. H. and Sarofim A. F.. Optical constants of soot and their application to heat-flux calculations. J. Heat Transfer, 91(1):100-104, 1969.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D'alessio A., Beretta F., and Venitozzi C.. Optical investigations on soot forming methane-oxygen flames. Combustion Science and Technology, 5(1):263-272, 1972.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
