<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24911077</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>FEATURE</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Solving a Problem with Either-Or Constraints and a Nonlinear Objective Function as a Mixed Integer Linear Program in order to Reconfigure the Force with a Minimum of Disruption</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Tama</surname>
                  <given-names>Joseph M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr. Joseph M. Tama has a doctorate in operations research from Carnegie Mellon University and has worked as a modeler and tool developer in USAF/A9 and its predecessor AFSAA since 2002. The most notable projects on which he has worked have been the 2004 Capabilities Review and Risk Assessment (CRRA), the 2005 BRAC, and in 2010 the Total Force Enterprise Project.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Gallagher</surname>
                  <given-names>Mark A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr. Mark A. Gallagher, a senior level executive, is the technical director, Studies and Analyses, Assessments and Lessons Learned, Headquarters Air Force (USAF/A9). This directorate conducts analyses for both the Secretary and Chief of Staff of the Air Force. Dr. Gallagher is a graduate of the Air Force Academy and has served as an officer in the Office of the Secretary of Defense (Program Analysis and Evaluation) and at US Strategic Command. Subsequently, in civil service Dr. Gallagher has served as Chief of Analysis Management Division and Chief of Missile Defense and Combating Weapons of Mass Destruction Capabilities Division at the US Strategic Command before joining USAF/A9 as deputy director, Resource Analysis Directorate.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hill</surname>
                  <given-names>Justin M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Major Justin M. Hill has been an AF Operations Research analyst since graduating from the USAF Academy in 1998. In that time he has worked on various projects for the Air Force Personnel Center, the Joint Staff, NASA, and Headquarters Air Force. He has a master’s degree in operations research from the Air Force Institute of Technology and a doctorate in industrial and systems engineering from Virginia Tech.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>SEPTEMBER 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>45</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e24911056</issue-id>
         <fpage>35</fpage>
         <lpage>39</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2012, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24911077"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
