<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26812187</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Optimal Income Tax Structures</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Taxing the Job Creators</article-title>
            <subtitle>Efficient Progressive Taxation with Wage Bargaining</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lawson</surname>
                  <given-names>Nicholas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">107</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26812141</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>44</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26812187"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The standard economic view of the personal income tax is that it is a distortionary way of raising revenue which nonetheless has value because it tends to increase equality. However, when wages deviate from marginal product, the laissez-faire equilibrium is inecient, and there can be an independent eciency rationale for income taxation. I study a setting of wage bargaining within hierarchical teams of workers and managers, and show that the eciency case for taxing managers depends on a “job-creation” effect: if increased labour supply allows managers to supervise larger teams and thus collect larger rents, they will have an incentive to work too hard to create jobs at their firm. In other words, it is <italic>because</italic> of their job-creation activity that the “job creators” should be heavily taxed. Simulation of a calibrated model suggests an ecient tax schedule that is progressive over most of the income distribution with a top marginal rate of between 50% and 60%, and this result is not sensitive to the magnitude of the labour supply response to taxation. For a planner with redistributive motives, optimal marginal tax rates are also considerably higher at the top of the distribution in the presence of wage bargaining rather than a competitive labour market.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Abowd, J. M., F. Kramarz, and D. N. Margolis (1999): \High Wage Workers and High Wage Firms,” Econometrica, 67(2), 251{333.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Andrews, M., L. Gill, T. Schank, and R. Upward (2008): \High Wage Workers and Low Wage Firms: Negative Assortative Matching or Limited Mobility Bias?,” Journal of the Royal Statistical Society, 171(3), 673{697.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Andrews, M. (2012): \High Wage Workers Match With High Wage Firms: Clear Evidence of the E ects of Limited Mobility Bias,” Economics Letters, 117(3), 824{827.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Antras, P., L. Garicano, and E. Rossi-Hansberg (2005): \O shoring in a Knowledge Economy,” Working Paper no. 11094, NBER, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Antras, P.(2006): \O shoring in a Knowledge Economy,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 121(1), 31{77.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Blomquist, S., V. Christiansen, and L. Micheletto (2010): \Public Provision of Private Goods and Nondistortionary Marginal Tax Rates,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 2(2), 1{27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Boadway, R., and M. Sato (2014): \Optimal Income Taxation and Risk: The Extensive-Margin Case,” Annals of Economics and Statistics, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Boone, J., and L. Bovenberg (2002): \Optimal Labour Taxation and Search,” Journal of Public Economics, 85(1), 53{97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Cahuc, P., and G. Laroque (2014): \Optimal Taxation and Monopsonistic Labor Market: Does Monopsony Justify the Minimum Wage?,” Journal of Public Economic Theory, 16(2), 259{273.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Diamond, P., and E. Saez (2011): \The Case for a Progressive Tax: From Basic Research to Policy Recommendations,” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 25(4), 165{190.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Diamond, P. A. (1998): \Optimal Income Taxation: An Example with a U-Shaped Pattern of Optimal Marginal Tax Rates,” American Economic Review, 88(1), 83{95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Eeckhout, J., and P. Kircher (2011): \Identifying Sorting { In Theory,” Review of Economic Studies, 78(3), 872{906.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Feldstein, M. (1995): \The E ect of Marginal Tax Rates on Taxable Income: A Panel Study of the 1986 Tax Reform Act,” Journal of Political Economy, 103(3), 551{572.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Gruber, J., and E. Saez (2002): \The Elasticity of Taxable Income: Evidence and Implications,” Journal of Public Economics, 84(1), 1{32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Hope, O.-K., and W. B. Thomas (2008): \Managerial Empire Building and Firm Disclosure,” Journal of Accounting Research, 46(3), 591{626.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Hosios, A. J. (1990): \On the Eciency of Matching and Related Models of Search and Unemployment,” Review of Economic Studies, 57(2), 279{298.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Hungerb&#x7f;uhler, M., and E. Lehmann (2009): \On the Optimality of a Minimum Wage: New Insights from Optimal Tax Theory,” Journal of Public Economics, 93(3-4), 464{481.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Hungerb&#x7f;uhler, M., E. Lehmann, A. Parmentier, and B. van der Linden (2006): \Optimal Redistributive Taxation in a Search Equilibrium Model,” Review of Economic Studies, 73(3), 743{767.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Jacquet, L., E. Lehmann, and B. van der Linden (2013): \Optimal Redistributive Taxation with Both Extensive and Intensive Responses,” Journal of Economic Theory, 148(5), 1770{1805.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Jacquet, L. (2014): \Optimal Income Taxation with Kalai Wage Bargaining and Endogenous Participation,” Social Choice and Welfare, 42(2), 381{402.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Jensen, M. C. (1986): \Agency Costs of Free Cash Flow, Corporate Finance, and Takeovers,” American Economic Review, 76(2), 323{329.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Keane, M., and R. Rogerson (2012): \Micro and Macro Labor Supply Elasticities: A Reassessment of Conventional Wisdom,” Journal of Economic Literature, 50(2), 464{476.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Krugman, P. (November 22, 2011): \Taxing Job Creators,” http://krugman.blogs.nytimes. com/2011/11/22/taxing-job-creators/, New York Times.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Lehmann, E., A. Parmentier, and B. van der Linden (2011): \Optimal Income Taxation with Endogenous Participation and Search Unemployment,” Journal of Public Economics, 95(11-12), 1523{1537.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Lockwood, B. B., C. G. Nathanson, and E. G. Weyl (2014): \Taxation and the Allocation of Talent,” Unpublished Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Mankiw, N. G., M. Weinzierl, and D. Yagan (2009): \Optimal Taxation in Theory and Practice,” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 23(4), 147{174.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Manning, A. (2003): Monopsony in Motion: Imperfect Competition in Labor Markets. Princeton University Press, Princeton, NJ.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Manning, A. (2011): \Imperfect Competition in the Labor Market,” in Handbook of Labor Economics, ed. by D. Card, and O. Ashenfelter, vol. 4b, Elsevier, pp. 973{1041.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Mirrlees, J. (1971): \An Exploration in the Theory of Optimum Income Taxation,” Review of Economic Studies, 38(2), 175{208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Persson, M., and A. Sandmo (2005): \Taxation and Tournaments,” Journal of Public Economic Theory, 7(4), 543{559.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Piketty, T., E. Saez, and S. Stantcheva (2014): \Optimal Taxation of Top Labor Incomes: A Tale of Three Elasticities,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 6(1), 230{271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Robin, J.-M., and S. Roux (2002): \An Equilibrium Model of the Labour Market with Endogenous Capital and Two-Sided Search,” Annales d'Economie et de Statistique, 67/68, 257{307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Rothschild, C., and F. Scheuer (2013): \Redistributive Taxation in the Roy Model,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 128(2), 623{668.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Saez, E. (2001): \Using Elasticities to Derive Optimal Income Tax Rates,” Review of Economic Studies, 68(1), 205{229.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Saez, E., J. Slemrod, and S. H. Giertz (2012): \The Elasticity of Taxable Income with Respect to Marginal Tax Rates: A Critical Review,” Journal of Economic Literature, 50(1), 3{50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Sandmo, A. (1998): \Redistribution and the Marginal Cost of Public Funds,” Journal of Public Economics, 70(3), 365{382.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Spanos, G. (2013): \Sorting Within and Across French Production Hierarchies,” Unpublished Paper, University of Toronto.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Stantcheva, S. (2014): \Optimal Income Taxation with Adverse Selection in the Labor Market,” Review of Economic Studies, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Varian, H. (1980): \Redistributive Taxation as Social Insurance,” Journal of Public Economics, 14(1), 49{68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Competitive Wage and Matching Functions with Uniform Distribution</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Wage and Matching Functions with Wage Bargaining and Uniform Distribution</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Wage and Matching Functions with Uniform Distribution</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Efficient Taxes with Wage Bargaining and Uniform Distribution</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Efficient Taxes with Wage Bargaining and Calibrated Distribution</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Optimal Tax Schedule with Log Utility and Competitive Wages</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Values of R and S for Competitive Wages, Baseline Taxes and G = 12.21</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Optimal Tax Schedule with Log Utility and Wage Bargaining</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Values of R and S for Wage Bargaining, Baseline Taxes and G = 12.21</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Calibrated Skill Density f(𝓩) with Wage Bargaining</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 11:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Calibrated Skill Density f(𝓩) with Competitive Wages</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 12:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Optimal Tax Schedule with Uniform F(𝓩), Log Utility and Competitive Wages</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 13:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Values of R and S for Uniform F(𝓩), Competitive Wages, Zero Taxes and G = 0</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 14:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Optimal Tax Schedule with Uniform F(𝓩), Log Utility and Wage Bargaining</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 15:</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Values of R and S for Uniform F(𝓩), Wage Bargaining, Zero Taxes and G = 0</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 16:</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Efficient Taxes with ETI = 1, Wage Bargaining and Uniform Distribution</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 17:</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Efficient Taxes with ETI = 1, Wage Bargaining and Calibrated Distribution</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 18:</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Optimal Tax Schedule with ETI = 1, Log Utility and Competitive Wages</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 19:</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Optimal Tax Schedule with ETI = 1, Log Utility and Wage Bargaining</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Optimal Bracketed Taxes</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
