<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939528</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Housing, Commercial Property and Local Taxes</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effect of Property Taxes on Businesses</article-title>
            <subtitle>Evidence from a Dynamic Regression Discontinuity Approach</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Enami</surname>
                  <given-names>Ali</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reynolds</surname>
                  <given-names>C. Lockwood</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rohlin</surname>
                  <given-names>Shawn M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>41</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939528"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The endogenous nature of property taxation makes it difficult to properly understand the effects of property taxation on businesses. We employ a dynamic regression discontinuity design comparing business outcomes in areas that barely passed additional school property taxes to business outcomes in areas that barely failed to do so. To do so, we collect data on school property tax levies in Ohio from 2003-2016 and combine it with longitudinal data on the universe of establishments during the same period. The findings suggest that passage of a property tax referendum has a negative effect on the number of establishments in the district in the following years. Further evidence suggests that the effect is driven by an immediate adverse effect on new business formation and migration of firms to new areas, and not due to firm deaths. The results suggest that areas experience negative, although inelastic, effects of property taxes on the number of local businesses.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Albouy, David, Leibovici, Fernando, and Warman, Casey, 2013. “Quality of life, firm productivity, and the value of amenities across Canadian cities.” Canadian Journal of Economics 46(2).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Alm, James, Robert Buschman and David Sjoquist, 2011. “Rethinking local government reliance on the property tax.” Regional Science and Urban Economics, 41, 320-331.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Barrow, Lisa and Cecelia Elena Rouse, 2004. “Using market valuation to assess public school spending.” Journal of Public Economics, 88(9), 1747-1769.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bartik, Timothy. 1985. “Business location decisions in the United States: Estimates of the effects of unionization, taxes, and other characteristics of states,” Journal of Business and Economic Statistics, 3, 14-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Black, Sandra E., and Stephen Machin, 2011. "Housing valuations of school performance." Handbook of the Economics of Education 3, 485-519.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Brueckner, J.K., and L.A. Saavedra. 2001. “Do local governments engage in strategic tax competition?” National Tax Journal 54: 203-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Brülhart, Marius, Jametti Mario &amp; Schmidheiny, Kurt, 2012. "Do agglomeration economies reduce the sensitivity of firm location to tax differentials?" Economic Journal, 122(563), 1069-1093.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Carlton, D.,1983. “The location and employment choices of new firms: An econometric model with discrete and continuous endogenous variables.” Review of Economics and Statistics, 65, 440-49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Carlton, Dennis, 1979. “Births of single establishment firms and regional variation in economic cost.” Paper 2, Report 7729. Center for Mathematical Studies in Business and Economics, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Cellini, Stephanie Riegg, 2009. "Crowded colleges and college crowd-out: The impact of public subsidies on the two-year college market." American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 1(2), 1-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Cellini, Stephanie Riegg, Fernando Ferreira, and Jesse Rothstein, 2010. “The value of school facility investments: Evidence from a dynamic regression discontinuity design.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 125(1), 215-261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">DiNardo, John, and David S. Lee, 2004. "Economic impacts of new unionization on private sector employers: 1984-2001." Quarterly Journal of Economics, 119(4), 1383-1441.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Due, John. 1961. “Studies of state-local tax influences on location of industry,” National Tax Journal, 14, 163-173.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Duranton G., Gobillon L. and H. Overman 2011. “Assessing the effects of local taxation using microgeographic data.” Economic Journal, 121(555), pp. 1017-1046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Dye, Richard, Therese McGuire, and David Merriman. 2001. “The impact of property taxes and property tax classification on business activity in the Chicago metropolitan area,” Journal of Regional Science, 41, 757-778.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Enami, Ali, 2018. “Labor versus Capital in the Provision of Public Services: Estimating the Marginal Products of Inputs in the Production of Student Outcomes.” Manuscript.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Feld, L.P. and Kirchgassner, G. (2003). “The impact of corporate and personal income taxes on the location of firms and on employment: some panel evidence for the Swiss cantons”, Journal of Public Economics, 87(1), 129-55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Ferreira, Fernando and Joseph Gyourko, 2009. “Do political parties matter? Evidence from US cities.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 124(1), 399-422.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Fox, William, 1986. “Tax structure and the location of economic activity along state borders,” National Tax Journal, 39, 387-401.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Gabriel, Stuart and Stuart S Rosenthal, 2004. “Quality of the business environment versus quality of life: Do firms and households like the same cities?” Review of Economics and Statistics, 86: 438-444.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Hoyt, William H. and J. William Harden, 2005. “MSA location and the impact of state taxes on employment and population: A comparison of border and interior MSAs,” Institute for Federalism and Intergovernmental Relations, Working Paper No. 2005-01.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Imbens, Guido W., and Thomas Lemieux, 2008. "Regression discontinuity designs: A guide to practice." Journal of Econometrics 142(2), pp. 615-635.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Isen, Adam, 2014. “Do Local Fiscal Spillovers Exist? Evidence from Counties, Municipalities, and School Districts.” Journal of Public Economics, 110, 57-73</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Jackson, C. Kirabo, Rucker C. Johnson, and Claudia Persico. 2015 "The effects of school spending on educational and economic outcomes: Evidence from school finance reforms." Quarterly Journal of Economics 131(1), 157-218.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Kneller, Richard and McGowan, Danny, 2011. “Taxation, entrepreneurship and self-employment: Evidence from a regression discontinuity design” working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Lee, David S., Enrico Moretti, and Matthew J., 2004. “Do voters affect or elect policies? Evidence from the US House.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 119(3), 807-859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Papke, Leslie E., 1991. “Interstate business tax differentials and new firm location: evidence from panel data.” Journal of Public Economics, 45, 47-68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Oates, Wallace, 1969. "The effects of property taxes and local public spending on property values: An empirical study of tax capitalization and the Tiebout Hypothesis." Journal of Political Economy, 77(6), 957-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Palmon, Oded, Smith, Barton A., 1998. “New evidence on property tax capitalization.” Journal of Political Economy, 106 (5), 1099-1111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Rohlin, Shawn, Stuart Rosenthal, and Amanda Ross, 2014. “Tax avoidance and business location in a state border model,” Journal of Urban Economics, 83, 34-49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Schmenner, Roger., 1982. Making Business Location Decisions. Prentice-Hall, Englewood Cliffs, NJ.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Serrato J.C. and Zidar O., 2016. “Who benefits from state corporate tax cuts? A local labor markets approach with heterogeneous firms.” American Economic Review, 106(9): 2582-2624.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Thompson, Jeffrey and Shawn Rohlin, 2012. “The effect of sales taxes on employment: New evidence from cross-border panel data analysis,” National Tax Journal, 65 (4), 1023-41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Wasylenko, Michael, 1997. “Taxation and economic development: the state of the economic literature,” New England Economic Review, (Mar), 37-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Walker, Robert and David Greenstreet. 1991. “The effect of government incentives and assistance on location and job growth in manufacturing,” Regional Studies, 25, 13-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Yinger, John, Bloom, Howard, Borsch-Supan, Axel and Ladd, Helen, “Property Taxes and House Values: The Theory and Estimation of Intrajurisdictional Property Tax Capitalization,” Academic Press, New York 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Youngman, Joan, 2002. “Enlarging the property tax debate: regressivity and fairness.” StateTax Notes 26(3), 45-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Zodrow, George. 2014. “Intrajurisdictional capitalization and the incidence of the property tax” Regional Science and Urban Economics, 45 (57-66).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Density of Vote Shares in School Property Tax Referenda</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Summary Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>ITT and TOT Effects of Property Tax Referenda on the Number of Establishments, All Industries</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>ITT and TOT Effects of Property Tax Referenda on Establishment Births and Deaths, All Industries</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Estimated Effects of Property Taxes on Manufacturing Establishments</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>TOT Effects of Property Taxes on Retail and Service Establishments</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Figure A-1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>ITT Estimates of the Effect of Property Tax Levies on Number of Firms 3 Years After Passage</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table A-1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>ITT and TOT Effects of Property Taxes on Establishments, All Industries, logged estimates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A-2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Estimated Effects of Property Taxes on All Non-Manufacturing Establishments</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table A-3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>ITT Effects of Property Taxes on Retail and Service Establishments</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
