<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">qjfinacct</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000678</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Quarterly Journal of Finance and Accounting</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Creighton University</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19398123</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23278250</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90010050</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Do the Properties of Analyst Earnings Forecasts Improve When Firms Are Managed by Female CFOs?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>KIM</surname>
                  <given-names>HYUNG TAE (TED)</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Arkansas State University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>Spring 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>55</volume>
         <issue>1-2</issue>
         <issue-id>e90010047</issue-id>
         <fpage>27</fpage>
         <lpage>52</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90010050"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Using 1,021 CFO transitions, we find that analyst earnings forecasts become more dispersed after male CFOs are changed to male CFOs, whereas such deterioration in forecast dispersion is much weaker following male-to-female CFO transition. The result suggests that female CFOs mitigate the impact of CFO transitions on analyst earnings forecasts. We also document more accurate and consistent analyst earnings forecasts for female-CFO-led companies compared to firms with male-CFO-led companies. Overall, our findings suggest that the quality of analyst earnings forecasts is better when firms are managed by female CFOs. This study provides empirical evidence of benefit from female executives in line with existing gender studies in accounting and finance literature. Rather than female executives’ managerial behavior, this study examines how female CFOs affect the quality of analysts’ forecasts and supports previous findings that female CFOs tend to report financial information with better quality and make more prudent corporate decisions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adams, R., and D. Ferreira. "Women in the Boardroom and Their Impact on Governance and Performance.” Journal of Financial Economics, vol. 94, no. 2, 2009, pp. 291–309.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Agnew, J., P. Balduzzi, and A. Sunden. “Portfolio Choice and Trading in a Large 401(K) Plan.” American Economic Review, vol. 93, no. 1, 2003, pp. 193–215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barua, A., L.F. Davidson, D.V. Rama, and S. Thiruvadi. “CFO Gender and Accruals Quality.” Accounting Horizons, vol. 24, no. 1, 2010, pp. 25–39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Behn, B.K., J-H. Choi, and T. Kang. “Audit Quality and Properties of Analyst Earnings Forecasts.” The Accounting Review, vol. 83, no. 2, 2008, pp. 327–349.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bernardi, R.A., and D.F. Arnold. “An Examination of Moral Development within Public Accounting by Gender, Staff Level, and Firm.” Contemporary Accounting Research, vol. 14, no. 4, 1997, pp. 653-668.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bernasek, A., and S. Shwiff. “Gender, Risk, and Retirement.” Journal of Economic, vol. 35, no. 2, 2001, pp. 345–356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Betz, M., L. O’Connell, and J.M. Shepard. “Gender Differences in Proclivity for Unethical Behavior.” Journal of Business Ethics, vol. 8, no. 5, 1989, pp. 321–324.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Clement, M. “Analyst Forecast Accuracy: Do Ability, Resources, and Portfolio Complexity Matter?” Journal of Accounting and Economics, vol. 27, no. 3, 1999, pp. 285–303.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Francis, B., I. Hasan, J. Park, and Q. Wu. “Gender Differences in Financial Reporting Decision-making: Evidence from Accounting Conservatism.” Contemporary Accounting Research, vol. 32, no. 3, 2015, pp. 1285–1318.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Francis, B., I. Hasan, and Q. Wu. “The Impact of CFO Gender and Bank Loan Contracting.” Journal of Accounting, Auditing and Finance, vol. 28, no. 1, 2013, pp. 53–78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Francis, B., I. Hasan, Q. Wu, and M. Yan. “Are Female CFOs Less Tax Aggressive? Evidence from Tax Aggressiveness.” The Journal of the American Taxation Association, vol. 36, no. 2, 2014, pp. 171–202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gul, F.A., M. Hutchinson, and K.M.Y. Lai. “Gender-diverse Boards and Properties of Analyst Earnings Forecasts.” Accounting Horizons, vol. 27, no. 3, 2013, pp. 511–538.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heflin, F., K.R. Subramanyam, and Y. Zhang. “Regulation FD and the Financial Information Environment: Early Evidence.” The Accounting Review, vol. 78, no.1, 2003, pp. 1–37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hong, H., an d J. Kubik. “Analyzing the Analysts: Career Concerns and Biased Earnings Forecasts.” The Journal of Finance, vol. 58, no. 1, 2003, pp. 313–351.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://fortune.com/2015/02/24/58-women-cfos-in-the-fortune-500-is-this-progress/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://money.cnn.com/2015/03/24/investing/female-ceo-pipeline-leadership/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, J., and D. Kisgen. “Gender and Corporate Finance: Are Male Executives Overconfident Relative to Female Executives?” Journal of Financial Economics, vol. 108, no. 3, 2013, pp. 822–839.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jurkus, A.F., J.C. Park, and L.S. Woodard. “Women in Top Management and Agency Costs.” Journal of Business Research, vol. 64, no. 2, 2011, pp. 180–186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, A., and S.G. Chung. “Are Female CFOs Better at Improving the Readability of the Annual Reports? 2014. Available at SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=2402879 or http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2402879</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krishnan, G.V., and L.M. Parsons. “Getting to the Bottom Line: An Exploration of Gender and Earnings Quality.” Journal of Business Ethics, vol. 78, no. 1-2, 2008, pp. 65–76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kross, W., B.T. Ro, and D. Schroeder. “Earnings Expectations: The Analysts’ Information Advantage.” The Accounting Review, vol. 65, no .2, 1990, pp. 461–476.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lang, M., and R. Lundholm. “Corporate Disclosure Policy and Analyst Behavior.” The Accounting Review, vol. 71, no. 4, 1996, pp. 467–492.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lanis, R., G. Richardson, and G. Taylor. “Board of Director Gender and Corporate Tax Aggressiveness: An Empirical Analysis.” Journal of Business Ethics, 2015. doi:10.1007/s10551-015-2815-x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lehavy, R., F. Li, and K. Merkley. “The Effect of Annual Report Readability on Analyst Following and the Properties of Their Earnings Forecasts.” The Accounting Review, vol. 86, no. 3, 2011, pp. 1087–1115.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peni, E., and S. Vahamaa. “Female Executives and Earnings Management.” Managerial Finance, vol. 36, no. 7, 2010, 629–645.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roter, D.L., A. Hall, and Y. Aoki. “Physician Gender Effects in Medical Communication.” The Journal of American Medical Association, vol. 288, no. 6, 2002, pp. 756–764.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sunden, A., and B. Surette. “Gender Differences in the Allocation of Assets in Retirement Savings Plans.” American Economic Review, vol. 88, no. 2, 1998, pp. 207–211.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Terejesen, S., and V. Singh. “Female Presence on Corporate Boards: A Multi-country Study of Environmental Context.” Journal of Business Ethics, vol. 83, no. 1, 2008, pp. 55–63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
