<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">jinsuissu</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007470</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Journal of Insurance Issues</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Western Risk and Insurance and the Southern Risk and Insurance Associations</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15316076</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23324244</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26505753</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>ARTICLES</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Culture and Life Insurance Ownership</article-title>
            <subtitle>Is It an Issue?</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Outreville</surname>
                  <given-names>J. François</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="af1">¹</xref>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="af1">
               <label>¹</label>Université Bourgogne Franche-Comté, Burgundy School of Business, Dijon, Francea</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>Fall 2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>41</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26505749</issue-id>
         <fpage>168</fpage>
         <lpage>192</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 by the Western Risk and Insurance Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26505753"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Although life insurance consumption increases from low income group to high income group, there is a substantial variation in life insurance density across-country in each income group. The level of national income can explain peoples’ ability to afford insurance, while cultural traits and the sociopolitical environment not only affect the amount of perceived risk and uncertainty but also influence people’s attitudes and ways of handling perceived risks. The main objective of this paper is to review the definitions of culture to include dimensionalist and non-dimensionalist measures of culture and to investigate how national culture and the sociopolitical environment influence the level of life insurance pervasiveness. The results, based on a representative sample of emerging countries, show that the sociopolitical environment is clearly more important than the limited dimensionalist definition of culture.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Key words:</label> 
            <kwd>Insurance demand</kwd> 
            <kwd>economic growth</kwd> 
            <kwd>cultural distance</kwd> 
            <kwd>governance</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aggarwal, R., C. Kearney, and B. Lucey (2012) “Gravity and Culture in Foreign Portfolio Investment,” Journal of Banking &amp; Finance 36(2): 525–538.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alhassan, A. L. and N. Biekpe (2016) “Determinants of Life Insurance Consumption in Africa,” Research in International Business and Finance 37(1): 17–27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beck, T., and I. Webb (2003) “Economic, Demographic, and Institutional Determinants of Life Insurance Consumption across Countries,” World Bank Economic Review 17(1): 51–88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beugelsdijk, S., T. Kostova, and K. Roth (2017) “An Overview of Hofstede‐Inspired Country‐Level Culture Research in International Business Since 2006,” Journal of International Business Studies 48(1): 30–47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beugelsdijk, S., T. Kostova, V. E. Kunst, E. Spadafora, and M. van Essen (2018) “Cultural Distance and Firm Internationalization: A Meta‐Analytical Review and Theoretical Implications,” Journal of Management 44(1): 89–130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bevan, A. A. and S. Estrin (2004) “The Determinants of Foreign Direct Investment into European Transition Economies,” Journal of Comparative Economics 32(4): 775–787.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bevan, A., S. Estrin, and K. Meyer (2004) “Foreign Investment, Location and Institutional Development in Transition Economies,” International Business Review 13(1): 43–64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brokešová, Z., E. Pastoráková, and T. Ondruška (2014) “Determinants of Insurance Industry Development in Transition Economies: Empirical Analysis of Visegrad Group Data,” Geneva Papers on Risk and Insurance 39(3): 471–492.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brouthers, L. E., V. B. Marshall, and D. L. Keig (2016) “Solving the Single‐Country Sample Problem in Cultural Distance Studies,” Journal of International Business Studies 47(1): 1–9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Browne, M. J. and K. Kim (1993) “An International Analysis of Life Insurance Demand,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 60(4): 616–634.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brügger, B., R. Lalive, A. Steinhauer, and J. Zweimüller (2011) “The Demand for Social Insurance: Does Culture Matter?” University of Zurich, Department of Economics, Working paper 41 (October).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burnett, J. J. and B. A. Palmer (1984) “Examining Life Insurance Ownership Through Demographic and Psychographic Characteristics,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 51(3): 453–467.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chui, A. C. and C. C. Kwok (2008) “National Culture and Life Insurance Consumption,” Journal of International Business Studies 39(1): 88–101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chui, A. C. and C. C. Kwok (2009) “Cultural Practices and Life Insurance Consumption: An International Analysis using GLOBE Scores,” Journal of Multinational Financial Management 19(2): 273–290.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chui, A. C., A. Lloyd, and C. Kwok (2002) “The Determination of Capital Structure: Is National Culture a Missing Piece to the Puzzle?” Journal of International Business Studies 33(1): 99–127.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cole, C. R., R. B. Lee, and K. A. McCullough (2007) “A Test of the Eclectic Paradigm: Evidence from the U.S. Reinsurance Market,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 74(2): 493–522.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dikova, D. and K. Brouthers (2016) “International Establishment Mode Choice: Past, Present and Future,” Management International Review 56(4): 489–530.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Douglas, M. and A. Wildavsky (1982) Risk and Culture, University of California Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dow, D. and A. Karunaratna (2006) “Developing a Multidimensional Instrument to Measure Psychic Distance Stimuli,” Journal of International Business Studies 37(5): 578–602.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dragos, S. L. (2014) “Life and Non‐Life Insurance Demand: The Different Effects of Influence Factors in Emerging Countries from Europe and Asia,” Economic Research—Ekonomska Istraživanja 27(1): 169–180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Drogendijk, R. and A. Slangen (2006) “Hofstede, Schwartz, or Managerial Perceptions? The Effects of Different Cultural Distance Measures on Establishment Mode Choices by Multinational Enterprises,” International Business Review 15(4): 361–380.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eck, J. R. and D. Nizovtsev (2006) “The Impact of Culture on the Purchase of Life Insurance in Latin America and the Caribbean,” International Business and Economics Research Journal 5(1): 31–45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elango, B. and J. Jones (2011) “Drivers of Insurance Demand in Emerging Markets,” Journal of Service Science Research 3(2): 185–204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Esho, N., A. Kirievsky, D. Ward, and R. Zurbruegg (2004) “Law and the Determinants of Property‐Casualty Insurance,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 71(2): 265– 283.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Feyen, E., R. Lester, and R. Rocha (2013) “What Drives the Development of the Insurance Sector? An Empirical Analysis Based on a Panel of Developed and Developing Countries,” Journal of Financial Perspectives 1(1): 1–27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ghemawat, P. (2001) “Distance Still Matters: The Hard Reality of Global Expansion,” Harvard Business Review (September): 137–147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guiso, L., P. Sapienza, and L. Zingales (2007) “Does Culture Affect Economic Outcomes?” Journal of Economic Perspectives 20(2): 23–48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harzing, A. W. and M. Pudelko (2016) “Do We Need to Distance Ourselves from the Distance Concept? Why Home and Host Country Context Might Matter More Than (Cultural) Distance,” Management International Review 56(1): 1–34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Henderson, G. and V. H. Milhouse (1987) International Business and Cultures: A Human Relations Perspective, Cummings &amp; Hathaway.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hill, C. W. L. (2005) International Business: Competing in the Global Marketplace, 5th ed., McGraw Hill Irwin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hofstede, G. (1980) Culture’s Consequence, Sage Publications.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hofstede, G. (1984) Culture’s Consequences: International Differences in Work‐Related Values, Sage Publications.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hofstede, G. (1995) “Insurance as a Product of National Values,” Geneva Papers on Risk and Insurance 77(20): 423–429.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hofstede, G. H. (2001) Culture’s Consequences: Comparing Values, Behaviors, Institutions, and Organizations across Nations, 2nd edition, Sage Publications.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hwang, T., and S. Gao (2003) “The Determinants of the Demand for Life Insurance in an Emerging Economy—The Case of China,” Managerial Finance 29(5/6): 82– 96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hwang, T., and B. Greenford (2005) “A Cross‐Section Analysis of the Determinants of Life Insurance Consumption in Mainland China, Hong‐Kong and Taiwan,” Risk Management and Insurance Review 8(1): 103–125.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inglehart, R. and W. E. Baker (2000) “Modernization, Cultural Change, and the Persistence of Traditional Values,” American Sociological Review 65(1): 19–51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaufmann, D. (2003) “Rethinking Governance: Empirical Lessons Challenge Orthodoxy,” World Bank Research Paper, World Bank, Washington, DC. Available at www.worldbank.org/wbi/governance/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaufmann, D. and A. Kraay (2002) “Growth without Governance,” Economia 3(1): 169–229.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaufmann, D., A. Kraay, and P. Zoido‐Lobaton (2000) “Governance Matters: From Measurement to Action,” Finance and Development 37(2): 10–13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kirkman, B. L., K. B. Lowe, and C. B. Gibson (2006) “A Quarter Century of ‘Culture’s Consequences’: A Review of Empirical Research Incorporating Hofstede’s Cultural Values Framework,” Journal of International Business Studies 37(3): 285–320.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kjosevski, J. (2012) “The Determinants of Life Insurance Demand in Central and Southeastern Europe,” International Journal of Economics and Finance 4(3): 237– 247.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knack, S. and P. Keefer (1995) “Institutions and Economic Performance: Cross‐Country Tests Using Alternative Institutional Measures,” Economic and Politics 7(3): 207–227.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knack, S. and P. Keefer (1997) “Does Social Capital Have an Economic Payoff? A Cross‐Country Investigation,” Quarterly Journal of Economics 112(4): 1251–1288.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kogut, B. and H. Singh (1988) “The Effect of National Culture on the Choice of Entry Mode,” Journal of International Business Studies 19(3): 411–432.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">La Porta, R., F. Lopez‐de‐Silanes, A. Shleifer, and R. Vishny (1997) “Legal Determinants of External Finance,” Journal of Finance 52(3): 1131–1150.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">La Porta, R., F. Lopez‐de‐Silanes, A. Shleifer, and R. Vishny (1998) “Law and Finance,” Journal of Political Economy 106: 1133–1155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, C. C., and Y. B. Chiu (2012) “The Impact of Real Income on Insurance Premiums: Evidence from Panel Data,” International Review of Economics and Finance 21(1): 246–260.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, C‐C., Y.‐B. Chiu, and C.‐H. Chang (2013) “Insurance Demand and Country Risks: A Nonlinear Panel Data Analysis,” Journal of International Money and Finance 36(Sept): 68–85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, S. J., S. I. Kwon, and S. Y. Chung (2010) “Determinants of Household Demand for Insurance: The Case of Korea,” Geneva Papers on Risk and Insurance 35 (Supplement 1): S82–S91.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, D., F. Moshirian, P. Nguyen, and T. Wee (2007) “The Demand for Life Insurance in OECD Countries,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 74(3): 637–652.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, G. (2016a) “The S‐Curve and Reality,” Geneva Papers on Risk and Insurance 41: 608–625.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, G. (2016b) “The Income Elasticity of Non‐Life Insurance: A Reassessment,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 83(2): 335–361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, G. and Carmeci, G. (2015) “A Sub‐Regional Panel Data Analysis of Life Insurance Consumption in Italy,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 82(2): 317–340.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nesterova, D. (2008) Determinants of the Demand for Life Insurance: Evidence from Selected CIS and CEE Countries, Masters thesis, National University “Kyiv‐Mohyla Academy,” Ukraine.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ngwenduna, K. S., M. G. Hayes, and J. Angove (2015) “An Investigation into Life Assurance Markets in Africa,” presented at the Actuarial Society of South Africa’s 2015 Convention,17–18 November.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Njegomir, V. and D. Stojic (2012) “Determinants of Nonlife Insurance Market Attractiveness for Foreign Investments: Eastern European Evidence,” Economic Research—Ekonomska Istraživanja 25(2): 297–310.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Outreville, J. F. (1996) “Life Insurance Markets in Developing Countries,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 63(2): 263–278.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Outreville, J. F. (2008) “Foreign Affiliates of the Largest Insurance Groups: Location‐Specific Advantages,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 75(2): 463–491.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Outreville, J. F. (2013) “The Relationship between Insurance and Economic Development: 85 Empirical Papers for a Review of the Literature,” Risk Management and Insurance Review 16(1): 71–122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Outreville, J. F. (2014) “Risk Aversion, Risk Behavior, and Demand for Insurance: A Survey,” Journal of Insurance Issues 37(2): 158–186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Outreville, J. F. (2015) “The Relationship Between Relative Risk Aversion and the Level of Education: A Survey and Implications for the Demand for Life Insurance,” Journal of Economic Surveys 29(1): 97–111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, H. (1993) “Cultural Impact on Life Insurance Penetration: A Cross‐National Analysis,” International Journal of Management 10(3): 342–350.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, H., S. F. Borde, and Y. Choi (2002) “Determinants of Insurance Pervasiveness: A Cross‐National Analysis,” International Business Review 11(1): 79–96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, S. C. and J. Lemaire (2011) “Culture Matters: Long‐Term Orientation and the Demand for Life Insurance,” Asia‐Pacific Journal of Risk and Insurance 5(2): ISSN (Online) 2153–3792.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, S. C., and J. Lemaire (2012) “The Impact of Culture on the Demand for Non‐Life Insurance,” Astin Bulletin 42(2): 501–527.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reuter, C. H. (2011) “A Survey of ‘Culture and Finance’,” Finance 32(1): 76–152.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rottig, D. (2016) “Institutions and Emerging Markets: Effects and Implications for Multinational Corporations,” International Journal of Emerging Markets 11(1): 2– 17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schwartz, S. H. (1992) “Universals in the Content and Structure of Values: Theory and Empirical Tests in 20 Countries,” in M. Zanna, ed., Advances in Experimental Social Psychology, Vol. 25: pp. 1–65, Academic Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schwartz, S. H. (1994) “Are There Universal Aspects in the Content and Structure of Values?” Journal of Social Issues 50(4): 19–45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref71">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schwartz, S. H. (2004) “Mapping and Interpreting Cultural Differences around the World,” in H. Vinken, J. Soeters, and P. Ester, eds., Comparing Cultures: Dimensions of Culture in a Comparative Perspective, Brill Academic Publishers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref72">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schwartz, S. H. (2006) “A Theory of Cultural Value Orientations: Explication and Applications,” Comparative Sociology 5(2–3): 137–182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref73">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siegel, J. I., A. N. Licht, and S. H. Schwartz (2011) “Egalitarianism and International Investment,” Journal of Financial Economics 102(3): 621–642.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref74">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siegel, J. I., A. N. Licht, and S. H. Schwartz (2013) “Egalitarianism, Cultural Distance, and Foreign Direct Investment: A New Approach,” Organization Science 24(4): 1174–1194.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref75">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Trinh, T. (2016) Non‐Life Insurance Expenditure in Developed and Developing Countries, Ph.D. Thesis, Deakin University, Australia.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref76">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Trinh, T., X. Nguyen, and P. Sgro (2016) “Determinants of Non‐Life Expenditure in Developed and Developing Countries: An Empirical Investigation,” Applied Economics 48(58): 5639–5653.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref77">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vadlamannati, K. (2008) “Do Insurance Sector Growth and Reforms Effect Economic Development? Empirical Evidence from India,” Journal of Applied Economic Research 2(1): 43–86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
