<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">26</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</issue>
         <issue-id>i24464752</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24464754</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>With a Little Help from My (Random) Friends: Success and Failure in Post-Business School Entrepreneurship</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Josh</given-names>
                  <surname>Lerner</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ulrike</given-names>
                  <surname>Malmendier</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2013</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2411</fpage>
         <lpage>2452</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24464754"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>How do individuals decide to become entrepreneurs and learn to make optimal entrepreneurial decisions? The concentration of entrepreneurs in regions such as Silicon Valley has stimulated research and policy interest into the influence of peers, but the causal effect is hard to identify empirically. We exploit the exogenous assignment of students into business-school sections to identify the causal effect of entrepreneurial peers. We show that, in contrast to prior findings, a higher share of entrepreneurial peers decreases, rather than increases, entrepreneurship. The decrease is driven by a reduction in unsuccessful entrepreneurial ventures; the effect on successful ventures is significantly more positive.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1e254a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e261" publication-type="other">
Landier and Thesmar (2009) find that firms run by optimists—a characteristic that has been shown by Evans and
Leighton (1989) to be associated with the decision to become an entrepreneur—grow less, die sooner, and are
less profitable, despite the fact that these owners tend to put in more effort.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e274a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e281" publication-type="other">
Entrepreneurial peers might also introduce section-mates with promising ideas to venture capitalists or other
sources of financing.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e291a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e298" publication-type="other">
Kremer and Levy (2008), for example, study the peer effects of college students who frequently consumed
alcohol prior to college on the GPA of their roommates, and find systematically different effects in the samples
of randomly-assigned and self-selected roommates. Duflo and Saez (2002) analyze the influence of co-workers
on the decision to invest in a retirement account in a setting with endogenous sorting. When they re-analyze the
effect in a randomized experiment (Duflo and Saez 2003), they find significantly smaller (if any) peer effects.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e317a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e324" publication-type="other">
In the context of school outcomes, Sacerdote (2001) finds a significant correlation in the GPAs of randomly-
assigned college roommates but little evidence that roommates' pre-college academic background (SAT scores
and high-school performance) matter. Hence, common shocks due to dorm room characteristics, infections, or
joint class choices might explain part of the results (Kremer and Levy 2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e341a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e348" publication-type="other">
Students were allowed in these years to involve students from other schools but not first-year students. In our
calculations, we consider all pairwise combinations, ignoring non-HBS students. For example, a team consisting
of three students, hailing from sections A, A and C, was regarded as involving three pairs, one of which consisted
of students in the same section and two of which did not. There were 277 student teams consisting of 566 pairs
of second-year students, and 185 of those pairs, or 33%, consisted of section-mates.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e367a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e374" publication-type="other">
http://www.hbs.edu/about/mba.html (accessed September 16, 2011) and unpublished tabulations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e381a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e388" publication-type="other">
Due to software limitations (the program requires an exact match), this category works very poorly. For instance,
it recognizes "McKinsey &amp; Co." or "McKinsey &amp; Company," but not "McKinsey" or "McKinsey Chicago."
Out of approximately 450 admits in the class of 2010 that we examined, the program only recognized the firms
for about 10%. All others were bunched together in "other," along with former entrepreneurs and students who
worked for smaller firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e407a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e414" publication-type="other">
Examples include leadership positions at non-profits (e.g., an associate at a foundation), at for-profit organizations
(e.g., the program director at a sports training academy, the general manager of a number of restaurants, or the
senior manager of new business development at a heathcare firm), and in the military (e.g., junior officers).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e427a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e434" publication-type="other">
The fact that the class card information is drawn from applications alleviates concerns that students exaggerate
their accomplishments. Lying on one's application is a very high-risk strategy, as it can lead to expulsion from the
school or even the voiding of a degree. HBS takes ethics during the application process very seriously: several
years ago, some accepted students who had checked the status of their application on a website earlier than
allowed had their offers rescinded (Broughton 2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e453a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e460" publication-type="other">
This calculation is based on estimates by school administrators. While U.S. Census data suggest that the average
graduate of an undergraduate program is considerably older, the majority of the school's enrollees complete their
undergraduate programs faster. The primary exceptions are Mormon students, who frequently take two years off
from college to serve as missionaries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e477a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e484" publication-type="other">
We use a 60-industry scheme of the hiring and compensation database at HBS Career Services. Students who
worked in multiple industries are coded as having participated in all of them. The results are robust to assigning
each student to a single field—the one in which he or she spent the most time or, if the student worked an equal
amount of time in two fields, the area in which he or she worked most recently.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e500a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e507" publication-type="other">
jVy pjus js an association of administrators of leading schools, which includes the Ivy League schools plus
CalTech, University of Chicago, Duke, MIT, Stanford, and the Universities of Cambridge and Oxford. In
unreported analyses, we also use a classification that adds the top non-U.S. schools, as defined by the Times
Higher Education Supplement, in addition to Cambridge and Oxford: the Ecole Polytechnique and the London
School of Economics. These changes make little difference to the results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e526a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e535" publication-type="other">
The data are based on a survey of 25,000 households in 2003 (62% response rate). Several injury measures are
provided (e.g., total injuries, injuries resulting in an emergency room visit, etc.), which tend to be quite correlated.
For sports not included in the American Sports Data, we substitute the closest sport (e.g., baseball for cricket,
day hiking for orienteering). If there is no comparable listing, we assign the top ranking if they appear to be very
high risk (e.g., motorcycle racing) and the median ranking if they are more moderate (e.g., fencing). We exclude
activities that do not involve physical exertion (e.g., fantasy football and pigeon racing) or are too vague (e.g.,
"athletics" or "all sports").</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e561a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e568" publication-type="other">
Freelance consulting is not counted as starting a business unless there are other consultants working for that
person. We also do not include a small number of cases where students operated franchises as entrepreneurs
since operating a franchise is more similar to running a corporate unit.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e581a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e588" publication-type="other">
Note that the cut-off is lower than in the definition of the success for post-business school entrepreneurship
discussed below. The lower hurdle reflects that students engaging in pre-business school entrepreneurship had a
lower opportunity cost.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e601a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e608" publication-type="other">
In the more expansive samples (all sections or all sections with 40+ class cards), we also replicated our analyses
weighting the observations by the number of class cards. All of our main results are robust to all of these
alternative approaches, though in some cases the levels of statistical significance are lower, which is consistent
with underlying selection bias. All replication tables are available from the authors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e625a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e632" publication-type="other">
The variation in the share of investment bankers (10th versus 90th percentile) reflects in large part time-series
variation, i.e., the ebb-and-flow of these admits across classes, rather than inter-section differences.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e642a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e651" publication-type="other">
The survey does not capture students who drop out without completing a degree. This (very small) fraction,
typically considerably under 1 %, overwhelmingly represents students who leave the program involuntarily due
to poor academic performance. Even at the peak of the Internet boom, only a handful of students permanently
left school before graduation to pursue an entrepreneurial opportunity.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e667a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e674" publication-type="other">
We use a 30% rate in the results reported in the paper, based on the Rock Center survey described below. In
unreported analyses, we also use other rates, e.g., 23% as suggested by our class card data (see Panel B of
Table 2), and find little impact.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e687a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e694" publication-type="other">
While we would have liked to determine the success as of a set time after graduation (e.g., three years after
degree completion), this information proved infeasible to gather.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e704a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e711" publication-type="other">
According to Thomson Reuters SDC data, the median multiple of valuation to the last 12 months revenues in all
U.S. IPOs between 1997 to 2004 was 1.55; when excluding the "bubble years" of 1999 and 2000, it was 0.99.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e721a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e728" publication-type="other">
The survey used a "viral" approach, whereby known entrepreneurs were asked to identify other entrepreneurs
among their classmates, and encourage them to complete the survey. Alumni were initially contacted via email in
January 2005. Non-respondents were contacted three times via email and telephone. Overall, 41% of all contacted
students participated. This rate is consistent with or above the level of responses typical in social science studies
of this cohort (Baruch 1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e748a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e755" publication-type="other">
An alternative approach would have been to define all variables only for individuals with general management
experience. We cannot implement the alternative specification since we do not have outcome variables by
individual, or for the subset of individuals with general management experience.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e768a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e775" publication-type="other">
This is calculated by subtracting out the number of pre-and-post-MB A entrepreneurs (the first of the two possible
corrective methodologies described in Section 2).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e785a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e792" publication-type="other">
While we believe that we identified a virtually comprehensive list of successful HBS entrepreneurs from the
classes in our sample, a similar approach is not feasible for unsuccessful entrepreneurs. Unsuccessful ventures
are much less visible after failure, and participants are often unwilling to disclose their failure (e.g., in response
to a survey request).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e808a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e815" publication-type="other">
The calculation of the success rate excludes sections with no post-MBA entrepreneurship.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e822a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e829" publication-type="other">
The information on Guru.com was obtained from http://www.venturexpert.com (accessed September 16, 2011),
Factiva, and other on-line sources.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e839a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e846" publication-type="other">
Because the number of electives shifted over time, and the number of sections with 70 or more class cards is
not evenly distributed, we repeated these analyses for all sections and for the set of the sections with 40 or more
class cards. We use weighted and unweighted data. The results are the same.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1e868a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e872" publication-type="other">
American Sports Data. 2005. A Comprehensive Study of Sports Injuries in the U.S. Cortlandt Manor, NY: American
Sports Data.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e882a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e886" publication-type="other">
Arabsheibani, G, D. De Meza, J. Maloney, and B. Pearson. 2000. And a vision appeared unto them of a great
profit: Evidence of self-deception among the self-employed. Economic Letters 67:35-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e896a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e900" publication-type="other">
Baruch, Y. 1999. Response rates in academic studies—a comparative analysis. Human Relations 52:421-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e907a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e911" publication-type="other">
Bernardo, A., and I. Welch. 2001. On the evolution of overconfidence and entrepreneurship. Journal of Economics
&amp; Management Strategy 10:301-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e922a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e926" publication-type="other">
Bhide, A. 2003. The Origins and Evolution of New Businesses. New York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e933a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e937" publication-type="other">
Brav, A., and P. Gompers. 1997. Myth or reality? The long-run underperformance of initial public offerings:
Evidence from venture and nonventure capital-backed companies. Journal of Finance 52:1791-821.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e947a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e951" publication-type="other">
Broughton, P. D. 2008. Ahead of the Curve: Two Years at Harvard Business School. New York: Penguin.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e958a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e962" publication-type="other">
Camerer, C., and D. Lovallo. 1999. Overconfidence and excess entry: An experimental approach. American
Economic Review 89:306-18.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e972a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e976" publication-type="other">
Cohen, L., A. Frazzini, and C. J. Malloy. 2008. The small world of investing: Board connections and mutual
fund returns. Journal of Political Economy 116:951-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e986a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e990" publication-type="other">
. 2010. Sell-side school ties. Journal of Finance 65:1409-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e998a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1002" publication-type="other">
Cruikshank, J. L. 2005. Shaping the Waves: A History of Entrepreneurship at Harvard Business School. Boston:
Harvard Business School Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1012a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1016" publication-type="other">
Davis, S. J., J. C. Haltiwanger, and S. Schuh. 1998. Job Creation and Destruction. Cambridge, Massachusetts:
MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1026a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1030" publication-type="other">
De Meza, D., and C. Southey. 1996. The borrower's curse: Optimism, finance, and entrepreneurship. Economic
Journal 106:375-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1040a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1044" publication-type="other">
Djankov, S., R. La Porta, F. Lopez-de-Silanes, and A. Shleifer. 2002. The regulation of entry. Quarterly Journal
of Economics 117:1-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1054a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1058" publication-type="other">
Duflo, E-, and E. Saez. 2002. Participation and investment decisions in a retirement plan: The influence of
colleagues' choices. Journal of Public Economics 85:121-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1068a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1072" publication-type="other">
. 2003. The role of information and social interactions in retirement plan decisions: Evidence from a
randomized experiment. Quarterly Journal of Economics 118:815-42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1083a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1087" publication-type="other">
Eesley, C., D. Hsu, and E. Roberts. 2007. Entrepreneurs from technology-based universities: Evidence from
MIT. Research Policy 36:768-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1097a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1101" publication-type="other">
Evans, D. S., and L. S. Leighton. 1989. Some empirical aspects of entrepreneurship. American Economic Review
79:519-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1111a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1115" publication-type="other">
Ewing, D. W. 1990. Inside Harvard Business School: Strategies and Lessons of America's Leading School of
Business. New York: Times Books.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1125a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1129" publication-type="other">
Giannetti, M., and A. Simonov. 2009. Social interactions and entrepreneurial activity. Journal of Economics and
Management Strategy 18:665-709.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1139a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1143" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P. A., A. Kovner, J. Lerner, and D. Scharfstein. 2010. Performance persistence in entrepreneurship.
Journal of Financial Economics 96:18-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1153a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1157" publication-type="other">
. 2008. Venture capital investment cycles: The impact of public markets. Journal of Financial Economics
87:1-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1168a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1172" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P. A., J. Lerner, and D. Scharfstein. 2005. Entrepreneurial spawning: Public corporations and the
genesis of new ventures, 1986 to 1999. Journal of Finance 60:577-614.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1182a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1186" publication-type="other">
Hall, R. E., and S. E. Woodward. 2010. The burden of the nondiversifiable risk of entrepreneurship. American
Economic Review 100:1163-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1196a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1200" publication-type="other">
Hamilton, B. 2000. Does entrepreneurship pay? An empirical analysis of the returns to self-employment. Journal
of Political Economy 108: 604-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1210a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1214" publication-type="other">
Hurst, E. K., and B. W. Pugsley. Forthcoming. What do small businesses do? Brookings Papers on Economic
Activity.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1224a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1228" publication-type="other">
Jovanovic, B. 1982. Selection and the evolution of industry. Econometrica 50:649-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1235a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1239" publication-type="other">
Kanniainen, V., and C. Keuschnigg. 2004. Venture Capital, Entrepreneurship, and Public Policy. Cambridge,
Massachusetts: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1250a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1254" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S. and A. Schoar. 2005. Private equity performance: Returns, persistence, and capital flows. Journal of
Finance 60:1791 -823.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1264a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1268" publication-type="other">
Katz, J. A. 2004. Survey of Endowed Positions in Entrepreneurship and Related Fields in the United States. St
Louis, Missouri: J. A. Katz and Associates.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1278a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1282" publication-type="other">
Kerr, W., J. Lerner and A. Schoar. Forthcoming. The consequences of entrepreneurial finance: Evidence from
angel financings. Review of Financial Studies.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1292a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1296" publication-type="other">
Korteweg, A. and M. Sorensen. 2010. Risk and return characteristics of venture capital-backed entrepreneurial
companies. Review of Financial Studies 23:3738-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1306a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1310" publication-type="other">
Kremer, M. and D. Levy. 2008. Peer effects and alcohol use among college students. Journal of Economic
Perspectives 22:189-206.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1320a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1324" publication-type="other">
Landier, A., and D. Thesmar. 2009. Financial contracting with optimistic entrepreneurs: Theory and evidence.
Review of Financial Studies 22:117-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1335a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1339" publication-type="other">
Manski, C. F. 1993. Identification of endogenous social effects: The reflection problem. Review of Economic
Studies 60:531-42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1349a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1353" publication-type="other">
Moskowitz, T. and A. Vissing-Jorgensen. 2002. The returns to entrepreneurial investment: A private equity
premium puzzle? American Economic Review 92:745-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1363a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1367" publication-type="other">
Nanda, R., and J. Sorensen. 2010. Workplace peer effects and entrepreneurship. Management Science 56:1116-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1374a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1378" publication-type="other">
National Venture Capital Association. 2005. 2005 Venture Capital Yearbook. Newark, New Jersey: Venture
Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1388a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1392" publication-type="other">
Orth, C. D., III. 1963. Social Structure and Learning Climate: The First Year at the Harvard Business School.
Boston: Division of Research, Graduate School of Business Administration, Harvard University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1402a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1406" publication-type="other">
Parker, S. C. 2004. The Economics of Self-Employment and Entrepreneurship. New York: Cambridge University
Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1417a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1421" publication-type="other">
Phalippou, L., and O. Gottschalg. 2009. The performance of private equity funds. Review of Financial Studies
22:1747-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1431a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1435" publication-type="other">
Ritter, J. 1991. The long-run performance of initial public offerings. Journal of Finance 46:3-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1442a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1446" publication-type="other">
Sacerdote, B. 2001. Peer effects with random assignment: Results for dartmouth roommates. Quarterly Journal
of Economics 116: 681-704.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1456a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1460" publication-type="other">
Shue, K. 2011. Executive networks and firm policies: Evidence from the random assignment of MBA peers.
Unpublished Paper, Harvard University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


