<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26169169</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Internal Cell Temperature Measurement and Thermal Modeling of Lithium Ion Cells for Automotive Applications by Means of Electrochemical Impedance Spectroscopy</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Haussmann</surname>
                  <given-names>Peter</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Melbert</surname>
                  <given-names>Joachim</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Ruhr-University Bochum</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>July 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>6</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26169161</issue-id>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169169"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Battery safety is the most critical requirement for the energy storage systems in hybrid and electric vehicles. The allowable battery temperature is limited with respect to the battery chemistry in order to avoid the risk of thermal runaway. Battery temperature monitoring is already implemented in electric vehicles, however only cell surface temperature can be measured at reasonable cost using conventional sensors. The internal cell temperature may exceed the surface temperature significantly at high current due to the finite internal electrical and thermal cell resistance. In this work, a novel approach for internal cell temperature measurement is proposed applying on board impedance spectroscopy. The method considers the temperature coefficient of the complex internal cell impedance. It can be observed by current and voltage measurements as usually performed by standard battery management systems. The relevant frequency range considered for temperature measurements is chosen for high sensitivity and robust behavior and takes state of charge variations as well as aging effects into account. Transient temperature variations caused by various load profiles are analyzed in order to characterize the static and dynamic thermal properties of the cell. The resulting thermal equivalent model describes temperature changes inside the cell dependent on load current and ambient temperature. The temperature measurement approach and the thermal model are suitable for on board implementation in battery management systems. A dedicated battery excitation is not required, as signal components in the relevant frequency range are inherently present in typical driving current profiles. Thereby, significant improvements in terms of on-board diagnostics and battery safety can be achieved without any additional hardware effort.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, G., Ge, S., Xu, T., Yang, X.-G. , “Rapid self-heating and internal temperature sensing of lithium-ion batteries at low temperatures,” Electrochimica Acta 218:149–155, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.electacta.2016.09.117.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, P., Zhang, X., Yang Le, Zhang, X. , “Real-time monitoring of internal temperature evolution of the lithium-ion coin cell battery during the charge and discharge process,” Extreme Mechanics Letters, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.eml.2016.03.013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Richardson, R.R., Ireland, P.T., and Howey, D.A., “Battery internal temperature estimation by combined impedance and surface temperature measurement,” Journal of Power Sources 265:254–261, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.jpowsour.2014.04.129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lohmann, N., Haussmann, P., Wesskamp, P., Melbert, J.., "Employing Real Automotive Driving Data for Electrochemical Impedance Spectroscopy on Lithium-Ion Cells," SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 4(2):308–317, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1187.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dey, S., Biron, Z.A., Tatipamula, S., Das, N.., “Model-based real-time thermal fault diagnosis of Lithium-ion batteries,” Control Engineering Practice 56:37–48, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.conengprac.2016.08.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pesaran, A.A., “Battery thermal models for hybrid vehicle simulations,” Journal of Power Sources 110(2):377–382, 2002, doi:10.1016/S0378-7753(02)00200-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lohmann, N., Weßkamp, P., Haußmann, P., Melbert, J. , “Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy for lithium-ion cells: Test equipment and procedures for aging and fast characterization in time and frequency domain,” Journal of Power Sources 273:613–623, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.jpowsour.2014.09.132.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weßkamp, P., Haußmann, P., and Melbert, J., “600-A Test System for Aging Analysis of Automotive Li-Ion Cells With High Resolution and Wide Bandwidth,” IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas. 65(7):1651–1660, 2016, doi:10.1109/TIM.2016.2534379.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haußmann, P. and Melbert, J., “Impedance spectroscopy on lithium ion cells for automotive applications with optimized measurement duration and frequency resolution,” in: 18. GMA/ITG-Fach-ta-gung Sen-so-ren und Mess-sys-te-me, Nürn-berg, AMA Ser-vice GmbH:308–315.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmidt, J.P., Weber, A., and Ivers-Tiffée, E., “A novel and precise measuring method for the entropy of lithium-ion cells: ΔS via electrothermal impedance spectroscopy,” Electrochimica Acta 137:311–319, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.electacta.2014.05.153.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thomas, K.E. and Newman, J., “Thermal Modeling of Porous Insertion Electrodes,” J. Electrochem. Soc. 150(2):A176, 2003, doi:10.1149/1.1531194.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hu, X., Lin, S., Stanton, S., and Lian, W., “A Foster Network Thermal Model for HEV/EV Battery Modeling,” IEEE Trans. on Ind. Applicat. 47(4):1692–1699, 2011, doi:10.1109/TIA.2011.2155012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Samba, A., Omar, N., Gualous, H., Firouz, Y. , “Development of an Advanced Two-Dimensional Thermal Model for Large size Lithium-ion Pouch Cells,” Electrochimica Acta 117:246–254, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.electacta.2013.11.113.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chiang, Y.-H., Sean, W.-Y., and Ke, J.-C., “Online estimation of internal resistance and open-circuit voltage of lithium-ion batteries in electric vehicles,” Journal of Power Sources 196(8):3921–3932, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.jpowsour.2011.01.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
