<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="other"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">3663728</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/377036</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB760408</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Notes</article-title>
            <subtitle>University Schools of Business</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2003</year>
            <string-date>October 2003</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>76</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2003.76.issue-4</issue-id>
         <fpage>699</fpage>
         <lpage>703</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/377036"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <title>Appointments</title>
         <p>Jeffrey Anderson, instructor, Ohio Univ., July 2001.</p>
         <p>Thomas M. Arnold, asst. prof., finance, Richmond, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Eric J. Arnould, interim director, agribusiness programs, and prof., marketing, Nebraska—Lincoln, Jan. 2003.</p>
         <p>Nathasha Burns, asst. prof., Univ. Georgia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Laura Cardinal, assoc. prof., Tulane, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Huseyin Cavusoglu, asst. prof., Tulane, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Sudheer Chava, asst. prof., finance, Houston, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Hugh Courtney, teaching prof., Maryland, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Dean D. Croushore, assoc. prof., economics, and Rigsby Fellow in economics, Richmond, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Prabuddha De, Accenture Professor, information technology, Purdue, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Martin Dierker, asst. prof., finance, Houston, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Rita Durant, visiting asst. prof., Tulane, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Nancy M. Epling, asst. prof., business economics and public policy, Indiana, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Amit Eynan, prof., management systems, Richmond, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Juan Feng, asst. prof., Univ. Florida, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Chitru Fernando, assoc. prof., finance, Univ. Oklahoma, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Raymond P. H. Fishe, prof. and distinguished chair, finance, Richmond, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Karen Foust, clinical prof., Tulane, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Amanda Friedenberg, asst. prof., economics, Washington Univ., July 2003.</p>
         <p>William L. Gardner III, Howard Hawks Chair in ethics and leadership and prof., management, Nebraska—Lincoln, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Gautam Gowrisankaram, asst. prof., economics, Washington Univ., July 2003.</p>
         <p>Nandini Gupta, asst. prof., finance, Indiana, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Dirk Hackbarth, asst. prof., finance, Indiana, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Yufeng Han, asst. prof., Tulane, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Rich Hanna, asst. prof., Boston College, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Carrie Heilman, asst. prof., marketing, Washington Univ., July 2003.</p>
         <p>James Hess, Bauer Professor, marketing and entrepreneurship, Houston, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Leslie Hodder, asst. prof., accounting, Indiana, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Dana Hollie, asst. prof., accounting/taxation, Houston, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>John S. Howe, Missouri Bankers Chair, Missouri—Columbia, Jan. 2003.</p>
         <p>Paul Irvine, asst. prof., Univ. Georgia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Norman Johnson, asst. prof., DISC, Houston, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Iris M. Junglas, asst. prof., decision and information sciences, Houston, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Adwait Khare, asst. prof., marketing and entrepreneurship, Houston, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Monika Kukar‐Kinney, asst. prof., marketing, Richmond, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Tim Landry, asst. prof., marketing and supply chain management, Univ. Oklahoma, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Robyn LeBoeuf, asst. prof., Univ. Florida, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Dmitry Livdan, asst. prof., finance, Houston, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Charles L. Martin, Jr., visiting prof., Maryland, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Sean McGann, visiting asst. prof., Ohio Univ., Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Elizabeth Gelfand Miller, asst. prof., Boston College, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Soonhong Min, asst. prof., marketing and supply chain management, Univ. Oklahoma, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Debanjan Mitra, asst. prof., Univ. Florida, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>David L. Nasser, teaching prof., Maryland, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Xing Pan, asst. prof., Marketing, Indiana, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Elizabeth Plummer, asst. prof., Univ. North Texas, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Mattias Polborn, asst. prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Janya Portniaguina, asst. prof., finance, Univ. Oklahoma, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Kislaya Prasad, visiting assoc. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Andrew Prevost, asst. prof., Ohio Univ., Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Linda L. Price, chair and E. J. Faulkner Professor, marketing, Nebraska—Lincoln, Jan. 2003.</p>
         <p>John Puthenpurackal, asst. prof., Ohio Univ., Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Ryan Quinn, asst. prof., organizational behavior, Washington Univ., July 2003.</p>
         <p>Leonardo Rezende, asst. prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Glenn R. Richey, Jr., asst. prof., Alabama, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Asleigh Shelby Rosette, asst. prof., management, Houston, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Raja Roy, asst. prof., Tulane, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Amit Saini, asst. prof., marketing, Nebraska—Lincoln, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Dan E. Schendel, Blake Family Endowed Chair in strategic management, Purdue, Feb. 2003.</p>
         <p>Kathleen Seiders, assoc. prof., Boston College, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Myeong‐Gu Seo, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Debra L. Shapiro, prof., Maryland, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Geoff Steward, asst. prof., marketing and supply chain management, Univ. Oklahoma, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Jill M. Sundie, asst. prof., marketing and entrepreneurship, Houston, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Brett Trueman, prof., UCLA, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Andrey D. Ukhov, asst. prof., finance, Indiana, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Valaria P. Vendryzk, assoc. prof., accounting, Richmond, Aug. 2003.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <title>Leaves</title>
         <p>S. Christopher Albright, prof., operations and decision technology, Indiana; Fall 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Michael Baye, prof., economics and public policy, Indiana; Fall 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Anil Bera, prof., economics, Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign; Jan. 2004–May 2004; sabbatical leave for research on hypothesis testing with misspecified models and complete ongoing work on Neyman's Smooth Test and history of statistics and econometrics.</p>
         <p>Utpal Bhattacharya, assoc. prof., finance, Indiana; academic year 2003–4; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Bradford Cornell, prof., UCLA, April 2004‐June 2004; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Catherine Daily, prof., management, Indiana; Fall 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Aimee L. Drolet, asst. prof., UCLA; Jan. 2004‐Mar. 2004; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Sebastian Edwards, prof., UCLA; Oct. 2003‐Dec. 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Eric G. Flamholtz, prof., UCLA; Oct. 2003‐Dec. 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Michele Fratianni, chair, business economics and public policy, Indiana; Fall 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>J. Fred Giertz, prof., department of economics and institute of government and public affairs, Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign; Jan. 2004–May 2004; sabbatical leave to study a long‐standing interest concerning the centralization and decentralization of state (regional) and local governments in the United States and other federal countries.</p>
         <p>Lester Heitger, prof., accounting, Indiana; Fall 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>John Hogan, asst. prof., Boston College; July 2003–July 2004; spending a year at the Strategic Pricing Group.</p>
         <p>Matthias Kahl, asst. prof., UCLA; July 2003–June 2004; special leave.</p>
         <p>Edward E. Leamer, prof., UCLA; Jan. 2004–June 2004; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Anne Massey, chair, information systems, Indiana; Spring 2004; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Kevin F. McCardle, prof., UCLA; Jan. 2004–Mar. 2004; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Bruce L. Miller, prof., UCLA; Apr. 2004–June 2004; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Monika Piazzesi, asst. prof., UCLA; July 2003–June 2004; special leave.</p>
         <p>William P. Pierskalla, prof., UCLA; Oct. 2003–Dec. 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Avanidhar Subrahmanyan, prof., UCLA; July 2003–June 2004; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Iris Vessey, prof., information systems, Indiana; academic year 2003–4; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Anne Villamil, prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign; Jan. 2004–May 2004; sabbatical leave to conduct research on the effect of the legal system on firm finance—to develop computable contract model to analyze the effect of alternative policy proposals on firm finance.</p>
         <p>Dwight Worker, lecturer, information systems, Indiana; Spring 2003; leave (with pay).</p>
         <p>Nicholas Yannelis, prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign; Jan. 2004–May 2004; sabbatical leave to conduct research activities, in particular to complete a book as well as new research papers.</p>
         <p>Shi Zhang, asst. prof., UCLA; Apr. 2004–June 2004; sabbatical.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <title>Promotions</title>
         <p>Charalambos Aliprantis, distinguished prof., economics, Purdue, Feb. 2003.</p>
         <p>John Aloysius, assoc. prof. (with tenure), Arkansas, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Gurdip S. Bakshi, prof., Maryland, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Dennis Bozeman, assoc. prof., management, Houston, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>J. Stuart Bunderson, assoc. prof., organizational behavior, Washington Univ., July 2003.</p>
         <p>Zhi‐Long Chen, assoc. prof. (with tenure), Maryland, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>C. Mitchell Conover, assoc. prof., finance, Richmond, Mar. 2003.</p>
         <p>Randolph Cooper, prof., decision and information sciences, Houston, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Charles J. Corbett, assoc. prof., UCLA, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Thomas J. Cossé, prof., marketing, assoc. dean of international business programs, and CSX Chair in management and accounting, Richmond, 2003–4.</p>
         <p>Martin E. Dresner, prof., Maryland, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>John H. Earl, Jr., assoc. prof., finance and David Meade White Distinguished Teaching Fellow, Richmond, 2003–4.</p>
         <p>Louis Ederington, Michael F. Price Chair no. 3, Univ. Oklahoma, Mar. 2003.</p>
         <p>Teri Elkins, assoc. prof., management, Houston, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Gary W. Emery, Michael F. Price Professor, finance, and senior assoc. dean, Univ. Oklahoma, July 2002.</p>
         <p>David Haeberle, clinical asst. prof., finance, Indiana, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Andreas Hauskrecht, clinical asst. prof., business economics and public policy, Indiana, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Robert Jennings, chair, finance, Indiana, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Idalene Kesner, chair, MBA programs, Indiana, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Ilene K. Kleinsorge, Sara Hart Kimball Dean, Oregon State, Mar. 2003.</p>
         <p>Parthasarathy Krishnamurthy, assoc. prof., marketing and entrepreneurship, Houston, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Katherine Lemon, assoc. prof., Boston College, Apr. 2003.</p>
         <p>Scott O'Leary‐Kelly, assoc. prof. (with tenure), Arkansas, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Cynthia K. Riemenschneider, assoc. prof. (with tenure), Arkansas, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Daniel Smith, assoc. dean of academics, Indiana, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Rosann Spiro, chair, marketing, Indiana, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Harish Sujan, full prof., Tulane, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Paul E. Tesluk, assoc. prof. (with tenure), Maryland, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Mary Waller, assoc. prof. (with tenure), Tulane, July 2003.</p>
         <p>James Wimbush, chair, management, Indiana, Aug. 2003.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <title>Resignations</title>
         <p>Amy Dittmar, asst. prof., finance, Indiana, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Robert Dittmar, asst. prof., finance, Indiana, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Amit Eynan, assoc. prof., operations and manufacturing management, Washington Univ., June 2003.</p>
         <p>V. Padmanabhan, Wallace prof., marketing, Washington Univ., June 2003.</p>
         <p>David M. Porter, asst. prof., UCLA, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Richard Rosen, asst. prof., finance, Indiana, May 2003.</p>
         <p>Sung‐Soo Yoon, asst. prof., UCLA, July 2003.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc5">
         <title>Retirements</title>
         <p>Jose de le Torre, prof., UCLA, March 2003.</p>
         <p>Martin J. Gannon, prof., Maryland, July 2003.</p>
         <p>John W. Goebel, prof., accountancy and business law, Nebraska—Lincoln, May 2003.</p>
         <p>F. Charles Lamphear, director, Bureau of Business Research, Nebraska—Lincoln, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Wayne Shafer, prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, May 2003.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc6">
         <title>Deaths</title>
         <p>Dean H. Kropp, Broida Professor of Operations and Manufacturing Management, Washington Univ.; April 11, 2003; St. Louis.</p>
      </sec>
   </body>
</article>
