<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26649127</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Computational Study of Abnormal Combustion Characteristics in Spark Ignition Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ali</surname>
                  <given-names>Mohammed Jaasim Mubarak</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sow</surname>
                  <given-names>Aliou</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pérez</surname>
                  <given-names>Francisco E. Hernández</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Im</surname>
                  <given-names>Hong Guen</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">11</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26649117</issue-id>
         <fpage>743</fpage>
         <lpage>756</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26649127"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Super-knock that occurs in spark ignition (SI) engines is investigated using two-dimensional (2D) numerical simulations. The temperature, pressure, velocity, and mixture distributions are obtained and mapped from a top dead center (TDC) slice of full-cycle three-dimensional (3D) engine simulations. Ignition is triggered at one end of the cylinder and a hot spot of known temperature was used to initiate a pre-ignition front to study super-knock. The computational fluid dynamics code CONVERGE was used for the simulations. A minimum grid size of 25 μm was employed to capture the shock wave and detonation inside the domain. The Reynolds-averaged Navier-Stokes (RANS) method was employed to represent the turbulent flow and gas-phase combustion chemistry was represented using a reduced chemical kinetic mechanism for primary reference fuels. A multi-zone model, based on a well-stirred reactor assumption, was used to solve the reaction terms. Hot spots introduced inside the domain at various initial temperatures initiated a pre-ignition front, which resulted in super-knock due to detonation of the end gas. The detonation was induced for temperatures greater than 1000 K during the start of pre-ignition flame propagation. The detonation speed was around 2000 m/s, at temperatures higher than 1000 K. For temperatures between 800 K and 1000 K, detonation was observed near the end of combustion. The laminar pre-ignition flame front speed calculated from the simulations was an order of magnitude higher than the one-dimensional laminar flame speed, which is characteristic of sequential auto-ignition. Multiple auto-ignition sites in the end-gas region were observed at higher temperatures. The auto-ignition location initiated an auto-ignition front of higher velocity that later transitioned into detonation. Interaction between the detonating fronts generated local pressure peaks inside the domain. End-gas reactivity was characterized by the formation of formaldehyde (CH₂O) and was an indicator for occurrence of auto-ignition/detonation. Negative temperature coefficient regimes (750 K-850 K) exhibited higher mass fraction of CH₂O indicating enhanced reactivity of end gas, leading to highest peak pressures during detonation onset. The low-temperature case, 700 K, exhibited a deflagration mode of flame propagation without detonation development. The results were analyzed and reported by comparison with Bradley diagram, which predicted a deflagration mode of combustion for the lowest temperature case, and developing a detonation mode for all other cases considered in this study.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c1">G.T.S. WEC, 2050, World Energy Council, Londons, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Chen, Y. and Raine, R., “Engine Knock in an SI Engine with Hydrogen Supplementation under Stoichiometric and Lean Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):595-605, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1220.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Alger, T., Mangold, B., Roberts, C., and Gingrich, J., “The Interaction of Fuel Anti-Knock Index and Cooled EGR on Engine Performance and Efficiency,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1229-1241, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bradley, D., “Hot Spots and Gasoline Engine Knock, Journal of the Chemical Society,” Faraday Transactions 92:2959- 2964, 1996, doi:10.1039/FT9969202959.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Chen, L., Li, T., Yin, T., and Zheng, B., “A Predictive Model for Knock Onset in Spark-Ignition Engines with Cooled EGR,” Energy Convers Manag 87:946-955, 2014, doi:10.1016/j. enconman.2014.08.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Da Silva, R., Cataluna, R., de Menezes, E.W., Samios, D. et al., “Effect of Additives on the Antiknock Properties and Reid Vapor Pressure of Gasoline,” Fuel 84:951-959, 2005, doi:/10.1016/j.fuel.2005.01.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Grandin, B. and Denbratt, I., “The Effect of Knock on Heat Transfer in SI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0238, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0238.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Peyton Jones, J., Muske, K., Frey, J., and Scholl, D., “A Stochastic Knock Control Algorithm,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1017, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Vallinayagam, R., Vedharaj, S., Naser, N., Roberts, W.L. et al., “Terpineol as a Novel Octane Booster for Extending the Knock Limit of Gasoline,” Fuel 187:9-15, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2016.09.034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Caton, P., Hamilton, L., and Cowart, J., “An Experimental and Modeling Investigation into the Comparative Knock and Performance Characteristics of E85, Gasohol [E10] and Regular Unleaded Gasoline [87 (R+M)/2],” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0473, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0473.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Khalil, S., Camal, R., Olivier, L., and Laurent, T., “Description of Knock Limit in a CFR Engine: Effects of Engine Settings and Gas Quality,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2620, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2620.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Lecointe, B. and Monnier, G., “Downsizing a Gasoline Engine Using Turbocharging with Direct Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0542, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0542.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Leduc, P., Dubar, B., Ranini, A., and Monnier, G., “Downsizing of Gasoline Engine: An Efficient Way to Reduce CO2 Emissions,” Oil Gas Sci. Technol. 58:115-127, 2003, doi:10.2516/ogst:2003008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Dahnz, C., Han, K., Spicher, U., Magar, M. et al., “Investigations on Pre-Ignition in Highly Supercharged SI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):214-224, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Ranjith Kumar, T. and Yadav, A., “New Control Strategies to Avoid Pre-Ignition in Higher CR Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-28-0004, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-28-0004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Gupta, A., Shao, H., Remias, J., Roos, J. et al., “Relative Impact of Chemical and Physical Properties of the Oil-Fuel Droplet on Pre-Ignition and Super-Knock in Turbocharged Gasoline Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-2278, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-2278.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Kassai, M., Torii, K., Shiraishi, T., Noda, T. et al., “Research on the Effect of Lubricant Oil and Fuel Properties on LSPI Occurrence in Boosted S. I. Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-2292, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-2292.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Mayer, M., Hofmann, P., Geringer, B., Williams, J. et al., “Influence of Different Oil Properties on Low-Speed Pre- Ignition in Turbocharged Direct Injection Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0718, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0718.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Qi, Y., Xu, Y., Wang, Z., and Wang, J., “The Effect of Oil Intrusion on Super Knock in Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1224, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01- 1224.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Haenel, P., Kleeberg, H., de Bruijn, R., and Tomazic, D., “Influence of Ethanol Blends on Low Speed Pre-Ignition in Turbocharged, Direct-Injection Gasoline Engines,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 10(1):95-105, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0687.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Wang, Z., Liu, H., Song, T., Qi, Y. et al., “Relationship between Super-Knock and Pre-Ignition,” Int. J. Eng. Res. 16:166-180, 2015, doi:10.1177/1468087414530388.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Heron, S. and Gillig, F., “Supercharged Knock Testing,” 2nd World Petroleum Congress, World Petroleum Congress, 1937.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Rothrock, A. M., Biermann, A. E., “The Knocking Characteristics of Fuels in Relation to Maximum Permissible Performance of Aircraft Engines,” NACA Technical Report 655, 1939.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Gao, Y. and Chen, Z., “Autoignition and Detonation Development from a Hot Spot in Hydrogen/Air Mixture,” 26th ICDERS, Boston, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Wang, Z., Qi, Y., He, X., Wang, J. et al., “Analysis of Pre- Ignition to Super-Knock: Hot Spot-Induced Deflagration to Detonation,” Fuel 144:222-227, 2014, doi:10.1016/j. fuel.2014.12.061.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Kalghatgi, G., Bradley, D., Andrae, J., Harrison, A., “The Nature of ‘superknock’and its Origins in SI Engines,” Proceedings of the Conference on Internal Combustion Engines: Performance, Fuel Economy and Emissions, London, UK, Dec. 9, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Pan, J., Wei, H., Shu, G., and Chen, T., “Effect of Pressure Wave Disturbance on Auto-Ignition Mode Transition and Knocking Intensity under Enclosed Conditions,” Combust. Flame 185:63-74, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2017.07.004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Bates, L. and Bradley, D., “Deflagrative, Auto-Ignitive, and Detonative Propagation Regimes in Engines,” Combust. Flame 175:118-122, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2016.05.023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Bates, L., Bradley, D., Paczko, G., and Peters, N., “Engine Hot Spots: Modes of Auto-Ignition and Reaction Propagation,” Combust. Flame 166:80-85, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2016.05.023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Sow, A., Lee, B.J., and Im, H.G., “A Computational Study of the End Gas Autoignition and Shock Development by Flame Front and Local Hot Spot,” 26th ICDERS, Boston, MA, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Javed, T., Badra, J., Jaasim, M., Es-Sebbar, E. et al., “Shock Tube Ignition Delay Data Affected by Localized Ignition Phenomena,” Combust. Sci. Tech. 1138-1161, 2016, doi:10.108 0/00102202.2016.1272599.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Mubarak Ali, M., Hernandez Perez, F., Vedharaj, S., Vallinayagam, R. et al., “Effect of Timing and Location of Hotspot on Super Knock during Pre-Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-0686, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0686.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Babajimopoulos, A., Assanis, D., Flowers, D., and Aceves, S., “A Fully Coupled Computational Fluid Dynamics and Multi-Zone Model with Detailed Chemical Kinetics for the Simulation of Premixed Charge Compression Ignition Engines,” Int. J. Eng. Res. 6:497-512, 2005, doi:10.1243/146808705X30503.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Liu, Y.D., Jia, M., Xie, M.Z., and Pang, B., “Development of a New Skeletal Chemical Kinetic Model of Toluene Reference Fuel with Application to Gasoline Surrogate Fuels for Computational Fluid Dynamics Engine Simulation,” Energy &amp; Fuels 27:4899-4909, 2013, doi:10.1021/ef4009955.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Richards, K., Senecal, P., and Pomraning, E., CONVERGE 2.2.0 Theory Manual (Madison, WI: Convergent Science Inc., 2013).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Im, H.G., Pal, P., Wooldridge, M.S., and Mansfield, A.B., “A Regime Diagram for Autoignition of Homogeneous Reactant Mixtures with Turbulent Velocity and Temperature Fluctuations,” Combust Sci Technol 187:1263-1275, 2015, doi: 10.1080/00102202.2015.1034355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <label>37.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Bradley, D., Morley, C., Gu, X., and Emerson, D., “Amplified Pressure Waves during Autoignition: Relevance to CAI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2868, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2868.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <label>38.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Reitz, R. and Diwakar, R., “Structure of High-Pressure Fuel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 870598, 1987, doi:10.4271/870598.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <label>39.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Reitz, R. and Diwakar, R., “Effect of Drop Breakup on Fuel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 860469, 1986, doi:10.4271/860469.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <label>40.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Chumakov, S.G. and Rutland, C.J., “Dynamic Structure Subgrid-Scale Models for Large Eddy Simulation,” Int J Numer Methods Fluids 47:911-923, 2005, doi:10.1002/fld.907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>(a) Base grid with AMR. (b) Grid inset with AMR at flame front location. (c) Mesh convergence test. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>(a) Initial temperature distribution with local hot spots. (b) Fuel distribution at TDC. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Cases considered for the study, Initial pressure, P = 30 bar, φ = 1. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Ignition delay time as a function of temperature for iso-octane (Pressure, P = 30 bar; Equivalence ratio, φ = 1). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Maximum pressure history with different initial mean temperatures. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Temperature history of the end gas at different initial mean temperatures. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Illustration of flame initiation and propagation at various time instants through iso-contour of temperature, pressure difference, and mass fraction of formaldehyde for case 1 (T = 1280 K). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Transition of pre-ignition flame front to detonation front for case 2 (T = 1080 K, detonation shown at inset) illustrated with iso-contour of temperature, pressure difference, and mass fraction of formaldehyde. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Illustration of flame initiation and propagation at various time instants through iso-contour of temperature, pressure difference, and mass fraction of formaldehyde (case 2, T = 1080 K). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Illustration of flame initiation, propagation, and detonation (shown in inset) at various time instants through iso-contour of temperature, pressure difference, and mass fraction of formaldehyde for case 3 (T = 1000 K). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Shock wave at end of combustion for case 4 (T = 950 K) shown with iso-contours of temperature, pressure difference, and mass fraction of formaldehyde. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Flame propagation, end-gas reactivity, and detonation for case 6 (T = 800 K) are shown with iso-contours of temperature, pressure difference, and mass fraction of formaldehyde. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Flame propagation at various time instants for case 8 (T = 700 K) shown with iso-contours of temperature, pressure difference, and mass fraction of formaldehyde. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Low-temperature reactivity in end gas at different initial temperatures (mass fraction of formaldehyde (CH₂O)). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Mass history of formation of formaldehyde at end gas for different cases. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Maximum temperature history for all the different cases. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Pre-ignition front laminar flame speed compared with calculated 1D flame speed using CHEMKIN™ at stoichiometry, P = 30 bar. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Heat release rate for various cases 1-8. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Calculated nondimensional end-gas parameters for different cases (1-8). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 18</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Comparison of cases 1-8 with Bradley diagram. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Engine specifications and operating condition. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>CAD geometry shown at background (a) Grid developed with spark plug and injector, (b) Grid section at top dead center. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
