<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308423</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A New Method to Detect Knocking Zones</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hettinger</surname>
                  <given-names>Alexander</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kulzer</surname>
                  <given-names>André</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Robert Bosch GmbH, Stuttgart</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>645</fpage>
         <lpage>665</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308423"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>It is a well known fact that indicated efficiency of a SI engine at WOT is predominantly limited by knock occurrence. Therefore many investigations have been carried out to avoid knocking. Considering the further development of downsized engines knocking will also pose a greater challenge. Not only knocking but also irregular combustion in general will require further investigation in supercharged SI eingines. Premature ignition, for instance, hasn’t yet been completely understood and therefore limits the low end torque of supercharged SI engines.</p>
            <p>The purpose of this paper is to introduce different analysis methods which allow to identify the knock onset and the knocking zones in the combustion chamber. In addition to established methods new techniques have been developed to account for the complex nature of pressure oscillation during knocking combustion.</p>
            <p>Experimental data was acquired on a single cylinder research engine to validate the methodology using six pressure transducers.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Douaud, P. Eyzat, “Four-Octane-Numer Method for Predicting the Anti-Knock Behaviour of Fuels and Engines”, SAE paper 780080, 1978</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Castagné, J.P. Dumas, S. Henriot, F.A. Lafossas, T. Mazoyer, “New knock localization methodology for SI engines”, SAE paper 2003-01-1118, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Worret, S. Bernhard, F. Schwarz, U. Spicher, „Application of Different Cylinder Pressure Based Knock Detection Methods in Spark Ignition Engines“, SAE paper 2002-01-1668, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P.M. Liiva, J.N. Valentine, J.M. Cobb, W.P. Acker, “Use of multiple pressure transducers to find incylinder knock location”, SAE paper 922368, 1992</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Jenkin, E. James, W. Malalasekera, “Prediction the Onset of End-Gas Autoignition with a Quasidimensional Spark Ignition Engine Model”, SAE paper 972877, 1997</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. Wayne, N. Clark, C. Atkinson, “Numerical Prediction of Knock in a Bi-Fuel Engine”, SAE paper 982533, 1998</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. Franzke, “Beitrag zur Ermittlung eines Klopfkriteriums der ottomotorischen Verbrennung und zur Vorausberechnung der Klopfgrenze”, Ph.D.- Thesis, Technical University of Munich, 1981</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">François-Alexandre Lafossas, Michel Castagne, Jean-Pierre Dumas, Stephane Henriot, “Development and Validation of a Knock Model in Spark Ignition Engines Using a CFD Code”, SAE paper 2002-01-2701, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U. Spicher, R. Worret, “Klopfkriterium - Entwicklung eines Kriteriums zur Vorausberechnung der Klopfgrenze”, FVV Abschlussbericht Vorhaben 700, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Michael Günther, Steffen Zwahr, Philipp Langfritz, Ralf Totzauer, „Methoden und Tools zur Klopfortbestimmung und effektiven Klopfregelungsapplikation“, Klopfregelung für Ottomotoren II - Haus der Technik Fachbuch, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mahle Powertrain „Advanced Downsizing Technology“, AutoTechnology 2/2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klaas Burgdorf, Ingemar Denbratt, “Comparison of Cylinder Pressure Based Knock Detection Methods”, SAE paper 972932, 1997</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rainer Golloch, Günter P. Merker, „Downsizing bei Verbrennungsmotoren - Grundlagen, Stand der Technik und zukünftige Konzepte“, MTZ article, 2/2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Volker Korte, David Hancock, Hugh Blaxill, „Downsizing-Motor von Mahle als Technologiedemonstrator Konzept, Auslegung und Konstruktion“, MTZ article, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Königstein, P.-I. Larsson, U.D. Grebe, K.-J. Wu, „Differenzierte Analyse von Downsizing-Konzepten - Differentiated Analysis of Downsizing Concepts“, 29. Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Prevedel, P. Kapus, „Hochaufladung beim Ottomotor - ein lohnender Ansatz für die Serie?“, 11. Aufladetechnische Konferenz, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">B. Grandin, H.E. Angström, P. Stalhammar, E. Olofson, „Knock Suppression in a Turbocharged SI Engine by Using Cooled EGR“, SAE paper 982476, 1998</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K-M. Han, U. Spicher, U. Maas, “Premature ignition during high-pressure supercharging”, 1st FVV Work Committee Meeting on Premature Ignition in SI engines, August 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. Kleinschmidt, „Zur Simulation des Betriebes von Ottomotoren an der Klopfgrenze“, VDIFortschrittsberichte, Reihe 12 422, VDI 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Carstens-Behrens, „Untersuchung klopfender Verbrennungen im Ottomotor mit Druck, Körperschall und Ionenstrom“, Ph.D.-Thesis Ruhr- Universität Bochum, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Bertola, J. Stadler, T. Walter, P. Wolfer, C. Grossweiler, M. Rothe, „Pressure indication during knocking conditions“, 7th International Symposium on Combustion Diagnostics, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U. Spicher, H. Kröger, J. Ganser, „Detection of knocking combustion using simultaneously highspeed schlieren cinematography and multi optical fiber technique“, SAE paper 912312, 1991</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P.-W. Manz, M. Daniel, K.-N. Jippa, J. Willand, „Vorentflammung bei hoch aufgeladenen Turbomotoren, Analyseverfahren und Ergebnisse“, 8th International Symposium on Combustion Diagnostics, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Zahdeh, Dr. P. Rothenberger, J. Schäfer, “Diagnosing Engine Combustion Using High Speed Photography in Conjunction with CFD”, 8th International Symposium on Combustion Diagnostics, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hans-Peter Kollmeier, “Untersuchungen über die Flammenausbreitung bei klopfender Verbrennung“, Ph.-D. Thesis, RWTH Aachen, 1987</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C.S. Draper, „Pressure Waves Accompanying Detonation in the Internal Combustion Engine“, J. Aeronaut. Sci. 5, 219-226, 1938</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The MathWorks Matlab Documentation, Matlab Version R2006b, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jonathan M. Borg, Alex C. Alkidas, “Investigation of the Effects of Autoignition on the Heat Release Histories of a Knocking SI Engine Using Wiebe Functions”, SAE paper 2008-01-1088, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Kulzer, D. Lejsek, A. Kiefer, A. Hettinger, “Pressure Trace Analysis Methods to Analyze Combustion Features and Cyclic Variability of Different Gasoline Combustion Concepts”, 2009-01- 0501, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leonhard Glas, “Grundsatzuntersuchung zur Gemischbildung und Verbrennung am optisch zugänglichen Verbrennungsmotor”, Diplomarbeit HS München / Robert Bosch GmbH, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
