<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285027</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Waste Heat Recovery for Light-Duty Truck Application Using ThermoAcoustic Converter Technology</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Sahoo</surname>
                  <given-names>Dipankar</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tenneco Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kotrba</surname>
                  <given-names>Adam</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tenneco Inc</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Steiner</surname>
                  <given-names>Tom</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Etalim Inc</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Swift</surname>
                  <given-names>Greg</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Los Alamos National Laboratory</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285020</issue-id>
         <fpage>196</fpage>
         <lpage>202</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285027"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Nearly a third of the fuel energy is wasted through the exhaust of a vehicle. An efficient waste heat recovery process will undoubtedly lead to improved fuel efficiency and reduced greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. Currently, there are multiple waste heat recovery technologies that are being investigated in the auto industry. One innovative waste heat recovery approach uses Thermoacoustic Converter (TAC) technology. Thermoacoustics is the field of physics related to the interaction of acoustic waves (sonic power) with heat flows. As in a heat engine, the TAC produces electric power where a temperature differential exists, which can be generated with engine exhaust (hot side) and coolant (cold side). Essentially, the TAC converts exhaust waste heat into electricity in two steps: 1) the exhaust waste heat is converted to acoustic energy (mechanical) and 2) the acoustic energy is converted to electrical energy. The converted electrical energy can be used to offload the alternator, supplying power for auxiliary loads as well as battery charging. In the event of excess electrical energy, it can be returned to the drivetrain through a motor connected to the front end accessory drive (FEAD). With the increasing demand for clean energy, TAC could be an attractive alternative for reducing fuel consumption and CO₂ emissions. Such a technology will become more attractive as electric power loads on a vehicle increase through hybridization and the increased usage of infotainment systems, media, and connected vehicles.</p>
            <p>In this paper, the fundamental principle of TAC technology is described and the TAC waste heat recovery vehicular integration with exhaust is presented. Numerical simulations are performed on light-duty gasoline pick-up truck engine exhausts over the US certification cycles to assess the performance and potential of TAC technology. Finally, some of the technical challenges are presented as well, acknowledging technology maturity and risks.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">https://www3.epa.gov/otaq/climate/regs-light-duty.htm</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kadota, M. and Yamamoto, K., “Advanced Transient Simulation on Hybrid Vehicle Using Rankine Cycle System,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):240–247, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0310.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">El Chammas, R. and Clodic, D., “Combined Cycle for Hybrid Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1171, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1171.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sprouse, C.III and Depcik, C., “Review of Organic Rankine Cycles for Internal Combustion Engine Exhaust Waste Heat Recovery”, Applied Thermal Engineering, 51, 711–722, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Endo, T., Kawajiri, S., Kojima, Y., Takahashi, K. , “Study on Maximizing Exergy in Automotive Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0257, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0257.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karlsson, M., Åbom, M., Lalit, M., and Glav, R., “A Note on the Applicability of Thermo-Acoustic Engines for Automotive Waste Heat Recovery,” SAE Int. J. Mater. Manf. 9(2):286–293, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keolian, R., “Truck Thermoacoustic Generator and Chiller”, DOE Project DE-FC26-04NT42113, CPR/IW Project 17057, October 2004 – March 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fritzsche, Jorg. , “Thermoacoustics as an Alternative Technology for Waste Heat Recovery in Automotive and (Heavy) Duty Applications”, 24th Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technology, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swift, G.W., Thermoacoustic energy conversion, Chapter 7 of the Springer Handbook of Acoustics (edited by Rossing Thomas, Springer, 2007). http://www.lanl.gov/org/padste/adeps/materials-physicsapplications/condensed-matter-magnet-science/thermoacoustics/_assets/docs/SpringerHandbook.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swift, G.W., Thermoacoustics: A Unifying Perspective for Some Engines and Refrigerators (Acoustical Society of America, 2002).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strutt J.W., (Baron Rayleigh), The Theory of Sound, (2nd edition, Dover, 1945, Sec. 322).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walker, G., Stirling Engines (Clarendon, 1960).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tijani, M. E. H., and Spoelstra, S., “A High Performance Thermoacoustic Engine,” J. Appl. Phys. 110, 093519 (2011), http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.3658872.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arman, B., Wollan, J., Kotsubo, V., Backhaus, S., and Swift, G., “Operation of Thermoacoustic Stirling Heat Engine Driven Large Multiple Pulse Tube Refrigerators,” Cryocoolers 13 (Springer, 2005), pages 181–188.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haberbusch, M.S., Nguyen, C., Walker, A.R., and Sasson, J., “Thermoacoustic Duplex Technology for Cooling and Powering a Venus Lander,” 12th International Energy Conversion</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steiner, T. and Archibald, G., “A High Pressure and High Frequency Diaphragm Engine: Comparison of Measured Results with Thermoacoustic Predictions”, Applied Energy 114(2014), 709–716, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Backhaus, S., Swift, G.W., and Reid, R.S., “High-temperature Self- Circulating Thermoacoustic Heat Exchanger,” Applied Physics Letters, 87, 014102 1–3, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swift, G. and Backhaus, S., “A Resonant Self-Pumped Circulating Thermoacoustic Heat Exchanger,” Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 116, 2923–2938, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://transportpolicy.net/index.php?title=US:_Vehicle_Definitions</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">https://www.dieselnet.com/standards/cycles/ftp75.php</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lorimer , “Thermoelectric Exhaust Heat Recovery — Demonstration of Power Generation and Fuel Economy Benefits on Light Duty Trucks”, SAE Thermal Management Systems Symposium (TMSS), Mesa, AZ, October 18–20, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
