<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24439199</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Use of Credit and Arrears on Debt among Low-Income Families in the United Kingdom</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>SARAH</given-names>
                  <surname>BRIDGES</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>RICHARD</given-names>
                  <surname>DISNEY</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2004</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">25</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24438462</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>25</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2004</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24439199"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Household accumulation of debt and arrears on debt, especially among low-income families, is an extremely topical issue in the UK media and in policy circles. This paper utilises data from the UK's Survey of Low Income Families in order to examine use of credit, and default and arrears, among low-income families with children. It shows how credit use and accumulation of arrears differ between single parents and couples with children, and also between homeowners and renters. It also briefly examines the persistence of arrears on specific forms of credit using the panel element of the data-set, now named the Families and Children Survey.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d29e245a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e252" publication-type="other">
For example, 'Fears rise over debt level of poor'. Financial Times, front page, 19 November 2002.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e259a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e266" publication-type="other">
Citizens Advice (2003) used surveys and an analysis of 8,000 cases to argue that both the incidence and the
depth of debt problems had increased significantly in recent years.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e276a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e283" publication-type="other">
See www.debt-on-our-doorstep.com/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e290a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e297" publication-type="other">
Waves 5 and 10 of the British Household Panel Survey (BHPS) asked questions about the magnitude of
aggregate household debt, ownership of specific assets and the use of particular credit instruments (Cox,
Whitley and Brierley, 2002). Moreover, the BHPS is a representative sample of British households. However,
the questions on debt in the two waves are not fully comparable — see Banks, Smith and Wakefield (2002).
The Family Expenditure Survey contains details of types/amount of loans, hire-purchase agreements and
mortgages but asks no questions on the level of overdrafts or credit-card balances.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e321a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e328" publication-type="other">
Exploiting the panel element of the data-set to examine the covariates of credit and arrears of debt — for
example, whether changes in household circumstances induce changes in use of (access to) credit and of
indebtedness — is the focus of future work.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e341a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e348" publication-type="other">
Usually led by the Daily Express's front-page headlines: 'Debt disaster' (20 November 2002) and 'Spending is
out of control: consumers in massive debt as credit card borrowing and re-mortgaging hit new record' (23 April
2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e361a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e368" publication-type="other">
In the USA, for example, 70 per cent of households with a credit card carry interest-accruing balances at any
one time whilst also typically having money in savings accounts earning lower rates of interest than that
accrued on the credit card (see Laibson, Repetto and Tobacman (2003)). For evidence on simultaneous
ownership of assets, savings and debt among UK households, see Banks, Smith and Wakefield (2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e384a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e391" publication-type="other">
The influential study by Citizens Advice (2003) grosses up numbers in financial difficulties from CAB
caseloads. There are two difficulties of interpretation here: (i) the sample of people who approach CABs may
not be representative of the relevant segment of the population in so far as the sample may have excessive debts
but (ii) those who approach a CAB because they are aware of their 'debt problem' may actually be in better
shape than those who have serious problems but have not yet taken any kind of advice. The parallel with
various forms of addiction is obvious.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e414a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e421" publication-type="other">
For further details, see Marsh et al. (2001) and Marsh and Rowlingson (2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e428a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e435" publication-type="other">
Between 1988 and October 1999, family credit was the main in-work benefit in Britain (Dilnot and McCrae,
1999). It was designed to encourage low-income families with children to remain in work. In order to be
eligible for family credit, a family with children needed to have at least one adult working more than 16 hours a
week. In October 1999, family credit was replaced by the working families' tax credit (WFTC).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e452a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e459" publication-type="other">
Up to a maximum of 35 per cent above the upper threshold for eligibility for family credit for a family of
given composition.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e469a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e476" publication-type="other">
Of course, the probability of homeownership and being a couple with children versus being a single parent
may be simultaneously determined, but this issue lies beyond the scope of this paper.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e486a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e493" publication-type="other">
In the BHPS Wave 10 (2000), 53 per cent of households report having a credit or store card. The fraction is
slightly higher among heads of households aged 18-50. Note also the distinction between ownership and use of
a card.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e506a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e513" publication-type="other">
A simple count regression model of number of credit and borrowing arrangements, conditioning on family
income sources, demographic characteristics and educational qualifications, shows that homeownership is
associated with a significantly higher number of credit arrangements for both couples with children (t-ratio
2.89) and single parents (t-ratio 3.51).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e529a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e536" publication-type="other">
However, these qualitative studies do suggest that such low-income families attempt to adopt the
'accountant'/'shopper' dichotomy (Haliassos and Reiter, 2003) by keeping separate accounts (even in cash
terms), distinguishing between 'regular' expenditure commitments and windfalls — see Economic and Social
Research Council (2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e552a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e559" publication-type="other">
2.8/3.2=0.875.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e567a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e574" publication-type="other">
Other candidate models include a simple probit/logit of whether the household has arrears, or a count model
of number of arrears (the latter is used in Bridges and Disney (2002)). If we believe that access to credit is an
additional constraint, then we should model the probability of having arrears and the magnitude of those arrears
in a simultaneous model.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e590a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e597" publication-type="other">
0nly 39 families are involved, and this trimming makes no significant difference to the coefficient
magnitudes or standard errors. Results with no trimming are available from the authors on request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d29e616a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e620" publication-type="other">
Banks, J., Smith, Z. and Wakefield, M. (2002), 'The distribution of financial wealth in the UK:
evidence from 2000 BHPS data', Institute for Fiscal Studies, Working Paper no. WP02/21
(www.ifs.org.uk/workingpapers/wp0221.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e633a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e637" publication-type="other">
Bridges, S. and Disney, R. (2002), 'Access to credit, and debt, among low income families in the
UK: an exploratory analysis', University of Nottingham, mimeo, available at
www.nottingham.ac.uk/economics/ExCEM/publications/index.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e650a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e654" publication-type="other">
Citizens Advice (2003), In Too Deep: CAB Clients' Experience of Debt, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e661a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e665" publication-type="other">
Cox, P., Whitley, J. and Brierley, P. (2002), 'Financial pressures in the UK household sector:
evidence from the British Household Panel Survey', Bank of England Quarterly Bulletin, vol.
42, pp. 410-19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e679a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e683" publication-type="other">
Dilnot, A. and McCrae, J. (1999), Family Credit and the Working Families' Tax Credit, Briefing
Note no. 3, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies (www.ifs.org.uk/labmarket/wftc.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e693a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e697" publication-type="other">
Dominy, N. and Kempson, E. (2003), Can't Pay, Won't Pay: A Review of Creditor and Debtor
Approaches to the Non-Payment of Bills, London: Lord Chancellor's Department.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e707a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e711" publication-type="other">
Economic and Social Research Council (2002), How People on Low Incomes Manage Their
Finances, Report on a Scoping Seminar, Swindon.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e721a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e725" publication-type="other">
Goodman, A., Johnson, P. and Webb, S. (1997), Inequality in the UK, Oxford: Oxford University
Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e735a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e739" publication-type="other">
Haliassos, M. and Reiter, M. (2003), 'Credit card debt puzzles', mimeo, conference on 'The
Economics of Consumer Credit: European Experience and Lessons from the US', May,
Finance and Consumption, European University Institute, Florence.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e752a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e756" publication-type="other">
Laibson, D., Repetto, A. and Tobacman, J. (2003), 'Wealth accumulation, credit card borrowing
and consumption-income comovement', mimeo, conference on 'The Economics of Consumer
Credit: European Experience and Lessons from the US', May, Finance and Consumption,
European University Institute, Florence.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e773a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e777" publication-type="other">
Kempson, E. (2002), Overindebtedness in Britain, London: Department of Trade and Industry,
www.dti.gov.uk/ccp/topicsl/overindebtedness.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e787a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e791" publication-type="other">
Marsh, A. and Rowlingson, S. (2002), Low/Moderate Income Families in Britain: Changes in
1999-2000, Research Report no. 162, London: Department for Work and Pensions.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e801a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e805" publication-type="other">
Marsh, S., McKay, S., Smith, A. and Stephenson, A. (2001), Low Income Families in Britain,
Research Report no. 138, London: Department for Work and Pensions.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
