<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">115</volume>
         <issue-id>i40196094</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44687335</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Cavitation Inside Multi-hole Injectors for Large Diesel Engines and Its Effect on the Near-nozzle Spray Structure</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>M.</given-names>
                  <surname>Gavaises</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Andriotis</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2006</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>634</fpage>
         <lpage>647</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2007 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44687335"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The cavitating flow characteristics inside multi-hole injectors for large Diesel engines have been investigated. Flow imaging obtained inside transparent nozzle replicas using simultaneously two high speed cameras and various illumination light sources has shown that cavitation is formed not only at the hole entrance due to the local pressure drop induced by nozzle inlet geometry, but also inside the volume of nozzle tip just upstream of the injection holes. CFD calculations of the internal nozzle flow have shown that cavitation strings are formed in the areas where large vortical structures are present. Processing of the acquired images has allowed estimation of the mean location and probability of appearance of the cavitating strings in the 3-D space. Parametric studies have also revealed the effect of the needle lift, cavitation number and Reynolds number. Simultaneous imaging of the flow inside the nozzle, the injection holes and the near-nozzle spray structure has revealed the effect of string cavitation on the hole flow structure and the consequent effect on spray cone and deflection angles. Those have been found to vary considerably and in a transient mode in the presence of a string inside inside the hole from which they are injected.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d624e346a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e353" publication-type="other">
He, L. and F. Ruiz, Effect of Cavitation on Flow and Tur-
bulence in Plain Orifice for High-Speed Atomization. At-
omization and Sprays, 1995. 5(6): p. 569-584.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e366a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e373" publication-type="other">
Kim, J.H., K. Nishida, and H. Hiroyasu. Characteristics of
Internal Flow in a Diesel Injection Nozzle, in Proc.
ICLASS. 1997, August 18-22. Seul, Korea.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e386a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e393" publication-type="other">
Soteriou, C., M. Smith, and R.J. Andrews, Diesel Injec-
tion - Laser Light Sheet Illumination of the Development
of Cavitation in Orifices. IMechE Paper C529/018/98,
1998.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e409a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e418" publication-type="other">
Chaves, H. and F. Obermeier. Correlation between Light
Absorption Signals of Cavitating Nozzle Flow within and
outside of the Hole of a Transparent Diesel Injection
Nozzle, in Proc. ILASS-EUROPE. 1998, July 6-8. Man-
chester, UK.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e438a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e445" publication-type="other">
Soteriou, C., R.J. Andrews, and M. Smith, Direct Injec-
tion Diesel Sprays and the Effect of Cavitation and Hy-
draulic Flip on Atomization. SAE Paper 950080, 1995</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e458a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e465" publication-type="other">
Arcoumanis, C., M. Badami, H. Flora, and M. Gavaises,
Cavitation in Real-Size Multi-Hole Diesel Injector Noz-
zles. SAE Paper 2000-01-1249, 2000.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e478a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e485" publication-type="other">
Arcoumanis, C., M. Gavaises, J.M. Nouri, E. Abdul-
Wahab, and R.W. Horrocks, Analysis of the Flow in the
Nozzle of a Vertical Multi Hole Diesel Engine Injector.
SAE Paper 980811, 1998.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e501a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e508" publication-type="other">
Soteriou, C., R.J. Andrews, N. Torres, M. Smith, and R.
Kunkulagunta. Through the Diesel Nozzle Hole -A Jour-
ney of Discovery II. in Proc. ILASS-Europe. 2001, Sep-
tember 2-6. Zurich, Switzerland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e524a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e531" publication-type="other">
Afzal, H., C. Arcoumanis, M. Gavaises, and N. Kampa-
nis, Internal Flow in Diesel Injector Nozzles: Modelling
and Experiments. IMECHE Paper S492/S2/99, 1999</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e544a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e551" publication-type="other">
Roth H., Gavaises M. and Arcoumanis C. "Cavitation Ini-
tiation, Its Development and Link with Flow Turbulence
in Diesel Injector Nozzles", SAE Paper 2002-01-0214,
SAE Transactions, 2002</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e568a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e575" publication-type="other">
Giannadakis, E., M. Gavaises, H. Roth, and C. Arcou-
manis. Cavitation Modelling in Single-Hole Diesel Injec-
tor Based on Eulerian-Lagrangian Approach, in Proc.
THIESEL International Conference on Thermo-and
Fluid Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines. Valencia,
Spain. 2004.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e598a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e605" publication-type="other">
Gavaises, M. and E. Giannadakis. Modelling Of Cavita-
tion In Large Scale Diesel Injector Nozzles, in ILASS
2004. Nottingham, UK. 2004.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e618a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e625" publication-type="other">
Patankar SV, Spalding BD. A calculation procedure for
heat, mass and momentum transfer in three-dimensional
parabolic flows. Int. J. Heat and Mass Transfer 15 (1972)
1787-1806</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e641a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e648" publication-type="other">
Giannadakis E. 'Modelling of cavitation in automotive fuel
injector nozzles', PhD Thesis, Imperial College London,
UK, 2005</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


