<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26296383</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PROFESSIONAL FEATURE</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Method for Improving Strategic Decisions and Senior-level Teamwork in US National Security Organizations, Part 2</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Thomason</surname>
                  <given-names>James S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr. Jim Thomason is the director of the Strategy and Risk Program at the Institute for Defense Analyses and is an assistant director in the Strategy, Forces and Resources Division. He has worked at IDA for 32 years.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Bexfield</surname>
                  <given-names>James N.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Jim Bexfield is an adjunct research staff member at IDA and is a Past President, 1994 Wanner Award winner, and Fellow of MORS. He retired from OSD CAPE about five years ago.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>June 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>50</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26296366</issue-id>
         <fpage>40</fpage>
         <lpage>47</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2017, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26296383"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burns, K. E., Thomason, J. S., and Morgeson, J. D. 2014. Applying the Integrated Risk Assessment and Management Model (IRAMM) to the Assessment of Risk for Non-fuel Strategic Materials. IDA Paper P-5104. Institute for Defense Analyses.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Commission on America’s National Interests. 2000. America’s National Interests. Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs, Harvard University (July).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edwards, W. 1977. How to Use Multi-attribute Utility Measurement for Social Decision Making, IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics, Vol SMC- 7, No 5, (May 1977): 326 – 340.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hogarth R. 1980. Judgment and Choice: The Psychology of Decisions. John Wiley &amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaplan, S., and Garrick, J. B. 1981. On the Quantitative Definition of Risk, Risk Analysis, Vol 1, No 1, p. 13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">National Commission on the Future of the Army (NCFA). 2016. Report to the President and the Congress of the United States. (January 28). http://www.ncfa.ncr.gov.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thomason, J. S. 2009. IDA’s Integrated Risk Assessment and Management Model. IDA Paper P-4470. Institute for Defense Analyses.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thomason, J. S., Barnett, D. S., Bell, J. P., Bracken, J., and Schwartz, E. L. 2015. Strategic Material Shortfall Risk Mitigation Optimization Model, Military Operations Research, Vol 20, No 4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wright, G., and Ayton, P. 1994. Subjective Probability. John Wiley &amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
