<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26296420</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>MORS/MAS</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>MORS 2017 Annual Membership Survey</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Goerger</surname>
                  <given-names>Simon</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr. Simon R. Goerger is the ERDC Director of the Institute for Systems Engineering Research (ISER) at the Information Technology Laboratory (ITL) of the US Army Engineer Research and Development Center (ERDC) in Vicksburg, Mississippi. He was awarded his bachelor of science from the United States Military Academy, his master of science in national security strategy from the National War College, and his MS in computer science and doctorate of philosophy in modeling and simulations from the Naval Postgraduate School. His research interests include decision analysis, systems modeling, combat modeling and simulations, agent-based modeling, tradespace analysis, human factors, and training in virtual environments.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Richards</surname>
                  <given-names>Jed</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Mr. James “Jed” Richards is an operations research analyst in the Institute for Systems Engineering Research (ISER) at the US Army Corps of Engineers, Engineer Research and Development Center. He received a bachelor’s degree in mechanical engineering from West Point and his master’s degree in system design and management from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. His current research focuses on lifecycle cost analysis applied to early acquisition trades for the Engineered Resilient Systems (ERS) program.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>December 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>50</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26296415</issue-id>
         <fpage>8</fpage>
         <lpage>10</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2017, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26296420"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
