<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">jcompmath</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017830</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Journal of Computational Mathematics</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Chinese Academy of Mathematices and System Sciences (AMSS) Chinese Academy of Sciences</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">02549409</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19917139</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">32</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">6</issue>
         <issue-id>i40148840</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">43693831</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>DISCONTINUOUS GALERKIN CALCULATIONS FOR A NONLINEAR PDE MODEL OF DNA TRANSCRIPTION WITH SHORT, TRANSIENT AND FREQUENT PAUSING</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Lisa</given-names>
                  <surname>Davis</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Tomáš</given-names>
                  <surname>Gedeon</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Jennifer</given-names>
                  <surname>Thorenson</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>601</fpage>
         <lpage>629</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2014 AMSS, Chinese Academy of Sciences</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/43693831"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>A discontinuous Galerkin finite element method is used to approximate solutions to a classical traffic flow PDE. This PDE is used to model the biological process of transcription; the process of transferring genetic information from DNA either to mRNA or to rRNA. The transcription process is punctuated by short, frequent RNAP pauses which are incorporated into the model as traffic lights. These pauses cause a delay in the average transcription process. The DG solution of the nonlinear model is used to calculate the delay and to determine the effect of the pauses on the average transcription time. Numerical error measurements between the DG solution and the true solution (derived by the method of characteristics) are given for a simple model problem. It shows an excellent agreement in a neighborhood away from the shocks as well as O(Δx) convergence for the delay calculation. Preliminary parameter studies indicate that in a system with multiple pauses both the location and time duration of the pauses can significantly affect the average delay experienced by an RNAP.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1399904e287a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e294" publication-type="other">
H. Bremer and P. P. Dennis, Escherichia coli and Salmonella typhi-murium: Cellular and Molec-
ular Biology, Chapter -Modulation of chemical composition and other parameters of the cell by
growth rate, eds. Neidhardt EA (Sinauer, Sunderland, MA) 2nd Ed., College Station, Texas,
(1996), 421.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e310a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e317" publication-type="other">
B. Cockburn, Discontinuous Galerkin methods for convection-dominated problems, In High-order
methods for computational physics, Volume 9 of Lect. Notes Comp. Sci. Eng. Springer, Berlin,
1999, 69-224.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e330a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e337" publication-type="other">
B. Cockburn and C.-W. Shu, Runge-Kutta discontinuous Galerkin methods for convection-
dominated problems, J. Sci. Comput., 16:3 (2001), 173-261.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e347a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e354" publication-type="other">
Bernardo Cockburn and Chi-Wang Shu, TVB Runge-Kutta Local projection discontinuous
Galerkin finite element method for conservation laws II: General Framework, Math. Comp., 52:186
(1989), 411-435.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e368a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e375" publication-type="other">
C. Condon, S. French, C. Squires, and C. L. Squires, Depletion of functional ribosomal RNA
opérons in Escherichia coli causes increased expression of the remaining intact copies, The EMBO
Journal, 12:11 (1993), 4305-4315.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e388a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e395" publication-type="other">
L. Davis, T. Gedeon, J. Gedeon, and J. Thorenson, A traffic flow model for bio-polymerization
processes, J. Math. Bio., 68:3 (2014), 667-700.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e405a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e412" publication-type="other">
P.P. Dennis, M. Ehrenberg, D. Fange, and H. Bremer, Varying rate of RNA chain elongation
during rrn transcription in escherichia coli. J. Bacter., 191:11 (2009), 3740-3746.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e422a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e429" publication-type="other">
S. Gottlieb, C.-W. Shu, and E. Tadmor, Strong stability-preserving high-order time discretization
methods. SIAM Rev., 43:1 (2001), 89-112 (electronic).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e439a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e446" publication-type="other">
R. Haberman, Mathematical models: Mechanical vibrations, population dynamics, and traffic
flow, volume 21 of Classics in Applied Mathematics, SIAM, Philadelphia, PA, 1998 (Reprint of
the 1977 original).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e459a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e466" publication-type="other">
J. S. Hesthaven and T. Warburton, Nodal Discontinuous Galerkin Methods: Algorithms, analysis,
and applications, volume 54 of Texts in Applied Mathematics. Springer, New York, 2008.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e477a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e484" publication-type="other">
M.L. Kireeva and M. Kashlev, Mechanism of sequence-specific pausing of bacterial RNA poly-
merase, PNAS, 106:22 (2009), 8900-8905.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e494a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e501" publication-type="other">
S. Klumpp and T. Hwa, Stochasticity and traffic jams in the transcription of ribosomal RNA:
Intriguing role of termination and antitermination, PNAS, 105:47 (2008), 18159-164.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e511a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e518" publication-type="other">
R. Landick, Transcriptional pausing without backtracking, PNAS, 106:22 (2009), 8797-8798.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e525a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e532" publication-type="other">
Randall LeVeque, Finite Volume Methods for Hyperbolic Problems, Cambridge University Press,
New York, NY, 2002.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e542a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e549" publication-type="other">
M.J. Lighthill and G.B. Whitham, On kinematic waves, ii. a theory of traffic flow on long crowded
roads, Proceedings of the Royal Society of London. Series A, 229:1178 (1955), 317-345.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e559a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e566" publication-type="other">
R.-X. Liu, H. Li, and Z.-F. Wang, The discontinuous finite element method for red-and-green light
models for the traffic flow. Math. Comput. Simulation, 56:1 (2001), 55-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e577a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e584" publication-type="other">
K.C. Neuman, E.A. Abbondanzieri, R. Landick, J. Gelles and S.M. Block, Ubiquitous transcrip-
tional pausing is independent of RNA polymerase bactracking, Cell, 115:4 (2003), 437-447.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e594a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e601" publication-type="other">
P. I. Richards, Shock waves on the highway. Operations Research, 4:1 (1956), 42-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e608a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e615" publication-type="other">
P. Zhang and R.-X. Liu, Generalization of Runge-Kutta discontinuous Galerkin method to LWR
traffic flow model with inhomogeneous road conditions, Numer. Methods Partial Differential Equa-
tions, 21:1 (2005), 80-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1399904e628a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1399904e635" publication-type="other">
R.K.P. Zia, J.J. Dong and B. Schmittmann, Modeling translation in protein synthesis with TASEP:
a tutorial and recent developments, J. Stat. Phys., 144:2 (2011), 405-428.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


