<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24439992</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Population Ageing, Fiscal Pressure and Tax Smoothing: A CGE Application to Australia</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Ross</given-names>
                  <surname>Guest</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2006</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24439987</issue-id>
         <fpage>183</fpage>
         <lpage>203</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2006</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24439992"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper analyses the fiscal pressure from population ageing using an intertemporal CGE model, applied to Australia, and compares the results with those of a recent government-commissioned study. The latter study uses an alternative modelling approach based on extrapolation rather than optimising behaviour of consumers and firms. The deadweight losses from the fiscal pressure caused by population ageing are equivalent to an annual loss of consumption of $260 per person per year in 2003 dollars in the balanced-budget scenario. A feasible degree of tax smoothing would reduce this welfare loss by an equivalent of $70 per person per year. Unlike the extrapolation-based model, the CGE approach takes account of feedback effects of ageing-induced tax increases on consumption and labour supply, which in turn impact on the ultimate magnitude of fiscal pressure and therefore tax increases. However, a counterfactual simulation suggests that the difference in terms of deadweight losses between the two modelling approaches is modest, at about $30 per person per year.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d8e178a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e185" publication-type="other">
The author is grateful to the Australian Research Council for funding related to this project.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e192a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e199" publication-type="other">
This is not to say that the extrapolation approach is inferior. The fact that it lacks behavioural
foundations may be seen by some as a strength, rather than a weakness, on the basis that an extrapolation
of past trends is at least as reliable as a guide to the future as one based on assumptions about behaviour
that may be inaccurate.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e215a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e222" publication-type="other">
In PC (2005), the increase in government spending on pensions is projected to be only 1.7 per cent of
GDP from 2004 to 2045, compared with an increase of 6 per cent through health and aged care. The
relatively small impact of ageing on public pension spending in Australia is due to its compulsory private
pension system combined with means testing of the public pension.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e238a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e245" publication-type="other">
We are grateful to officers at the Productivity Commission for providing various spreadsheets with
these calculations, as some spreadsheets were not included in the CD accompanying the Productivity
Commission report.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e259a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e266" publication-type="other">
For the assumptions about non-demographic growth rates in PC (2005), see page 167 for health, page
182 for aged care and page 208 for education.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e276a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e283" publication-type="other">
Lower labour force growth implies less demand for capital for a given capital-labour ratio, therefore
allowing a higher consumption share of output.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e293a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e300" publication-type="other">
We constrain the tax rate on capital income to be equal to the tax rate on labour income. This is
important later when we discuss tax smoothing where the government chooses an optimal tax rate. In that
case, the choice refers to the choice of the labour income tax rate; the capital income tax rate is
constrained to be equal to that rate. This is done for simplicity in order to abstract from the problem of
choosing the optimal tax rate on capital. Floden (2003) employs a somewhat similar assumption. For a
discussion of the optimal tax rate on capital, see Chamley (1986).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e323a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e330" publication-type="other">
Here, the terms 'long-run' and 'steady-state' are used synonymously.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e337a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e344" publication-type="other">
This is simply the open-economy analogue to the Solow effect, which refers to the capital-widening
effects of employment growth on investment - in particular, slower employment growth lowers
investment and therefore allows higher consumption as a share of output.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e357a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e364" publication-type="other">
The Solow effect in the open economy applies not just to capital, K, but to wealth defined as K-D.
Lower employment growth means that there are fewer new workers available to saddle with new debt
financed by consumption. This restricts consumption.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e378a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e385" publication-type="other">
The 'dollars' are Australian dollars which, at 29 March 2006, exchanged for 0.405 British pounds.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e392a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e399" publication-type="other">
The calculation is done by comparing the optimal consumption paths under the counterfactual and
base-case simulations, and using the following data: total final consumption expenditure in 2002-03 was
$590,050 million and the total population was 19.8 million.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e412a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e419" publication-type="other">
The optimal tax rate is not exactly constant because it must vary slightly in order to smooth the
relative price of leisure which implies smoothing the after-tax real wage (Floden, 2003; Andersen and
Dogonowski, 2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d8e441a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e445" publication-type="other">
Andersen, T. and Dogonowski, R. (2004), 'What should optimal income taxes smooth?',
Journal of Public Economie Theory, vol. 6, pp. 491-507.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e455a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e459" publication-type="other">
Auerbach, A. (1994), 'The US fiscal problem: where we are, how we got there, and where
we're going', National Bureau of Economic Research, Working Paper no. 4709.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e469a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e473" publication-type="other">
—, Gale, W. and Orszag, P. (2004), 'The fiscal gap and retirement saving revisited', Tax
Notes, 26 July, Brookings Institution, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e483a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e487" publication-type="other">
Australian Government (2002), Intergenerational Report 2002-2003, 2002-03 Budget Paper
no. 5, Commonwealth of Australia, Canberra.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e498a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e502" publication-type="other">
Carroll, C. D., Overland, J. and Weil, D. N. (1997), 'Comparison utility in a growth model',
Journal of Economic Growth, vol. 2, pp. 339-67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e512a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e516" publication-type="other">
Chamley, C. (1986), 'Optimal taxation of capital income in general equilibrium with infinite
lives', Econometrica, vol. 54, pp. 607-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e526a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e530" publication-type="other">
Coakley, J., Kulasi, F. and Smith, R. (1998), 'The Feldstein-Horioka puzzle and capital
mobility: a review', International Journal of Finance and Economics, vol. 3, pp. 169-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e540a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e544" publication-type="other">
Cutler, D. M., Poterba, J. M., Sheiner, L. M. and Summers, L. H. (1990), 'An aging society:
opportunity or challenge?', Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, vol. 1, pp. 1-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e554a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e558" publication-type="other">
European Commission (2003), Public Finances in EMU 2003, Brussels: Commission of the
European Communities.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e568a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e572" publication-type="other">
Farque, H. and Muhleisen, M. (2001), 'Population ageing in Japan: demographic shock and
fiscal sustainability', International Monetary Fund, Working Paper no. 01/40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e583a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e587" publication-type="other">
Floden, M. (2003), 'Public saving and public policy coordination in aging economies',
Scandinavian Journal of Economics, vol. 105, pp. 379 400.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e597a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e601" publication-type="other">
Foertsch, T. (2004), 'Macroeconomic impacts of stylized tax cuts in an intertemporal
computable general equilibrium model', Technical Paper Series, Congressional Budget
Office, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e614a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e618" publication-type="other">
Gordon, R. H. and Bovenberg, A. L. (1996), 'Why is capital so immobile internationally?
Possible explanations and implications for capital income taxation', American Economic
Review, vol. 86, pp. 1057-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e631a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e635" publication-type="other">
Guest, R. and McDonald, I. M. (2003), 'Vintage versus homogeneous capital in simulations
of population ageing: does it matter?', Applied Economics Letters, vol. 10, pp. 149-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e645a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e649" publication-type="other">
HM Treasury (2003), Long-Term Public Finance Report: Fiscal Sustainability with an
Ageing Population, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e659a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e663" publication-type="other">
Obstfeld, M. and Rogoff, K. (1996), Foundations of International Macroeconomics,
Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e674a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e678" publication-type="other">
Oksanen, H. (2003), 'Population ageing and public finance targets', European Commission
Economic Paper no. 193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e688a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e692" publication-type="other">
Productivity Commission (2005), Economic Implications of an Ageing Australia, Canberra:
Commonwealth of Australia.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e702a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e706" publication-type="other">
Turner, D., Giorno, C., DeSerres, A., Vourch, A. and Richardson, P. (1998), 'The
macroeconomic implications of ageing in a global context', OECD Economics
Department, Working Paper no. 193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
