<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278225</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Computational Analysis of Internal and External EGR Strategies Combined with Miller Cycle Concept for a Two Stage Turbocharged Medium Speed Marine Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Millo</surname>
                  <given-names>Federico</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Torino</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bernardi</surname>
                  <given-names>Marco Gianoglio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Torino</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Delneri</surname>
                  <given-names>Diego</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Wartsila</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1319</fpage>
         <lpage>1330</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278225"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In this work different internal and external EGR strategies, combined with extreme Miller cycles, were analyzed by means of a one dimensional CFD simulation code for a Wärtsilä 6 cylinder, 4 strokes, medium speed marine diesel engine, to evaluate their potential in order to reach the IMO Tier 3 NOx emissions target.</p>
            <p>By means of extreme Miller cycles, with Early Intake Valve Closures (up to 100 crank angle degrees before BDC), a shorter compression stroke and lower charge temperatures inside the cylinder can be achieved and thanks to the cooler combustion process, the NOx specific emissions can be effectively reduced. EIVC strategies can also be combined with reductions of the scavenging period (valve overlap) to increase the amount of exhaust gases in the combustion chamber. However, the remarkably high boost pressure levels needed for such extreme Miller cycles, require mandatorily the use of two stage turbocharging systems.</p>
            <p>Despite two stages turbocharging, combined with extreme Miller timings, may allow up to 50 % NOx reduction compared to a conventional, single stage turbocharger architecture, further NOx emissions reductions are necessary to meet the IMO Tier 3 NOx limit. Higher EGR percentages, which could be achieved by means of external circuits, were therefore also evaluated.</p>
            <p>However, it should be pointed out that, although the external EGR technology is well established for automotive and heavy duty diesel engines, it is not yet state of the art for marine diesel engines, and its application to a highly boosted engine using extreme Miller timings is not straightforward.</p>
            <p>Several different complex EGR routes were thus investigated, and for the preliminary assessment of their NOx emissions abatement potentialities, the use of numerical simulation allowed a detailed and extensive evaluation of the effects on engine performance, fuel consumption, NOx emissions and thermal and mechanical loads on engine components of the combination of different intake valve profiles, intake valve closure timings and scavenging periods with different external exhaust gas recirculation solutions.</p>
            <p>Percentages of exhaust gases recirculated in the combustion chamber up to 20% were evaluated that combined with extreme Miller timings (up to 100 crank angle degrees before BDC) allowed up to 90% NOx reduction compared to a conventional, single stage turbocharger architecture, with only moderate BSFC increase.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BRITT-MARI KULLAS-NYMAN, “Ocean Industry Synergies in Reducing Emissions through Innovative Technologies”, Sustainable Ocean Summit, July 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MILLER, R., LIEBERHERR, H.U., “The Miller Supercharging system for Diesel and Gas Engines operating Characteristics”, CIMAC Proceedings, Zurich 1957.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ISAKSSON, S., “The Miller Cycle and its Application on a Medium Speed Diesel Engine”, Master Thesis, Helsinki University of Technology, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">WIK, C., HALLBÄCK, B., “Reducing emissions using 2- stage turbo charging”, Wärtsilä Technical Journal, January 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MILLO, F., GIANOGLIO, M., DELNERI, D., “Combining dual stage turbocharging with extreme Miller timings to achieve NOx emissions reductions in marine diesel engines”, CIMAC Proceedings, Bergen 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stebler, H., Weisser, G., Horler, H., Boulouchous, K., “Reduction of NOx Emissions of D.I. Diesel Engines by Application of the Miller System: An Experimental and Numerical Investigation,” SAE Technical Paper 960844, 1996, doi: 10.4271/960844.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edwards, S. P., Frankle, G. R., Wirtbeleit, F., Raab, A., “The Potential of a Combined Miller Cycle and Internal EGR Engine for Future Heavy Duty Truck Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 980180, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, F., Mallamo, F., Mego, G., “The Potential of Dual Stage Turbocharging and Miller Cycle for HD Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0221, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-0221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gamma Technologies Inc., “GT-POWER User's Manual”, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T., Keribar, R., Leonard, A., “Virtual Engine/Powertrain/Vehicle Simulation Tool Solves Complex Interacting System Issues,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0372, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0372.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keribar, R., Ciesla, C. R., Morel, T., “Engine/Powertrain/Vehicle Modeling Tool Applicable to all Stages of the Design Process,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0934, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-0934.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoshizaki, T., Nishida, K., Hiroyasu, H., “Approach to Low NOx and Smoke Emissions Engines by Using Phenomenological Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 930612, 1993, doi: 10.4271/930612.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MOREL, T., WAHIDUZZAMAN, S.: “Modeling of Diesel Combustion and Emissions”, FISITA, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
