<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440191</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Do Charitable Solicitations Matter? A Comparative Analysis of Fundraising Methods</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Baris K.</given-names>
                  <surname>Yoruk</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2012</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">33</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440186</issue-id>
         <fpage>467</fpage>
         <lpage>487</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2012 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440191"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The existing literature either treats fundraising as an aggregate variable by ignoring the existence of several different fundraising methods through which charitable contributions are generated or focuses on the effectiveness of a particular fundraising method without making any comparison with alternative methods. Using biennial household surveys of charitable giving in the United States conducted from 1988 to 1999, which contain detailed questions on several fundraising methods, I first document that people are more responsive to certain fundraising methods. Next, I investigate the factors associated with donors' responsiveness to alternative fundraising techniques. The results show that several observable characteristics of charitable donors are associated with some people being more responsive to particular fundraising techniques than others are.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d29e169a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e176" publication-type="other">
Submitted November 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e183a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e190" publication-type="other">
Source: Annual Report of the Giving USA Foundation, 2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e197a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e204" publication-type="other">
The most recent Internal Revenue Service (1RS) data on charitable organisations show that charities
spend roughly 18 per cent of charitable contributions on fundraising activities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e214a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e221" publication-type="other">
Andreoni (2006) further discusses the pros and cons of using data from the tax returns of charitable
organisations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e232a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e239" publication-type="other">
Using data from a public university, Meer and Rosen (2011) document a similar effect.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e246a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e253" publication-type="other">
For instance, several studies using field experiments collect data via door-to-door solicitations of a
random sample of individuals. However, whether the same individuals would behave differently had they
received the same information via some other charitable solicitation method, such as letter, phone, print
ad or TV, is unknown.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e269a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e276" publication-type="other">
independent Sector is a charitable organisation that supports the development and dissemination of
strategies to strengthen volunteering, voting, giving and other forms of citizen engagement.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e286a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e293" publication-type="other">
independent Sector also collected data for 2001. However, the 2001 edition did not obtain sufficient
information on fundraising methods. Raw data, sampling procedures and technical documentation for the
Gallup surveys are accessible at http://www.CDanda.org/stage/studies/e0002 l?view=summarv.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e306a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e313" publication-type="other">
These categories are health, education, religious, human services, environment, public benefit,
recreation, art, youth development, private community, international and other unnamed organisations.
Compared with the other editions, the wording of the questions on giving and volunteering to different
areas of charitable activity is slightly different in the 1988 edition. For this particular survey year, I
estimate total giving as the sum of money that the respondent has reported contributing to each of the
specific charity groups that they were asked about, excluding donations to political organisations. 1 also
exclude informal and work-related contributions, and contributions to friends, neighbours, relatives and
strangers.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e342a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e349" publication-type="other">
These figures are comparable to those in other sources of data on charitable donations in the US such
as the Panel Study of Income Dynamics. Table Al in the online appendix presents the summary statistics
and definitions of key variables used in the empirical analysis (see http://www.ifs.org.uk/docs/fsdecl2
voruk appendix.pdf).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e366a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e373" publication-type="other">
Donors were asked the following question: 'How was it you came to give to [name of the charitable
category]? Would you say that you decided to give on your own, responded to being asked by someone,
to a letter, (to a phone call), to an advertisement in the media, or to some other fundraising method?'
(donors were given the option to reply 'responded to a phone call' only in the 1990 edition). In both 1988
and 1990 editions, some respondents picked multiple choices and some others either did not answer this
question or said that they did not remember the catalyst for their donation. Since it is impossible to make
comparisons across donors who reported donating as a response to multiple fundraising methods, I only
consider those donors who reported giving as a response to a single fundraising method. As a result, I
deleted 1,251 observations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e405a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e412" publication-type="other">
This estimate may be misleading due to the low sample size of those who reported giving solely as a
response to a telephone solicitation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e422a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e429" publication-type="other">
The survey does not provide any information about the proportion of people who are approached to
give by different fundraising methods. If the proportion of people who are approached to give by a certain
fundraising method is significantly larger or smaller than the proportion who are approached to give by
other fundraising methods, then survey responses will reflect this fact. Therefore sample statistics should
be interpreted with caution. I acknowledge an anonymous referee for pointing out this caveat.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e448a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e455" publication-type="other">
The wording of this question was as follows: 'How important is each of the following reasons to you
for contributing to a charitable organization? Receiving a letter asking you to give, receiving a phone call
asking you to give, someone coming to the door asking you to give, being asked at work to give, being
asked by someone you know well to give, seeing a television commercial asking you to give, reading a
newspaper or magazine advertisement asking you to give, reading or hearing a news story, being asked to
give in a telethon or radiothon, being asked by clergy to give, being asked by a celebrity to give either on
television, radio, or through the mail, reading about an opportunity or being solicited over the internet,
[and having] volunteered at the organization before. ' This question was not asked in the 1990 edition of
the survey. The 1988 edition included a similar question, but the wording of the question and the coding
of the responses were considerably different from in the other editions, so I exclude the responses from
this year.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e493a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e500" publication-type="other">
Although professional fundraisers are well aware of this result, most charities keep using direct-mail
and telephone solicitations, TV ads, and newspaper or magazine ads (Hopkins, 2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e510a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e517" publication-type="other">
Since the empirical analysis is based on self-reported survey data, the results may be prone to
measurement error and self-reporting bias. If self-reporting bias is correlated with the amount of
charitable contribution and the responsiveness to a certain fundraising method, then the empirical analysis
does not yield consistent estimates of the impact of alternative fundraising methods on the amount of
charitable contributions. Similarly, the empirical analysis is based on pooled cross-sectional data due to
the unavailability of panel data on alternative fundraising methods. Therefore, one cannot control for
individual fixed effects that may affect giving behaviour. If individual fixed effects or other unobserved
variables that may affect charitable behaviour are also correlated with respondents' responsiveness to
certain fundraising methods, then one cannot estimate the impact of alternative fundraising methods on
charitable giving using a simple regression model that assumes the exogeneity of fundraising methods.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e553a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e560" publication-type="other">
Following the standard practice in the literature, 1 use the natural logarithm transformations of
household income and the tax price of giving. The selection of control variables is based on the earlier
literature that investigates the determinants of charitable giving. Andreoni (2006) provides a detailed
discussion of this literature. Religious attendance is documented to be an important determinant of
charitable giving (Gruber, 2004; Yörük, 2009). Yörük (2011) argues that people who have lived in their
community longer are more integrated into their neighbourhood and are more likely to receive certain
types of charitable requests such as personal solicitations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e586a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e593" publication-type="other">
http://www.ifs.org.uk/docs/fsdecl2 voruk appendix.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e600a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e609" publication-type="other">
A potential problem in equation (1) is the endogeneity of the tax price of giving. A widely-used
instrument for the last-dollar price of giving in the literature is the first-dollar price, which excludes the
charitable contributions. Since the main variable of interest is not the tax price, instrumenting this variable
with the first-dollar price or, alternatively, excluding it from the empirical analysis has a very minor
impact on the estimated effects of fundraising methods on charitable behaviour. For instance, when I
exclude the tax price from the regression and re-estimate equation (1), I find the coefficients and standard
errors on alternative fundraising methods to be as follows: asked by someone = -0.409 (0.170); direct-
mail solicitation = -0.566 (0.356); media ad = -1.015 (0.276); and other fundraising method = -0.353
(0.096). These estimates are quite similar to the results reported in the first column of Table A2.
Furthermore, tests find that the differences between the alternative estimates are statistically insignificant.
I also instrument the last-dollar price with the first-dollar price and re-estimate equation (1). Again, the
coefficients on alternative fundraising methods remain quite similar to those reported in Table A2. This
analysis suggests that potential problems due to the possible endogeneity of the tax price have no
significant effect on the estimated coefficients of alternative fundraising methods.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e657a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e664" publication-type="other">
I have also estimated alternative models that control for the possibility of donating money as a
response to multiple fundraising methods. As additional covariates, these models included interaction
dummies that control for each possible combination of fundraising methods. However, in these models,
the coefficients on interaction dummies were mostly insignificant, which suggests that interaction among
alternative fundraising strategies does not play an important role in charitable contributions. These results
are available from the author upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e687a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e694" publication-type="other">
I also repeated the exercise using each fundraising method as the base group. Although not reported,
the results are comparable to those reported in Table 4; they are available on request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e704a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e711" publication-type="other">
If some unobserved covariates are correlated with the amount of donation and responsiveness to a
certain fundraising method, then matching-adjusted estimates are biased. The empirical analysis focuses
on four fundraising methods: personal solicitations, mail solicitations, media ads and telephone
solicitations. Yörük (2012) shows that solicitations via media are random and matching estimators should
provide a reliable estimate. It is plausible that people who are more likely to give are also more likely to
receive personal, mail or telephone solicitations. However, the outcome variable in the empirical analysis
is the amount of charitable contributions of those who are already donors. Therefore, a possible selection
problem is partially controlled for due to the nature of the outcome variable.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e741a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e748" publication-type="other">
I also assume that the matching assumption is satisfied such that Pr( fundIJt =1| f^.(Xl7))e (0,1).
This assumption ensures that for each value of the propensity score, there are both treated and untreated
individuals.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e761a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e768" publication-type="other">
Similarly, in 'high-to-low' matching, the treatment units are ranked according to their propensity
score in a descending order. This method yields similar results to the low-to-high matching under
different specifications. The results are available from the author upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e781a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e788" publication-type="other">
I report the results from the RM with a caliper of 0.005. However, in order to test the robustness of
the results to the selection of neighbourhood, I have implemented the same estimator using several
calipers between 0.001 and 0.005. The results are comparable to the reported estimates and are available
upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e804a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e811" publication-type="other">
Black and Smith (2004) find that the Epanechnikov kernel estimator performs better than the
Gaussian kernel independent of the bandwidth selected and that the performance of the kernel estimator is
relatively independent of the selection of bandwidth until one gets to very small bandwidths. I have also
tried several bandwidths between 0.001 and 0.1. The results are comparable to my original estimate and
are available upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e830a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e837" publication-type="other">
The following variables are used as controls, as described in Table Al: Income90, Tax price of
giving, and Black, Hispanic, Female, Age, Family size, Married, Employed, Homeowner, Churchgoer,
education, community and year dummies. For each fundraising method, I ensure that the propensity score
satisfies the balancing property and conduct the standard t-tests for equality of means in the treatment and
control groups, both before and after matching. These tests and the first-stage probit estimation results are
available upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e860a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e867" publication-type="other">
Although there is no reason to believe that the effectiveness of alternative fundraising methods
differs by state, I also include state fixed effects in equation (5) and re-estimate ordered probit models for
each fundraising method. The results are similar to those from the original models and are available from
the author upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e884a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e891" publication-type="other">
Coefficient estimates for the ordered probit model are available from the author upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e898a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e905" publication-type="other">
I thank an anonymous referee for this suggestion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d29e921a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e925" publication-type="other">
Andreoni, J. (1998), 'Toward a theory of charitable fund-raising', Journal of Political
Economy, vol. 106, pp. 1186-213.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e935a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e939" publication-type="other">
— (2006), 'Philanthropy', in S-C. Kolm and J. Mercier Ythier (eds), Handbook of Giving,
Reciprocity and Altruism, Amsterdam: North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e949a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e953" publication-type="other">
Black, D. A. and Smith, J. A. (2004), 'How robust is the evidence on the effects of college
quality? Evidence from matching', Journal of Econometrics, vol. 121, pp. 99-124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e963a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e967" publication-type="other">
Brown, P. H. and Minty, J. H. (2008), 'Media coverage and charitable giving after the 2004
tsunami', Southern Economic Journal, vol. 75, pp. 9-25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e978a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e982" publication-type="other">
Dehejia, R. H. and Wahba, S. (2002), 'Propensity score-matching methods for
nonexperimental causal studies', Review of Economics and Statistics, vol. 84, pp. 151-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e992a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e996" publication-type="other">
Duncan, B. (1999), 'Modeling charitable contributions of time and money', Journal of Public
Economics, vol. 72, pp. 213^-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1006a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1010" publication-type="other">
— (2002), 'Pumpkin pies and public goods: the raffle fund-raising strategy', Public Choice,
vol. Ill, pp. 49-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1020a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1024" publication-type="other">
Glazer, A. and Konrad, A. K. (1996), 'A signaling explanation for charity', American
Economic Review, vol. 86, pp. 1019-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1034a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1038" publication-type="other">
Gruber, J. (2004), 'Pay or pray? The impact of charitable subsidies on religious attendance',
Journal of Public Economics, vol. 88, pp. 2635-55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1048a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1052" publication-type="other">
Harbaugh, W. T. (1998), 'What do donations buy? A model of philanthropy based on prestige
and warm glow', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 67, pp. 269-84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1063a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1067" publication-type="other">
Hopkins, B. R. (2009), The Law of Fundraising, 4th edition, Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp;
Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1077a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1081" publication-type="other">
Khanna, J., Posnett, J. and Sandler, T. (1995), 'Charity donations in the UK: new evidence
based on panel data', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 56, pp. 257-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1091a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1095" publication-type="other">
Landry, C., Lange, A., List, J. A., Price, M. K. and Rupp, N. (2006), 'Toward an
understanding of the economics of charity: evidence from a field experiment', Quarterly
Journal of Economics, vol. 121, pp. 747-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1108a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1112" publication-type="other">
List, J. A. and Lucking-Reiley, D. (2002), 'The effects of seed money and refunds on
charitable giving: experimental evidence from a university capital campaign', Journal of
Political Economy, vol. 110, pp. 215-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1125a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1129" publication-type="other">
Meer, J. and Rosen, H. S. (2011), 'The ABCs of charitable solicitation', Journal of Public
Economics, vol. 95, pp. 363-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1139a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1143" publication-type="other">
Okten, C. and Weisbrod, B. A. (2000), 'Determinants of donations in private non-profit
markets', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 75, pp. 255-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1154a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1158" publication-type="other">
Romano, R. and Yildirim, H. (2001), 'Why charities announce donations: a positive
perspective', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 81, pp. 423^17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1168a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1172" publication-type="other">
Rose-Ackerman, S. (1982), 'Charitable giving and "excessive" fundraising', Quarterly
Journal of Economics, vol. 97, pp. 193-212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1182a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1186" publication-type="other">
Rosenbaum, P. R. (1995), Observational Studies, New York, NY: Springer Verlag.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1193a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1197" publication-type="other">
— and Rubin, D. B. (1983), 'The central role of the propensity score in observational studies
for causal effects', Biometrika, vol. 70, pp. 41-55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1207a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1211" publication-type="other">
Yörük, B. K. (2009), 'How responsive are charitable donors to requests to give?', Journal of
Public Economics, vol. 93, pp. Ill 1-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1221a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1225" publication-type="other">
— (2010), 'Charitable giving by married couples revisited', Journal of Human Resources,
vol. 45, pp. 497-516.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1236a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1240" publication-type="other">
— (2011), 'Do fundraisers select charitable donors based on gender and race? Evidence from
survey data Journal of Population Economics, vol. 25, pp. 219—43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1250a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1254" publication-type="other">
— (2012), 'The effect of media on charitable giving and volunteering: evidence from the
"Give Five" campaign', Journal of Policy Analysis and Management, vol. 31, PP- 813-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
