<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278176</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of a Solid Exhaust Particle Number Measurement System Using a Catalytic Stripper Technology</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Khalek</surname>
                  <given-names>Imad A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bougher</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Southwest Research Institute</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>639</fpage>
         <lpage>649</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278176"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A solid particle number measurement system (SPNMS) was developed using a catalytic stripper (CS) technology instead of an evaporation tube (ET). The ET is used in commercially available systems, compliant with the Particle Measurement Program (PMP) protocol developed for European Union (EU) solid particle number regulations. The catalytic stripper consists of a small core of a diesel exhaust oxidation catalyst. The SPNMS/CS met all performance requirements under the PMP protocol. It showed a much better performance in removing large volatile tetracontane particles down to a size well below the PMP lower cut-size of 23 nm, compared to a SPNMS equipped with an ET instead of a CS. The SPNMS/CS also showed a similar performance to a commercially available system when used on a gasoline direct injection (GDI) engine exhaust.</p>
            <p>While both the SPNMS/CS and the SPNMS/ET will likely perform similarly when used within the confinement of Euro 6/VI regulations, the SPNMS/CS has some advantages over an SPNMS/ET in its ability to evaporate and oxidize the volatile hydrocarbon materials instead of simply transferring them to the gas phase as done with the ET. Oxidizing the volatile hydrocarbon species promotes a faster droplet evaporation and reduces any potential artifact particle formation downstream of the CS, as compared with the ET, during dilution and/or cooling. This performance characteristic may give the SPNMS/CS a wider flexibility for measuring solid particle number from various combustion sources with high volatile particulate matter, well beyond the current scope of regulatory requirements. Relative to the potential sulfuric acid formation downstream of the CS, we were able to demonstrate in previous work that sulfuric acid formation does not occur at the CS operating temperature of 300°C. In addition, using synthetic gas containing high concentration of SO2 in air (∼80 ppm), this CS showed high adsorption of SO₂ with no sign of SO₃ formation at its operating temperature of 300°C.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.arb.ca.gov/msprog/levprog/leviii/leviii.htm</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel, B., Wang, X., Horn, H., Spielvogel, J., Gerhart, C., Southgate, J., Jing, L., Kasper, M., Drossinos, Y., Krasenbrink, A., “Calibration of Condensation particle Counters for Legislated Vehicle Number Emission Measurements,” Aero. Sci. &amp; Tech., Vol 43, PP 1164-1173, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.unece.org/trans/main/wp29/wp29wgs/wp29grpe/pmpFCP.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel, B., Carriero, M., Martini, G., Krasenbrink, A. et al., “Calibration and Validation of Various Commercial Particle Number Measurement Systems,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1):512-530, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1115.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel, B. and Drossinos, Y., “Theoretical Investigation of Volatile Removal Efficiency of Particle Number Measurement Systems,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1): 1140-1151, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel, B., Chirico, R., DeCarlo, P., Clairotte, M., Adam, T., Martini, G., Heringa, M., Richter, R., Prevot, A., Baltensperger, U., Astorga, C., “Evaluation of the Particle Measurement Programme (PMP) Protocol to Remove the Vehicles Exhaust Aerosol Volatile Phase,” Sci. of Tot. Env., Vol 408, pp 5106-5116, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kasper, M, “The Number Concentration of Non-Volatile Particles - Design Study for an Instrument According to the PMP Recommendations,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0960, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0960.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei, Q., Oestergaard, K., Porter, S., Ichiro, A. et al., “Real-Time Measuring System for Engine Exhaust Solid Particle Number Emission - Design and Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0864, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0864.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel, B., Gresnoverh, M., Jorgl, H. and Alexander, A., “Calibration and Accuracy of a Particle Number Measurement System,” Meas. Sci. Technol., Vol 21, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swanson, J. and Kittelosn, D., “Evaluation of Thermal Denuder and Catalytic Stripper Methods for Solid Particle Measurements,” J. Aerosol Sci., Vol. 41, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hands, T., Symonds, J., Finch, A.J., and Nickolaus, C., “Real-time Particle Emissions from 2-stroke Motorbikes with and without PMP Sampling System,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-32-0047, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-32-0047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdul-Khalek, I.S. and Kittelson, D.B., “Real Time Measurement of Volatile and Solid Exhaust Particles Using a Catalytic Stripper,” SAE Technical Paper 950236, 1995, doi: 10.4271/950236.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek, I.A., “Sampling System for Solid and Volatile Exhaust Particle Size, Number, and Mass Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0307, SAE Transactions - Journal of Fuels and Lubricants, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">TSI Manual, CPC 3025A.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hinds, “Aerosol Technology Properties, Behavior, and Measurement of Airborne Particles,” 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek, I.A., Kittelson, D.B., and Brear, F., “Nanoparticle Growth During Dilution and Cooling of Diesel Exhaust: Experimental Investigation and Theoretical Assessment,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0515, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-0515.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mohn, J., Emmenegger, L., “Determination of sulfur dioxide by pulsed laser UV-Flurorescence,” Swiss Federal Laboratories for Materials Testing and Research (EMPA), http://www.empa.ch/plugin/template/empa/*/5638/---/1=2</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek, I.A., Bougher, T., and Jetter, J.J., “Particle Emissions from a 2009 Gasoline Direct Injection Engine Using Different Commercially Available Fuels,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(2):623-637, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2117.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
