<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440299</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Contract Type and the Cost of Provision: Evidence from Maintenance Service Contracts</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Paul H.</given-names>
                  <surname>Jensen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Robin E.</given-names>
                  <surname>Stonecash</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">30</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440093</issue-id>
         <fpage>279</fpage>
         <lpage>296</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2009</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440299"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>More than half a billion dollars are spent each year on the maintenance of Australia's urban water and sewerage networks. Expenditure is governed through a mix of in-house and outsourced maintenance service contracts. We re-examine issues relating to the relationship between the cost of maintenance service provision and the type of contract used. We take advantage of the fact that water retailers in Melbourne use a mix of contract types – including fixed-price (FP) and cost-plus (C+) contracts – for the provision of water and sewerage network maintenance services. Our results suggest that the C+ contract results in substantial savings.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d36e171a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e178" publication-type="other">
Submitted September 2007.
The authors are appreciative of the important contributions to this paper made by the Editor (Gareth
Myles), two anonymous referees, Harry Bloch, Stephen King, Robert Marks, John Quiggin, Simon
Sheather, Beth Webster and Jongsay Yong. All errors remain the authors'. Funding for the research came
from an Australian Research Council Linkage Grant (C00106893), under which the authors' Linkage
Partner (Serco Asia-Pacific) made both cash and in-kind contributions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e201a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e208" publication-type="other">
See Lafontaine and Slade (2001) and Prendergast (2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e215a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e222" publication-type="other">
Such spikes may occur in emergency services, for example, when there are severe weather episodes.
The market approach of raising price is not possible because of the political and social welfare
implications of doing so. This is perhaps one important reason why many such services remain in public
hands.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e238a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e245" publication-type="other">
See Chakravarty and MacLeod (2004) and Corts (2007).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e253a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e260" publication-type="other">
Corporatisation refers to the process whereby public agencies are subjected to performance measures
similar to private sector firms. However, the government retains ownership of the agency and its assets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e270a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e277" publication-type="other">
Banerjee and Duflo, 2000; Corts and Singh, 2004; Corts, 2007; Kalnins and Mayer, 2004.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e284a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e291" publication-type="other">
However, note that since quality is difficult to observe in the provision of maintenance services, price
may be the most important criterion used by the government to evaluate the tenders.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e301a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e308" publication-type="other">
Although the budgets for these two classes of maintenance activities are separated, there is a
relationship between the two, since low levels of preventative maintenance generally increase the
frequency of system failures. Allowing the contractor to determine the level of preventative maintenance
may, therefore, be undesirable since it provides a perverse incentive to underinvest in preventative
maintenance. This problem is overcome here since the retailers determine expenditure on preventative
maintenance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e331a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e338" publication-type="other">
The assumption of risk aversion for the agent and risk neutrality for the principal is standard in the
contract theory literature.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e348a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e355" publication-type="other">
We are grateful to a referee who pointed out that contractors working on a C+ basis still have an
incentive to 'chisel' quality in this context for the following reason: they can spend three hours
performing the task to a low level of quality in the knowledge that they could be back working tomorrow
repairing the same problem.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e372a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e379" publication-type="other">
The Victorian government made this decision in 1993 in order to prevent the possibility that one
company could monopolise the provision of water and sewerage maintenance services in Victoria.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e389a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e396" publication-type="other">
For example, fixing a burst water main less than two metres underground has a different price from
fixing a burst water main that is more than two metres underground. In order to get a single price, a
weighted average was calculated using the expected distribution of activities provided in the request-for-
tender documentation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e412a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e419" publication-type="other">
There are also the negative externalities associated with increased traffic congestion related to
maintenance work performed in the CBD area, but these are unpriced.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e429a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e436" publication-type="other">
Unplanned interruptions are severe failures in the system that require the water to be turned off
completely. Only a small proportion of all reactive maintenance activities are recorded as unplanned
interruptions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e449a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e456" publication-type="other">
This is a common problem in attempting to analyse expenditures pre- and post-outsourcing,
particularly for government entities, since wholly-owned government entities often did not keep detailed
data on services performed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e469a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e476" publication-type="other">
See Card and Krueger (1994).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e484a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e491" publication-type="other">
As already mentioned, there were two types of maintenance work that the contractors provided:
reactive and preventative. The work that is the focus of this study is the reactive (i.e. unplanned)
component, which is exogenously determined by factors such as the weather and asset conditions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e504a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e511" publication-type="other">
Obviously, this condition would not hold if the observations were made in different cities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e518a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e525" publication-type="other">
There are seven types of maintenance activity included in the analysis. For each type of maintenance
activity, there are multiple jobs in each month. Our data are expressed in total monthly expenditure and
the number of jobs performed per activity type.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e538a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e545" publication-type="other">
See Burnett and Wampler (1998) and Ewerhart and Fieseler (2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e552a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e559" publication-type="other">
The reason that bidding behaviour cannot be considered here is that we do not have access to the data
on the bids submitted by each tenderer. All we have access to are the unit prices submitted by the winning
bidders.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e572a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e579" publication-type="other">
See Bajari and Tadeiis (2001).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d36e595a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e599" publication-type="other">
Bajari, P., Houghton, S. and Tadelis, S. (2007), 'Bidding for incomplete contracts: an
empirical analysis of adaptation costs', unpublished mimeo, University of Minnesota, 8
January.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e612a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e616" publication-type="other">
— and Tadelis, S. (2001), 'Incentives versus transaction costs: a theory of procurement
contracts', RAND Journal of Economics, vol. 32, pp. 387—407.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e626a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e630" publication-type="other">
Banerjee, A. and Duflo, E. (2000), 'Reputation effects and the limits of contracting: a study of
the Indian software industry', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 115, pp. 989-1017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e640a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e644" publication-type="other">
Burnett, J. E. and Wampler, B. M. (1998), 'Unit price contracts: a practical framework for
determining competitive bid prices', Journal of Applied Business Research, vol. 14, pp.
63-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e658a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e662" publication-type="other">
Card, D. and Krueger, A. B. (1994), 'Minimum wages and employment: a case study of the
fast-food industry in New Jersey and Pennsylvania', American Economic Review, vol. 84,
pp. 772-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e675a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e679" publication-type="other">
Chakravarty, S. and MacLeod, W. B. (2004), 'On the efficiency of standard form contracts:
the case of construction', University of Southern California (USC), Center in Law,
Economics and Organization (CLEO), Research Paper no. C04-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e692a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e696" publication-type="other">
Corts, K. (2007), 'The interaction of implicit and explicit contracts in construction and
procurement contracting', unpublished mimeo, University of Toronto, 20 December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e706a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e710" publication-type="other">
— and Singh, J. (2004), 'The effect of repeated interaction on contract choice: evidence from
offshore drilling \ Journal of Law, Economics and Organization, vol. 20, pp. 230-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e720a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e724" publication-type="other">
Crocker, K. J. and Reynolds, K. J. (1993), 'The efficiency of incomplete contracts: an
empirical analysis of Air Force engine procurement', RAND Journal of Economics, vol.
24, pp. 126-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e737a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e741" publication-type="other">
Ewerhart, C. and Fieseler, K. (2003), 'Procurement auctions and unit-price contracts', RAND
Journal of Economics, vol. 34, pp. 569-81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e752a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e756" publication-type="other">
Hart, O., Shleifer, A. and Vishny, R. W. (1997), 'The proper scope of government: theory and
an application to prisons', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 112, pp. 1127-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e766a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e770" publication-type="other">
Holmström, B. and Milgrom, P. (1991), 'Multitask principal-agent analyses: incentive
contracts, asset ownership, and job design', Journal of Law, Economics and Organization,
vol. 7, pp. 24-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e783a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e787" publication-type="other">
Kalnins, A. and Mayer, K. (2004), 'Relationships and hybrid contracts: an analysis of contract
choice in information technology', Journal of Law, Economics and Organization, vol. 20,
pp. 207-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e800a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e804" publication-type="other">
Laffont, J. J. and Tirole, J. (1993), A Theory of Incentives in Procurement and Regulation,
Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e814a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e818" publication-type="other">
Lafontaine, F. and Slade, M. E. (2001), 'Incentive contracting and the franchise decision', in
K. Chatteijee and W. F. Samuelson (eds), Game Theory and Business Applications,
Boston, MA: Kluwer Academic.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e831a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e835" publication-type="other">
McAfee, R. P. and McMillan, J. (1988), Incentives in Government Contracting, Toronto:
University of Toronto Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e846a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e850" publication-type="other">
Meyer, B. D. (1994), 'Natural and quasi-experiments in economics', National Bureau of
Economic Research (NBER), Technical Working Paper no. 170.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e860a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e864" publication-type="other">
Prendergast, C. (2002), 'The tenuous tradeoff between risk and incentives', Journal of
Political Economy, vol. 110, pp. 1071-102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e874a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e878" publication-type="other">
Water Services Association of Australia (2008), Performance of the Australian Urban Water
Industry and Projections for the Future, Sydney: Water Services Association of Australia.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
