<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">jfinancialedu</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007490</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Journal of Financial Education</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Financial Education Association (FEA)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00933961</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2332421X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26573539</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>SPECIAL TOPICS</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Lessons Learned from the MBA Program for a Successful Online MSF Program</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Butchey</surname>
                  <given-names>Deanne</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Florida International University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Dandapani</surname>
                  <given-names>Krishnan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Florida International University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Lawrence</surname>
                  <given-names>Edward</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Florida International University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>SPRING 2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>44</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e26573531</issue-id>
         <fpage>127</fpage>
         <lpage>145</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26573539"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The recent shift towards online education portends the development of specialized master’s programs such as the Master of Science in Finance (MSF) program. In this paper, we translate lessons learned from the online MBA program to produce a successful specialized graduate finance program, with the potential of reaching a larger global market. We aim to extrapolate on the potential for success of the online MSF by evaluating the efficacy of the long running online MBA program at our university, the Corporate MBA (CMBA). All Professional MBA (PMBA) programs, including the CMBA, share equivalent student learning outcomes and curriculum. We compare admission standards, retention data, and end of program assessments to analyze the common characteristics that preclude student success under the two separate modes of instruction. The paper describes further measures necessary to enhance the value of an online program. Through this study, the authors hope to advance the discussion of graduate online education in Finance to service a more extensive customer base while ensuring better-prepared graduates.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label> 
            <kwd>Distance learning</kwd> 
            <kwd>educational research</kwd> 
            <kwd>accreditation</kwd> 
            <kwd>pedagogy</kwd> 
            <kwd>MSF program</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allen, I. E., &amp; Seaman, J. (2013). Changing Course: Ten Years of Tracking Online Education in the United States. Sloan Consortium. PO Box 1238, Newburyport, MA 01950.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allen, I. E., &amp; Seaman, J. (2016). Online Report Card: Tracking Online Education in the United States. Babson Survey Research Group.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aragon, S. R., &amp; Johnson, E. S. (2008). Factors influencing completion and noncompletion of community college online courses. The American Journal of Distance Education, 22(3), 146-158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arbaugh, J. B. (2002). Managing the on-line classroom: a study of technological and behavioral characteristics of web-based MBA courses. Journal of High Technology Management Research, 13, 203–223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arbaugh, J. B., &amp; Duray, R. (2002). Technological and structural characteristics, student learning and satisfaction with web-based courses– An exploratory study of two on-line MBA programs. Management Learning, 33(3), 331–347.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aronen, R., &amp; Dieressen, G. (2001). Improvement equipment reliability through e-Learning. Hydrocarbon Processing, 47–57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baker, K. (2010). Clinical teaching improves with resident evaluation and feedback.The Journal of the American Society of Anesthesiologists, 113(3), 693-703.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bannier, B. J. (2010). Motivating and assisting adult, online chemistry students: A review of the literature. Journal of Science Education and Technology, 19(3), 215-236.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bawa, P. (2016). Retention in Online Courses: Exploring Issues and Solutions—A Literature Review. Sage Open, 6(1), 2158244015621777.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Betts, K., &amp; Heaston, A. (2014). Build it but will they teach?: Strategies for increasing faculty participation &amp; retention in online &amp; blended education. Online Journal of Distance Learning Administration, 17(2), n2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bocchi, J., Eastman, J. K., &amp; Swift, C. O. (2004). Retaining the online learner: Profile of students in an online MBA program and implications for teaching them. Journal of Education for Business, 79(4), 245-253.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Breslow, L., Pritchard, D. E., DeBoer, J., Stump, G. S., Ho, A. D., &amp; Seaton, D. T. (2013). Studying learning in the worldwide classroom: Research into edX’s first MOOC. Research &amp; Practice in Assessment, 8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bunn, J. (2004). Student persistence in a LIS distance education program. Australian Academic Research Libraries, 35(3), 253-270.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, W. L. C., &amp; Bagakas, J. G. (2003). Understanding the dimensions of selfexploration in web-based learning environments. Journal of Research on Technology in Education, 34(3), 364–373.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chiyaka, E., Sithole, A., Manyanga, F., McCarthy, P., &amp; Bucklein, B. (2016). Institutional characteristics and student retention: What integrated postsecondary education data reveals about online learning. Online Journal of Distance Learning Administration, 19(2).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coates, D., Humphreys, B., Kane, J., Vachris, M. (2004). No Significant distance between face-to-face and online instruction: evidence from principles of economics. Economics of Education Review, 23, 533-546.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dykman, C., Davis, C. (2008). The Shift Toward Online Education, Journal of Information Systems Education; West Lafayette Vol. 19, Iss. 1: 11-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eom, S. B., Wen, H. J., &amp; Ashill, N. (2006). The determinants of students’ perceived learning outcomes and satisfaction in university online education: An empirical investigation. Decision Sciences Journal of Innovative Education, 4(2), 215-235.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farinella, J. (2007). Professor and Student Performance in Online vs. Traditional introductory finance courses. Journal of Economics and Finance Education, 6, 40-47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrell, G. M. (2009). Results-Based Monitoring and Evaluation at the Commonwealth of Learning. Commonwealth of Learning (COL).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferguson, J. M., &amp; DeFelice, A. E. (2010). Length of online course and student satisfaction, perceived learning, and academic performance. The International Review of Research in Open and Distributed Learning, 11(2), 73-84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gratton-Lavoie, C. Stanley D., (2009). Teaching and learning principles of microeconomics online: An empirical assessment. Journal of Economic Education, Winter, 3-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harrell, I. L., &amp; Bower, B. L. (2011). Student characteristics that predict persistence in community college online courses. American Journal of Distance Education, 25(3), 178-191.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hart, C. (2012). Factors associated with student persistence in an online program of study: A review of the literature. Journal of Interactive Online Learning, 11(1).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hawkins, A., Barbour, M. K., &amp; Graham, C. R. (2012). “Everybody is their own island”: Teacher disconnection in a virtual school. The International Review of Research in Open and Distributed Learning, 13(2), 124-144.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Holder, B. (2007). An investigation of hope, academics, environment, and motivation as predictors of persistence in higher education online programs. The Internet and Higher Education, 10(4), 245-260.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hong, K. S. (2002). Relationships between students’ and instructional variables with satisfaction and learning from a Web-based course. The Internet and Higher Education, 5, 267–281.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ivankova, N. V., &amp; Stick, S. L. (2007). Students’ persistence in a distributed doctoral program in educational leadership in higher education: A mixed methods study. Research in Higher Education, 48(1), 93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnston, J., Killion, J., &amp; Oomen, J. (2005). Student satisfaction in the virtual classroom. Internet Journal of Allied Health Sciences and Practice, 3(2), 6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Katiso, A. E. (2015).Online adult students’ time management skills and their academic achievement and persistence: Technology-based learning and student success (Order No. 10099971). Available from ProQuest Dissertations &amp; Theses Global. (1783598302). Retrieved on 12/6/2017 from http://ezproxy.liberty.edu:2048/login?url=http://search.proquest.com/ docview/1783598302?accountid=12008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, K. J., &amp; Frick, T. W. (2011). Changes in student motivation during online learning. Journal of Educational Computing Research, 44(1), 1-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, K. J., Liu, S., &amp; Bonk, C. J. (2005). Online MBA students’ perceptions of online learning: Benefits, challenges, and suggestions. The Internet and Higher Education, 8(4), 335-344.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kunz, M. B., &amp; Cheek, R. G. (2016). How AACSB-Accredited Business Schools Assure Quality Online Education. Academy of Business Journal, 1(1), 105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, J. H., &amp; Choi, M. N. (2011). Evaluation of effects of a clinical reasoning course among undergraduate nursing students. Korean Journal of Adult Nursing, 23(1), 1-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lewis, C. (2002). Driving factors for e-Learning: an organizational perspective. Perspectives, 6(2), 50–54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lim, D. H., &amp; Kim, H. (2003). Motivation and learner characteristics affecting online learning and learning application. Journal of Educational Technology Systems, 31(4), 423-439.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Means, B., Toyama, Y., Murphy, R., Bakia, M., Jones, K. (2009, April 30, Revised September 2010). Evaluation of Evidence-Based Practices in Online Learning: A Meta-Analysis and Review of Online Learning Studies. Retrieved December 06, 2017, from https://eric.ed.gov/?id=ED505824.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meyer, K. A., Bruwelheide, J., &amp; Poulin, R. (2009). Why they stayed: Nearperfect retention in an online certification program in library media. Journal of Asynchronous Learning Networks, 13(3), 129-145.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Müller, T. (2008). Persistence of women in online degree-completion programs. The International Review of Research in Open and Distributed Learning, 9(2).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Normandy &amp; Damman (2016, September, 12/12/2016, Faculty Training for Online Course Development: Connecting to Student Success, Retrieved from www. sacscoc.org/2016amho/CS%20Handouts/CS-118_Normandy.pdf on 12/6/2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piccoli, G., Ahmad, R., &amp; Ives, B. (2001). Web-based virtual learning environments: a research framework and a preliminary assessment of effectiveness in basic IT skill training. MIS Quarterly, 25(4), 401–426.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rovai, A. P. (2003). In search of higher persistence rates in distance education online programs. The Internet and Higher Education, 6(1), 1-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sansone, C., Fraughton, T., Zachary, J. L., Butner, J., &amp; Heiner, C. (2011). Selfregulation of motivation when learning online: The importance of who, why and how. Educational Technology Research and Development, 59(2), 199-212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smith, A. R. (2016). Ensuring Quality: The Faculty Role in Online. Handbook of Research on Building, Growing, and Sustaining Quality E-Learning Programs, 210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stokes, S. P. (2001). Satisfaction of college students with the digital learning environment. Do Learners’ temperaments make a difference? The Internet and High Education, 4, 31–44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun P., Tsai R.J., Finger G., Chen Y. and Yeh D., (2008). What drives a successful e-learning? An empirical investigation of the critical factors influencing learner satisfaction. Computers and Education, 50, 1183-1202</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The AACSB Accreditation Standards, World Headquarters. (n.d.). Eligibility Procedures and Accreditation Standards for Business Accreditation. Retrieved on November 1, 2017, from http://www.aacsb.edu/accreditation/standards.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Principles of Accreditation: Foundations for Quality Enhancement 2012. Retrieved November 1, 2017, from the World Wide Web: http://www.sacscoc. org/principles.asp</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thurmond, V. A., Wambach, K., &amp; Connors, H. R. (2002). Evaluation of student satisfaction: determining the impact of a web-based environment by controlling for student characteristics. The American Journal of Distance Education, 163, 169–189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Trawick M.W, Lile S.E. and Howsen R.M. (2010). Predicting Performance for online students: Is it better to be home alone? Journal of Applied Economics and Policy, Volume 29, 34-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Willging, P. A., &amp; Johnson, S. D. (2004). Factors that influence students’ decision to dropout of online courses. Journal of Asynchronous Learning Networks, 8, 105-118.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wu, J. P., Tsai, R. J., Chen, C. C., &amp; Wu, Y. C. (2006). An integrative model to predict the continuance use of electronic learning systems: hints for teaching. International Journal on E-Learning, 5, 287–302.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, D., Richardson, J. C., French, B. F., &amp; Lehman, J. D. (2011). The development of a content analysis model for assessing students’ cognitive learning in asynchronous online discussions. Educational Technology Research and Development, 59(1), 43-70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
