<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">9</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466905</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466910</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Valuation, Adverse Selection, and Market Collapses</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Michael J.</given-names>
                  <surname>Fishman</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Jonathan A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Parker</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2575</fpage>
         <lpage>2607</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466910"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We study a market for funding real investment where valuation—meaning investors devoting resources to acquiring information about future payoffs—creates an adverse selection problem. Unlike previous models, more valuation is associated with lower market prices and so greater returns to valuation. This strategic complementarity in the capacity to do valuation generates multiple equilibria. With multiple equilibria, the equilibrium without valuation is most efficient despite funding some unprofitable investments. Switches to valuation equilibria, valuation runs, look like credit crunches. A large investor can ensure the efficient equilibrium only if it can precommit to a price and potentially, only if subsidized.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d726312e171a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e178" publication-type="other">
As we discuss, this channel is different from that in Dang (2008) and Glode et al. (2012) both technically,
as valuation in our model uncovers information about the joint surplus from trade, and economically, as the
externality in our model operates through the market price.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e191a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e198" publication-type="other">
In the language of Hellwig and Veldkamp (2009), the choice of the technology to uncover information is a
strategic complement, but information is a strategic substitute, in that sophisticated investors want different
information from each other (information about different assets).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e211a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e218" publication-type="other">
Over a different region of parameters, the market can either be in a pooling equilibrium or a mixed equilibrium
with low prices but in which sophisticated investors value as many assets as they can, purchase only the good
ones, and unsophisticated investors purchase both the rejected assets and the unvalued assets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e231a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e238" publication-type="other">
In a bank run, agents protect themselves by withdrawing funds because they expect others to do so and funds
are not lent to one bank; in our model, sophisticated agents protect themselves by investing in valuation capacity
because they expect others to do so and funds are not lent to many distinct entities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e252a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e259" publication-type="other">
Although we do not model what happens to assets once sold, in mapping to the real world, all investors potentially
have mark-to-market losses on asset holdings because of the price decline.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e269a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e276" publication-type="other">
Notably, the model omits many benefits of valuation, and in particular that valuation might reveal information
about the aggregate payoff of all assets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e286a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e293" publication-type="other">
If in our setting there were always gains from trade as in Dang (2008) then trade would never collapse.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e300a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e307" publication-type="other">
Two other papers on security design are worth noting. Marin and Rahi (2000) considers security design and
shows how the optimality of complete versus incomplete markets (complete versus incomplete revelation of
private information) depends on the costs of adverse selection on private information relative to the costs of
reduced ex ante insurance. Pagano and Volpin (2012) considers security design and then a later equilibrium in
which trade occurs in a noisy rational expectations equilibrium so that information can get rents. Even though
the model exhibits an externality from valuation, it does not generate multiplicity of equilibrium beyond those
always possible in noisy rational expectations equilibria (Breon-Drish 2015), nor is there a role for commitment,
and so optimal policy is different.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e336a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e343" publication-type="other">
It is also possible that our model may prove useful in undertanding high-frequency patterns where there is
evidence that informed traders can "cream skim" the best deals (Seppi 1990; Easley et al. 1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e353a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e360" publication-type="other">
The limit can be due to a limited number of people with the ability to do valuation. An alternative assumption
with the same implications is that there is a limit on the amount of financial capital available to the sophisticated
investors. That is, the aggregate constraint on valuation could be due to limits-to-arbitrage rather than a
technological or resource constraint.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e377a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e384" publication-type="other">
An interesting paper with a similar approach to information but a different structure and implications is Broecker
(1990), in which valuation is costless but noisy, and correlated across lenders. In equilibrium, the winners curse
from noisy valuation interacts with the adverse selection problem to generate an equilibrium with a continuum
of interest rates across different banks.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e400a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e407" publication-type="other">
Although it is possible that a sophisticated investor that does not invest in valuation capacity mimics an
unsophisticated investor and chooses a large amount of funding capacity, this does not affect the equilibrium
price or quantity, and we ignore this for ease of exposition.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e420a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e427" publication-type="other">
Another potential screening mechanism could involve a penalty on a seller depending on the asset's payoff
(rather than the valuation)—that is, have the seller bear some risk. Two common foundations that preclude such
an arrangement are moral hazard on the part of the new owner (the investor) or there being no resources for the
investor to collect if the asset turns out to be bad.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e443a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e450" publication-type="other">
There is a discontinuity (outside our assumed range) at X= 1, where the valuation equilibrium cannot occur for
c&gt;0 even when H = 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e460a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e467" publication-type="other">
As an aside, there is also no higher payoff to the sellers of good assets relative to bad assets in the pure valuation
equilibrium because both receive their reservation values. This result would change if sellers with good assets
received some of the rents.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e480a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e487" publication-type="other">
Gorton and Ordonez (2014) also draws out new insights for fluctuations in informed lending by incorporating
secondary markets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e498a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e505" publication-type="other">
Similarly, Kurlat (2012) analyzes a model in which increases in the volume of assets for sale induces the entry
of valuation skill. This worsens adverse selection problems and lower prices, rationalizing declines in prices
associated with fire sales.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e518a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e527" publication-type="other">
An alternative set up with identical results has sellers, after a possible valuation, sell through a second-price
sealed-bid auction with a reservation price of 1. The optimal bid in a second-price auction is one's valuation.
Thus a sophisticated investor who knows the asset is good wins the auction and pays either the reservation price
(as in the pure valuation equilibrium) or the bid of unsophisticated investors (as in the mixed equilibrium). If no
sophisticated investor has valued the asset, then an unsophisticated investor wins the auction, paying the bid of
other unsophisticated investors (as in the pooling equilibrium).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e550a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e557" publication-type="other">
Guerrieri and Shimer (2014) and Chang (2011) analyze fire sales in a model in which sellers who know the
quality of their asset can signal their information by delaying the sale of their asset.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e567a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e574" publication-type="other">
It seems more likely that credit bureaus, like ratings agencies, simply segment assets into markets, each of which
is either in a pooling equilibrium or valuation equilibrium, where buyers do or do not investigate beyond the
credit check. It is notable that credit bureaus may not reveal the identity of those who conduct credit checks and
so do not reveal the purpose of the check (information that an unsophisticated investor would find useful).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e590a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e597" publication-type="other">
Even though we do not see this as a realistic feature of asset markets, similar policies are imposed in insurance
markets where insurance cannot be predicated on testing. In addition, auctioneers as market makers may not
make items available for inspection prior to the auction.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e610a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e617" publication-type="other">
Sorkin (2009) describes several episodes during the U.S. financial crisis of commercial banks valuing an
investment bank for purchase in which both parties, but especially the investment bank, tried to keep secret
the fact that a valuation was occurring.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726312e631a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726312e638" publication-type="other">
Although, if the tax and subsidy plan were balanced-budget and orthogonal to the mean payoff, then such a policy
could avoid diminishing the incentive to collect information about asset-class wide payoffs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d726312e657a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e661" publication-type="other">
Akerlof, G 1970. The market for "lemons": Quality uncertainty and the market mechanism. The Quarterly
Journal of Economics 84:488-500.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e671a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e675" publication-type="other">
Axelson, U. 2007. Security design with investor private information. Journal of Finance 62:2587-632.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e682a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e686" publication-type="other">
Bolton, P., T. Santos, and J. Scheinkman. 2011. Cream skimming in financial markets. Working Paper 16804,
National Bureau of Economic Research, Inc.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e696a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e700" publication-type="other">
Breon-Drish, B. 2015. Asymmetric information in financial markets: Anything goes. Review of Economic Studies
Forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e711a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e715" publication-type="other">
Broecker, T. 1990. Credit-worthiness tests and interbank competition. Econometrica 58:429-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e722a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e726" publication-type="other">
Chang, B. 2011. Adverse selection and liquidity distortion in decentralized markets. Working Paper, Northwestern
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e736a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e740" publication-type="other">
Dang, T. 2008. Bargaining with endogenous information. Journal of Economic Theory 140:339-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e747a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e751" publication-type="other">
Dang, T., G Gorton, and B. Holmstrom. 2009. Opacity and the optimality of debt for liquidity provision. Working
Paper, Yale University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e761a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e765" publication-type="other">
Dell'Ariccia, G, and R. Marquez. 2006. Lending booms and lending standards. Journal of Finance 61:2511-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e772a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e776" publication-type="other">
DeMarzo, P. 2005. The pooling and tranching of securities: A model of informed intermediation. The Review of
Financial Studies 18:1-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e787a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e791" publication-type="other">
DeMarzo, P., and D. Duffie. 1999. A liquidity-based model of security design. Econometrica 67:65-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e798a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e802" publication-type="other">
Easley, D., N. Kiefer, and M. O'Hara. 1996. Cream-skimming or profit-sharing? The curious role of purchased
order flow. Journal of Finance 51:811-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e812a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e816" publication-type="other">
Eisfeldt, A. 2004. Endogenous liquidity in asset markets. The Journal of Finance 59:1-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e823a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e827" publication-type="other">
Farhi, E., J. Lerner, and J. Tirole. 2013. Fear of rejection? Tiered certification and transparency. RAND Journal
of Economics 44:610-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e837a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e841" publication-type="other">
Glode, V., R. Green, and R. Lowery. 2012. Financial expertise as an arms race. Journal of Finance 67:1723-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e848a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e852" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G 2010. Slapped by the invisible hand: The panic of2007. New York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e860a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e864" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G, and G Ordonez. 2014. Collateral crises. American Economic Review 104:343-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e871a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e875" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G, and G Pennacchi. 1990. Financial intermediaries and liquidity creation. The Journal of Finance
45:49-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e885a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e889" publication-type="other">
Guerrieri, V., and R. Shimer. 2014. Dynamic adverse selection: A theory of illiquidity, fire sales, and flight to
quality. American Economic Review 104:1875-908.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e899a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e903" publication-type="other">
Hellwig, C., and L. Veldkamp. 2009. Knowing what others know: Coordination motives in information
acquisition. Review of Economic Studies 76:223-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e913a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e917" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, J. 1971. The private and social value of information and the reward to inventive activity. The American
Economic Review 61:561-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e927a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e931" publication-type="other">
Kindleberger, C. 2000. Manias, panics, and crashes: A history of financial crises. London: Palgrave Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e939a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e943" publication-type="other">
Kurlat, P. 2010. Lemons, market shutdowns and learning. Working Paper, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e950a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e954" publication-type="other">
. 2012. Asset markets with heterogeneous information. Working Paper, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e961a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e965" publication-type="other">
Malherbe, F. 2014. Self-fulfilling liquidity dry-ups. Journal of Finance 69:947-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e972a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e976" publication-type="other">
Mankiw, N. 1986. The allocation of credit and financial collapse. The Quarterly Journal of Economics
101:455-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e986a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e990" publication-type="other">
Marin, J., and R. Rahi. 2000. Information revelation and market incompleteness. The Review of Economic Studies
67:563-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e1000a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e1004" publication-type="other">
Morris, S., and H. Shin. 2012. Contagious adverse selection. American Economic Journal: Macroeconomics
4:1-21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e1015a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e1019" publication-type="other">
Pagano, M., and P. Volpin. 2012. Securitization, transparency and liquidity. Review of Financial Studies
25:2417-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e1029a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e1033" publication-type="other">
Philippon, T., and V. Skreta. 2012. Optimal interventions in markets with adverse selection. American Economic
Review 102:1-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e1043a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e1047" publication-type="other">
Ruckes, M. 2004. Bank competition and credit standards. Review of Financial Studies 17:1073-102.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e1054a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e1058" publication-type="other">
Seppi, D. J. 1990. Equilibrium block trading and asymmetric information. Journal of Finance 45:73-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e1065a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e1069" publication-type="other">
Sorkin, A. 2009. Too big to fail. New York: Viking.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726312e1076a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726312e1080" publication-type="other">
Zhu, H. 2012. Finding a good price in opaque over-the-counter markets. Review of Financial Studies 25:1255-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


