<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007490</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">jfinancialedu</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Journal of Financial Education</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00933961</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2332421X</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Financial Education Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26775511</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>SPECIAL TOPICS</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>What Determines Financial Knowledge among College Students?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Annabi</surname>
                  <given-names>Amira</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>González-Ramírez</surname>
                  <given-names>Jimena</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Müller</surname>
                  <given-names>Fabian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>Winter 2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">44</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26775502</issue-id>
         <fpage>344</fpage>
         <lpage>366</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26775511"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The rapidly growing literature on financial literacy finds an alarmingly low level of financial knowledge among young adults. During their college years, students are likely to face expenditure, savings, credit card, and student loan decisions for the first time on their own. At the same time, they are investing in their human capital, which will allow them to become better decision-makers. As students enter the workforce, their lack of financial literacy could prevent them from making adequate financial decisions, such as buying a house or preparing for retirement. Hence, our objective is to assess financial knowledge at this early stage of their adulthood. More specifically, we empirically identify key determinants that increase financial knowledge among undergraduate college students while controlling for confounding variables that could affect it. Using data from a survey we administer at a private college in the Northeast, we identify a number of key determinants that influence financial knowledge including but not limited to being a first-generation student and having a student loan or owning a credit card. Based on our analysis, we recommend the implementation of school-wide personal finance classes for non-business students. We suggest offering personal finance workshops especially targeting minorities, women, first-generation students, and students who have a student loan.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Atkinson, A., &amp; Messy, F. (2012). Measuring Financial Literacy: Results of the OECD/International Network on Financial Education (INFE) Pilot Study. OECD Working Papers on Finance, Insurance and Private Pensions 15, OECD Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Bucher-Koenen, T., Lusardi, A., Alessie, R., &amp; van Rooij, M. (2017). How financially literate are women? An overview and new insights. The Journal of Consumer Affairs, 51(2), 255-283.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Carlin, B. I., &amp; Robinson, D. T. (2012). What does financial literacy training teach us? The Journal of Economic Education, 43(3), 235-247.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Chen, H., &amp; Volpe, R. P. (1998). An analysis of personal financial literacy among college students. Financial services Review, 7(2), 107-128.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Chen, H., &amp; Volpe, R. P. (2002). Gender differences in personal financial literacy among college students. Financial Services Review, 11(3), 289-307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Eitel, S. J., &amp; Martin, J. (2009). First-generation female college students’ financial literacy: Real and perceived barriers to degree completion. College Student Journal, 43(2), 616-630.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Federal Reserve Bank of New York. (2013). Quarterly Report on Household Debt and Credit. New York City: Research and Statistics Group. Microeconomic Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Knoll, M. A., &amp; Houts, C. R. (2012). The financial knowledge scale: An application of item response theory to the assessment of financial literacy. The Journal of Consumer Affairs, 46(3), 381-410.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Lusardi, A., &amp; Mitchell, O. S. (2007). Financial Literacy and Retirement Planning: New Evidence from the Rand American Life Panel. Working Papers wp157. University of Michigan: Michigan Retirement Research Center.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Lusardi, A., &amp; Mitchell, O. S. (2011). Financial Literacy and Planning: Implications for Retirement Wellbeing. NBER Working Paper 17078. National Bureau of Economic Research, Inc.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Lusardi, A., Mitchell, O. S., &amp; Curto, V. (2010). Financial literacy among the young. The Journal of Consumer Affairs, 44(2), 358-380.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Mandell, L. (2008). The Financial Literacy of Young American Adults. Washington, DC: The Jump$tart Coalition for Personal Financial Literacy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Mandell, L., &amp; Klein, L. S. (2009). The impact of financial literacy education on subsequent financial behavior. Journal of Financial Counseling and Planning, 20(1), 15-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Remund, D. L. (2010). Financial literacy explicated: The case for a clearer definition in an increasingly complex economy. The Journal of Consumer Affairs, 44(2), 276-295.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Robb, C. A. (2011). Financial knowledge and credit card behavior of college students. Journal of Family and Economic Issues, 32(4), 690-698.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Rosacker, K., Gillispie, M., &amp; Ragothaman, S. (2009). Financial literacy of freshmen business school students. College Students Journal, 43(2), 391-399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Scheresberg, C., Lusardi, A., &amp; Yakoboski, P. J. (2014). College-Educatd Millenials: An Overview of their Personal Finances. Global Financial Literacy Excellence Center. TIAA-CREF Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Seyedian, M., &amp; Yi, T. D. (2011). Improving financial literacy of college students: A cross-sectional analysis. College Student Journal, 45(1), 177-189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Stolper, O. A., &amp; Walter, A. (2017). Financial literacy, financial advice and financial behavior. Journal of Business Economics, 87(5), 1-63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Walstad, W. B., &amp; Rebeck, K. (2017). The test of financial literacy: Development and measurement characteristics. The Journal of Economic Education, 48(2), 113-122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Walstad, W. B., Rebeck, K., &amp; MacDonald, R. A. (2010). The effects of financial education on the financial knowledge of high school students. The Journal of Consumer Affairs, 44(2), 336-357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Wooldridge, J. M. (2010). Econometric analysis of cross section and panel data. MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Summary of Results for Financial Knowledge Questions</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Characteristics of the sample</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Summary of Dichotomous Variables</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Average Marginal Effects of Logistic Regression.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
