<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277613</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Real-Time Estimation of Intake O₂ Concentration in Turbocharged Common-Rail Diesel Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Arsie</surname>
                  <given-names>Ivan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Salerno</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cricchio</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrea</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Salerno</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pianese</surname>
                  <given-names>Cesare</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Salerno</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>De Cesare</surname>
                  <given-names>Matteo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Magneti Marelli SpA Powertrain Division</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277593</issue-id>
         <fpage>237</fpage>
         <lpage>245</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277613"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Automotive engines and control systems are more and more sophisticated due to increasingly restrictive environmental regulations. Particularly in both Diesel and SI lean-burn engines NOx emissions are the key pollutants to deal with and sophisticated Engine Management System (EMS) strategies and after-treatment devices have to be applied. In this context, the in-cylinder oxygen mass fraction plays a key-role due its direct influence on the NOx formation mechanism. Real-time estimation of the intake O₂ charge enhances the NOx prediction during engine transients, suitable for both dynamic adjustments of EMS strategies and management of after-treatment devices.</p>
            <p>The paper focuses on the development and experimental validation of a real-time estimator of O₂ concentration in the intake manifold of an automotive common-rail Diesel engine, equipped with turbocharger and EGR system. The paper analyzes the air intake process and the influence of the exhaust gas recirculation system based on a mean value modeling approach. All variables required are available at EMS level, thus allowing an on-board implementation without extra costs for additional sensors.</p>
            <p>The accuracy of the developed estimator is assessed by comparing simulated and experimental trajectories of O₂ concentration, measured by a Universal Exhaust Gas Oxygen (UEGO) sensor located in the intake manifold. The experimental tests were carried out at the test bench, imposing severe engine transients. The results evidence that the O₂ estimator presents a good accuracy vs. experiments and offers significant opportunities for improving engine control and after-treatment devices management during transient operation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">del Re, L., Langthaler, P., Furtmueller, C., Winkler, S. et al., “NOx Virtual Sensor Based on Structure Identification and Global Optimization,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0050, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-0050.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arsie, I., Pianese, C., Sorrentino, M., “Development of Recurrent Neural Networks for Virtual Sensing of NOx Emissions in Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(2):354-361, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2009-24-0110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Cesare, M. and Covassin, F., “Neural Network Based Models for Virtual NOx Sensing of Compression Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0157, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-24-0157.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guardiola, C., Lopez, J.J., Martin, J., Garcia-Sarmiento, D., “Semiempirical in-cylinder pressure based model for NOx prediction oriented to control applications”, Applied Thermal Engineering 31: 3275-3286, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, McGraw- Hill, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ramos, J.I., “Internal Combustion Engine Modeling,” Hemisphere Publishing Corporation, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arsie, I., Pianese, C., and Rizzo, G., “An Integrated System of Models for Performance and Emissions in SI Engines: Development and Identification,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1052, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-1052.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arsie I., Pianese C., Sorrentino M., “Effects of Control Parameters on Performance and Emissions of HSDI Diesel Engines: Investigation via Two Zone Modelling”, Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology - Revue de l'IFP, 62 (4): 457-469, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Müller, M., Hendricks, E., and Sorenson, S., “Mean Value Modelling of Turbocharged Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 980784, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980784.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fons, M., Muller, M., Chevalier, A., Vigild, C. et al., “Mean Value Engine Modelling of an SI Engine with EGR,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0909, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-0909.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Canova, M., Fiorani, P., Gambarotta, A., Tonetti, M., “A Real-time Model of a Small Turbocharged Multijet Diesel Engine: Application and Validation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-24-065, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-24-065.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diop, S., Moraal, P.E., Kolmanovsky, I.V., van Nieuwstadt, M., “Intake oxygen concentration estimation for DI diesel engines”, Proc. of IEEE Int. Conference on Control Applications, Kohala Coast-Island of Hawai'i, USA, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jung, M., Glover, K., “Calibratable linear parameter-varying control of a turbocharged diesel engine”, Proc. of IEEE Conference on Control Applications - CCA, vol. 1, pp. 155-160 vol. 1, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, J., “Air fraction estimation for multiple combustion mode diesel engines with dual-loop EGR systems”, Control Engineering Practice 16: 1479-1486, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alberer, D. and del Re, L., “Fast Oxygen Based Transient Diesel Engine Operation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):405-413, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0622.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Müller, M., Olin, P., and Schreurs, B., “Dynamic EGR Estimation for Production Engine Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0553, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-0553.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yurkovich, S., Meyer, J., Midlam-Mohler, S., “In-cylinder Oxygen Concentration Estimation for Diesel Engines Via Transport Delay Modeling”, Proc. of 2011 American Control Conference, San Francisco, USA, June 29 - July 01, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yan, F., Wang, J., “Control of Dual Loop EGR Air-Path Systems for Advanced Combustion Diesel Engines by a Singular Perturbation Methodology”, Proc. of 2011 American Control Conference, San Francisco, USA, June 29 - July 01, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wahlstrom, J., Eriksson, L., “Modeling diesel engines with a variablegeometry turbocharger and exhaust gas recirculation by optimization of model parameters for capturing non-linear system dynamics”, Proc. of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D, Journal of Automobile Engineering, 225 (7), 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
