<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278096</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Comparison between Internal and External EGR Performance on a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine by Means of a Refined 1D Fluid-Dynamic Engine Model</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Baratta</surname>
                  <given-names>Mirko</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Finesso</surname>
                  <given-names>Roberto</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Misul</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniela</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Spessa</surname>
                  <given-names>Ezio</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Politecnico di Torino</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>November 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278095</issue-id>
         <fpage>1977</fpage>
         <lpage>1992</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278096"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The potential of internal EGR (iEGR) and external EGR (eEGR) in reducing the engine-out NOx emissions in a heavy-duty diesel engine has been investigated by means of a refined 1D fluid-dynamic engine model developed in the GT-Power environment. The engine is equipped with Variable Valve Actuation (VVA) and Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT) systems. The activity was carried out in the frame of the CORE Collaborative Project of the European Community, VII FP.</p>
            <p>The engine model integrates an innovative 0D predictive combustion algorithm for the simulation of the HRR (heat release rate) based on the accumulated fuel mass approach and a multi-zone thermodynamic model for the simulation of the in-cylinder temperatures. NOx emissions are calculated by means of the Zeldovich thermal and prompt mechanisms.</p>
            <p>As a first step, the model has been calibrated and assessed on the basis of experimental tests carried out on four characteristic operating conditions within the WHSC (World Harmonized Stationary Cycle). The considered engine points have been used to identify the optimal engine parameters on the basis of a DoE approach.</p>
            <p>As a second step, sweeps simulations centered on the previously considered operating points have been run for iEGR and eEGR in order to study the effects of these latter on combustion and NOx formation processes at steady-state conditions.</p>
            <p>Finally, a ramp from the WHTC (World Harmonized Transient Cycle) has been reproduced with both iEGR and eEGR modes and the engine performance have been compared in terms of fuel consumption, combustion and NOx emissions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naseri, M., Chatterjee, S., Castagnola, M., Chen, H. et al., “Development of SCR on Diesel Particulate Filter System for Heavy Duty Applications,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1798-1809, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, McGraw- Hill Intern. Editions, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöblom, J., “Combined Effects of Late IVC and EGR on Lowload Diesel Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(1):60-67, 2015, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2878.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Verschaeren, R., Schaepdryver, W., Serruys, T., Bastiaen, et al., “Experimental study of NOx reduction on a medium speed heavy duty diesel engine by the application of EGR (exhaust gas recirculation) and Miller timing”, Energy 76:614-621, 2014. doi:10.1016/j.energy.2014.08.059.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schwoerer, J., Dodi, S., Fox, M., Huang, S. et al., “Internal EGR Systems for NOx Emission Reduction in Heavy-Duty Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1315, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1315.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dittrich, P., Peter, F., Huber, G., and Kuehn, M., “Thermodynamic Potentials of a Fully Variable Valve Actuation System for Passenger- Car Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1199, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1199.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Balaji, J., M.V., G., Rao, L., Bandaru, B. et al., “Modelling and Experimental Study of Internal EGR System for NOx Control on an Off-Road Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-2645, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2645.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edwards, S., Frankle, G., Wirbeleit, F., and Raab, A., “The Potential of a Combined Miller Cycle and Internal EGR Engine for Future Heavy Duty Truck Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 980180, 1998, doi:10.4271/980180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baratta, M., Finesso, R., Kheshtinejad, H., Misul, D. et al., “Use of an Innovative Predictive Heat Release Model Combined to a 1D Fluid- Dynamic Model for the Simulation of a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(3):1566-1579, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D'Ambrosio S., Finesso R., Spessa E., “Calculation Of Mass Emissions, Oxygen Mass Fraction And Thermal Capacity Of The Inducted Charge In SI And Diesel Engines From Exhaust And Intake Gas Analysis”, Fuel 90(1): 152-166, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2010.08.025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gamma Technologies Inc., “GT-SUITE Engine Performance Application Manual”, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A.E., Finesso, R., Spessa, E., “Predictive Zero-Dimensional Combustion Model for DI Diesel Engine Feed-Forward Control”, Energy Conversion and Management. 52(10):3159-3175, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2011.05.003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A., Finesso, R., Spessa, E., Catanese, A. et al., “Combustion Prediction by a Low-Throughput Model in Modern Diesel Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):2106-2123, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1410.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania A.E., Finesso R., Spessa E., “Assessment of a Low-Throughput Predictive Model for Indicated Cycle, Combustion Noise and NOx Calculation in Diesel Engines in Steady-State and Transient Operations”, Proceedings of the ASME 2012 Internal Combustion Engine Division Spring Technical Conference, ICES2012, May 6-9, 2012, Torino, Piemonte, Italy, doi:10.1115/ICES2012-81094.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Finesso, R. and Spessa, E., “Real-Time Predictive Modeling of Combustion and NOx Formation in Diesel Engines Under Transient Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0899, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Finesso, R. and Spessa, E., “Analysis of Combustion and Emissions in a EURO V Diesel Engine by Means of a Refined Quasi-Dimensional Multizone Diagnostic Model,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):886-908, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1066.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Egnell, R., “A Simple Approach to Studying the Relation between Fuel Rate Heat Release Rate and NO Formation in Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3548, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3548.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, R., Davis, G., Lavoie, G., Newman, C. et al., “A Super-Extended Zel'dovich Mechanism for Nox Modeling and Engine Calibration,” SAE Technical Paper 980781, 1998, doi:10.4271/980781.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fenimore, C. P., “Formation of Nitric Oxide in Premixed Hydrocarbon Flames,” In 13th Symp. (Int'l.) on Combustion, page 373. The Combustion Institute, 1971, doi:10.1016/s0082-0784(71)80040-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A., Finesso, R., and Spessa, E., “Real-Time Calculation of EGR Rate and Intake Charge Oxygen Concentration for Misfire Detection in Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0149, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
