<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">15</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830275</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830280</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>NIGERIAN VILLAGE MONEY LENDERS AND THEIR USURIOUS INTEREST RATES: AN ANALYSIS OF INTERVENING FACTORS / LES PRETEURS DE VILLAGE DU NIGERIA ET LES FACTEURS QUI INFLUENT SUR LEURS TAUX D'INTERET</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>E. C.</given-names>
                  <surname>Eboh</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>O.</given-names>
                  <surname>Ugama</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>O.</given-names>
                  <surname>Okereke</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1991</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>361</fpage>
         <lpage>372</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830280"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The paper examines the factors responsible for high interest rates on loans granted by private village money lenders. Empirical testing of the lender's risk hypothesis and the theory of collateral undervaluation was carried out, using data obtained from money lenders and their clients in Onicha and Ohaozara Local Government Areas of Imo State, Nigeria. Monopoly profit was found to account for a far greater proportion of interest rate charged by money lenders. Though, money lenders faced default risks, administrative and opportunity costs, the theory of collateral undervaluation largely stood out as more relevant in explaining what is commonly referred to as usurious interest rates charged by money lenders. Les auteurs ont analysé les facteurs responsables des taux d'intérêt excessifs que demandent les prêteurs d'argent particuliers dans les villages. Sur la base des données obtenues des prêteurs et de leurs clients dans les régions d'Onitsha et de Ohaozara de l'Etat d'Imo au Nigéria, ils ont effectué une évaluation empirique de l'hypothèse de risque des prêteurs et de la théorie de la sous-évaluation des garanties accessoires. Ils ont observé que dans une très grande mesure c'est le profit de nature monopoliste qui determine le taux d'intérêt fixé pour les prêts. Certes, les prêteurs doivent faire face aux risques de défaillance, aux coûts administratifs et aux coûts d'opportunité, mais, en tout cas, c'est la théorie de la sous-évaluation des garanties accessoires qui s'avère être le facteur le plus pertinent pour expliquer les taux d'intérêt normalement définis usuraires demandés par les prêteurs de village. L'allocation des crédits institutionnels aux associations de fermier pour qu'elles les acheminent directement aux emprunteurs-fermiers limiterait le pouvoir monopoliste des prêteurs particuliers et leurs pratiques rapaces. Encore, une plus grande disponibilité de fonds pour le crédit les obligerait à reduire leur taux d'intérêt.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d36e168a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e172" publication-type="other">
Basu, K. 1983. "The Emergence of Isolation and Interlinkage in Rural Markets", Oxford Economic Papers, Vol. 35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e179a1310">
          
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e185" publication-type="other">
Basu, K. 1984. "Implicit interest rates, usury and Isolation in backward agriculture", Cambridge Journal of
Economics, June.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e195a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e199" publication-type="other">
Borroah, V. 1980. "High Interest Rates in Backward Agricultural Communities", Cambridge Journal of Economics,
Vol. 4, No. 2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e209a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e213" publication-type="other">
Bottomley, A. 1963a. "The Premium for Risk As a Determinant of Interest Rates in Underdeveloped Rural Areas",
Quarterly Journal of Economics, Vol. 79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e224a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e228" publication-type="other">
Bottomley, A. 1963b. "The Cost of Administering Private Loans in Underdeveloped Areas", Oxford Economic
Papers, Vol. 15.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e238a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e242" publication-type="other">
Bottomley, A. 1964. "The Determination of Pure Rates of Interest in Underdeveloped Areas", Review of Economics
and Statistics, Vol. XIV.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e252a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e256" publication-type="other">
Ghose, A.K. 1980. "The Formation of Usurious Interest Rates", Cambridge Journal of Economics, Vol. 4, No. 2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e263a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e267" publication-type="other">
Ijere, M.0.1975. "The Lessons of State Credit Institutions in Developing Countries - The Nigerian Experience",
Agricultural Administration, Vol. 2, No. 2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e277a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e281" publication-type="other">
Okorie, A. 1988. "Rural Banking in Nigeria: Lessons from Other Developing Countries", Agricultural Administration
and Extension, 28, 147 - 159.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e291a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e295" publication-type="other">
Okorie, A. 1990. Rural Banking in Nigeria: Determining Appropriate Policy Variables, African Rural Social Science
Series Research Report No. 9, Winrock International Institute for Agricultural Development.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e306a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e310" publication-type="other">
Saleem, ST. 1987. "On the Determination of Interest Rates in Rural Credit Markets: A Case Study of Sudan",
Cambridge Journal of Economics (2).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e320a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e324" publication-type="other">
Ugama, 0.1990. "Interest Rate Determination in Informal Rural Credit Markets of Onicha and Ohaozara LGAs
of Imo State", Unpublished B. Agric (Agric. Econs) Thesis, Department of Agricultural Economics, University
of Nigeria, Nsukka.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e337a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e341" publication-type="other">
Wai, U.T. 1958. "Interest Rates outside the Organised Money Markets of Underdeveloped Countries", IMF Staff
Papers, Vol. 6.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


