<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26649138</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investigation of the Influence of Different Asperity Contact Models on the Elastohydrodynamic Analysis of a Conrod Small-End/Piston Pin Coupling</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ferretti</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrea</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Giacopini</surname>
                  <given-names>Matteo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mastrandrea</surname>
                  <given-names>Luca Nicolo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dini</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniele</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">11</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26649117</issue-id>
         <fpage>919</fpage>
         <lpage>934</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26649138"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Bearings represent one of the main causes of friction losses in internal combustion engines, and their lubrication performance has a crucial influence on the operating condition of the engine. In particular, the conrod small-end bearing is one of the most critical engine parts from a tribological point of view since limited contact surfaces have to support high inertial and combustion forces. In this contribution an analysis is performed of the tribological behavior of the lubricated contact between the piston pin and the conrod small-end of a high performance motorbike engine. A mass-conserving algorithm is employed to solve the Reynolds equation based on a complementarity formulation of the cavitation problem. The analysis of the asperity contact problem is addressed in detail. A comparison between two different approaches is presented, the former based on the standard Greenwood/Tripp theory and the latter based on a complementarity formulation of the asperity contact problem. Differently from the Greenwood/Tripp method, the complementarity formulation needs only one parameter related to the roughness of the mating surfaces to be set and allows a solution to be obtained without the need of an iterative procedure thus avoiding convergence issues. Similar results are obtained comparing both the approaches used to solve the asperity contact problem. However, such an agreement is only reached after an appropriate calibration of the model input data is performed; a remarkable sensitivity of the results obtained using the Greenwood/Tripp model to the adjustment parameters is found and highlighted. Finally, a full model validation is performed by comparing the results obtained adopting the proposed algorithm, using the implementation of the Greenwood/Tripp asperity contact model, with those obtained adopting the commercial software AVL Excite Power Unit.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Andersson, B.S., “Company’s Perspective in Vehicle Tribology,” Tribology Series 18:503-506, 1991, doi:10.1016/S0167-8922(08)70168-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Baker, C.E., Theodossiades, S., Rahnejat, H., and Fitzsimons, B., “Influence of In-Plane Dynamics of Thin Compression Rings on Friction in Internal Combustion Engines,” Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 134(9), Article number 92801, 2012, doi:10.1115/1.4006690.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Ba, L., He, Z., Liu, Y.-H., and Zhang, G.-C., “Analysis of Piston-Pin Lubrication Considering the Effects of Structure Deformation and Cavitation,” Journal of Zhejiang University: Science A 16(6):443-463, 2015, doi:10.1631/jzus.A1400105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Zhang, C., Cheng, H.S., Qiu, L., Knipstein, K.W. et al., “Scuffing Behaviour of Piston-Pin/Bore Bearing in Mixed Lubrication-Part I: Experimental Studies,” Tribology Transactions 46(2):193-199, 2003, doi:10.1080/10402000308982616.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Zhang, C., Cheng, H.S., Qiu, L., Knipstein, K.W. et al., “Scuffing Behaviour of Piston-Pin/Bore Bearing in Mixed Lubrication-Part II: Scuffing Mechanism and Failure Criterion,” Tribology Transactions 47(1):149-156, 2004, doi:10.1080/05698190490279100.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Marmorini, L., Baldini, A., Bertocchi, E., Giacopini, M. et al., “On the Loosening Mechanism of a Bush Press-Fitted in the Small End of a Connecting Rod,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering 226(3):312-324, 2012, doi:10.1177/0954407011417498.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Suhara, T., Ato, S., Takiguchi, M., and Furuhama, S., “Friction and Lubrication Characteristics of Piston Pin Boss Bearings of an Automotive Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 970840, 1997, doi:10.4271/970840.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Takiguchi, M., Nagasawa, K., and Suhara, T., “Friction and Lubrication Characteristics of Small End Connecting Rod Bearing of an Automotive Engine,” 18th Annual Fall Technical Conference of the ASME Internal Combustion Engine Division, Part 2, Fairborn, OH, 1996, 1-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Antoni, N., Nguyen, Q.S., Ligier, J.L., Saffre, P. et al., “On the Cumulative Microslip Phenomenon,” Eur. J. Mechanics - A/Solids 26(4):626-646, 2007, doi:10.1016/j. euromechsol.2006.09.004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Aitken, M.B. and McCallion, H., “Elastohydrodinamic Lubrication of Big-End Bearings, Part 1: Theory,” Proc. IMechE, Part C: J. Mech. Eng. Sci. 205:99-106, 1991, doi:10.1243/PIME_PROC_1991_205_097_02.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Fantino, B., Frene, J., and du Parquet, J., “Elastic Connecting-Rod Bearing with a Piezoviscous Lubricant: Analysis of the Steady-State Characteristics,” J. Lubr. Tech. 101(2):190-197, 1979, doi:10.1115/1.3453316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Giacopini, M., Bertocchi, L., Baldini, A. and Dini, D., “A Complementarity Formulation for the EHL Analysis of a Conecting Rod Big End Bearing,” 5th WTC, Torino, Italy, Sept. 8-13, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Dini, D., Mastrandrea, L.N., Giacopini, M., and Bertocchi, E., “Numerical Investigation of the Cavitation Damage in a High Performance Engine Conrod Big End Bearing via a Mass-Conserving Complementarity Algorithm,” Society of Tribologists and Lubrication Engineers Annual Meeting and Exhibition 2014, Lake Buena Vista, FL, May 18-22, 2014, Code 108715.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Wang, D., Mian, O., Merritt, D., and Zhu, G., “Elasto- Hydrodinamic Lubrication Analysis and Wear Predction of Connecting Rod Small-End Bush Piston Pin Interface,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-36-0068, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-36-0068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Ligier, J. and Ragot, “Small End Conrod Lubrication,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1101, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Spuria, M., Bonneau, D. Le Baratoux, Y. and , Molari, G., “A Dynamic Model for an Internal Combustion Engine Full- Floating Piston Pin in Lubricated Conditions,” XVII Congresso dell’Associazione Italiana di Meccanica Teorica e Applicata, Firenze, Sept. 11-15, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Bonneau, D. and Optasanu, V., “Finite Element Mass- Conserving Cavitation Algorithm in Pure Squeeze Motion. Validation/Application to a Connecting-Rod Small End Bearing,” Journal of Tribology 122(1):162-169, 2000, doi:10.1115/1.555339.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Bertocchi, L., Giacopini, M., and Dini, D., “Analysis of the Lubrication Regimes at the Small End and Big End of a Connecting Rod of a High Performance Motorbike Engine,” Proceedings of the ASME/STLE 2012 International Joint Tribology Conference, Denver, CO, Oct. 7-10, 2012, doi:10.1115/IJTC2012-61087</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Clark, K., Antonevich, J., Kemppainen, D., and Barna, G., “Piston Pin Dynamics and Temperature in a CI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):91-105, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01- 0189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Ligier, J.L. and Ragot, “Piston Pin: Wear and Rotating Motion,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1651, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1651.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Mastrandrea, L., Giacopini, M., Dini, D., and Bertocchi, E., “Elastohydrodynamic Analysis of the Conrod Small-End of a High Performance Motorbike Engine via a Mass Conserving Cavitation Algorithm,” ASME International Mechanical Engineering Congress and Exposition, Vol. 15, 2015, doi:10.1115/IMECE2015-51603.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Bertocchi, L., Giacopini, M., Dini, D., Fowell, M. et al., “A Mass-Conserving Complementarity Formulation to Study Fluid Film Lubrication in the Presence of Cavitation for Non-Newtonian and Compressible Fluids,” ASME 2012 11th Biennial Conference on Engineering Systems Design and Analysis, ESDA 2012, 2012, Code 99242, doi:10.1115/ESDA2012-82885</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Giacopini, M., Dini, D., Fowell, M., and Strozzi, A., “A Mass- Conserving Complementarity Formulation to Study Lubricant Films in the Presence of Cavitation,” Journal of Tribology 132(4), Article number 041702, 2010, doi:10.1115/1.4002215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Greenwood, J.A. and Williamson, J.B., “Contact of Nominally Flat Surfaces,” Proceedings of the Royal Society A: Mathematical, Physical and Engineering Sciences 295(1442):300-319, 1966, doi:10.1098/rspa.1966.0242.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Greenwood, J.A. and Tripp, J.H., “The Contact of Two Rough Nominally Flat Rough Surfaces,” Proc. Instn. Mech. Eng. 185:625-633, 1970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Ma, M.-T. and Loibnegger, B., “Simulation of EHD Lubrication of Common-Pin Conrod Big End Bearings in High Speed IC Engines,” Proceedings of WTC2005, World Tribology Congress III, Washington, DC, Sept. 12-16, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Offner, G. and Knaus, O., “A Generic Friction Model for Radial Slider Bearing Simulation Considering Elastic and Plastic Deformation,” Lubricants 3:522-538, 2015, doi:10.3390/lubricants3030522.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Wei, L. and Wei, H., “An EHD-Mixed Lubrication Analysis of Main Bearings for Diesel Engine Based on Coupling between Flexible Whole Engine Block and Crankshaft,” Industrial Lubrication and Tribology 67(2):150-158, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Zhenpeng, H., Junhong, Z., Guichang, Z., Zhouyu, L. et al., “Crankshaft-Bearing Evolution Indexes Investigation and Asperity Contact Identification Based on Neural Network,” Applied Mathematical Modelling 38:506-523, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Karimaei, H. and Chamani, H., “Study of Cavitation and Wear Damages in Conrod Big End Bearing of a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine by Using Elasto-Hydrodynamic Method,” Proceedings of the ASME Internal Combustion Engine Division 2009 Fall Technical Conference, Lucerne, Switzerland, Sept. 27-30, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Hu, Y., Cheng, H.S., Arai, T., Kobayashi, Y. et al., “Numerical Simulation of Piston Ring in Mixed Lubrication - A Nonaxisymmetrical Analysis,” Journal of Tribology 116(3):470-478, 1994, doi:10.1115/1.2928867.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Giacopini, M., Sissa, S., Rosi, R., and Fantoni, S., “Influence of Different Temperature Distributions on the Fatigue Life of a Motorcycle Piston,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering 229:1276-1288, doi:10.1177/0954407014560201.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Craig, R. and Bampton, M., “Coupling of Substructures for Dynamic Analyses,” AIAA Journal, American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics 6(7):1313-1319, 1968.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Elrod, H.G., “A Cavitation Algorithm,” ASME J. Lubr. Technol. 103(3):350-354, 1981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Jakobsson, B. and Floberg, L., The Finite Journal Bearing Considering Vaporization (Goteborg, Sweden: Transactions of Chalmers University of Technology, 1957), 190.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Olsson, K.O., Cavitation in Dynamically Loaded Bearings (Goteborg, Sweden: Transactions of Chalmers University of Technology, 1965), 308.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Elastic and geometric contributions to the total film thickness. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Schematic of the coordinate system. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Flow chart of the proposed EHD algorithm. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Finite element discretization. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Material properties of assembly component. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Radial displacement of the component interface under the action of unitary radial pressure. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Lubricant properties. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Oil supply schemes. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Schematic of boundary condition depicted using a planar view of the bearing shell. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>External forces. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Simulation data. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Complementarity asperity contact model input. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Greenwood/Tripp asperity contact model input. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Comparison between asperity contact pressure-clearance height relations for the two asperity contact models. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Orbit diagram obtained using LCP asperity contact algorithm. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Orbit diagram obtained using G/T asperity contact algorithm. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Comparison between minimum oil film thicknesses calculated with the two asperity contact algorithms. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Analyzed piston pin areas. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>MOFT in different sections for different asperity contact algorithms. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>MOFT in different sections for different asperity contact algorithms – detail. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Comparison between mean hydrodynamic pressure distributions obtained with the two different asperity contact algorithms. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Comparison between mean asperity contact pressure distributions obtained with the two different asperity contact algorithms. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 18</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Comparison between total pressure distributions obtained with the two different asperity contact algorithms. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 19</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>New G/T asperity contact pressure-clearance curves. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>Input parameter for stiffer G/T asperity contact pressure - clearance relationship. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Input parameter for softer G/T asperity contact pressure - clearance relationship. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 20</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>Comparison between minimum oil film thicknesses calculated with different G/T parameters. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 21</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>MOFT in different sections for G/T set with Table 5 parameters and G/T set with Table 6 parameters. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 22</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>MOFT in different sections for G/T set with Table 5 parameters and G/T set with Table 7 parameters. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 23</label>
         <caption id="ca-30">
            <p>Comparison between mean hydrodynamic pressure distributions calculated with different G/T parameters. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 24</label>
         <caption id="ca-31">
            <p>Comparison between mean direct contact pressure distributions calculated with different G/T parameters. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 25</label>
         <caption id="ca-32">
            <p>AVL Excite Power Unit model. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 26</label>
         <caption id="ca-33">
            <p>3D View of AVL Excite Power Unit model. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 27</label>
         <caption id="ca-34">
            <p>Comparison between the proposed algorithm and the Excite MOFT results. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 28</label>
         <caption id="ca-35">
            <p>Averaged pressure distributions obtained using Excite. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 29</label>
         <caption id="ca-36">
            <p>Comparison in terms of MOFT of the different Excite model setups. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
