<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90013667</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Original Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Computational fluid dynamics analysis of a modified Savonius rotor and optimization using response surface methodology</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Sheikh</surname>
                  <given-names>Haris Moazam</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Shabbir</surname>
                  <given-names>Zeeshan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ahmed</surname>
                  <given-names>Hassan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Waseem</surname>
                  <given-names>Muhammad Hamza</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a3">
                  <sup>3</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Sheikh</surname>
                  <given-names>Muhammad Zubair</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>1</sup>Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Engineering and Technology, Lahore, Lahore, Pakistan</aff>
            <aff id="a2">
               <sup>2</sup>Department of Mechanical Engineering, NED University of Engineering and Technology, Karachi, Pakistan</aff>
            <aff id="a3">
               <sup>3</sup>Department of Electrical Engineering, University of Engineering and Technology, Lahore, Lahore, Pakistan</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>October 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>41</volume>
         <issue>5</issue>
         <issue-id>e90013665</issue-id>
         <fpage>285</fpage>
         <lpage>296</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© SAGE Publications Ltd, 2017</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90013667"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>This article aims to present a two-dimensional parametric analysis of a modified Savonius wind turbine using computational fluid dynamics. The effects of three independent parameters of the rotor, namely, shape factor, overlap ratio, and tip speed ratio on turbine performance were studied and then optimized for maximum coefficient of performance using response surface methodology. The rotor performance was analyzed over specific domains of the parameters under study, and three-variable Box-Behnken design was used for design of experiment. The specific parametric combinations as per design of experiment were simulated using ANSYS Fluent<sup>®</sup>, and the response variable, coefficient of performance (C<sub>p</sub>), was calculated. The sliding mesh model was utilized, and the flow was simulated using Shear Stress Transport (SST) k − ω model. The model was validated using past experimental results and found to predict parametric effects accurately. Minitab<sup>®</sup> and ReliaSoft DOE++<sup>®</sup> were used to develop regression equation and find the optimum combination of parameters for coefficient of performance over the specified parametric domains using response surface methodology.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label>
            <kwd>Vertical axis wind turbine</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>modified Savonius wind turbine</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>computational fluid dynamics</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>parametric optimization</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>response surface methodology</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akwa JV, Júnior GADS and Petry AP (2012a) Discussion on the verification of the overlap ratio influence on performance coefficients of a Savonius wind rotor using computational fluid dynamics. Renewable Energy 38: 141–149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akwa JV, Vielmo HA and Petry AP (2012b) A review on the performance of Savonius wind turbines. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 16: 3054–3064.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alexander A and Holownia B (1978) Wind tunnel tests on a Savonius rotor. Journal of Industrial Aerodynamics 3: 343–351.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ANSYS (2006) Modeling Turbulent Flows, Introductory FLUENT Training. ANSYS Inc. Proprietary. Available at: www.ansys.com</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blackwell BF, Sheldahl RE, Feltz LV, et al. (1977) Wind tunnel performance data for two and three bucket Savonius rotor. Journal of Energy 2: 160–164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burton T, Sharpe D, Jenkins N, et al. (2001) Wind Energy Handbook. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons, pp. 41–45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Damak A, Driss Z and Abid M (2013) Experimental investigation of helical Savonius rotor with a twist of 180. Renewable Energy 52: 136–142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fernando M and Modi V (1989) A numerical analysis of the unsteady flow past a Savonius wind turbine. Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics 32: 303–327.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fujisawa N and Gotoh F (1992) Pressure measurements and flow visualization study of a Savonius rotor. Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics 39: 51–60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hayashi T, Li Y, Hara Y, et al. (2005) Wind tunnel tests on a three-stage out-phase Savonius rotor. JSME International Journal Series B: Special Issue on Experimental Mechanics in Heat and Fluid Flow 48: 9–16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Howell R, Qin N, Edwards J, et al. (2010) Wind tunnel and numerical study of a small vertical axis wind turbine. Renewable Energy 35: 412–422.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ivan D and Fawaz M (2011) CFD and PIV investigation of unsteady flow through, Savonius wind turbine. Energy Procedia 6: 711–720.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kacprzak K, Liskiewicz G and Sobczak K (2013) Numerical investigation of conventional and modified Savonius wind turbines. Renewable Energy 60: 578–585.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamoji M, Kedare S and Prabhu S (2008) Experimental investigations on single stage modified Savonius rotor. Applied Energy 86: 1064–1073.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamoji M, Kedare S and Prabhu S (2009) Performance tests on helical Savonius rotors. Renewable Energy 34: 521–529.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawamura T and Sato Y (2002) Numerical simulation of the flow around a cross-flow wind turbine. Research Institute of Mathematical Science, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan, pp. 44–51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mohamed M, Janiga G, Pap E, et al. (2011) Optimal blade shape of a modified Savonius turbine using an obstacle shielding. Energy Conversion and Management 52: 236–242.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ogawa T, Toshida H and Yokota Y (1989) Development of rotational speed control systems for a Savonius-type wind turbine. Journal of Fluids Engineering 111: 53–58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rogowski K and Maroński R (2015) CFD computation of the Savonius rotor. Journal of Theoretical and Applied Mechanics 53: 37–45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saha U and Rajkumar MJ. (2006) On the performance analysis of Savonius rotor with twisted blades. Renewable Energy 31: 1776–1788.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saha U, Thotla S and Maity D (2008) Optimum design configuration of Savonius rotor. Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics 96: 1359–1375.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Savonius S (1931) The S-rotor and its applications. Mechanical Engineering 53: 333–338.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Svetlana M (2016) Performance of a Savonius wind turbine in urban sites using CFD analysis. Available at: http://www.uva.fi/materiaali/pdf/isbn_978-952-476-675-3.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tian W, Song B, VanZwieten JH, et al. (2015) Computational fluid dynamics prediction of a modified Savonius wind turbine with novel blade shapes. Energies 8: 7915–7929.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao Y, Zheng Z, Xu X, et al. (2009) Research on the improvement of the performance of Savonius rotor based on numerical study. In: Proceedings of the IEEE international conference of sustainable power generation and supply, Nanjing, China, 6–7 April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
