<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308288</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Comparative Assessment of Electric Propulsion Systems in the 2030 US Light-Duty Vehicle Fleet</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kromer</surname>
                  <given-names>Matthew A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Heywood</surname>
                  <given-names>John B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>372</fpage>
         <lpage>391</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308288"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper quantifies the potential of electric propulsion systems to reduce petroleum use and greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions in the 2030 U.S. light-duty vehicle fleet. The propulsion systems under consideration include gasoline hybrid-electric vehicles (HEVs), plug-in hybrid vehicles (PHEVs), fuel-cell hybrid vehicles (FCVs), and battery-electric vehicles (BEVs).</p>
            <p>The performance and cost of key enabling technologies were extrapolated over a 25-30 year time horizon. These results were integrated with software simulations to model vehicle performance and tank-to-wheel energy consumption. Well-to-wheel energy and GHG emissions of future vehicle technologies were estimated by integrating the vehicle technology evaluation with assessments of different fuel pathways.</p>
            <p>The results show that, if vehicle size and performance remain constant at present-day levels, these electric propulsion systems can reduce or eliminate the transport sector’s reliance on petroleum. However, continued reliance on fossil-fuels without effective carbon capture and sequestration for producing electricity and hydrogen constrain the GHG emission and energy reductions to about 60% below that of present-day spark-ignition technology.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kasseris, E and Heywood, J. “Comparative Analysis f Automotive Powertrain Choices for the Next 25 ears”. SAE 2007-01-1605. April 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Energy Information Administration (EIA), U.S. DOE. “Annual Energy Outlook 2006”. DOE/IEA- 0383(2006). February 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">General Motors, Argonne National Lab (GM/ANL). “Well-to-Wheel Energy Use and Greenhouse Gas missions of Advanced Fuel/Vehicle Systems – orth American Analysis”, Vol. 2. May 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moon, P, Burnham, A, and Wang, M. “Vehicle-Cycle nergy and Emissions Effects of Conventional and dvanced Vehicles”. SAE 2006-01-0375. April 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kromer, M and Heywood, J. “Electric Powertrains: pportunities and Challenges in the US Light-Duty ehicle Fleet”. LFEE 2007-03 RP. May 2007. ttp://lfee.mit.edu/public/LFEE_2007-03_RP.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">National Research Council (NRC). “Review of the esearch Program of the FreedomCAR and Fuel artnership”. Washington, D.C., 2005. 0-309- 09730-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, T. “Hybrid Battery Technology and hallenges”. Technology Review’s Emerging echnology Conference, 9/28/2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderman, M. “Brief Assessment of Improvements n EV Battery Technology Since the BTAP June 2000 eport”. Agreement #02-611. California Air esources Board (CARB). 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ritchie, Andrew. “Recent Developments and Likely dvances in Lithium-Ion Batteries”. Journal of ower Sources 136 (2004). Pp 285-289.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ritchie, Andrew and Howard, Wilmont. “Recent evelopments and Likely Advances in Lithium-Ion atteries”. Journal of Power Sources 162 (2006). p 809-812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sadoway, Donald and Mayes, Anne. “Portable ower: Advanced Rechargeable Lithium Batteries”. RS Bulleton, August 2002. Pp 590-596.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saft Website. www.saftbatteries.com. Accessed 10/2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thackeray, Michael. “An Unexpected Conductor”. ature Materials, October 2002. Pp 81-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brodd, Ralph. “Factors Affecting US Production ecisions: Why are There No Volume Lithium-Ion attery Manufacturers in the United States?” repared for National Institute of Standards, ontract SB 1341-02-W-1445. June 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A123 Website. www.a123.com. Accessed January 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderman M, F Kalhammer, and D MacArthur. “Advanced Batteries for Electric Vehicles: An ssessment of Performance, Cost, and Availability”. alifornia Air Resources Board, June 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, T. “Technological Opportunities and Barriers“. lug-In Hybrid Panel, MIT Energy Conference, arch 10, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE J1711 Technical Standard. “Recommended ractice for Measuring the Exhaust Emissions and uel Economy of Hybrid-Electric Vehicles”. Society f Automotive Engineers. March 1999 Standards.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kleisch J, and T Langer. “Plug-In Hybrids: An nvironmental and Economic Performance Outlook”. merican Council for an Energy-Efficient Economy, eport T061. September 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oak Ridge National Laboratory [ORNL]. “2001 ational Household Travel Survey”. Oak Ridge ational Laboratory. January 2004. Online at ttp://nhts.ornl.gov/publications.shtml.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Electric Power Research Institute (EPRI). “Comparing the Benefits and Impacts of Hybrid ehicle Options”. EPRI, Palo Alto, CA. July 2001. eport 1000349.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Markel, Tony and Simpson, Andrew. “Plug-In Hybrid lectric Vehicle Energy Storage System Design”. dvanced Automotive Battery Conference. May 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">National Research Council (NRC), Committee on lternatives and Strategies for Future Hydrogen roduction and Use. “The Hydrogen Economy: pportunities, Costs, Barriers, and R&amp;D Needs”. ashington, D.C., 2004. 0-309-09163-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guzy, Chris. “Fuel Cells for Transportation pplications”. Presented at the CARB ZEV ymposium. Sept 25, 2006. Ballard Power ystems. Available online at ttp://www.arb.ca.gov/msprog/zevprog/symposium/p esentations/presentations.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gasteiger, H, S Kocha, B Sompalli, F Wagner. “Activity Benchmarks and Requirements for Pt, Ptalloy, nd non-Pt Oxygen Reduction Catalysts for EMFCs”. Applied Catalysis B: Environmental 56, 2005. Pp 9-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tiax. DOE “Compress/Expander Module evelopment Program Merit Review Meeting”. Tiax LC. Reference DE-FC04-01AL67603. May 22, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carlson, E, P Kopf, J Sinha, S Sriramulu. “Cost nalysis of PEM Fuel Cell Systems for ransportation”. National Renewable Energy aboratory. Subcontract Report NREL/SR-560- 39104. September 30, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weiss M. A., J.B. Heywood, E.M. Drake, A. Schafer, nd F. AuYeung. “On the Road in 2020: A life-cycle nalysis of New Automobile Technologies”. MIT aboratory for Energy and the Environment Report, IT EL 00-003, October 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schlapbach, L and A Zuttel. “Hydrogen Storage aterials for Mobile Applications”. Nature 414: 353- 358. 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CONCAWE, EUCAR, and ECJRC (EUWTW), “Wellto- heels Analysis of Future Automotive Fuels and owertrains in the European Context - Well-to heels Report, Version 2b”. May 2006. Available t:http://ies.jrc.cec.eu.int/wtw.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duleep, KG. Personal Correspondence. March 9, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Energy and Environmental Analysis, Inc (EEA). “Analysis and Forecast of the Performance and Cost f Conventional and Electric-Hybrid Vehicles”. ontract No 500-00-002 (WA 8). March 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosencranz, C. “Deep-cycle Batteries for Plug-In ybrid Applications”. Presented at EVS Plug-In ybrid Workshop, Monaco. Nov 15, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Markel, T and A Simpson. “Energy Storage Systems onsiderations for Grid-Charged Hybrid Electric ehicles”. SAE Future Transportation Technology nd IEEE Vehicle Power and Propulsion Joint onferences. September 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrington, R and J Rugh. “Impact of Vehicle Air- onditioning on Fuel Economy, Tailpipe Emissions, nd Electric Vehicle Range”. National Renewable nergy Laboratory. Contract No. DE-AC36-99- O10337. October 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Environmental Protection Agency. “Fuel Economy abeling of Motor Vehicle Revisions to Imporve alculation of Fuel Economy Estimates, Final echnical Support Document”. EPA 420 R/06/017. ecember 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
