<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278204</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>An Iterative Markov Chain Approach for Generating Vehicle Driving Cycles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gong</surname>
                  <given-names>Qiuming</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Midlam-Mohler</surname>
                  <given-names>Shawn</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Marano</surname>
                  <given-names>Vincenzo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rizzoni</surname>
                  <given-names>Giorgio</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Ohio State Univ.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1035</fpage>
         <lpage>1045</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278204"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>For simulation and analysis of vehicles there is a need to have a means of generating drive cycles which have properties similar to real world driving. A method is presented which uses measured vehicle speed from a number of vehicles to generate a Markov chain model. This Markov chain model is capable of generating drive cycles which match the statistics of the original data set. This Markov model is then used in an iterative fashion to generate drive cycles which match constraints imposed by the user. These constraints could include factors such number of stops, total distance, average speed, or maximum speed.</p>
            <p>In this paper, systematic analysis was done for a PHEV fleet which consists of 9 PHEVs that were instrumented using data loggers for a period of approximately two years. Statistical analysis using principal component analysis and a clustering approach was carried out for the real world velocity profiles. After dividing the real velocity profiles into segments, they were clustered into several different clusters based on statistical data. This data set is also used to generate the Markov chain model technique described above which is the central development of this work. The work of this paper is a part of a larger project in which a mass simulation of a neighborhood of PHEVs will be conducted based on statistical representations of key factors such as vehicle usage patterns, vehicle characteristics, and market penetration of PHEVs. This approach can be used as critical input of the large scale simulation model to generate random velocity profiles of various driving patterns.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Midlam-Mohler, Shawn; Ewing, Sean; Marano, Vincenzo; Guezennec, Yann; Rizzoni, Giorgio, “PHEV fleet data collection and analysis,” 5th IEEE Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference, VPPC '09, p 1205-1210, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bata, R., Yacoub, Y., Wang, W., Lyons, D. et al., “Heavy Duty Testing Cycles: Survey and Comparison,” SAE Technical Paper 942263, 1994, doi: 10.4271/942263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carlson, T.R., Austin, R.C. “Development of speed correction cycles”. Sierra Research, Inc., Sacramento, CA, Report SR97-04-01 (1997)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cloke, J., Harris, G., Latham, S., Quimby, A., Smith, E., Baughan, C. “Reducing the environmental impact of driving: a review of training and in-vehicle technologies”. Transport Res. Lab., Crowthorne, U.K., Report 384 (1999)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ericsson, E. “Variability in urban driving patterns”. Transportation Res. Part D 5, 337-354 (2000)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ericsson, E. “Independent driving pattern factors and their influence on fuel-use and exhaust emission factors”. Transportation Res. Part D 6, 325-341 (2001)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Vlieger, I., De Keukeleere, D., Kretzschmar, J. “Environmental effects of driving behaviors and congestion related to passenger cars.” Atmosph. Environ. 34, 4649-4655 (2000)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jeon, S., Jo, S., Park, Y., Lee, J.M., “Multi-Mode Driving Control of a Parallel Hybrid Electric Vehicle Using Driving Pattern Recognition”, Journal of Dynamic Systems, Measurement, and Control, Transactions of the ASME, Vol. 124, pp.141-148, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.C., Peng, H., Jeon, S., Lee, J.M., “Control of a Hybrid Electric Track Based on Driving Pattern Recognition”, Proceedings of the Advanced Vehicle Control Conference, Hiroshima, Japan, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jeon, S., Lee, J.M., Park, Y.I., “Adaptive multi-mode control strategy for a parallel hybrid electric vehicle based on driving pattern recognition”, Proceedings of IMECE, 2003 ASME international Mechanical Engineering Congress, Washington, D.C., November 15-21, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bo, Gu; Rizzoni, G.., “An adaptive algorithm for hybrid electric vehicle energy management based on driving pattern recognition”, Proceedings of 2006 ASME International Mechanical Engineering Congress and Exposition, Dynamic Systems and Control Division, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Langari, R., Won, J.-S. “Intelligent energy management agent for a parallel hybrid vehicle-part I: system architecture and design of the driving situation identification process”. IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology 54(3), 925-934 (2005)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Won, J.-S., Langari, R. “Intelligent energy management agent for a parallel hybrid vehicle-part II: torque distribution, charge sustenance strategies, and performance results”. IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology 54(3), 935-953 (2005)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murphey, Yi L.; Chen, ZhiHang; Kiliaris, Leo; Park, Jungme; Kuang, Ming; Masrllr, Abul; Phillips, Anthony, “Neural learning of driving environment prediction for vehicle power management,” Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks, p 3755-3761, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gong, Q., Li, Y., and Peng, Z.-R., “Trip Based Optimal Power Management of Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicle with Advanced Traffic Modeling,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1)861-872, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tulpule, P., Stockar, S., Marano, V. and Rizzoni, G. “Optimality assessment of equivalent consumption minimization strategy for PHEV applications,” Dynamic Systems and Control Conference (DSCC 2009), Hollywood, California, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, C., Vahidi, A., Li, X., and Essenmachaer, D., “Role of trip information preview in fuel economy of plug-in hybrid vehicles,” Dynamic Systems and Control Conference (DSCC2009), Hollywood, California, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dembski, N., Rizzoni, G., Soliman, A., Fravert, J. et al., “Development of Refuse Vehicle Driving and Duty Cycles”, SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1165, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-1165.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, Jie; Niemeier, Debbie A. “Estimating regional air quality vehicle emission inventories: Constructing robust driving cycles”, Transportation Science, v 37, n 3, p 330-346, August 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moura, S., Callaway, D., Fahty, H., and Stein, J., “Tradeoffs between battery energy capacity and stochastic optimal power management in plug-in hybrid electric vehicles,” Journal of Power Sources, Vol. 195, pp. 2979-2988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gong, Q.; Midlam-Mohler, S.; Marano, V.; Rizzoni, G.; Guezennec, Y.; “Statistical Analysis of PHEV Fleet Data,” 6th IEEE Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference, VPPC, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dembski, N., Guezennec, Y., and Soliman, A., “Analysis and Experimental Refinement of Real-World Driving Cycles,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0069, 2002, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-0069.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matlab help notes, “K-Means Clustering”.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moura, S. J., Fathy, H. K., Callaway, D. S., and Stein, J. L., “A stochastic optimal control approach for power management in plug-in hybrid electric vehicles,” Proceedings of the 2008 ASME Dynamic Systems and Control Conference, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, Chan-Chiao (Dept. of Mechanical Engineering, University of Michigan, MI 48109-2125); Peng, Huei; Grizzle, J.W. “A Stochastic Control Strategy for Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” Proceedings of the American Control Conference, v 5, p 4710-4715, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Googlemap, “http://maps.google.com/”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
