<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25829867</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25829870</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>DEMANDE DE MONNAIE: LE CAS DU MAROC / MONEY DEMAND: THE MOROCCAN CASE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Zejly</given-names>
                  <surname>Ahmed</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1984</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>15</fpage>
         <lpage>39</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25829870"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The purpose of this article is to evaluate the function of money demand on the basis of the Moroccan data relating to the 1961-77 period. It has been assumed that at each period the agents adjust proportionally their ready cash to the discrepancy between the desired level and that the cash reached one period before. Estimates carried out show that only 30% to 35% od adjustments takes place within one year. The short-period elasticity does not move far away from one, while the long-period elasticity settles at values between 2.1 and 3.1 for the three definitions of the money. This gives to money the characteristic of luxury goods. The high levels of the long-term elasticity reflect as well the monetization process which has caused the volume of circulating money to grow faster than the G.N.P. From the results seen, the inflation rate did not affect significantly the determination of the real cash during the 1961-77 period. This is due to the fact that the agents get sensitive to the depreciation of their assets only if the inflation rate is high, which was not the case of the 1961-77 period. The substitution between monetary assets is tested by introducing the credit interest rate in the equations. Neither money availability, nor the monetary mass is affected as for the remuneration of deposits for the following reasons: — the monetary mass includes term deposits which vary in the same sense of interest rates; — the financial market is « repressed » in the sense that the interest rates being fixed administratively, they do not reflect the adjustment conditions of capital supply and demand; — the third reason, which is linked to the second one, has an econometric character. The nominal interest rates appear in an ascending order which is constant until 1974 and the two discontinuity points in 1974 and 1975 account inadequately for the substitution effect. This variable at most underlines the disparity of inflation rates during the 1961-77 period: stability up to 1973 and very high inflation rate from then. On the other hand, the interest rate has a significant coefficient in the demand of fiduciary money. Finally, the three equations are simulated on the observation period by assigning to the shifted variable the observated values (static simulation). They provide quite a good description of the variations of the real monetary series.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>fre</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>BIBLIOGRAPHIE</title>
        <ref id="d50e290a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e294" publication-type="other">
S. Goldfeld, The demand for money Revisited, Brooking Papers on Economics Activity, 3: 1973.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e301a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e305" publication-type="other">
J. O. Adekunle, The demand for money: Evidence from developed and Less Developed Economics,
International Monetary Fund, Staff Papers.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e319" publication-type="other">
La demande de monnaie dans les principaux pays de I'O.C.D.E., Perspectives economiques de I'O.C.D.E.,
Janvier 1979.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e329a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e333" publication-type="other">
J. Militz, La demande de monnaie en France: tentative d'explication, Statistiques et Etudes financieres, 3eme
trimestre 1973/11.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


