<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277596</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Comparative Study of a Spark Ignition Engine Running on Hydrogen, Synthesis Gas and Natural Gas</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Orbaiz</surname>
                  <given-names>Pedro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Brear</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Abbasi</surname>
                  <given-names>Payman</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dennis</surname>
                  <given-names>Peter A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Melbourne</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277593</issue-id>
         <fpage>23</fpage>
         <lpage>44</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277596"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper presents an experimental, numerical and theoretical study of the performance of the same spark ignition engine running on four different gaseous fuels: hydrogen, two synthesis gases and natural gas. Measurements of the brake thermal efficiency, the combustion variability, the engine out emissions and the indicated, pumping and friction mean effective pressures are first presented, with particular interest placed on the lean burn performance. Combustion analysis is then undertaken, with the crank angle resolved in-cylinder turbulence and the flame propagation plotted on the so-called ‘Bradley diagram’ for turbulent premixed combustion. The loci of the combustion events on the Bradley diagram are then used to explain the observed, relative performance of the engine running on these four fuels. In particular, turbulent flame stretch is argued to play a significant role in determining variations in engine performance on these four fuels, and also appears to explain the ability of hydrogen-rich fuels to perform well over a relatively wide range of lean engine operating conditions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herdin, G., Gruber, F., Klausner, J., Robitschko, R. et al., “Hydrogen and Hydrogen Mixtures as Fuel in Stationary Gas Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0012, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boehman A.L. and Corre O. Le. Combustion of syngas in internal combustion engines. Combustion Science and Technology, 180: 1193-1206, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chaos M. and Dryer F. L.. Syngas combustion kinetics and applications. Combustion Science and Technology, 180: 1053-1096, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dry M.E.. Present and future applications of the Fischer-Tropsch process. Applied Catalysis, 276: 1-3, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dry M.E.. The Fischer-Tropsch process. Catalysis Today, 71: 227-241, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elshout R.. Hydrogen production by steam reforming. Chemical Engineering, May 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosen M.A.. Thermodynamic comparison of hydrogen production processes. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 21: 349-365, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Simpson A.P. and Lutz A.E.. Exergy analysis of hydrogen production via steam methane reforming. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 32: 4811-4820, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chiesa P., Consonni S., Kreutz Thomas, and Williams Robert. Coproduction of hydrogen, electricity and CO2 from coal with commercially ready technology. Part A: Performance and emissions. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 30: 747-767, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IEA. World Energy Outlook. Technical report, International Energy Agency, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BP statistical review of world energy. Technical report, British Petrolum, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ma F., Wang Y., Liu H., Wang J. Li Y., and Zhao S.. Experimental study on thermal efficiency and emission characteristics of a lean burn hydrogen enriched natural gas engine. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 32: 5067-5075, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bauer C.G. and Forest T.W.. Effect of hydrogen addition on the performance of methane fuelled vehicles. Part I: Effect on S.I. engine performance. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 26: 55-70, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akansu S. Orhan, Kahraman N., and Çeper B.. Experimental study on a spark ignition engine fuelled by methane-hydrogen mixtures. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 32: 4279-4284, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jensen, T., Schramm, J., Søgaard, C., and Ahrenfeldt, J., “Hydrocarbon Emissions from a SI Engine Using Different Hydrogen Containing Gaseous Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2824, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-2824.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bika A.S., Franklin L., and Kittelson D.B.. Engine knock and combustion characteristics of a spark ignition engine operating with varying hydrogen and carbon monoxide proportions. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 36: 5143-5152, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, H., Karim, G., and Sohrabi, A., “Knock and Combustion Characteristics of CH4, CO, H2 and Their Binary Mixtures,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3088, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3088.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ilbas M., Crayford A.P., Yilmaz I., Bowen P.J., and Syred N.. Laminarburning velocities of hydrogen-air and hydrogen-methane-air mixtures: An experimental study. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 31: 1768-1779, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Halter F., Chauveau C., and Gökalp I.. Characterization of the effects of hydrogen addition in premixed methane/air flames. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 32: 2585_2592, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Milton B.E. and Keck J.C.. Laminar burning velocities in stoichiometric hydrogen and hydrogen-hydrocarbon gas mixtures. Combustion and Flame, 58: 13-22, 1984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yu G., Law C.K., and Wu C.K.. Laminar flame speeds of hydrocarbon + air mixtures with hydrogen addition. Combustion and Flame, 63: 339-347, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scholte T.G. and Vaags P.B.. Burning velocities of mixtures of hydrogen, carbon monoxide and methane with air. Combustion and Flame, 3: 511-524, 1959.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh D., Nishiie T., Tanvir S., and Qiao L.. An experimental and kinetic study of syngas/air combustion at elevated temperatures and the effect of water addition. Fuel, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karim G.A., Wierzba I., and Al-alousi Y.. Methane-hydrogen mixtures as fuels. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 21: 625-631, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thurnheer T., Soltic P., and Eggenschwiler P. D.. S.I. engine fuelled with gasoline, methane and methane/hydrogen blends: Heat release and loss analysis. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 34(5): 2494-2503, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ma F., Liu H., Wang Y., Li Y., Wang J., and Zhao S.. Combustion and emission characteristics of a port-injection HCNG engine under various ignition timings. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 33: 816-822, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Søgaard, C., Schramm, J., and Jensen, T., “Reduction of UHC-emissions from Natural Gas Fired SI-engine - Production and Application of Steam Reformed Natural Gas,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2823, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-2823.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gamiño B. and Aguillón J.. Numerical simulation of syngas combustion with a multi-spark ignition system in a Diesel engine adapted to work at the Otto cycle. Fuel, 89: 581-591, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akansu S. Orhan, Dulger Z., Kahraman N., and Veziroglu T.N.. Internal combustion engines fuelled by natural gas-hydrogen mixtures. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 29: 1527-1539, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li H. and Karim G.A.. Exhaust emissions from an SI engine operating on gaseous fuel mixtures containing hydrogen. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 30 (13-14): 1491-1499, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dalhuijsen, W., Bosma, H., Merts, M. and Buning, L., “Internal Combustion Engine Vehicle: Emissions and Performance Using Blends of Natural Gas and Hydrogen,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-32-0072, 2007. doi:10.4271/2007-32-0072</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dimopoulos, P., Boulouchos, K., Rechsteiner, C., Soltic, P. and Hotz, R., “Combustion Characteristics of Hydrogen-Natural Gas Mixtures in Passenger Car Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0065, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-24-0065.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dimopoulos P., Bach C., Soltic P., and Boulouchos K.. Hydrogennatural gas blends fuelling passenger car engines: Combustion, emissions and well-to-wheels assessment. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 33 (23): 7224-7236, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrianov Denis. Minimising Cold Start Fuel Consumption and Emissions from a Gasoline Fuelled Engine. PhD thesis, Mechanical Engineering Department, The University of Melbourne, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Australian energy market operator website, viewed Dicember 2009, http://www.aemo.com.au/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Natarajan J., Lieuwen T., and Seitzman J.. Laminar flame speeds of H2/CO mixtures: Effect of CO2 dilution, preheat temperature, and pressure. Combustion and Flame, 151: 104-119, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lemmon E.W., McLinden M.O., and Friend D.G.. Thermophysical properties of fluid systems. NIST Chemistry WebBook, NIST Standrd Reference Database Number 69, December 2010. Eds. Lindstrom, P.J., and Mallard, W. G.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gamma Technologies. GT-Power User's Manual: Application for Engine Performance, Acoustics and Control Simulation, Version 7.2. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Verhelst S. and Sierens R.. A quasi-dimensional model for the power cycle of a hydrogen-fuelled ICE. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 32: 3545-3554, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Demuynck J., Pauwels S., Verhelst S., De Paepe M., and Sierens R.. Experimental research on the heat transfer inside a hydrogen combustion engine: evaluation and construction of measurement methods. FISITA World Automotive Congress, Paper F2008-SC-037, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Demuynck J., Raes N., Zuliani M., De Paepe M., Sierens R., and Verhelst S.. Local heat flux measurements in a hydrogen and methane spark ignition engine with a thermopile sensor. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 34: 9857-9868, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sierens R., Demuynck J., De Paepe M., and Verhelst S.. Heat transfer comparison between methane and hydrogen in a spark ignited engine. Proceedings of the World Hydrogen Energy Conference 2010, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Demuynck J., De Paepe M., Huisseune H., Sierens R., Vancoillie J., and Verhelst S.. On the applicability of empirical heat transfer models for hydrogen combustion engines. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 36: 975-984, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blizard, N. and Keck, J., “Experimental and Theoretical Investigation of Turbulent Burning Model for Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 740191, 1974, doi:10.4271/740191.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hires, S., Tabaczynski, R., and Novak, J., “The Prediction of Ignition Delay and Combustion Intervals for a Homogeneous Charge, Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 780232, 1978, doi: 10.4271/780232.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T. and Keribar, R., “A Model for Predicting Spatially and Time Resolved Convective Heat Transfer in Bowl-in-Piston Combustion Chambers,” SAE Technical Paper 850204, 1985, doi:10.4271/850204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ma F., Wang Y., Liu H., Li Y., Wang J., and Ding S.. Effects of hydrogen addition on cycle-by-cycle variations in a lean burn natural gas spark-ignition engine. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 33: 823-831, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ma F. and Wang Y.. Study on the extension of lean operation limit through hydrogen enrichment in a natural gas spark-ignition engine. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 33: 1416-1424, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tunestål, P., Christensen, M., Einewall, P., Andersson, T. et al., “Hydrogen Addition For Improved Lean Burn Capability of Slow and Fast Burning Natural Gas Combustion Chambers,” SAE Technical Paper !2002-01-2686, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2686.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood J.B.. Internal combustion engine fundamentals. McGraw-Hill, New York, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Safari H., Jazayeri S.A., and Ebrahimi R.. Potentials of NOx emission reduction methods in SI hydrogen engines: Simulation study. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 34: 1015-1025, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Homan H.S., DE Boer P.C.T., and McLean W.J.. The effect of fuel injection on NOx emissions and undesirable combustion for hydrogenfuelled piston engines. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 8: 131-146, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kahramana E., Cihangir Ozcanl S., and Ozerdem B.. An experimental study on performance and emission characteristics of a hydrogen fuelled spark ignition engine. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 32: 2066-2072, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>54.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Natkin, R., Tang, X., Boyer, B., Oltmans, B. et al., “Hydrogen IC Engine Boosting Performance and NOx Study,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0631, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0631.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>55.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Verhelst, S., Sierens, R., and Verstraeten, S., “A Critical Review of Experimental Research on Hydrogen Fueled SI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0430, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0430.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>56.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">White C.M., Steeper R.R., and Lutz A.E.. The hydrogen-fuelled internal combustion engine: a technical review. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 31: 1292-1305, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>57.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borghi R.. On the structure and morphology of turbulent premixed flames. Recent advances in the aerospace sciences (A 85-47304 23-31). New York, Plenum Press, pages 177-138, 1985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>58.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peters N.. Laminar flamelet concepts in turbulent combustion. Symposium (International) on Combustion, 21: 1231-1250, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>59.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdel-Gayed R.G., Bradley D., and Lung F.K.K.. Combustion regimes and the straining of turbulent premixed flames. Combustion and Flame, 76 (2): 213-218, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>60.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merdjani, S. and Sheppard, C., “Gasoline Engine Cycle Simulation Using the Leeds Turbulent Burning Velocity Correlations,” SAE Technical Paper 932640, 1993, doi:10.4271/932640.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <label>61.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turns S.R.. An Introduction to Combustion: Concepts and Applications. McGraw-Hill Education, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <label>62.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bradley D., Lau A.K.C, and Lawes M.. Flame stretch rate as a determinant of turbulent burning velocity. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London. Series A: Physical and Engineering Sciences, (1650): 338-359, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <label>63.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdel-Gayed R.G., Bradley D., and Lawes M.. Turbulent burning velocities: a general correlation in terms of straining rates. Proceedings of the Royal Society of London. A Mathematical and Physical Sciences, 414 (1847): 389, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <label>64.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gillespie, L., Lawes, M., Sheppard, C., and Woolley, R., “Aspects of Laminar and Turbulent Burning Velocity Relevant to SI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0192, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0192.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <label>65.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood J.B.. Combustion and its modeling in spark-ignition engines. International Symposium COMODIA 94, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <label>66.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Law C.K.. Combustion Physics. Cambridge University Press, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
