<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169214</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>An Assessment of the Effects of Passenger Vehicle Weight and Size on Accident and Fatality Risk Based on Data for 1991 through 2007 Model Year Vehicles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Van Auken</surname>
                  <given-names>R. Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zellner</surname>
                  <given-names>John W.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Dynamic Research, Inc.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169200</issue-id>
         <fpage>166</fpage>
         <lpage>191</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169214"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Quantifying the independent effects of vehicle weight and size on overall vehicle safety is necessary in order to assess the risks and benefits of vehicle weight reduction. This paper describes the results of one-stage and two-stage logistic regression analyses of the effects of passenger vehicle weight, wheelbase, track, and footprint on fatalities per accident, accidents per exposure (e.g., vehicle-miles-traveled), and fatalities per exposure using national and multi-state traffic accident and exposure databases. The analyses were accomplished in two phases. The first phase used 1995 though 2000 calendar year data for 1991 through 1999 model year vehicles. The second phase used 2002 through 2008 calendar year data for 2000 through 2007 model year vehicles. The overall fatalities per exposure results tend to confirm the one-stage results previously reported by NHTSA, however the new two-stage results provide additional insight into the independent effects of weight reduction and size reduction on vehicle crash involvement, crashworthiness and crash compatibility. The sensitivity of the results to various databases, variables, and assumptions was also investigated. The results from both phases indicated that the estimated overall effects of passenger vehicle weight reduction (while holding vehicle size constant) on fatalities are small in comparison to other variables and may not be statistically significant depending on various key assumptions (e.g., controlling for changes in wheelbase and track versus changes in footprint, and the type of induced-exposure data that are used), and this is due to small or opposing effects of these variables on crash involvement, crashworthiness and crash compatibility.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kahane, C.J., Relationships Between Vehicle Size and Fatality Risk in Model Year 1985-93 Passenger Cars and Light Trucks, Technical Report No. DOT HS 808 570, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Washington, D.C., January 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Auken, R.M., and Zellner, J.W., An Assessment of the Effects of Vehicle Weight on Fatality Risk in Model Year 1985-98 Passenger Cars and 1985-97 Light Trucks, DRI-TR-02-02, Dynamic Research, Inc., Torrance, CA, US Federal Docket No. NHTSA-2003-16318-2, February 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Auken, R.M., and Zellner, J.W., A Further Assessment of the Effects of Vehicle Weight and Size Parameters on Fatality Risk in Model Year 1985-98 Passenger Cars and 1985-97 Light Trucks, DRITR- 03-01, Dynamic Research, Inc., Torrance, CA, US Federal Docket No. NHTSA-2003-16318-3, January 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kahane, C.J., Vehicle Weight, Fatality Risk and Crash Compatibility of Model Year 1991-99 Passenger Cars and Light Trucks, Technical Report No. DOT HS 809 662, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Washington, D.C, October 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Auken, R.M., and Zellner, J.W., A Review of the Results in the 1997 Kahane, 2002 DRI, 2003 DRI, and 2003 Kahane Reports on the Effects of Passenger Car and Light Truck Weight and Size on Fatality Risk, DRI-TR-04-02, Dynamic Research, Inc., Torrance, US Federal Docket No. NHTSA-2003-16318-7, CA, March 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kebschull, S.A., Kelly, J., Van Auken, R.M., and Zellner, J.W., An Analysis of the Effects of SUV Weight and Length on SUV Crashworthiness and Compatibility Using Systems Modeling and Risk- Benefit Analysis, DRI-TR-04-04-2, Dynamic Research, Inc., Torrance, CA, Federal Docket No. NHTSA-2003-16128-1452, July 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Auken, R. and Zellner, J., “An Assessment of the Effects of Vehicle Weight and Size on Fatality Risk in 1985 to 1998 Model Year Passenger Cars and 1985 to 1997 Model Year Light Trucks and Vans,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1354, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-1354.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kahane, C.J., “Relationships Between Fatality Risk, Mass, and Footprint in Model Year 1991-1999 and Other Passenger Cars and LTVs,” Final Regulatory Impact Analysis, Corporate Average Fuel Economy for MY 2012-MY 2016 Passenger Cars and Light Trucks, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Washington, D.C., March 24, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kahane, C.J., Relationships Between Fatality Risk, Mass, and Footprint in Model Year 2000-2007 Passenger Cars and LTVs - Preliminary Report, Docket No. NHTSA-2010-0152-0023, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Washington, D.C., November 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wenzel, T., Assessment of NHTSA's Report “Relationships Between Fatality Risk, Mass, and Footprint in Model Year 2000-2007 Passenger Cars and LTVs”, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, Berkeley, California, Federal Docket No. NHTSA-2010-0152-0026, November 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wenzel, T., An Analysis of the Relationship between Casualty Risk Per Crash and Vehicle Mass and Footprint for Model Year 2000-2007 Light-Duty Vehicles, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, Berkeley, California, US Federal Docket No. NHTSA-2010-0152-0028, December 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Auken, R.M., and Zellner, J.W., Updated Analysis of the Effects of Passenger Vehicle Size and Weight On Safety, Phase I: Updated Analysis Based on 1995 to 2000 Calendar Year Data for 1991 to 1999 Model Year Light Passenger Vehicles, DRI-TR-11-01, Dynamic Research Inc., Torrance, CA, US Federal Docket No. NHTSA-2010-0152-0030, January 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Auken, R.M., and Zellner, J.W., Updated Analysis of the Effects of Passenger Vehicle Size and Weight on Safety, Phase II: Preliminary Analysis Based On 2002 To 2008 Calendar Year Data for 2000 to 2007 Model Year Light Passenger Vehicles, DRI-TR-12-01-01, Dynamic Research Inc., Torrance, CA, US Federal Docket No. NHTSA-2010-0152-0038, January 2012, Revised June 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Auken, R.M., and Zellner, J.W., Updated Analysis of the Effects of Passenger Vehicle Size and Weight on Safety: Supplemental Results on the Sensitivity of the Estimates for 2002 to 2008 Calendar Year Data for 2000 to 2007 Model Year Light Passenger Vehicles to Induced- Exposure Data and Vehicle Size Variables, DRI-TR-12-03-01, Dynamic Research Inc., Torrance, CA, US Federal Docket No. NHTSA-2010-0152-0039, February 2012, Revised June 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kahane, C.J., Relationships Between Fatality Risk, Mass, and Footprint in Model Year 2000-2007 Passenger Cars and LTVs - Final Report, Technical Report Number DOT HS 811 665, US Federal Docket No. NHTSA-2010-0152-0040, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Washington, D.C., August 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Joksch, H., Massie, D., and Pichler, R., Vehicle Aggressivity: Fleet Characterization Using Traffic Collision Data, Technical Report No. DOT HS 808 679, University of Michigan Transportation Research Institute, for the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Washington, D.C., February 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Crandall, R.W., and Graham, J.D., “The Effect of Fuel Economy Standards on Automobile Safety,” The Journal of Law &amp; Economics, Vol. XXXII (I), April, 1989, page 110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Neill, B., Joksch, H., and Haddon, W.Jr., “Empirical Relationships Between Car Size, Car Weight and Crash Injuries in Car-to-Car Crashes,” Proceedings of the 5th International Technical Conference on Experimental Safety Vehicles, London, June 4-7, 1974, pp 362-368.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">71 FR 17566, Average Fuel Economy Standards for Light Trucks Model Years 2008-2011, Federal Docket No. NHTSA-2006-24309-0007, April 6, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">77 FR 62624, 2017 and Later Model Year Light-Duty Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards, Federal Docket No. NHTSA-2010-0131-0412, October 15, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Evans, L., “How to Make a Car Lighter and Safer,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1172, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-1172.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weir, D., Shortwell, C., and Johnson, W., “Dynamics of the Automobile Related to Driver Control,” SAE Technical Paper 680194, 1968, doi: 10.4271/680194.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anon., FARS Analytic Reference Guide 1975 to 2008, Technical Report No. DOT HS 811 137, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Washington, DC, June 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anon., State Data System Crash Data Report: 1990 - 1999, Technical Report No. DOT HS 809 301, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Washington, July 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anon., National Vehicle Population Profile®, Source: Copyright © 2002, R. L. Polk &amp; Co., 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anon., Ward's Automotive Yearbook, annual publication, Wards Communications, Detroit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anon., Automotive News Market Data Book, Annual Publication, Crain Communications Inc., Detroit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McCullough, C., Hollowell, W., and Battisti, P., “Applications of NHTSA's Vehicle Parameter Database,” SAE Technical Paper 950360, 1995, doi: 10.4271/950360.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Draper, N.R., and Smith, H., Applied Regression Analysis, Second Edition, Wiley Interscience, New York, 1981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hosmer, D.W.Jr. and Lemeshow, S., Applied Logistic Regression, Wiley Interscience, New York, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, A., http://jblevins.org/mirror/amiller/logistic.f90 (Revised August 9, 2003) and http://jblevins.org/mirror/amiller/lsq.f90 (Version 1.14, 19 August 2002) (accessed May 15, 2011).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anon., SPSS® 13.0 Command Syntax Reference, SPSS Inc., Chicago, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allison, P.D., Logistic Regression Using SAS, Theory and Application, SAS Institute Inc., Cary, NC, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Menard, S., Applied Logistic Regression Analysis, Second Edition, Sage Publications, Thousand Oaks, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Brien, R.M., “A Caution Regarding Rules of Thumb for Variance Inflation Factors,” Quality &amp; Quantity, Vol. 41, 2007, pp 673-690.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
