<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">16</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830303</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830308</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE THEORY OF OPTIMUM CURRENCY AREAS AND MONETARY INTEGRATION IN AFRICA / LA THEORIE DE LA "ZONE MONETAIRE OPTIMALE" ET L'INTEGRATION MONETAIRE EN AFRIQUE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ben E.</given-names>
                  <surname>Algbokhan</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1992</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>275</fpage>
         <lpage>286</lpage>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830308"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The Organisation of African Unity at its Twenty-Seventh Summit in June 1991 signed the Treaty establishing the African Economic Community. Among the provisions of the Treaty is the establishment of an African Monetary Union and a single currency for Africa. The goal of monetary union and a single currency for Africa no doubt was informed by some perceived benefits from such an arrangement. But what are the conditions for an effective monetary union and a single currency area? This paper adopts the "optimum currency area" theory as a basis of answering this question, to assess the feasibility of a single currency for Africa, a continent with 51 countries. A number of economic characteristics, namely, degree of factor mobility, degree of openness, degree of financial integration, and degree of policy integration were selected. Analysis of African economies on the basis of these characteristics shows that, except for the few Francophone countries, levels of interactions among these economies are such that the continent could not be said to be ripe for a monetary union at the present time. A lot of effort is still required to bring about improvement in the selected economic characteristics. In addition, very strong political will is required to make member states see beyond individual national sovereignty and interests as to ensure a workable monetary union in Africa. Au cours de son vingt-septième sommet en juin 1991, l'Organisation de l'Unité Africaine a signé un traité pour fonder la Communauté Economique Africaine. Une des dispositions du traité est l'établissement d'une Union Monétaire Africaine et d'une monnaie unique pour l'Afrique. L'objectif de l'Union monétaire et d'une monnaie unique pour l'Afrique s'explique sans doute dans les profits aperçus d'une telle disposition. Mais quelles sont les conditions pour un bon fonctionnement d'une union monétaire et d'une monnaie unique? Pour répondre à cette question, cet exposé choisit comme base la théorie de la "zone monétaire optimale" pour évaluer la possibilité de réalisation d'une monnaie unique pour l'Afrique, un continent de 51 pays. Pour le faire, on a choisi un nombre de caractéristiques économiques, à savoir, le degré du facteur de mobilité, le degré de franchise, le degré d'intégration financière et le degré d'intégration politique. A l'exception de quelques pays francophones, l'analyse des économies Africaines sur la base de ces caractéristiques montre que le niveau d'intéraction entre ces économies est tel qu'on ne pourrait pas dire que le continent est prêt pour une union monétaire à l'heure actuelle. Il faut beaucoup d'efforts pour améliorer les caractéristiques économiques choisies. En plus, il faut une volonté trés forte au niveau politique pour faire voir aux pays membres au-delà de leur souveraineté et des intérêts nationals individuels et par conséquence arriver à une union monétaire réalisable en Afrique.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1e117a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e124" publication-type="other">
Ishiyama (1975).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e131a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e138" publication-type="other">
Africa Recovery (United Nations) June, 1991.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1e154a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e158" publication-type="other">
Aigbokhan, B.E. (1992) "Monetary Integration in the European Community: Some Lessons for the African
Economic Community", paper presented at the Nigerian Economic Society Annual Conference on The
Challenges of African Economic Integration, Kano (June).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e171a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e175" publication-type="other">
Ezenwe, Uka (1984) Ecowas and the Economic Integration of West Africa (Ibadan: West Books Publishers).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e182a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e186" publication-type="other">
Hacck, W.G.C. (1983) "The Selectivity of Economic Integration Theories: A Comparison of some Traditional
and Marxist Approaches", Journal of Common Market Studies (June), pp. 365-387.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e196a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e200" publication-type="other">
Ishiyame, Y. (1975) "The Theory of Optimum Currency Areas: A Survey", IMF Staff Papers (July), pp. 344-383.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e208a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e212" publication-type="other">
Ogbe, N.E. (1987) "Common Currency for the West African Sub-Region - Prospects for Nigeria", paper presented
at the Sixth West African Bankers' Association Day Celebration, Lagos, August 10th.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e222a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e226" publication-type="other">
Robson, P. (1980) The Economics of International Integration (London: George Allen &amp; Unwin).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e233a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e237" publication-type="other">
Tomori, S. (1990) "Towards Monetary Integration in West Africa", Nigerian Economic Society Presidential Ad-
dress.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


