<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440115</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Anticipated Capitalisation Effect of a New Metro Line on Housing Prices</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Claudio A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Agostini</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Gastón A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Palmucci</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2008</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">29</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440111</issue-id>
         <fpage>233</fpage>
         <lpage>256</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2008</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440115"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Housing units with closer access to public transportation enjoy a higher market value than those with similar characteristics but poorer access. This difference can be explained by the lower cost of transport to the main workplaces and shopping areas in town. For this reason, investments in public transport infrastructure, such as building a new metro line, are capitalised totally or partially into land and housing prices. This work empirically analyses the degree of capitalisation into housing prices of the benefits of the new Line 4 of the Santiago metro system, which began operating in December 2005. We focus on anticipated capitalisation into housing prices at the moment construction of Line 4 was announced and at the moment information on the basic engineering project was unveiled, identifying the location of the future stations. We use a unique database containing all home buying and selling transactions in the Greater Santiago area between December 2000 and March 2004. The results show that the average apartment price rose by between 4.2 per cent and 7.9 per cent after construction was announced and by between 3.1 per cent and 5.5 per cent after the location of the stations was identified. These increases were not distributed evenly, but depended on the distance from the apartment to the nearest station. An indirect effect of this kind of capitalisation is that property tax collections will increase if property is reappraised following the price rise. This effect is not negligible in magnitude and could represent 11 to 17 per cent of investment in the new metro line. This raises an interesting discussion on how the metro network extension is financed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d15e190a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e197" publication-type="other">
Submitted November 2006.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e204a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e211" publication-type="other">
The government's objective with the Transantiago plan is to generate an efficient public transport
system that reduces traffic jams and air pollution. Additionally, integrating all the available means of
public transport should improve the quality of service.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e224a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e231" publication-type="other">
The total project, including the extensions of Lines 2 and 5, encompassed 38.6 kilometres and 33
stations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e241a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e248" publication-type="other">
The reason is that enjoyment of local public goods is coupled with consumption of land, of which
there might be a fixed supply. This creates the possibility of capitalisation and that local public goods
might be 'located' in space, which implies that capitalisation differs within jurisdictions as well as
between jurisdictions (Oakland, 1987).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e265a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e272" publication-type="other">
See Grämlich and Rubinfeld (1982).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e279a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e286" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Vessali (1996) and Gibbons and Machin (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e293a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e300" publication-type="other">
The estimated coefficients may be interpreted as the willingness to pay for a marginal increase of
said characteristic.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e310a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e317" publication-type="other">
See Rubin (1974), Rosenbaum and Rubin (1983), Angrist, Imbens and Rubin (1996) and Heckman,
Ichimura and Todd (1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e327a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e334" publication-type="other">
Henneberry (1998), Lin and Hwang (2004), Laakso (1992) and McDonald and Osuji (1995) use
this type of estimation to analyse transport influences on property prices.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e344a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e351" publication-type="other">
This is basically an assumption of common time effects across groups (Blundell, Duncan and
Meghir, 1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e362a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e369" publication-type="other">
Bajic (1983), Dewees (1976), Gatzlaff and Smith (1993), Lee (1973) and McMillen and
McDonald (2004); although these works differ concerning model specification, in general the idea is to
compare changes in house prices in the area within reach of the metro impact with changes in prices of
the control housing units not in the scope of the metro impact.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e385a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e392" publication-type="other">
The Conservador de Bienes Raices de Santiago records all transactions involving housing, offices
and land in 25 communities out of 35 in the Greater Santiago area. This database was kindly provided by
Mapcity S.A.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e405a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e412" publication-type="other">
The location process is simply a means of assigning a pair of east-north coordinates to each
observation. The distance from the housing unit to the metro station is defined as d=sj(El -E,f +{N, -N„f ■</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e422a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e429" publication-type="other">
The Unidad de Fomento (UF) is an inflation-indexed unit of account authorised by the Central
Bank of Chile and used extensively throughout the economy. In September 2005, 1 UF equalled
ChS 17,700 or US$32.80.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e442a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e449" publication-type="other">
Decree Law 2 of 1959 (DFL2) establishes that income earned from the rental of houses and
apartments smaller than 140 square metres is exempt from income tax and other taxes, and income from
the sale of such properties is exempt from capital gains tax. Additionally, property taxes are reduced by
50 per cent for the first 10 years.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e465a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e472" publication-type="other">
Metro S.A. estimates that around 50 to 60 per cent of the demand is captured within 500 metres of
the station and 80 to 90 per cent within 1,000 metres.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e483a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e490" publication-type="other">
For example, prices in neighbouring communities may display a degree of spatial correlation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e497a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e504" publication-type="other">
There are no statistical differences before and after treatment for the variables Age, Number of
bedrooms, Number of bathrooms, Lift, Parking and Basement (for example, the average number of
bedrooms is 2.61 before treatment and 2.60 after treatment; the average number of bathrooms is 2.06
before treatment and 2.02 after treatment).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e520a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e527" publication-type="other">
For example, the coefficient for Announcement in model 1 was 0.040 (compared to 0.042) and the
coefficient for Announcement interacted with D\ooo was 0.046 (compared to 0.050). The R: was slightly
lower: 0.68 compared with 0.70).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e540a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e547" publication-type="other">
Non-agricultural areas zoned for housing enjoy a property tax exemption of Ch$10,878,522 as of 1
January 2005. For properties appraised above that amount, the excess value is taxed at 1.2 per cent per
year when the appraised value of the eligible property does not exceed Ch$37,526,739 and at 1.4 per cent
per year when the appraised value is over that amount.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e563a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e570" publication-type="other">
We are assuming a 40-year useful life for the metro trains (with 100 years for infrastructure and
rails) and an 8 per cent discount rate.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d15e589a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e593" publication-type="other">
Al-Mosaind, M., Dueker, K. and Strathman, J. (1993), 'Light rail stations and property
values: a hedonic price approach', Transportation Research Record', no. 1400, pp. 90-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e603a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e607" publication-type="other">
Alonso, W. (1964), Location and Land Use: Toward a General Theory of Land Rent,
Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e617a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e621" publication-type="other">
Angrist, J. and Imbens, G. (1994), 'Identification and estimation of local average treatment
effects', Econometrica, vol. 62, pp. 467-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e631a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e635" publication-type="other">
—, — and Rubin, D. (1996), 'Identification of causal effects using instrumental variables
(with discussion)', Journal of the American Statistical Association, vol. 91, pp. 444-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e646a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e650" publication-type="other">
Armstrong, R. (1994), 'Impacts of commuter rail service as reflected in single-family
residential property values', Transportation Research Record, no. 1466, pp. 88-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e660a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e664" publication-type="other">
Bajic, V. (1983), 'The effects of a new subway line on housing prices in metropolitan
Toronto', Urban Studies, vol. 20, pp. 147-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e674a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e678" publication-type="other">
Bartik, T. J. (1987), 'The estimation of demand parameter in hedonic price models', Journal
of Political Economy, vol. 95, pp. 81-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e688a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e692" publication-type="other">
Blomquist, G., Berger, M. and Hoenh, J. (1988), 'New estimates of quality of life in urban
areas', American Economic Review, vol. 78, pp. 89-107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e702a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e706" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R., Duncan, A. and Meghir, C. (1998), 'Estimating labour supply responses using
tax policy reforms', Econometrica, vol. 66, pp. 827-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e716a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e720" publication-type="other">
— and MaCurdy, T. (1999), 'Labor supply: a review of alternative approaches', in O.
Ashenfelter and D. Card (eds), Handbook of Labor Economics, vol. 3A, Amsterdam:
Elsevier North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e734a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e738" publication-type="other">
Bowes, D. and Ihlanfeldt, K. (2001), 'Identifying the impacts of rail transit stations on
residential property values', Journal of Urban Economics, vol. 50, pp. 1-25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e748a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e752" publication-type="other">
Damm, D., Lerman, S., Lemer-Lam, E. and Young, J. (1980), 'Response of urban real estate
values in anticipation of the Washington metro', Journal of Transport Economics and
Policy, vol. 14, pp. 315-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e765a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e769" publication-type="other">
Debrezion, G., Pels, E. and Rietveld, P. (2007), 'The impact of railway stations on residential
and commercial property value: a meta analysis', Journal of Real Estate Finance and
Economics, vol. 35, pp. 161-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e782a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e786" publication-type="other">
Dewees, D. N. (1976), 'The effect of a subway on residential property values in Toronto',
Journal of Urban Economics, vol. 3, pp. 357-69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e796a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e800" publication-type="other">
Dombusch, D. (1975), 'BART-induced changes in property values and rents', in Land Use
and Urban Development Projects, Phase I, BART: Final Report, US Department of
Transportation and US Department of Housing and Urban Development, Working Paper
no. WP21-5-76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e816a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e820" publication-type="other">
Dueker, K., Chen, H. and Rufolo, A. (1998), 'Measuring the impact of light rail systems on
single-family home values', Transportation Research Record, no. 1617, pp. 38-43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e831a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e835" publication-type="other">
Freeman, A. M. (1979), 'The hedonic price approach to measuring demand for neighborhood
characteristics', in D. Segal (ed.), The Economics of Neighborhood, New York: Academic
Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e848a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e852" publication-type="other">
Gatzlaff, D. and Smith, M. (1993), 'The impact of the Miami metrorail on the value of
residences near station locations', Land Economics, vol. 69, pp. 54—66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e862a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e866" publication-type="other">
Gibbons, S. and Machin, S. (2005), 'Valuing rail access using transport innovations', Journal
of Urban Economics, vol. 57, pp. 148-69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e876a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e880" publication-type="other">
Grämlich, E. M. and Rubinfeld, D. L. (1982), 'Micro estimates of public spending demand
functions and tests of the Tiebout and median-voter hypotheses', Journal of Political
Economy, vol. 90, pp. 536-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e893a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e897" publication-type="other">
Grass, R. G. (1992), 'The estimation of residential property values around transit station sites
in Washington, DC', Journal of Economics and Finance, vol. 16, pp. 139-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e907a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e911" publication-type="other">
Gyourko, J. and Tracy, J. (1989), 'Local public sector rent-seeking and its impact on local
land values', Regional Science and Urban Economics, vol. 19, pp. 493-516.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e922a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e926" publication-type="other">
— and — (1991), 'The structure of local public finance and the quality of life', Journal of
Political Economy, vol. 99, pp. 774-806.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e936a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e940" publication-type="other">
Heckman, J., Ichimura, H. and Todd, P. (1997), 'Matching as an econometric evaluation
estimator: evidence from evaluating a job training programme', Review of Economic
Studies, vol. 64, pp. 605-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e953a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e957" publication-type="other">
Henneberry, J. (1998), 'Transport investment and house prices', Journal of Property
Valuation and Investment, vol. 16, pp. 144-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e967a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e971" publication-type="other">
Laakso, S. (1992), 'Public transport investment and residential property values in Helsinki',
Scandinavian Housing &amp; Planning Research, vol. 9, pp. 217-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e981a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e985" publication-type="other">
Lee, D. B. (1973), Case Studies and Impacts of BART on Prices of Single Family Residences,
Berkeley, CA: Institute of Urban and Regional Development, University of California at
Berkeley.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e998a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1002" publication-type="other">
Lin, J. J. and Hwang, C. H. (2004), 'Analysis of property prices before and after the opening
of the Taipei subway system', Annals of Regional Science, vol. 38, pp. 687-704.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1013a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1017" publication-type="other">
McDonald, J. and Osuji, C. (1995), 'The effect of anticipated transportation improvement on
residential land values', Regional Science and Urban Economics, vol. 25, pp. 261-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1027a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1031" publication-type="other">
McMillen, D. and McDonald, J. (2004), 'Reaction of house prices to a new rapid transit line:
Chicago's Midway Line, 1983-1999', Real Estate Economics, vol. 32, pp. 463-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1041a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1045" publication-type="other">
Mills, E. S. (1967), 'Transportation and patterns of urban development', American Economic
Review, vol. 57, pp. 197-210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1055a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1059" publication-type="other">
Muth, R. (1969), Cities and Housing, Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1066a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1070" publication-type="other">
Oakland, W. (1987), 'Theory of public goods', in A. Auerbach and M. Feldstein (eds),
Handbook of Public Economics, vol. II, Amsterdam: Elsevier Science Publishers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1080a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1084" publication-type="other">
Roback, J. (1980), 'The value of the local urban amenities: theory and measurement', Ph.D.
dissertation, University of Rochester.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1095a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1099" publication-type="other">
— (1982), 'Wages, rents, and the quality of life', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 90, pp.
1257-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1109a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1113" publication-type="other">
Rosen, S. (1974), 'Hedonic pricing and implicit markets: product differentiation in pure
competition', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 82, pp. 34—55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1123a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1127" publication-type="other">
Rosenbaum, P. and Rubin, D. B. (1983), 'The central role of the propensity score in
observational studies for causal effects', Biometrika, vol. 70, pp. 41-55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1137a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1141" publication-type="other">
Rubin, D. B. (1974), 'Estimating causal effects of treatments in randomized and
nonrandomized studies', Journal of Educational Psychology, vol. 66, pp. 688-701.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1151a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1155" publication-type="other">
Rubinfeld, D. (1987), 'The economics of the local public sector', in A. Auerbach and M.
Feldstein (eds), Handbook of Public Economics, vol. II, Amsterdam: Elsevier Science
Publishers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1168a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1172" publication-type="other">
Sheppard, S. (1999), 'Hedonic analysis of housing markets', in P. C. Cheshire and E. S. Mills
(eds), Handbook of Regional and Urban Economics, vol. 3, Amsterdam: Elsevier Science
B.V.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1186a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1190" publication-type="other">
Vessali, K. (1996), 'Land use impacts of rapid transit: a review of the empirical literature',
Berkeley Planning Journal, vol. 11, pp. 71-105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1200a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1204" publication-type="other">
Voith, R. (1991), 'Capitalization of local and regional attributes into wages and rents:
differences and mixed-use communities', Journal of Regional Science, vol. 31, pp. 127—
45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1217a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1221" publication-type="other">
Von Thiinen, J. (1863), Der Isolierte Staat in Beziehung auf Landwirschaft und
Nationalökonomie, Munich: Pflaum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1231a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1235" publication-type="other">
Yinger, J. (1982), 'Capitalization and the theory of local public finance', Journal of Political
Economy, vol. 90, pp. 917-43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
