<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014362</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Review Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Emerging Trends and New Directions in Telecollaborative Learning</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>O’Dowd</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of León, Spain.</aff>
               <bio>
                  <p>Robert O’Dowd teaches EFL and Applied Linguistics at the University of León, Spain. He has taught at universities in Ireland, Germany, and Spain and has published widely on the application of telecollaborative networks in university education. His most recent publication is the coedited volume Online Intercultural Exchange Policy, Pedagogy, Practice for Routledge. He has participated in many international projects about telecollaboration and he recently coordinated INTENT—a project financed by the European Commission aimed at promoting online intercultural exchange in European Higher Education (www.unicollaboration.eu).</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>33</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014360</issue-id>
         <fpage>291</fpage>
         <lpage>310</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2016, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014362"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>This article provides an overview of the most significant emerging trends and tendencies in telecollaborative practice. In order to achieve this, I review the recent literature in the area and I identify recurring themes from the Telecollaboration in Higher Education conference which took place in Trinity College Dublin, Ireland from 21 to 23 April 2016. The main trends identified include the diversification of telecollaborative partnerships and networks, the rise of critical and cross-disciplinary approaches to telecollaboration, the combination and integration of telecollaboration with other modes of education, and, finally, the emergence of videoconferencing as an important tool for online intercultural interaction.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>telecollaboration</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>virtual exchange</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>online learning</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Azaoui, B. (2016). Dealing with unexpected technical interruption in telecollaborative exchanges. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barron, A., &amp; Black, E. (2015). Constructing small talk in learner–native speaker voicebased telecollaboration: A focus on topic management and backchanneling. System, 48, 112–128. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.system.2014.09.009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Belz, J. A., &amp; Thorne, S. L. (2006). Internet-mediated intercultural foreign language education. Boston, MA: Thomson Heinle.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benabdallah, N., &amp; Messaadia, M. (2016). “On the other side of the world” project: A 2.0. telecollaborative perspective facing the global digital divide. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blin, F., &amp; Dey-Plissonneau, A. (2016). Emerging affordances in telecollaborative multimodal interactions. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Byram, M. (2014). Twenty-five years on—from cultural studies to intercultural citizenship. Language, Culture and Curriculum, 27(3), 209–216. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/07908318.2014.974329</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Corbett, J. (2010). Intercultural language activities. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Council of Europe (2001). The common European framework of reference for languages: Learning, teaching, assessment. Retrieved from http://www.coe.int/t/dg4/linguistic/CADRE_EN.asp</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cummins, J., &amp; Sayers, D. (1995). Brave new schools: Challenging cultural literacy through global learning networks. New York: St. Martin’s Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deutscher, J. (2016). Beyond borders—Telecollaboration in secondary geography education in Germany. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Develotte, C. (2016). Towards the empowerment of the learner—students’ autonomy and uses of external resources in a multimodal environment. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diamond, A., Walkley, L., Forbes, P., Hughes, T., &amp; Sheen, J. (2011). Global graduates into global leaders. Retrieved from http://www.ncub.co.uk/reports/global-graduates-into-global-leaders.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dooly, M. (2015). It takes research to build a community: Ongoing challenges for scholars in digitally-supported communicative language teaching. CALICO Journal, 32(1), 172–194.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dooly, M. (2016). “Please remove your avatar from my personal space”: Competences of the telecollaboratively efficient person. In R. O’Dowd &amp; T. Lewis (Eds.), Online intercultural exchange: Policy, pedagogy, practice (pp. 192–208). New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duus, R., &amp; Cooray, M. (2014) Together we innovate: Cross-cultural teamwork through virtual platforms. Journal of Marketing Education, 36(3), 244–257. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0273475314535783</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elola, I., &amp; Oskoz, A. (2008). Blogging: Fostering intercultural competence development in foreign language and study abroad contexts. Foreign Language Annals, 41(3), 454–477. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1944-9720.2008.tb03307.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Furstenberg, G., Levet, S., English, K., &amp; Maillet, K. (2001). Giving a virtual voice to the silent language of culture: The culture project. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 5(1), 55–102. Retrieved from: http://llt.msu.edu/vol5num1/furstenberg/default.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giralt, M. (2016). Preparing students’ mobility through telecollaboration: Developing intercultural communication competence prior to the period abroad. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graddol, D. (2006). English next. Retrieved from http://englishagenda.britishcouncil.org/sites/ec/files/books-english-next.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grandin, J. M., &amp; Hedderich, N. (2009). Intercultural competence in engineering: Global competence for engineers. In D. K. Deardorff (Ed.), The SAGE handbook of intercultural competence (pp. 311–362). Los Angeles, CA: SAGE.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guichon, N. (2016). What you see is that I care: Reflections on online teacher presence. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guillen, G. (2016). How to keep students accountable? The problem of semi-controlled e-tandem assessment. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guth, S., &amp; Helm, F. (2010). Telecollaboration 2.0. Bern: Peter Lang.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guth, S., Helm, F., &amp; O’Dowd, R. (2012). University language classes collaborating online. A report on the integration of telecollaborative networks in European universities. Retrieved from http://coil.suny.edu/sites/default/files/intent_report_execsummary_june2012.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanna, B., &amp; de Nooy, J. (2009). Learning language and culture via public internet discussion forums. New York: Palgrave Macmillan. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1057/9780230235823</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hauck, M., &amp; MacKinnon, T. (2016). A new approach to assessing online intercultural exchange: Open badges for soft certification of participant engagement and task execution. In R. O’Dowd &amp; T. Lewis (Eds.), Online intercultural exchange: Policy, pedagogy, practice (pp. 209–234). New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hauck, M., &amp; Youngs, B. L. (2008). Telecollaboration in multimodal environments: The impact on task design and learner interaction. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 21(2), 87–124. Retrieved from http://doi:10.1080/09588220801943510</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Helm, F. (2013). A dialogic model for telecollaboration. Bellaterra Journal, 6(2), 28–48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Helm, F. (2016). Facilitated dialogue in online intercultural exchange. In R. O’Dowd &amp; T. Lewis (Eds.), Online intercultural exchange: Policy, pedagogy, practice (pp. 150–172). New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Helm, F., Guth, S., &amp; Farrah, M. (2012). Promoting dialogue or hegemonic practice? Power issues in telecollaboration. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 16(2), 103–127. Retrieved from http://llt.msu.edu/issues/june2012/helmguthfarrah.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huber, B. R. (2015). Tandem classroom-online course aims to create international network of “builders.” Retrieved from http://www.princeton.edu/main/news/archive/S42/98/12A55/index.xml?section=featured</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kern, R. (2014). Technology as Pharmakon: The promise and perils of the internet for foreign language education. Modern Language Journal, 98(1), 340–357. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.2014.12065.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kinginger, C. (2009). Language learning and study abroad: A critical reading of research. New York, NY: Palgrave Macmillan. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1057/9780230240766</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kohn, K., &amp; Hoffstaedter, P. (2015). Flipping intercultural communication practice: Opportunities and challenges for the foreign language classroom. Conference paper presented at ANTWERP CALL 2015 Conference: Task design and CALL, 6–8 July 2015, at Universitat Rovira i Virgili, Tarragona, Spain.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kramsch, C. (2006). From communicative competence to symbolic competence. Modern Language Journal, 90(2), 249–252. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.2006.00395_3.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kramsch, C. (2014). Teaching foreign languages in an era of globalization. Introduction. The Modern Language Journal, 98(1), 296–311. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.2014.12057.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lawton, W. (2015). Digital learning, mobility and internationalisation in European higher education. In H. de Wit, F. Hunter, L. Howard &amp; E. Egron-Polak (Eds.), Internationalisation of higher education (pp. 77–81). Brussels: European Parliament.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leahy, V. &amp; De Gruil, L. (2016). Combining telecollaboration with physical mobility. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lewis, T., &amp; O’Dowd, R. (2016). Online intercultural exchange and foreign language learning: A systematic review. In R. O’Dowd &amp; T. Lewis (Eds.), Online intercultural exchange: Policy, pedagogy, practice (pp. 21–68). New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liddicoat, A., &amp; Scarino, A. (2013). Intercultural language teaching and learning. Chichester: Wiley-Blackwell. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/9781118482070</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lindner, R. (2016). Developing communicative competence in global virtual teams: A multiliteracies approach to telecollaboration for students of business and economics. CASALC Review, 1, 144–156.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malinowski, D., &amp; Kramsch, C. (2014). The ambiguous world of heteroglossic computer-mediated language learning. In A. Blackledge &amp; A. Creese (Eds.), Heteroglossia as practice and pedagogy (pp. 155–178). Dordrecht: Springer. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-94-007-7856-6_9</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marturet de Paris, C., &amp; Coffey, C. (2016). Collective impact as a best practice method for scaling and enhancing learner experience in telecollaboration. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mason, J. (2016). Telecollaboration as a tool for building intercultural and inter-religious understanding: The Sousse–Villanova programme. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meechan, P. (2016). Extending telecollaboration to other disciplines. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Michel, M. M., &amp; Smith, B. (2016). Measuring structural alignment during L2 peer interaction via synchronous computer-mediated communication—An eye tracking study. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O’Dowd, R. (2006). Telecollaboration and the development of intercultural communicative competence. Munich: Langenscheidt.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O’Dowd, R. (2007). Online intercultural exchange: An introduction for foreign language teachers. Bristol, UK: Multilingual Matters.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O’Dowd, R. (2013). Telecollaboration and CALL. In M. Thomas, H. Reindeers, &amp; M. Warschauer (Eds.), Contemporary computer-assisted language learning (pp. 123–141). London: Bloomsbury Academic.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O’Dowd, R. (2015). Supporting in-service language educators in learning to telecollaborate. Language Learning and Technology, 19(1), 63–82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O’Dowd, R. (2016). Learning from the past and looking to the future of online intercultural exchange. In R. O’Dowd &amp; T. Lewis (Eds.), Online intercultural exchange: Policy, pedagogy, practice (pp. 273–298). New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O’Dowd, R. &amp; Ware, P. (2009). Critical issues in telecollaborative task design. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 22(2), 173–188. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09588220902778369</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olmo, Y. (2016). Obstacles to telecollaboration. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O’Rourke, B. (2007). Models of telecollaboration (1): E(tandem). In R. O’Dowd (Ed.), Online intercultural exchange: An introduction for foreign language teachers (pp. 41–62). Clevedon, UK: Multilingual Matters.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Porto, M. (2014). Intercultural citizenship education in an EFL online project in Argentina. Language and Intercultural Communication, 14(2), 245–261. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/14708477.2014.890625</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roberts, C., Byram, M., Barro, A., Jordan, S., &amp; Street, B. (2001). Language learners as ethnographers. Clevedon, UK: Multilingual Matters.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rubin, J. (2016). The Collaborative Online International Learning Network. In R. O’Dowd &amp; T. Lewis (Eds.), Online intercultural exchange: Policy, pedagogy, practice (pp. 263–272). New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmidt, T. Franz, J. Phillips, C., &amp; Kim, H. (2016). Telecollaboration in university education—Synchronous five universities, four countries—Global health live Pacific course. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schultheis Moore, A., &amp; Simon, S. (2015). Globally networked teaching in the humanities. New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tcherepashenets, N. (2016). Telecollaboration, world citizenship and the quest for the social justice: US–Mexico project. Paper presented at the Second International Conference on Telecollaboration in Higher Education, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Telles, J., &amp; Leone, P. (2016). The teletandem network. In R. O’Dowd &amp; T. Lewis (Eds.), Online intercultural exchange: Policy, pedagogy, practice (pp. 273–298). New York: Routledge. Thorne, S. (2006). Pedagogical and praxiological lessons from internet-mediated intercultural foreign language education research. In J. Belz &amp; S. L. Thorne (Eds.), Internet-mediated intercultural foreign language education (pp. 2–30). Boston, MA: Heinle &amp; Heinle.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thorne, S. (2010). The intercultural turn and language learning in the crucible of new media. In S. Guth &amp; F. Helm (Eds.), Telecollaboration 2.0: Language and intercultural learning in the 21st century (pp. 139–165). Bern: Peter Lang.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thorne, S. L., Black, R. W., &amp; Sykes, J. (2009). Second language use, socialization, and learning in internet interest communities and online gaming. Modern Language Journal, 93, 802–821. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.2009.00974.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vallance, M. &amp; Ibayashi, K. (2015). Post-Fukushima 3D virtual collaboration and communication for active learning. Retrieved from https://www.researchgate.net/publication/2812 55471_Engineering_Active_Learning_in_3D_Virtual_Worlds</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van der Kroon, L., Jauregi, K., &amp; Jan, D. t. T. (2015). Telecollaboration in foreign language curricula: A case study on intercultural understanding in video communication exchanges. International Journal of Computer-Assisted Language Learning and Teaching, 5(3). Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.4018/IJCALLT.2015070102</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van der Zwaard, R., &amp; Bannink, A. (2014). Video call or chat? Negotiation of meaning and issues of face in telecollaboration. System, 44, 137–148. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.system.2014.03.007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vriens, M., &amp; Van Petegem W. (Eds.). (2012). Make it work! Integrating virtual mobility in international work placements. EuroPACE ivzw, Leuven, 2011. Retrieved from http://www.euvip.eu/resources/Manual_ONLINE.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Warschauer, M. (Ed.). (1995). Virtual connections: Online activities &amp; projects for networking language learners (1st ed.). Honolulu: Second Language Teaching and Curriculum Center.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
