<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40172063</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44113768</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Translation project adaptation for MT-enhanced computer assisted translation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Mauro</given-names>
                  <surname>Cettolo</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Nicola</given-names>
                  <surname>Bertoldi</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Marcello</given-names>
                  <surname>Federico</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Holger</given-names>
                  <surname>Schwenk</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Loïc</given-names>
                  <surname>Barrault</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Christophe</given-names>
                  <surname>Servan</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>127</fpage>
         <lpage>150</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Springer Science+Business Media 2014</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44113768"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The effective integration of MT technology into computer-assisted translation tools is a challenging topic both for academic research and the translation industry. In particular, professional translators consider the ability of MT systems to adapt to the feedback provided by them to be crucial. In this paper, we propose an adaptation scheme to tune a statistical MT system to a translation project using small amounts of post-edited texts, like those generated by a single user in even just one day of work. The same scheme can be applied on a larger scale in order to focus general pmpose models towards the specific domain of interest. We assess our method on two domains, namely information technology and legal, and four translation directions, from English to French, Italian, Spanish and German. The main outcome is that our adaptation strategy can be very effective provided that the seed data used for adaptation is 'close enough' to the remaining text to be translated; otherwise, MT quality neither improves nor worsens, thus showing the robustness of our method.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d3159636e275a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d3159636e282" publication-type="other">
http://www.matecat.com.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d3159636e289a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d3159636e296" publication-type="other">
http://www.caitra.org.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d3159636e303a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d3159636e310" publication-type="other">
Available from http://www.statmt.org/wmtl3/translation-task.html.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d3159636e317a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d3159636e324" publication-type="other">
http://eur-lex.europa.eu/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d3159636e332a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d3159636e339" publication-type="other">
European Union, available at: http://www.europarl.europa.eu/sides/getDoc.do?
pubRef=-//EP//TEXT+REPORT+A7-2013-0039+0+DOC+XML+VO//EN.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d3159636e358a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e362" publication-type="other">
Axelrod A, He X, Gao J (2011) Domain adaptation via pseudo in-domain data selection. In: Proceedings
of the conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP). Edinburgh, pp
355-362</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e375a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e379" publication-type="other">
Bach N, Hsiao R, Eck M, Charoenpornsawat P, Vogel S, Schultz T, Lane I, Waibel A, Black AW (2009)
Incremental adaptation of speech-to-speech translation. In: Proceedings of the North American Chapter
of the Association for Computational Linguistics -Human Language Technologies (NAACL HLT)
Conference: Short Papers. Boulder, US-CO, pp 149-152</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e395a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e399" publication-type="other">
Bertoldi N, Cettolo M, Federico M, Buck C (2012) Evaluating the learning curve of domain adaptive statis-
tical machine translation systems. In: Proceedings of the Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation
(WMT). Montréal, pp 433-441</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e412a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e416" publication-type="other">
Bertoldi N, Cettolo M, Federico M (2013) Cache-based online adaptation for machine translation enhanced
computer assisted translation. In: Proceedings of the MT summit XIV. Nice, pp 35-42</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e427a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e431" publication-type="other">
Bisazza A, Ruiz N, Federico M (2011) Fill-up versus interpolation methods for phrase-based SMT adap-
tation. In: Proceedings of the International Workshop on Spoken Language Translation (IWSLT). San
Francisco, US-CA, pp 136-143</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e444a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e448" publication-type="other">
Bojar O, Buck C, Callison-Burch C, Federmann C, Haddow B, Koehn P, Monz C, Post M, Soricut R, Specia
L (2013) Findings of the 2013 workshop on statistical machine translation. In: Proceedings of the eighth
workshop on statistical machine translation. Sofìa, pp 1-44</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e461a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e465" publication-type="other">
Cettolo M, Servan C, Bertoldi N, Federico M, Barrault L, Schwenk H (2013) Issues in incremental adaptation
of statistical mt from human post-edits. In: Proceedings of the MT summit XIV Workshop on Post-editing
Technology and Practice (WPTP-2). Nice, pp 111-118</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e478a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e482" publication-type="other">
Chen SF, Goodman J (1999) An empirical study of smoothing techniques for language modeling. Comput
Speech Lang 4(13): 359-393</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e492a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e496" publication-type="other">
Crammer K, Dekel D, Keshet J, Shalev-Shwartz S, Singer Y (2006) Online passive-aggressive algorithms.
J Mach Learn Res 7:551-585</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e506a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e510" publication-type="other">
Federico M, Cattelan A, Trombetti M (2012) Measuring user productivity in machine translation enhanced
computer assisted translation. In: Proceedings of conference of the Association for Machine Translation
in the Americas (AMTA). San Diego, US-CA</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e524a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e528" publication-type="other">
Foster G, Kuhn R (2007) Mixture-model adaptation for SMT. In: Proceedings of the Workshop on Statistical
Machine Translation (WMT). Prague, pp 128-135</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e538a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e542" publication-type="other">
Foster G, Goutte C, Kuhn R (2010) Discriminative instance weighting for domain adaptation in statistical
machine translation. In: Proceedings of the conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language
Processing (EMNLP). Cambridge, US-MA, pp 451-459</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e555a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e559" publication-type="other">
Galley M, Manning CD (2008) A simple and effective hierarchical phrase reordering model. In: Proceedings
of the Conference on empirical methods in natural language processing (EMNLP). Honolulu, US-HI,
pp 848-856</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e572a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e576" publication-type="other">
Gao J, Zhang M (2002) Improving Language model size reduction using better pruning criteria. In: Pro-
ceedings of the annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL). Philadelphia,
US-PA, pp 176-182</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e589a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e593" publication-type="other">
Green S, Heer J, Manning CD (2013) The efficacy of human post-editing for language translation. In:
Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on human factors in computing systems. ACM, Paris, pp 439-
448</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e606a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e610" publication-type="other">
Guerberof A (2009) Productivity and quality in MT post-editing. In: Proceedings of the MT summit XII,
Beyond translation memories: new tools for translators workshop. Ottawa, Canada</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e621a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e625" publication-type="other">
Hardt D, Elming J (2010) Incremental re-training for post-editing SMT. In: Proceedings of the Conference
of the Association for Machine Translation in the Americas (AMTA). Denver, US-CO</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e635a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e639" publication-type="other">
Hasler E, Haddow B, Koehn P (2012) Sparse lexical ised features and topic adaptation for SMT. In: Pro-
ceedings of the International Workshop on Spoken Language Translation (IWSLT). Hong Kong, pp
268-275</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e652a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e656" publication-type="other">
Kneser R, Steinbiss V (1993) On the dynamic adaptation of stochastic language models. In: Proceedings
of the IEEE international conference on acoustics, speech and signal processing (ICASSP), vol II,
Minneapolis, US-MN, pp 586-588</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e669a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e673" publication-type="other">
Koehn P (2005) Europarl: a parallel corpus for statistical machine translation. In: Proceedings of the MT
summit X. Phuket, pp 79-86</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e683a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e687" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Schroeder J (2007) Experiments in domain adaptation for statistical machine translation. In:
Proceedings of the Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation (WMT). Prague, pp 224-227</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e697a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e701" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Axelrod A, Mayne AB, Callison-Burch C, Osborne M, Talbot D (2005) Edinburgh system descrip-
tion for the 2005 IWSLT speech translation evaluation. In: Proceedings of the international workshop
on spoken language translation (IWSLT). Pittsburgh, US-PA</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e715a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e719" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Hoang H, Birch A, Callison-Burch C, Federico M, Bertoldi N, Cowan B, Shen W, Moran C, Zens
R, Dyer C, Bojar O, Constantin A, Herbst E (2007) Moses: open source toolkit for statistical machine
translation. In: Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL): Companion
volume proceedings of the demo and poster sessions. Prague, pp 177-180</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e735a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e739" publication-type="other">
Läubli S, Fishel M, Massey G, Ehrensberger-Dow M, Volk M (2013) Assessing post-editing efficiency in
a realistic translationenvironment. In: Proceedings of the MT summit XIV, workshop on post-editing
technology and practice. Nice, pp 83-91</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e752a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e756" publication-type="other">
Liu L, Cao H, Watanabe T, Zhao T, Yu M, Zhu C (2012) Locally training the log-linear model for SMT.
In: Proceedings of the joint conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and
Computational Natural Language Learning (EMNLP-CoNLL). Jeju Island, pp 402-411</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e769a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e773" publication-type="other">
Matsoukas S, Rosti AVI, Zhang B (2009) Discriminative Corpus weight estimation for machine translation.
In: Proceedings of the conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP).
Singapore, pp 708-717</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e786a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e790" publication-type="other">
Moore RC, Lewis W (2010) Intelligent selection of language model training data. In: Proceedings of the
annual meeting of the Association of Computational (ACL): Short Papers. Uppsala, pp 220-224</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e800a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e804" publication-type="other">
Nakov P (2008) Improving English-Spanish Statistical machine translation: experiments in domain adapta-
tion, sentence paraphrasing, tokenization, and recasing. In: Proceedings of the Workshop on Statistical
Machine Translation (WMT). Columbus, US-OH, pp 147-150</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e818a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e822" publication-type="other">
Niehues J, Waibel A (2012) Detailed Analysis of different strategies for phrase table adaptation in SMT.
In: Proceedings of the conference of the Association for Machine Translation in the Americas (AMTA).
San Diego, US-CA</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e835a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e839" publication-type="other">
Noreen EW (1989) Computer intensive methods for testing hypotheses: an introduction. Wiley Interscience,
New York</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e849a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e853" publication-type="other">
Och FJ (2003) Minimum error rate training in statistical machine translation. In: Proceedings of the annual
meeting of the Association for Computational (ACL). Sapporo, pp 160-167</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e863a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e867" publication-type="other">
Och FJ, Ney H (2003) A systematic comparison of various statistical alignment models. Comput Linguist
29(1): 19-51</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e877a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e881" publication-type="other">
Papineni K, Roukos S, Ward T, Zhu W J (2002) BLEU: a method for automatic evaluation of machine trans-
lation. In: Proceedings of the annual meeting of the Association of Computational (ACL). Philadelphia,
US-PA, pp 311-318</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e894a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e898" publication-type="other">
Plitt M, Masselot F (2010) A productivity test of statistical machine translation post-editing in a typical
localisation context. Prague Bull Math Linguist 93:7-16</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e909a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e913" publication-type="other">
Quenouille MH (1956) Notes on bias in estimation. Biometrika 43:353-360</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e920a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e924" publication-type="other">
Rousseau A (2013) XenC: an open-source tool for data selection in natural language processing. Prague
Bull Math Linguist 100(1):73-82</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e934a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e938" publication-type="other">
Snover M, Dorr B, Schwartz R, Micciulla L, Makhoul J (2006) A study of translation edit rate with targeted
human annotation. In: Proceedings of the Conference of the association for machine translation in the
Americas (AMTA). Cambridge, US-MA, pp 223-231</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e951a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e955" publication-type="other">
Steinberger R, Pouliquen B, Widiger A, Ignat C, Eijavec T, Tufi§ D, Varga D (2006) The JRC-acquis: a
multilingual aligned parallel corpus with 20+ languages. In: Proceedings of the international conference
on language resources and evaluation (LREC). Genoa, pp 2142-2147</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e968a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e972" publication-type="other">
Tiedemann J (2012) Parallel Data, Tools and Interfaces in OPUS. In: Proceedings of the international
conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC). Istanbul, pp 2214-2218</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e982a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e986" publication-type="other">
Turian JP, Shen L, Melamed ID (2003) Evaluation of machine translation and its evaluation. In: Proceedings
of MT summit IX, New Orleans, US-LA, pp 386-393</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3159636e997a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3159636e1001" publication-type="other">
Yasuda K, Zhang R, Yamamoto H, Sumita E (2008) Method of Selecting training data to build a compact and
efficient translation model. In: Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Natural Language
Processing (IJCNLP). Hyderabad, pp 655-660</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


