<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica, Centre for Financial Assistance to African Countries</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i40209586</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44944821</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>ASSET AND LIABILITY MANAGEMENT OF COMMERCIAL BANKING FIRMS IN THE PROCESS OF MONETARY AND FINANCIAL POLICY MAKING IN NIGERIA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Tayo</given-names>
                  <surname>Fakiyesi</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1988</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>105</fpage>
         <lpage>126</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44944821"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The study examines the total effects of portfolio management activities of banking firms on the process of macro-policy in Nigeria. The study assumes that the firm maximizes expected Utility of Wealth, imposing a Lognormal Utility function, and maximizing expected utility of wealth subject to balance sheet constraints. This solution expresses the vector of choice Portfolio items in terms of non-choice portfolio items. After analysing the results, the following conclusions and implications were drawn from the study: (1) that interest rates were less important than other variables in the portfolio behaviour of the banks, although the influence of rates and yield on banking portfolio behaviour cannot be totally discounted. (2) that there is a predominance of risk averseness over speculative behaviour by the banks. (3) banks are more responsive in applying funds to their excess reserve portfolio than to the less liquid portfolio (4) on policy variables: required reserves appeared more important in terms of significance than public sector borrowing from the banks. (5) public sector borrowing affects banks' lending to private sector more than other variables, in other words there is tendency for public sector borrowing to crowd out lending to private sector rather than affecting banks' holding of short term instruments. (6) the study also finds net foreign asset (mainly trade balance holdings of the banks very important in affecting banks' allocation of funds to choice portfolio so also is net other asset of the banks. (7) the study was not constrained by lack of theory but by lack of requisite data; therefore important issues such as the effect of size, the relation between the so-called foreign owned and indigenous banks were omitted in the study. Cette étude analyse les effets globaux sur la politique macroéconomique de la gestion du portefeuille des banques commerciales au Nigéria. On avance l'hypothèse que les entreprises maximisent l'utilité attendue de la richesse. La fonction de l'utilité est supposée log-normale et on maximise l'utilité attendue de la richesse sous contrainte budgétaire. Après l'analyse des résultats, on peut en tirer les conclusions suivantes: 1) les taux d'intérêt sont moins importants que le autres variables en ce qui concerne la gestion du portefeuille des banques même si l'influence des taux d'intérêt et du rendement du portefeuille des banques ne peut pas être négligé 2) le comportement des banques favorise plus la précaution que la spéculation 3) les banques préfèrent détenir les fonds disponibles en formes liquides plutôt que de les investir à plus long terme 4) en ce qui concerne les variables de politique économique on peut souligner que les réserves obligatoires sont plus importantes que les emprunts du secteur publique du secteur bancaire 5) les emprunts du secteur public influencent les prêts bancaires au secteur privé plus que d'autres variables: en d'autres termes on a pu en général constater que les emprunts du secteur public réduisent les prêts au secteur privé plutôt que d'affecter la quantité d'instruments monétaires à court terme dans le portefeuille des banques 6) un facteur significatif dans l'allocation des fonds aux différentes composantes du portefeuille est constitué par les activités nettes étrangères (principalement celles découlant de l'activité d'import-export) 7) l'étude a été limitée non par le manque de théories explicatives mais à cause de données insuffisantes. On a du dans cette analyse négliger des aspects importants tels que, par exemple, l'effet de la dimension, les rélations entre les banques nationales et étrangères, etc.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1382995e162a1310">
            <label>*</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1382995e169" publication-type="other">
Parkin 1969, 1970.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1382995e176a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1382995e183" publication-type="other">
Adekunle (1968);</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1382995e189" publication-type="other">
Wong (1977)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>Bibliography</title>
        <ref id="d1382995e205a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e212" publication-type="other">
Adekunle, J.O., (1968). The demand for money, evidence from developed and less developed countries.
IMF Staff Papers, vol. 15 No. 2 (July) pp. 220-265.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e222a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e229" publication-type="other">
Adewumi, Wole; (1982). Loan Management in Nigerian Banks: A Study of Efficiency of the Commercial Banks'
Lending Function in a Developing Economy; Unpublished Ph. D Thesis, University Wales, Bangor.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e239a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e246" publication-type="other">
Baltensperger, E. (1980). Alternative approaches to the theory of banking firm. Journal of Monetary Economics
Vol. 6, pp. 1-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e256a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e263" publication-type="other">
Borch, K; (1969). A note on uncertainty and indifference curves, Review of Economic Studies, Vol. 36 No.
1 (January) pp. 1 -4.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e274a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e281" publication-type="other">
Fakiyesi, Tayo; (1984). Money, Finance and Portfolio Behaviors of Commercial Banks in LDCs: An Econometric
Analysis of the Nigerian Case; Unpublished Ph. D Thesis, University of Strathdyde, Glasgow.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e291a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e298" publication-type="other">
Hart, O. D. and Jaffee, D. M.; (1 974). On the application of portfolio theory to depository financial intermediaries;
Review of Economic Studies, vol. 41 pp. 129-147.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e308a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e315" publication-type="other">
Jones-Lee, W. M.; (1971). Some portfolio adjustment theorems for the case of non-negativity constraints
on security holdings; Journal of Finance, (June), pp. 763-775.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e325a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e332" publication-type="other">
Markowitz, Harry (1959). Portfolio Selection. Cowles Foundation, Monograph 16; Yale University Press, New
Haven.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e342a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e349" publication-type="other">
Masih, A.M.M; (1978). Specification and estimation of the commercial bank equations in a developing
economy: The case of Pakistan; Nigerian Journal of Economic and Social Studies Vol.20 No.1 (March).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e359a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e366" publication-type="other">
Mordi, Charles (1986). Specification and estimation of demand and supply functions of commercial banks'
loans and advances in Nigeria, Economic and Financial Review of the Central Bank of Nigeria, Vol. 24,
No. 1 pp 32-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e380a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e387" publication-type="other">
Orr, D. and Mellon, W.G., (1961) Stochastic reserve losses and expansion of bank credit, American Economic
Review Vol. 51, pp 614-623.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e397a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e404" publication-type="other">
Parkin, M., (1970). Discount house portfolio and debt selection; Review of Economic Studies, vol. 37 (Oc-
tober) pp 469-498.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e414a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e421" publication-type="other">
Pringle, J. J. (1974). The Capital decision in commercial banks; Journal of Finance, (June), pp 779-795.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e428a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e435" publication-type="other">
Tobin, J. (1982). The commercial banking firm: a simple model; Scandinavian Journal of Economics, vol.
84. No. 4 pp 495-530.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e445a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e452" publication-type="other">
Wong, C., (1977). Demand for money in developing countries: some theoretical and empirical results. Jour-
nal of Monetary Economics, vol. 2, (January) pp. 55-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382995e462a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382995e469" publication-type="other">
Zellner, A., (1963). Estimators for seemingly unrelated regression equations: Some exact finite sample results;
Journal of the American Statistical Association, Vol. 58, pp. 977-992.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


