<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26562377</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Energy Consumption Test and Analysis Methodology for Heavy-Duty Vehicle Engine Accessories</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Zhong</surname>
                  <given-names>Liang</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Dongfeng Commercial Vehicle Technology Center, China</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>11</volume>
         <issue>5</issue>
         <issue-id>e26562374</issue-id>
         <fpage>539</fpage>
         <lpage>546</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26562377"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Fuel economy is a crucial parameter in long-haulage heavy-duty vehicles. Researchers tended to focus initially on engine combustion efficiency, while modern researchers turn their attention to the energy consumption of engine accessories in an attempt to enhance fuel economy. The accessories investigated in this study include the cooling fan, water pump, air compressor, power steering pump, air-conditioning (AC) compressor, and generator. Normally, accessory energy consumption analysis is based on rig data and simulation results. Here, we focus on the disparate test environments between the rig and vehicle to establish a novel constant power test method; the proposed method provides accurate accessory power data under different working conditions. A typical highway driving cycle is selected to collect accessory duty-cycle. The heavy-duty vehicle accessories’ energy consumption distribution under highway road conditions is obtained through the repeated road tests. Accessories comprise energy consumption proportions of 4.7%-6.4% of the engine in winter and 10.3%-12.6% in summer; they show different characteristics under different temperature or road conditions. The two influence factors of accessory energy consumption, constant power and duty-cycle, are analyzed to evaluate possible energy-saving schemes. Applying the clutch or electrical accessories, especially for the cooling fan and air compressor, is recommended.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label> 
            <kwd>Engine accessory</kwd> 
            <kwd>Energy consumption</kwd> 
            <kwd>Fuel economy</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE International Surface Vehicle Recommended Practice, “Information Relating to Duty Cycles and Average Power Requirements of Truck and Bus Engine Accessories,” SAE Standard J1343, Rev. Aug. 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE International Surface Vehicle Recommended Practice, “Test Method for Measuring Performance of Engine Cooling Fans,” SAE Standard J1339, Rev. Apr. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE International Surface Vehicle Recommended Practice, “Test Method for Measuring Power Consumption of Air Conditioning and Brake Compressors for Trucks and Buses,” SAE Standard J1340, Rev. Sept. 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE International Surface Vehicle Recommended Practice, “Hydraulic Power Pump Test Procedure,” SAE Standard J745, Rev. June 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE International Surface Vehicle Recommended Practice, “Test Method for Measuring Power Consumption of Hydraulic Pumps for Trucks and Buses,” SAE Standard J1341, Rev. Nov. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE International Surface Vehicle Recommended Practice, “Test Method for Determining Power Consumption of Engine Cooling Fan Drive Systems,” SAE Standard J1342, Rev. June 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hendricks, T. and O’Keefe, M., “Heavy Vehicle Auxiliary Load Electrification for the Essential Power System Program: Benefits, Tradeoffs, and Remaining Challenges,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-3135, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-3135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kluger, M. and Harris, J., “Fuel Economy Benefits of Electric and Hydraulic off Engine Accessories,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0268, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0268.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lutsey, N., Wallace, J., Brodrick, C., Dwyer, H. et al., “Modeling Stationary Power for Heavy-Duty Trucks: Engine Idling vs. Fuel Cell APUs,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01- 1479, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1479.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LaClair, T.J., “Application of a Tractive Energy Analysis to Quantify the Benefits of Advanced Efficiency Technologies for Medium- and Heavy-Duty Trucks Using Characteristic Drive Cycle Data,” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 5(1):141-163, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pettersson, N. and Johansson, K.H., “Modelling and Control of Auxiliary Loads in Heavy Vehicles,” International Journal of Control 79(5):479-495, 2006, doi:10.1080//00207170600587333.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gao, Z., Finney, C., Daw, C., LaClair, T.J. et al., “Comparative Study of Hybrid Powertrains on Fuel Saving, Emissions, and Component Energy Loss in HD Trucks,” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 7(2):414-431, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2326.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Almeida, F.L., Capana, G.H., Moraes, H.F.D., and Sokolowski, D., “Forward 1D Vehicle Dynamics Simulation Focused on Fuel Consumption Concerns with the Inclusion of the Complete Driveline and Accessory Load Influence,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-36-0247, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-36-0247.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, J., Oh, S., Joo, K., Yi, S. et al., “A Study of the Auxiliary Belt Drive System for Actual Fuel Saving,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-0898, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0898.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carlson, R.B., Wishart, J., and Stutenberg, K., “On-Road and Dynamometer Evaluation of Vehicle Auxiliary Loads,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 9(1):260-268, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0901.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lycke, J., “Simulation and Control of Auxiliary Devices in Heavy-Duty Vehicles,” Master’s thesis, KTH Electrical Engineering, Sweden, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pettersson, N. and Johansson, K.H., “Modelica Library for Simulating Energy Consumption of Auxiliary Units in Heavy Vehicles,” presented at the 3rd International Modelica Conference, Sweden, Nov. 3-4, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Redfield, J., Surampudi, B., Ray, G., and Montemayor, A., “Accessory Electrification in Class 8 Tractors,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0215, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
