<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">105</volume>
         <issue-id>i40198805</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44725584</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental Study for Construction of Microalgae Culturing System to Eliminate CO₂ and O₂ Regeneration in the Closed Air -Elimination of CO₂ and Regeneration of O₂ Using Microalgae Under Low CO₂ Concentration in Aeration Air</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Tadashi</given-names>
                  <surname>Adachi</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Akiko</given-names>
                  <surname>Miya</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Shin</given-names>
                  <surname>Taniguchi</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1996</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>906</fpage>
         <lpage>910</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1997 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44725584"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We have constructed a unit that uses microalgae to treat atmospheres containing low (i.e., (1000 ppm to 1%) concentrations of carbon dioxide. This experimental unit consists of a 20 I microalgae cultivation tank with eleven fluorescent lamps installed uniformly inside; and an analyzer with aeration/discharge, cultivation solutions supply/discharge function, and control capabilities. Using this unit, we conducted a series of experiments designed to reduce CO₂ concentration in air from about 1000 ppm to atmospheric levels, and to regenerate oxygen. We used Chlorella sorokiniana ATCC22521, a species of green algae, which is said to have a relatively high growth rate. We studied a number of necessary conditions. We performed a series of experiments under various cultivation temperature conditions. Although temperature had some influence on specific growth rate, its influence was negligible on the equipment's maximum CO₂ removal rate, as signified by represented an maximum cell growth or photosynthesis activity. We also performed a series of experiments under various pH conditions. We found that the CO₂ removal rate rose at a pH value which exceeded the optimum growth pH. However, we did not see any significant influence of pH on algae growth. These findings suggest that the CO₂ formation rate had a larger influence on the growth and photosynthetic activities of Chlorella sorokiniana ATCC22521 than other factors. Next, we conducted a series of experiments in which the oxygen concentration of the aeration gas was suppressed intermittently. When the oxygen concentration is suppressed, the equipment's CO₂ removal rate went up quickly. We observed this phenomenon in every step of cell growth. Moreover, even in conditions when we did not suppress oxygen concentration, CO₂ -removal performance was improved relative to when the oxygen concentration of the aeration gas was not suppressed at all. We believe several reasons explain this phenomenon: 1) Since oxygen, a product of photosynthesis, is effectively removed, photosynthesis activities rose. 2) Because cellular photo-respiration was controlled effectively, apparent photosynthetic activity rose. 3) Decreasing the cell toxicity inherent to oxygen improved cellular activity. Hence, in order to improve the performance of an atmospheric air-adjusting unit which uses microalgae in a low-CO₂ environment, it is important to control oxygen concentration. Moreover, control of oxygen concentration will likely enable the unit to be better controlled as well.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1205e211a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1205e218" publication-type="other">
Adachi, T., and Miya, Α., presented at the 24th
ICES, Friedrichshafen, 1994</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1205e228a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1205e235" publication-type="other">
Adachi, T., and Miya, Α., presented at the 5th
JAPANESE CELSS CONFERENCE, Rokkasho, Ja-
pan, 1995</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1205e248a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1205e255" publication-type="other">
Adachi, T., Miya, Α., and Taniguchi, S., presented
at the 61th Conference, SCEJ, Nagoya, Japan, 1996</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1205e265a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1205e272" publication-type="other">
Nishida, K., UP BIOLOGY, Vol.62, Japan, 1986</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


