<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277624</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Comparison of Negative Valve Overlap (NVO) and Rebreathing Valve Strategies on a Gasoline PPC Engine at Low Load and Idle Operating Conditions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Borgqvist</surname>
                  <given-names>Patrick</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tunestal</surname>
                  <given-names>Per</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johansson</surname>
                  <given-names>Bengt</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Lund University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277593</issue-id>
         <fpage>366</fpage>
         <lpage>378</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277624"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Gasoline partially premixed combustion (PPC) has the potential of high efficiency and simultaneous low soot and NOx emissions. Running the engine in PPC mode with high octane number fuels has the advantage of a longer premix period of fuel and air which reduces soot emissions. The problem is the ignitability at low load and idle operating conditions.</p>
            <p>In a previous study it was shown that it is possible to use NVO to improve combustion stability and combustion efficiency at operating conditions where available boosted air is assumed to be limited. NVO has the disadvantage of low net indicated efficiency due to heat losses from recompressions of the hot residual gases. An alternative to NVO is the rebreathing valve strategy where the exhaust valves are reopened during the intake stroke. The net indicated efficiency is expected to be higher with the rebreathing strategy but the question is if similar improvements in combustion stability can be achieved with rebreathing as with NVO.</p>
            <p>The results show that the rebreathing valve strategy has similar improvements on combustion stability as NVO when the same fuel injection strategy is used. This work also includes results with the NVO valve strategy where a fuel injection is added during the NVO. When a fuel injection is added during the NVO, an additional improvement on combustion stability can be seen which is unmatched by the rebreathing valve strategy.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Willand, J., Nieberding, R., Vent, G., and Enderle, C., “The Knocking Syndrome - Its Cure and Its Potential,” SAE Technical Paper 982483, 1998, doi:10.4271/982483.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lavy, J., Dabadie, J., Angelberger, C., Duret, P. et al., “Innovative Ultra-low NOx Controlled Auto-Ignition Combustion Process for Gasoline Engines: the 4-SPACE Project,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1837, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1837.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Ogawa, H., Muranaka, S. et al., “New Combustion Concept for Ultra-Clean and High-Efficiency Small DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3681, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3681.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akihama, K., Takatori, Y., Inagaki, K., Sasaki, S. et al., “Mechanism of the Smokeless Rich Diesel Combustion by Reducing Temperature,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0655, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yanigahara, H., Sato, Y., Minuta, J., “A simultaneous reduction in NOx and soot in diesel engines under a new combustion system (Uniform Bulky Combustion System - UNIBUS)”, 17th International Vienna Motor Symposium, pp 303-314, 1996</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hasegawa, R. and Yanagihara, H., “HCCI Combustion in DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0745, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-0745.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Risberg, P., and Ångström, H., “Advantages of Fuels with High Resistance to Auto-Ignition in Late-Injection, Low- Temperature, Compression Ignition Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3385, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3385.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Risberg, P., and Ångström, H., “Partially Pre-Mixed Auto-Ignition of Gasoline to Attain Low Smoke and Low NOx at High Load in a Compression Ignition Engine and Comparison with a Diesel Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0006, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johansson, B., “High-Load Partially Premixed Combustion in a Heavy- Duty Diesel Engine”, 2005 Diesel Engine Emissions Reduction (DEER) Conference Presentations August 21-25, 2005 Chicago, Illinois</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., T., Hildingsson, L., Johansson, B., “Low NOx and Low Smoke Operation of a Diesel Engine using Gasoline-like Fuels”, ICES2009-76034, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hildingsson, L., Kalghatgi, G., Tait, N., Johansson, B. et al., “Fuel Octane Effects in the Partially Premixed Combustion Regime in Compression Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2648, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2648.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., T., Hildingsson, L., Harrison, A., Johansson, B., “Low- NOx, low-smoke operation of a diesel engine using “premixed enough” compression ignition - Effects of fuel autoignition quality, volatility and aromatic content”, THISEL 2010 Conference on Thermo- and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Johansson, B., Tunestal, P., and Cannella, W., “Effects of Different Type of Gasoline Fuels on Heavy Duty Partially Premixed Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):71-88, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-2668.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Zander, C., Johansson, B., Tunestal, P. et al., “An Advanced Internal Combustion Engine Concept for Low Emissions and High Efficiency from Idle to Max Load Using Gasoline Partially Premixed Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2198, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-2198.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Johansson, B., Tunestal, P., Sonder, M., Serra, S., “Gasoline Partially Premixed Combustion: High Efficiency, Low NOx and Low Soot by using an Advanced Combustion Strategy and a Compression Ignition Engine”, FCE09, Istanbul Turkey, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sellnau, M., Sinnamon, J., Hoyer, K., and Husted, H., “Gasoline Direct Injection Compression Ignition (GDCI) - Diesel-like Efficiency with Low CO2 Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):2010-2022, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1386.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sellnau, M., Sinnamon, J., Hoyer, K., and Husted, H., “Full-Time Gasoline Direct-Injection Compression Ignition (GDCI) for High Efficiency and Low NOx and PM,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):300-314, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0384.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Experiments and Modeling of Dual-Fuel HCCI and PCCI Combustion Using In-Cylinder Fuel Blending,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):24-39, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-2647.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “An Experimental Investigation of Fuel Reactivity Controlled PCCI Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):700-716, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0864.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., Kaddatz, J. et al., “Fuel Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Combustion in Light- and Heavy-Duty Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):360-374, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Fuel Effects on Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Combustion at Low Load,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):394-411, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Curran, S., Wagner, R., Kokjohn, S. et al., “Piston Bowl Optimization for RCCI Combustion in a Light-Duty Multi-Cylinder Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):286-299, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0380.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Law, D., Kemp, D., Allen, J., Kirkpatrick, G. et al., “Controlled Combustion in an IC-Engine with a Fully Variable Valve Train,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0251, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0251.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koopmans, L. and Denbratt, I., “A Four Stroke Camless Engine, Operated in Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Mode with Commercial Gasoline,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3610, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-3610.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cao, L., Zhao, H., Jiang, X., and Kalian, N., “Effects of Intake Valve Timing on Premixed Gasoline Engine with CAI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2953, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2953.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johansson, T., Johansson, B., Tunestål, P., and Aulin, H., “The Effect of Intake Temperature in a Turbocharged Multi Cylinder Engine operating in HCCI mode,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):452-466, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2009-24-0060.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borgqvist, P., Tunestal, P., and Johansson, B., “Gasoline Partially Premixed Combustion in a Light Duty Engine at Low Load and Idle Operating Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0687, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0687.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borgqvist, P., Tuner, M., Mello, A., Tunestal, P. et al., “The Usefulness of Negative Valve Overlap for Gasoline Partially Premixed Combustion, PPC,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1578, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1578.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borgqvist, P., Andersson, Ö., Tunestål, P., Johansson, B., “The Low Load Limit of Gasoline Partially Premixed Combustion using Negative Valve Overlap,” ASME, ICEF2012-92069, 2012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lang, O., Salber, W., Hahn, J., Pischinger, S. et al., “Thermodynamical and Mechanical Approach Towards a Variable Valve Train for the Controlled Auto Ignition Combustion Process,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0762, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0762.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urushihara, T., Hiraya, K., Kakuhou, A., and Itoh, T., “Expansion of HCCI Operating Region by the Combination of Direct Fuel Injection, Negative Valve Overlap and Internal Fuel Reformation,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0749, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Trajkovic, S., Milosavljevic, A., Tunestål, P., and Johansson, B., “FPGA Controlled Pneumatic Variable Valve Actuation,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0041,, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0041.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rothamer, A., Snyder, J., Hanson, R., Steeper, R., Fitzgerald, R., “Simultaneous imaging of exhaust gas residuals and temperature during HCCI combustion”, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 32 (2009) 2869-2876</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BOSCH Automotive Handbook, 6th edition, page 663, ISBN 1-86058-474-8, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
