<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26562364</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Analysis of Regulated Pollutant Emissions and Aftertreatment Efficiency in a GTDi Engine Using Different SOI Strategies</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Bermúdez</surname>
                  <given-names>Vicente</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universitat Politècnica de València</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Luján</surname>
                  <given-names>José Manuel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universitat Politècnica de València</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Climent</surname>
                  <given-names>Hector</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universitat Politècnica de València</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Soto</surname>
                  <given-names>Lian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universitat Politècnica de València</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Campos</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>AVL List GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>11</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26562355</issue-id>
         <fpage>363</fpage>
         <lpage>382</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26562364"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>In order to improve performance and minimize pollutant emissions in gasoline turbocharged direct-injection (GTDi) engines, different injection strategies and technologies are being investigated. The inclusion of exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) and the variation of the start of injection (SOI) are some of these strategies that can influence the air-to-fuel (AF) mixture formation and consequently in the combustion process and pollutant emissions. This article presents a complete study of the engine performance, pollutant emissions and aftertreatment efficiency that produces the SOI variation with a fixed EGR rate in a 4-cylinder, turbocharged, gasoline direct-injection engine with 2.0 L displacement. The equipment used in this study are TSI-EEPS for particle measurement and HORIBA MEXA 1230-PM for soot measurement being HORIBA MEXA 7100-DEGR with a heated line selector the system employed for regulated gaseous emission measurement and aftertreatment evaluation. The experimental results confirm how the use of an adequate SOI strategy is indispensable to obtain low exhaust emissions values and a balance between the different pollutants. There was found a slight reduction in brake specific fuel consumption (BSFC) with the SOI advance. The experiments showed a decrease in CO, a non-sensible variation of THC and an increase in NOx emissions with SOI delay. Additionally, a significant increase in particle emissions was observed with early SOIs. Finally, with the SOI delay the aftertreatment performance revealed an increase in the oxidation of CO and a decrease in the reduction of NOx.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label> 
            <kwd>GTDi engine</kwd> 
            <kwd>SOI variation</kwd> 
            <kwd>Engine performance</kwd> 
            <kwd>gaseous emission</kwd> 
            <kwd>Soot emission</kwd> 
            <kwd>Particle size distribution</kwd> 
            <kwd>TWC efficiency</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oberdörster, G., Oberdörster, E., and Oberdörster, J., “Nanotoxicology: An Emerging Discipline Evolving from Studies of Ultrafine Particles,” Environmental Health Perspectives 113(9):823-839, 2005, doi:10.1289/ehp.7339.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davidson, C.I., Phalen, R.F., and Solomon, P.A., “Airborne Particulate Matter and Human Health: A Review,” Aerosol Science Technology 39(8):737-749, 2005, doi:10.1080/02786820500191348.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, X., Wang, Y., Xing, Z., and Du, K., “Emission Factors of Air Pollutants from CNG-Gasoline Bi-Fuel Vehicles: Part II. CO, HC and NOx,” Science Total Environment 565:698- 705, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.scitotenv.2016.05.069.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kemball-Cook, S., Yarwood, G., Johnson, J., Dornblaser, B. et al., “Evaluating NOx Emission Inventories for Regulatory Air Quality Modeling Using Satellite and Air Quality Model Data,” Atmospheric Environment 117:1-8, 2015, doi:10.1016/J. ATMOSENV.2015.07.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zong-Jie, L., Song, L.-L., Jing-Zhu, M., and Li, Y., “The Characteristics Changes of pH and EC of Atmospheric Precipitation and Analysis on the Source of Acid Rain in the Source Area of the Yangtze River from 2010 to 2015,” Atmospheric Environment 156:61-69, 2017, doi:10.1016/J. ATMOSENV.2017.02.025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mamakos, A., Martini, G., and Manfredi, U., “Assessment of the Legislated Particle Number Measurement Procedure for a Euro 5 and a Euro 6 Compliant Diesel Passenger Cars under Regulated and Unregulated Conditions,” Journal of Aerosol Science 55:31-47, 2013, doi:10.1016/J. JAEROSCI.2012.07.012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Najafi, G., Ghobadian, B., Tavakoli, T., Buttsworth, D.R. et al., “Performance and Exhaust Emissions of a Gasoline Engine with Ethanol Blended Gasoline Fuels Using Artificial Neural Network,” Applied Energy 86(5):630-639, 2009, doi:10.1016/J.APENERGY.2008.09.017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Banerjee, R. and Kumar, S., “Numerical Investigation of Stratified Air/Fuel Preparation in a GDI Engine,” Applied Thermal Energy 104:414-428, 2016, doi:10.1016/j. applthermaleng.2016.05.050.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bermúdez, V., Luján, J.M., Climent, H., and Campos, D., “Assessment of Pollutants Emission and Aftertreatment Efficiency in a GTDi Engine Including Cooled LP-EGR System under Different Steady-State Operating Conditions,” Applied Energy 158:459-473, 2015, doi:10.1016/j. apenergy.2015.08.071.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alkidas, A.C., “Combustion Advancements in Gasoline Engines,” Energy Conversation Management 48(11):2751- 2761, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2007.07.027.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liati, A., Schreiber, D., Dimopoulos Eggenschwiler, P. et al., “Electron Microscopic Characterization of Soot Particulate Matter Emitted by Modern Direct Injection Gasoline Engines,” Combustion Flame 166:307-315, 2016, doi:10.1016/j. combustflame.2016.01.031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaddam, C.K. and Vander Wal, R.L., “Physical and Chemical Characterization of SIDI Engine Particulates,” Combustion Flame 160(11):2517-2528, 2013, doi:10.1016/j. combustflame.2013.05.025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cavina, N., Businaro, A., Moro, D., Di Gioia, R. et al., “Assessment of the Influence of GDI Injection System Parameters on Soot Emission and Combustion Stability through a Numerical and Experimental Approach,” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(5):2078-2088, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-24-2422.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Subramaniam, M.N., Hayes, C., Tomazic, D., Downey, M. et al., “Pre-Turbo Aftertreatment Position for Large Bore Diesel Engines - Compact Cost-Effective Aftertreatment with a Fuel Consumption Advantage,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):2065-2079, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0299.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, J. and Mital, R., “Effect of DPF Design Parameters on Fuel Economy and Thermal Durability,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0847, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0847.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Twigg, M.V., “Progress and Future Challenges in Controlling Automotive Exhaust Gas Emissions,” Applied Catalysis B Environment 70(1-4):2-15, 2007, doi:10.1016/J. APCATB.2006.02.029.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brisiey, R.J., Collins, N.R., French, A.C., Morris, D. et al., “Advanced Platinum-Rhodium Exhaust Catalysts - An Economic Alternative to Palladium-Rhodium,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1418, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01- 1418.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heck, R.M. and Farrauto, R.J., “Automobile Exhaust Catalysts,” Applied Catalysis A Genetics 221(1):443-457, 2001, doi:10.1016/S0926-860X(01)00818-3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hasan, A.O., Abu-Jrai, A., Turner, D., Tsolakis, A. et al., “Control of Harmful Hydrocarbon Species in the Exhaust of Modern Advanced GDI Engines,” Atmospheric Environment 129:210-217, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.atmosenv.2016.01.033.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Poulopoulos, S.G., Samaras, D.P., and Philippopoulos, C.J., “Regulated and Speciated Hydrocarbon Emissions from a Catalyst Equipped Internal Combustion Engine,” Atmospheric Environment 35(26):4443-4450, 2001, doi:10.1016/S1352-2310(01)00231-X.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mueller, M.E., Blanquart, G., and Pitsch, H., “Hybrid Method of Moments for Modeling Soot Formation and Growth,” Combustion Flame 156(6):1143-1155, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2009.01.025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, B., Mosbach, S., Schmutzhard, S., Shuai, S. et al., “Modelling Soot Formation from Wall Films in a Gasoline Direct Injection Engine Using a Detailed Population Balance Model,” Applied Energy 163:154-166, 2016, doi:10.1016/j. apenergy.2015.11.011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Su, J., Xu, M., Yin, P., Gao, Y. et al., “Particle Number Emissions Reduction Using Multiple Injection Strategies in a Boosted Spark-Ignition Direct-Injection (SIDI) Gasoline Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(1):20-29, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2845.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Price, P., Twiney, B., Stone, R., Kar, K. et al., “Particulate and Hydrocarbon Emissions from a Spray Guided Direct Injection Spark Ignition Engine with Oxygenate Fuel Blends,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0472, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0472.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stojkovic, B.D., Fansler, T.D., Drake, M.C., and Sick, V., “High-Speed Imaging of OH* and Soot Temperature and Concentration in a Stratified-Charge Direct-Injection Gasoline Engine,” Proceedings of Combustion Institute 30(2):2657-2665, 2005, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2004.08.021.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berndorfer, A., Breuer, S., Piock, W., and Von Bacho, P., “Diffusion Combustion Phenomena in GDi Engines Caused by Injection Process,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0261, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei, H., Zhu, T., Shu, G., Tan, L. et al., “Gasoline Engine Exhaust Gas Recirculation - A Review,” Applied Energy 99:534-544, 2012, doi:10.1016/J.APENERGY.2012.05.011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hedge, M., Weber, P., Gingrich, J., Alger, T. et al., “Effect of EGR on Particle Emissions from a GDI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):650-666, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0636.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wheeler, J., Polovina, D., Ramanathan, S., Roth, K. et al., “Increasing EGR Tolerance using High Tumble in a Modern GTDI Engine for Improved Low-Speed Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1123, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1123.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gu, X., Huang, Z., Cai, J., Gong, J. et al., “Emission Characteristics of a Spark-Ignition Engine Fuelled with Gasoline-N-Butanol Blends in Combination with EGR,” Fuel 93:611-617, 2012, doi:10.1016/J.FUEL.2011.11.040.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galloni, E., Fontana, G., and Palmaccio, R., “Effects of Exhaust Gas Recycle in a Downsized Gasoline Engine,” Applied Energy 105:99-107, 2013, doi:10.1016/J. APENERGY.2012.12.046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, C., Xu, H., Herreros, J.M., Wang, J. et al., “Impact of Fuel and Injection System on Particle Emissions from a GDI Engine,” Applied Energy 132:178-191, 2014, doi:10.1016/j. apenergy.2014.06.012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boccardi, S., Catapano, F., Costa, M., Sementa, P. et al., “Optimization of a GDI Engine Operation in the Absence of Knocking through Numerical 1D and 3D Modeling,” Advances in Engineering Software 95:38-50, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.advengsoft.2016.01.023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Costa, M., Sorge, U., and Allocca, L., “Increasing Energy Efficiency of a Gasoline Direct Injection Engine through Optimal Synchronization of Single or Double Injection Strategies,” Energy Conversion and Management 60:77-86, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2011.12.025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, Y., Zhao, H., Brouzos, N., Ma, T. et al., “Effect of Injection Timing on Mixture and CAI Combustion in a GDI Engine with an Air-Assisted Injector,” SAE Technical Paper 2006- 01-0206, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Price, P., Stone, R., Collier, T., and Davies, M., “Particulate Matter and Hydrocarbon Emissions Measurements: Comparing First and Second Generation DISI with PFI in Single Cylinder Optical Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1263, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bonatesta, F., Chiappetta, E., and La Rocca, A., “Part-Load Particulate Matter from a GDI Engine and the Connection with Combustion Characteristics,” Applied Energy 124:366- 376, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2014.03.030.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, Z., Tian, X., and Zhang, X., “Effects of Split Injection Proportion and the Second Injection Time on the Mixture Formation in a GDI Engine under Catalyst Heating Mode Using Stratified Charge Strategy,” Applied Thermal Engineering 84:237-245, 2015, doi:10.1016/J. APPLTHERMALENG.2015.03.041.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roth, D.B., Keller, P., and Becker, M., “Requirements of External EGR Systems for Dual Cam Phaser Turbo GDI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0588, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0588.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“EUR-Lex - 32016L0802 - EN - EUR-Lex.” EUR-Lex. 2016, http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?qid=152629 5324843&amp;uri=CELEX:32016L0802.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montajir, R.M., Kusaka, T., Bamba, Y., and Adachi, M., “A New Concept for Real-Time Measurement of Particulate Matter (Soot and SOF),” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3605, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3605.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bermúdez, V., Pastor, J.V., López, J.J., and Campos, D., “Experimental Correlations for Transient Soot Measurement in Diesel Exhaust Aerosol with Light Extinction, Electrical Mobility and Diffusion Charger Sensor Techniques,” Measurment Science and Technology 25(6):065204, 2014, doi:10.1088/0957-0233/25/6/065204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, D., Gautam, M., and Gera, D., “Parametric Studies on the Formation of Diesel Particulate Matter Via Nucleation and Coagulation Modes,” Journal of Aerosol Science 33(12):1609-1621, 2002, doi:10.1016/S0021- 8502(02)00119-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J.M., Bermúdez, V., Molina, S., and Linares, W.G., “Methodology for Measuring Exhaust Aerosol Size Distributions Using an Engine Test under Transient Operating Conditions,” Measurement Science and Technology 22(11):115101, 2011, doi:10.1088/0957- 0233/22/11/115101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittelson, D.B., Watts, W.F., Johnson, J.P., Schauer, J.J. et al., “On-Road and Laboratory Evaluation of Combustion Aerosols-Part 2: Summary of Spark Ignition Engine Results,” Journal of Aerosol Science 37(8):931-949, 2006, doi:10.1016/J. JAEROSCI.2005.08.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J.M., Bermúdez, V., Molina, S., and Linares, W.G., “Methodology for Measuring Exhaust Aerosol Size Distributions Using an Engine Test under Transient Operating Conditions,” Measurement Science and Technology 22(11):115101, 2011, doi:10.1088/0957- 0233/22/11/115101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seinfeld, J.H., Pandis, S., and Noone, K., Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics: From Air Pollution to Climate Change 2nd Edition (Hoboken: John Wiley &amp; Sons Inc, 2006).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kumar, P., Fennell, P., and Britter, R., “Effect of Wind Direction and Speed on the Dispersion of Nucleation and Accumulation Mode Particles in an Urban Street Canyon,” Science Total Environment 402(1):82-94, 2008, doi:10.1016/j. scitotenv.2008.04.032.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J.M., Bermúdez, V., Pastor, J.V., and Fuentes, E., “Investigation of the Influence of Post-Injection on Diesel Exhaust Aerosol Particle Size Distributions,” Aerosol Science Technology 40(1):80-96, 2006, doi:10.1080/02786820500466583.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haynes, B.S. and Wagner, H.G., “Soot Formation,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 7(4):229-273, 1981, doi:10.1016/0360-1285(81)90001-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">RÖnkkÖ, T., Virtanen, A., Kannosto, J., and Keskinen, J., “Nucleation Mode Particles with a Nonvolatile Core in the Exhaust of a Heavy Duty Diesel Vehicle,” Environmental Science Technology 41:6384-6389, 2007, doi:10.1021/ES0705339.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittelson, D.B., “Engines and Nanoparticles: A Review,” Journal of Aerosol Science 29(5):575-588, 1998, doi:10.1016/S0021-8502(97)10037-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lapuerta, M., Armas, O., and Gómez, A., “Diesel Particle Size Distribution Estimation from Digital Image Analysis,” Aerosol Science Technology 37(4):369-381, 2003, doi:10.1080/02786820300970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>54.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Luján, J.M., Climent, H., Novella, R., and Rivas-Perea, M.E., “Influence of a Low Pressure EGR Loop on a Gasoline Turbocharged Direct Injection Engine,” Applied Thermal Engineering 89:432-443, 2015, doi:10.1016/j. applthermaleng.2015.06.039.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>55.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rodriguez, J.F. and Cheng, W.K., “Effect of Operation Strategy on First Cycle CO, HC, and PM/PN Emissions in a GDI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(3):1098-1106, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0887.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>56.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Martín, J., Novella, R., and Thein, K., “Understanding the Performance of the Multiple Injection Gasoline Partially Premixed Combustion Concept Implemented in a 2-Stroke High Speed Direct Injection Compression Ignition Engine,” Applied Energy 161:465-475, 2016, doi:10.1016/J.APENERGY.2015.10.034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>57.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beavis, N.J., Ibrahim, S.S., and Malalasekera, W., “Impingement Characteristics of an Early Injection Gasoline Direct Injection Engine: A Numerical Study,” International Journal of Engine Research 18(4):378-393, 2017, doi:10.1177/1468087416663325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>58.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hennessey, R., Fuentes, A., and Wicker, R., “Effect of Injection Timing on Piston Surface Fuel Impingement and Vaporization in Direct Injection Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-2025, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-2025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>59.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arsie, I., Di Iorio, S., and Vaccaro, S., “Experimental Investigation of the Effects of AFR, Spark Advance and EGR on Nanoparticle Emissions in a PFI SI Engine,” Journal of Aerosol Science 64:1-10, 2013, doi:10.1016/j. jaerosci.2013.05.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>60.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Basshuysen, R. and Spicher, U., Gasoline Engine with Direct Injection: Processes, Systems, Development, Potential 1st Edition (Weisbaden: Vieweg + Teubner, 2009).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <label>61.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ma, F., Wang, Y., Wang, J., Ding, S. et al., “Effects of Combustion Phasing, Combustion Duration, and their Cyclic Variations on Spark-Ignition (SI) Engine Efficiency,” Energy &amp; Fuels 22(5):3022-3028, 2008, doi:10.1021/ef8003027.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <label>62.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murić, K., Stenlåås, O., and Tunestål, P., “Zero-Dimensional Modeling of NOx Formation with Least Squares Interpolation,” International Journal of Engine Research 15(8):944-953, 2014, doi:10.1177/1468087413495843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <label>63.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ozsezen, A.N. and Canakci, M., “Performance and Combustion Characteristics of Alcohol-Gasoline Blends at Wide-Open Throttle,” Energy 36(5):2747-2752, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2011.02.014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <label>64.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ozsezen, A., Turkcan, A., Sayin, C., and Canakci, M., “Comparison of Performance and Combustion Parameters in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine Fueled with Iso-Butanol/Diesel Fuel Blends,” Energy, Exploration and Exploitation 29(5):525-541, 2011, doi:10.1260/0144-5987.29.5.525.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <label>65.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Costa, M., Marchitto, L., Merola, S.S., and Sorge, U., “Study of Mixture Formation and Early Flame Development in a Research GDI (Gasoline Direct Injection) Engine through Numerical Simulation and UV-Digital Imaging,” Energy 77:88-96, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2014.04.114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <label>66.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Reuss, D., “NOx -Reduction by Injection- Timing Retard in a Stratified-Charge DISI Engine Using Gasoline and E85,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(3):1096-1113, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1643.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <label>67.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, C., Lee, S., and Yi, U., “Effects of Engine Operating Conditions on Particle Emissions of Lean-Burn Gasoline Direct-Injection Engine,” Energy 115:1148-1155, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2016.09.051.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <label>68.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kayes, D. and Hochgreb, S., “Mechanisms of Particulate Matter Formation in Spark-Ignition Engines. 2. Effect of Fuel, Oil, and Catalyst Parameters,” Environmental Science and Technology 33(22):3968-3977, 1999, doi:10.1021/ES981100W.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <label>69.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J.M., Bermúdez, V., García, A., and Linares, W.G., “A Comprehensive Study of Particle Size Distributions with the Use of Post Injection Strategies in DI Diesel Engines,” Aerosol Science Technology 45(10):1161-1175, 2011, doi:10.108 0/02786826.2011.582898.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <label>70.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bogarra, M., Herreros, J.M., Tsolakis, A., Rodríguez- Fernández, J. et al., “Gasoline Direct Injection Engine Soot Oxidation: Fundamentals and Determination of Kinetic Parameters,” Combustion and Flame 190:177-187, 2018, doi:10.1016/J.COMBUSTFLAME.2017.11.027.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref71">
            <label>71.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xing, J., Shao, L., Zheng, R., Peng, J. et al., “Individual Particles Emitted from Gasoline Engines: Impact of Engine Types, Engine Loads and Fuel Components,” Journal of Cleaner Products 149:461-471, 2017, doi:10.1016/J. JCLEPRO.2017.02.056.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref72">
            <label>72.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hasan, A.O., Abu-Jrai, A., Al-Muhtaseb, A.H., Tsolakis, A. et al., “HC, CO and NOx Emissions Reduction Efficiency of a Prototype Catalyst in Gasoline Bi-Mode SI/HCCI Engine,” Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering 4(2):2410-2416, 2016, doi:10.1016/j. jece.2016.04.015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref73">
            <label>73.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shamim, T., “The Effect of Space Velocity on the Dynamic Characteristics of an Automotive Catalytic Converter,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2160, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2160.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref74">
            <label>74.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alger, T., Gingrich, J., Khalek, I.A., and Mangold, B., “The Role of EGR in PM Emissions from Gasoline Engines,” SAE Int J Fuels Lubr. 3(1):85-98, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0353.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref75">
            <label>75.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontana, G. and Galloni, E., “Experimental Analysis of a Spark-Ignition Engine Using Exhaust Gas Recycle at WOT Operation,” Applied Energy 87(7):2187-2193, 2010, doi:10.1016/J.APENERGY.2009.11.022.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref76">
            <label>76.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galloni, E., Fontana, G., and Palmaccio, R., “Effects of Exhaust Gas Recycle in a Downsized Gasoline Engine,” Applied Energy 105:99-107, 2013, doi:10.1016/J. APENERGY.2012.12.046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref77">
            <label>77.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blank, H., Dismon, H., Kochs, M.W., Sanders, M. et al., “EGR and Air Management for Direct Injection Gasoline Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0707, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0707.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref78">
            <label>78.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Potteau, S., Lutz, P., Leroux, S., Moroz, S. et al., “Cooled EGR for a Turbo SI Engine to Reduce Knocking and Fuel Consumption,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-3978, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-3978.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref79">
            <label>79.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gu, X., Huang, Z., Cai, J., Gong, J. et al., “Emission Characteristics of a Spark-Ignition Engine Fuelled with Gasoline-N-Butanol Blends in Combination with EGR,” Fuel 93:611-617, 2012, doi:10.1016/J.FUEL.2011.11.040.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref80">
            <label>80.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maricq, M.M., Szente, J.J., and Jahr, K., “The Impact of Ethanol Fuel Blends on PM Emissions from a Light-Duty GDI Vehicle,” Aerosol Science Technology 46(5):576-583, 2012, doi:10.1080/02786826.2011.648780.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref81">
            <label>81.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kumar, P., Morawska, L., Birmili, W., Paasonen, P. et al., “Ultrafine Particles in Cities,” Environmental Institute 66:1- 10, 2014, doi:10.1016/J.ENVINT.2014.01.013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref82">
            <label>82.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kulmala, M., Asmi, A., Lappalainen, H.K., Baltensperger, U. et al., “General Overview: European Integrated Project on Aerosol Cloud Climate and Air Quality Interactions (EUCAARI) Integrating Aerosol Research from Nano to Global Scales,” Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics 11(24):13061-13143, 2011, doi:10.5194/acp-11-13061-2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref83">
            <label>83.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, S., Jeon, J., and Park, S., “Optimization of Combustion Chamber Geometry and Operating Conditions for Compression Ignition Engine Fueled with Pre-Blended Gasoline-Diesel Fuel,” Energy Conversion and Management 126:638-648, 2016, doi:10.1016/J. ENCONMAN.2016.08.046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref84">
            <label>84.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Nieuwstadt, M. and Ulrey, J., “Control Strategies for Gasoline Particulate Filters,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01- 0931, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref85">
            <label>85.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mizuno, T. and Suzuki, J., “Development of a New DPNR Catalyst,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0578, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0578.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref86">
            <label>86.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Whelan, I., Samuel, S., and Hassaneen, A., “Investigation into the Role of Catalytic Converters on Tailpipe-Out Nano- Scale Particulate Matter from Gasoline Direct Injection Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1572, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1572.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref87">
            <label>87.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Whelan, I., Timoney, D., Smith, W., and Samuel, S., “The Effect of a Three-Way Catalytic Converter on Particulate Matter from a Gasoline Direct-Injection Engine During Cold-Start,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):1035-1045, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1305.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
