<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277738</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>3D-CFD Virtual Engine Test Bench of a 1.6 Liter Turbo-Charged GDI-Race-Engine with Focus on Fuel Injection</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chiodi</surname>
                  <given-names>Marco</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FKFS</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Perrone</surname>
                  <given-names>Antonella</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FKFS</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Roberti</surname>
                  <given-names>Paolo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FKFS</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bargende</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FKFS</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ferrari</surname>
                  <given-names>Alessandro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>VW-Motorsport</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wichelhaus</surname>
                  <given-names>Donatus</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>VW-Motorsport</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>September 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277710</issue-id>
         <fpage>1834</fpage>
         <lpage>1845</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277738"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In the last years motorsport is facing a technical revolution concerning the engine technology in every category, from touring car championships up to the F1. The strategy of the car manufacturers to bring motorsport engine technology closer to mass production one (e.g. turbo-charging, downsizing and direct injection) allows both to reduce development costs and to create a better image and technology transfer by linking motorsport activities to the daily business.</p>
            <p>Under these requirements the so-called Global Race Engine (GRE) concept has been introduced, giving the possibility to use one unique engine platform concept as basis for different engine specifications and racing categories.</p>
            <p>In order to optimize the performance of this kind of engines, especially due to the highly complex mixture formation mechanisms related to the direct injection, it is nowadays mandatory to resort to reliable 3D-CFD simulations.</p>
            <p>In this paper the contribution of intensive CFD simulations within the engine development process will be shown, in particular some issues regarding the injection modeling and its influence on the prediction of the mixture formation, the combustion and the global engine performance will be analyzed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grill, M., Billinger, T., and Bargende, M., “Quasi- Dimensional Modeling of Spark Ignition Engine Combustion with Variable Valve Train,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1107, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-1107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chiodi M.: “An innovative 3D-CFD-Approach towards Virtual Development of Internal Combustion Engines”. Dissertation, Universität Stuttgart, June 2010. Vieweg+TeubnerVerlag 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”. McGraw- Hill International Editions, New York, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferrari G.: “Motori a Combustone Interna”. Edizioni “Il Capitello”, 2001, Torino</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jochmann, P., Köpple, F., Storch, A., Kufferath, A., Durst, B., Hußmann, B., Miklautschitsch, M., Schünemann, E.: “Minimizing the Particulate Emission of Gasoline Direct Injection Engines with central mounting Injector position through Innovative Injection Technologies and the Integrated Use of CFD and Engine Tests”, X International Symposium on Combustion Diagnostics, 22 - 23 May 2012, Baden- Baden</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N.N.: “Star-CD User Manual version 3.15”, Computational Dynamics Ltd., London, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R. and Diwakar, R., “Effect of Drop Breakup on Fuel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 860469, 1986, doi:10.4271/860469.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bai, C. and Gosman, A., “Development of Methodology for Spray Impingement Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 950283, 1995, doi: 10.4271/950283.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wentsch, M., Chiodi, M., Bargende, M., Wichelhaus, D., Brandt v. Fackh, J.: “3D-CFD-Modeling of Multi- Component Liquid Gasoline for an improved Analysis of In-Cylinder Internal Engine Phenomena”, JSAE Annual Congress, 22 - 24 May 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serras-Pereira, J., van Romunde, Z., Aleiferis, P.G., Richardson, D., Wallace, S., Cracknell, R.F., (2010) “Cavitation, primary break-up and flash boiling of gasoline, iso-octane and n-pentane with a real-size optical direct-injection nozzle”, FUEL, 89 (9) 2592-2607</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dirke, Von M., Krautter, A., Ostertag, J., Mennicken, M., Badock, C., “Simulation of Cavitating Flows in Diesel Injectors”, Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology, pp. 223-226, Vol.54, No.2, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmidt, D.P., “Cavitation in Diesel Fuel Injector Nozzles”, from PhD Thesis, University of Wisconsin, Madison, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zuelch, C., Kulzer, A., Chiodi, M., and Bargende, M., “The Directstart: Investigation of Mixture Formation by Means of Optical Measurements and 3D-CFD- Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3686, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3686.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Falfari, S.: “Sviluppo di metodologie per la simulazione di iniettori ad alta pressione e ad alta velocità di attuazione”, from PhD Thesis, Dottorato in Ingegneria delle Macchine e dei Sistemi Energetici XV ciclo, Dipartimento di Ingegneria delle Costruzioni Meccaniche, Nucleari, Aeronautiche e di Metallurgia, Università degli Studi di Bologna</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
