<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308257</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Potential of Enhanced HCCI / CAI Control Through the Application of Spray Guided Direct Injection</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Brewster</surname>
                  <given-names>Simon</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cathcart</surname>
                  <given-names>Geoffrey</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zavier</surname>
                  <given-names>Christian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Orbital Corporation Ltd.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>13</fpage>
         <lpage>26</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308257"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In the current study a single cylinder Spark Ignited engine has been operated in Controlled Auto Ignition mode with centrally mounted spray guided direct injection, employing negative valve overlap to achieve the conditions required for auto-ignition. The injector is a type known in the market and utilises air at elevated pressure to assist preparation of the fuel and delivery of the fuel spray into the combustion chamber. Operation of the injector enables a high degree of control for fuel and air delivery, particularly with regard to stratification of fuel, temperature, air and turbulence within the chamber.</p>
            <p>Engine test data show that variation in injection parameters at a fixed engine condition yields high authority over the CAI combustion process. A range of combustion phasing is achieved from 355 to 375 degrees ATDC for the timing of 50% Mass Fraction Burned, whilst the range of maximum pressure rise rate is 70 to 450 kPa / degree. The application of these injection strategies to load range extension enables a Net IMEP of 100 to 700 kPa at an engine speed of 2000 rpm whilst observing a maximum pressure rise rate of 300 kPa / degree.</p>
            <p>The ability to vary injection parameters on an individual cylinder and per-cycle basis, coupled with the high authority of this injection system over CAI combustion, indicates a clear potential to address the key issues of CAI operation in a dual-mode SI engine.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chernoby, M., Hermance, D.W., Moulton, J., Oge, .T., Smyth, J.G. and Botti, J.J.M.: “Hybrids vs. iesel vs. Modified Gasoline, The Near Term - Is It ime for a Reality Check?”, Panel Discussion, SAE orld Congress, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Onishi, S., Hong Jo, S., Shoda, K., Do Jo, P. and ato, S.: ”Active Thermo-Atmosphere Combustion (ATAC) – A New Combustion Process for Internal ombustion Engines”, SAE 790501, 1979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noguchi, M., Tanaka, Y., Tanaka, T. and Takeuchi, .: ”A Study on Gasoline Engine Combustion by bservation of Intermediate Reactive Products uring Combustion”, SAE 790840, 1979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Najt, P. and Foster, D.E.: ”Compression-Ignited omogeneous Charge Combustion”, SAE 830264, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thring, R. H., ”Homogeneous-Charge Compression- gnition (HCCI) Engines”, SAE 892068, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aoyama, T., Hattori, Y., Mizuta, J. and Sato, Y.: “An xperimental Study on Premixed-Charge ompression Ignition Gasoline Engine”, SAE 960081, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lavy, J., Dabadie, J.C., Angelberger, C., Duret, P., illand, J., Juretzka, A., Schaflein, J., Ma, T., endresse, Y., Satre, A., Schulz, C., Kramer, H., hao, H. and Damiano, L.: “Innovative Ultra-low NOx ontrolled Auto-Ignition Combustion Process for asoline Engines: the 4-SPACE Project”, SAE 2000-01-1837, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koopmans, L.: “HCCI Combustion by Retaining esiduals”, Thesis for Degree of Doctor of hilosophy, ISBN 91-7291-560-9, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, H.: “CHARGE and CHASE – The UK ORESIGHT VEHICLE Research on Extending CCI Engine Operating Boundaries”, HCCI ymposium, Lund, Sweden, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B.: “Internal Combustion Engine undamentals”, McGraw-Hill Book Company, ISBN 0-07-100499-8, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamaoka, S., Kakuya, H., Nakagawa, S., Okada, T., himada, A. and Kihara, Y.: “HCCI Operation ontrol in a Multi-Cylinder Gasoline Engine”, SAE 2005-01-0120, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J-O., Tunestal, P. and Johansson, B.: ”Closed-Loop Control of an HCCI Engine”, SAE 2001-01-1031, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brand, D., Onder, C. H. and Guzzella, L.: “Estimation of the Instantaneous In-Cylinder ressure for Control Purposes Using Crankshaft ngular Velocity”, SAE 2005-01-0228, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fuerhapter, A., Piock, W.F. and Fraidl, G.K.: “CSI – ontrolled Auto Ignition – the Best Solution for the uel Consumption Versus Emission Trade-Off?”, AE 2003-01-0754, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Larsson, S. and Andersson, I. K.: “An Experimental valuation of Torque Sensor-Based Feedback ontrol of Combustion Phasing in An SI Engine”, AE 2005-01-0060, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner, M., Böhme, J. F. and Förster, J.: “ In- ylinder Pressure Estimation from Structure-Borne ound”, SAE 2000-01-0930, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wilhelmsson, C., Tunestal, P. and Johansson, B.: “FPGA Based Engine Feedback Control Algorithms”, ISITA F2006P039, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schten, K., Ripley, G., Punater, A. and Erickson, C.: “Design of an Automotive Grade Controller for In- ylinder Pressure Based Engine Control evelopment”, SAE 2007-01-0774, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gerdes, C.: “Controlling HCCI with Physically-Based odels”, HCCI Symposium, Lund, Sweden, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tunestal, P.: “Closed-Loop Combustion Control ctivities in Lund”, HCCI Symposium, Lund, weden, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Milovanovic, N., Blundell, D., Pearson, R., Turner, J. nd Chen, R.: “Enlarging the Operational Range of a asoline HCCI Engine By Controlling the Coolant emperature”, SAE 2005-01-0157, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Milovanovic, N., Blundell, D., Turner, J. and Gedge, .: “Cam Profile Switching (CPS) and Phasing trategy vs Fully Variable Valve Train (FVVT) trategy for Transitions between Spark Ignition and ontrolled Auto Ignition Modes”, SAE 2005-01-0766, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stokes, J., Lake, T., Murphy, R., Osborne, R., atterson, J. and Seabrook, J.: “Gasoline Engine peration With Twin Mechanical Variable Lift (Tmvl) alvetrain-Stage 1: Si and Cai Combustion With Port uel Injection”, SAE 2005-01-0752, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, Y., Zhao, H., Brouzos, N. and Ma, T.: “Parametric tudy on CAI Combustion in a GDI Engine with an ir-Assisted Injector”, SAE 2007-01-0196, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaynor, J. A., Fleck, R., Kenny, R. G., Kee, R. J. nd Cathcart, G.: “An Investigation of Air-Assist njection Timings and Durations in a GDI CAI ngine”, JSAE 20077136, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cathcart, G. and Zavier, C.: “Fundamental haracteristics of an Air-Assisted Direct Injection ombustion System as Applied to 4 Stroke utomotive Gasoline Engines”, SAE 2000-01-0256, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Funaioli, A. E., Achleitner, E. and Baecker, H.: “Direct Injection Systems for Otto Engines”, SAE 2007-01-1416, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rassweiler, G.M. and Withrow, L.: “Motion Pictures f Engine Flames Correlated with Pressure Cards”. AE Journal (Trans), Vol. 42, pg. 185-204, May 1938. (Landmark Reprint paper, SAE 800131).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barber, T., “MFB Calculation”, Orbital Internal eport, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sellnau, M. C. and Matekunas, F. A.: “Cylinder- ressure-Based Engine Control Using Pressure- atio-Management and Low-Cost Non-Intrusive ylinder Pressure Sensors”, SAE 2000-01-0932, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
