<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>"Giordano dell'Amore" Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2</issue>
         <issue-id>i23026299</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23026301</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>INTEREST RATES, AND THE SAVING-INVESTMENT PROCESS IN BOTSWANA (*)</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>T.C.</given-names>
                  <surname>Matsheka</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1998</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>5</fpage>
         <lpage>23</lpage>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23026301"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper discusses interest rate policy in Botswana, and tests the impact of interest rates on savings and investment in Botswana. The study uses three measures of saving: total domestic saving; private saving; and financial saving. We find that high interest rates affect none of the types of saving positively. Instead, income emerges as the most important determinant of saving, however defined. With regard to the determinants of domestic investment the study identifies private sector credit as the important variable in the investment function. It is the conclusion of this paper that emphasis be placed on the promotion of investment given that saving is explicable only by past development (Schumpeter, 1961). The level of output and employment depend on investment, which in turn, depends on finance and business expectations (Asimakopulos, 1986; Davidson 1986; Chick, 1987). L'auteur analyse les politiques des taux d'intérêt au Botswana et l'impact des taux sur l'épargne et l'investissement en utilisant trois mesures de l'épargne: l'épargne intérieure totale, l'épargne privée et l'épargne financière. On a observé que les taux d'intérêt élevés n'influent positivement sur aucun des types d'épargne considerés, tandis qu'il résulte que le déterminant le plus important de toute forme d'épagne semble être le revenu. En ce qui concerne les déterminants de l'épargne des ménages, l'étude a identifié le crédit au secteur privé comme la variable la plus importante dans la fonction de l'investissement. La conclusion de cet étude est, donc, qu'il faut mettre l'accent sur la promotion des investissements puisque l'épargne s'explique seulement comme résultat du developpement préalable. Les niveaux de la production et de l'emploi dependent de l'investissement qui à son tour depend des attentes dans le domaine économique et financier.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d624e110a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d624e117" publication-type="other">
Seek and EL. Nil (1993)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d624e123" publication-type="other">
SAPs(p.1878).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d624e130a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d624e137" publication-type="other">
World Tables (Worl Bank, 1995)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d624e144a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d624e151" publication-type="other">
Seek and EL. Nil, 1993</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d624e157" publication-type="other">
Khatkhate, 1988</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d624e163" publication-type="other">
World Bank, 1989</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d624e170a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d624e177" publication-type="other">
Seek and EL.Nil, 1993</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d624e183" publication-type="other">
Kariuki, 1996</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d624e199a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e203" publication-type="other">
Arrieta, G., Interest Rates, Savings and Growth in LDCs: An Assessment of Empirical Research, World
Development, Vol 16, No 5, 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e213a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e217" publication-type="other">
Asimakopulos, A., Keynes and Kaleckion Finance, Investment and Saving, Cambridge Journal of Economics,
Vol 7, 1983.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e227a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e231" publication-type="other">
Bank of Botswana-Annual Reports for the various years.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e238a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e242" publication-type="other">
Chick, V., Saving and Finance, in The New Pelgrave: A Dictionary of Economics, Eatwell J, MilgateM, Newman,
P., (editors).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e253a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e257" publication-type="other">
DeGregorio, J. And P.E. Guidotti, Financial Development and Economic Growth, World Development, Vol 23,
No 3, 1995.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e267a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e271" publication-type="other">
Boskin, M.J., Taxation, Saving and the Interest Rate, Journal of Political Economy, Vol 86, No 2, 1978.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e278a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e282" publication-type="other">
Buckett, P. and Dutt, A. K., Interest Rate Policy, Effective Demand and Growth in LDCs, International Review
of Applied Economic, Vol 5, No 2, 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e292a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e296" publication-type="other">
Davidson, P., Finance, Funding, Saving and Investment, Journal of Post Keynesian Economics, Vol IX, 1986.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e303a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e307" publication-type="other">
Dornbusch, R., Policies to move from Stabilisation to Growth, Proceedings of the World Bank Conference on
Development Economics, World Bank, Washington D.C., 1990.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e317a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e321" publication-type="other">
Gibson, H. and Tsakoiotos, E., The Scope and Limits of Financial Liberalisation in Developing Countries,
Journal of Development Studies, Vol 30, No 3, 1994.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e332a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e336" publication-type="other">
Giovannini, A., Saving and the Real Interest Rate in LDC's, Journal of Development Economics, Vol 18,1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e343a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e347" publication-type="other">
Fry, M., Money and Capital or Financial Deepening in Economic Development, Journal of Money, Credit and
Banking, Vol 10, No 4, 1978.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e357a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e361" publication-type="other">
Fry, M., Savinqs, Investment, and Growth and the Cost of Financial Repression, World Development, Vol 8,
No 7, 1980.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e371a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e375" publication-type="other">
Fry, M., Models of Financially Repressed Economies, World Development, Vol 10, No 9,1982.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e382a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e386" publication-type="other">
Fry, M., Money Interest and Banking in Economic Development, Baltimore; John Hopkins university Press,
1995.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e396a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e400" publication-type="other">
Gupta, K.L., Aggregate Savings, Financial Intermediation and Interest Rate, Review of Economics and
Statistics, Vol 69, No 2, 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e411a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e415" publication-type="other">
Harris, J., Financial Deepening as a Prerequisite to Investment Growth: Empirical Evidence from Five Asian
Economics, Developing Economies, Vol 17, No 3, 1979.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e425a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e429" publication-type="other">
Hadji Michael, etal.,Sub-Saharan Africa; Growth, Savings and Investment, 1986-1993 IMF Occasional Paper,
No 118, 1995.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e439a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e443" publication-type="other">
Hope, K.R., Growth, Savings and Investment in Botswana, Savings and Development, Vol XXI, No 2, 1997.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e450a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e454" publication-type="other">
Jao, Y.C., Financial Deepening and Economic Growth: Theory, Evidence and Policy, Greek Economic Review,
Vol 7, No 3, 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e464a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e468" publication-type="other">
Japelli, T. and Pagano, M., Saving, Growth and Liquidity Constraints, Quarterly Journal of Economics, Vol 109,
No 1, 1994.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e478a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e482" publication-type="other">
Jefferis, K., 'An Unusual Case of "Financial Deepening"; Financial Reform and Economic Development in
Botswana', Department of Eonomics Seminar Paper, University of Botswana, 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e493a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e497" publication-type="other">
Jefferies, K., Interest Rate and the Demand for Credit in Botswana, Department of Economics Seminar Paper,
University of Botswana, 1993.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e507a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e511" publication-type="other">
Kariuki, P., Interest Rate Liberalisation and the Allocative Efficiency of Credit: Some Evidence from Small and
Medium scale Industry in Kenya, in Charles Harvey(ed), Constraints on the Sucess of Structural Adjustment
Programs in Africa, New York: St Martin Press, 1996.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e524a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e528" publication-type="other">
Khatkhate, D., Assessing the Impact of Interest Rates in Less Development Countries, World Development,
Vol 16, No 5, 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e538a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e542" publication-type="other">
Matsheka, T.C., The Financing of Economic Growth and Development in Botswana: 1973-1994, Unpublished
Ph. D thesis, University of Kent at Canterbury, Kent, 1997.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e552a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e556" publication-type="other">
McKinnon, R., Money and Capital in Economic Development, Washington; The Brookings Institute, 1973.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e563a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e567" publication-type="other">
Oshikoya, T.W., Interest Rate Liberalisation, Saving, Investment and Growth: The Case of Kenya, Savings and
Development, Vol XVI, No 3, 1992.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e578a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e582" publication-type="other">
Rittenberg, L., Investment Spending and Interest Rate Policy: The Case of Financial Liberalisation in Turkey,
Journal of Development Studies, Vol 27, No 2, 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e592a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e596" publication-type="other">
Schumpeter, J.A., The Theory of Economic Development: An Inquiry into Profits, Capital, Credit, Interest, and
the Business Cycle, New York: Oxford University Press, 1961.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e606a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e610" publication-type="other">
Seek, D. and El, Nil, Y.H., Financial Liberalisation in Africa, World Development, Vol 21, No 11,1993.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e617a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e621" publication-type="other">
Shaw, E., Financial Deepening in Economic Development, Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1973.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e628a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e632" publication-type="other">
Thirlwall, A.P., Inflation, Saving and Growth in Developing Economies, London:Macmillan, 1974.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e639a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e643" publication-type="other">
Thirlwall, A.P., Growth and Development, London: Macmillan, 1994.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e651a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e655" publication-type="other">
Warman, F and A.P., Interest Rate, Saving, Investment and Growth in Mexico, 1960-1990: Tests of the
Financial Liberalisation Hypothesis, Journal of Development Studies, Vol 30, Vol 3, 1994.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d624e665a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d624e669" publication-type="other">
World Bank, World Development Report: Financial Systems and Development, NewYork: Oxford University
Press, 1989.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


