<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014685</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Review Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Online Fan Practices and CALL</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Sauro</surname>
                  <given-names>Shannon</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Malmö University, Sweden.</aff>
               <bio>
                  <p>Shannon Sauro is Associate Professor in the Department of Culture, Languages and Media at Malmö University, Sweden. Her current area of research explores the intersection of online media fandoms and language and literacy development. She is co-editor with Carol Chapelle of The Handbook of Technology and Second Language Teaching and Learning (Wiley-Blackwell) and is a member of the CALICO executive board, serving as President of CALICO from 2016 to 2017. She is also active in the online Sherlock Holmes and Harry Potter fandoms where she engages in a wide range of fan practices.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>34</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014683</issue-id>
         <fpage>131</fpage>
         <lpage>146</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2017, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014685"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>This article provides a narrative overview of research on online fan practices for language and literacy learning, use, and identity work. I begin with an introduction to online fan communities and common fan practices found in these online affinity spaces, the best known of which is fan fiction, fictional writing that reinterprets and remixes the events, characters, and settings found in popular media. I then look to other online fan practices that have been explored in language and literacy learning research such as fan-subbing and scanlation, amateur subtitling and translation of popular media carried out by individual or teams of fans. Finally, this article concludes by looking to research that has begun to explore the integration of fan practices found in the digital wilds into the language classroom as a way to illuminate how our growing understanding of online fan practices can motivate the design of computer-mediated tasks or the integration of social media into formal language teaching.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>fans</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>fandom</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>fan fiction</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>translation</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>digital literacy</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>identity work</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>popular culture</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>21st century skills</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Behrenwald, S. J. (2012). Fan fiction practices in ESL writing classrooms. In G. Kessler, A. Oskoz, &amp; I. Elola (Eds.), Technology use across writing contexts (pp. 277–296). San Marcos, TX: CALICO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Black, R. W. (2005). Access and affiliation: The literacy and composition practices of English-language learners in an online fan fiction community. Journal of Adolescent and Adult Literacy, 49(2), 118–128. https://doi.org/10.1598/JAAL.49.2.4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Black, R. W. (2006). Language, culture, and identity in online fan fiction. E-learning, 3, 180–184.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Black, R. W. (2009). Online fan fiction, global identities, and imagination. Research in the Teaching of English, 43, 397–425.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cavicchi, D. (1998). Tramps like us: Music and meaning among Springsteen fans. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Council of Europe (2001). The common European framework of reference for languages: Learning, teaching, assessment. Retrieved from http://www.coe.int/t/dg4/linguistic/Source/Framework_EN.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coppa, F. (2013). An archive of our own: Fanfiction writers unite! In A. Jamison (Ed.), Fic: Why fan fiction is taking over the world (pp. 302–308). Dallas, TX: Smart Pop Books.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curwood, J. S. (2013). Fan fiction, remix culture, and The Potter Games. In V.E. Frankel (Ed.), Teaching with Harry Potter (pp. 81–92). Jefferson, NC: McFarland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duffett, M. (2013). Understanding fandom: An introduction to the study of media fan culture. New York: Bloomsbury.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fukunaga, N. (2006). “Those anime students”: Foreign language literacy development through Japanese popular culture. Journal of Adolescent and Adult Literacy, 50(3), 206–222. https://doi.org/10.1598/JAAL.50.3.5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hinck, A. (2012). Theorizing a public engagement keystone: Seeing fandom’s integral connection to civic engagement through the case of the Harry Potter Alliance. Transformative Works and Cultures, 10. https://doi.org/10.3983/twc.2012.0311.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inose, H. (2012). Scanlation – What fan translators of manga learn in the informal learning environment. International Symposium on Language and Communication: Research trends and challenges, Izmir, Turkey.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jamison, A. (2013). Why Fic? In A. Jamison (Ed.), Fic: Why fan fiction is taking over the world. Dallas, TX: Smart Pop Books.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jenkins, H. (2006). Fans, bloggers, and gamers: Exploring participatory culture. New York: New York University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lam, W. S. E. (2000). L2 Literacy and the design of the self: A case study of a teenager writing on the Internet. TESOL Quarterly, 34(3), 457–482. https://doi.org/10.2307/3587739</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lam, W. S. E. (2006). Re-envisioning language, literacy, and the immigrant subject in new mediascapes. Pedagogies: An International Journal, 1(3), 171–195. https://doi.org/10.1207/s15544818ped0103_2</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leppänen, S. (2007). Youth language in media contexts: Insights into the functions of English in Finland. World Englishes, 26(2), 149–169. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-971X.2007.00499.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lepännen, S. (2008). Cybergirls in trouble? Fan fiction as a discursive space for interrogating gender and sexuality. In C. R. Caldas-Coulthard &amp; R. Iedema (Eds.), Identity trouble: Critical discourse and contested identities (pp. 156–179). Houndsmills, UK: Palgrave Macmillan. https://doi.org/10.1057/9780230593329_9</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lepännen, S., Pitkänen-Huhta, A., Piirainen-Marsch, A., Nikula, T., &amp; Peuronen, S. (2009). Young people’s translocal new media uses: A multiperspective analysis of language choice and heteroglossia. Journal of Computer-Mediated Communication, 14(4), 1080–1107. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1083-6101.2009.01482.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, A. Y. M. (2015). Agency, language learning, and creative digital content production. Paper presented at the American Association for Applied Linguistics, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Minkel, E. (2015, March 25). From the Internet to the Ivy League: Fan fiction in the classroom. Retrieved from http://www.themillions.com/2015/03/from-the-internet-to-theivy-league-fanfiction-in-the-classroom.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pérez-González, L. (2007). Intervention in new amateur subtitling cultures: A multimodal account. Linguistica Antverpiensia, 6, 67–80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sauro, S. (2014). Lessons from the fandom: Task models for technology-enhanced language learning. In M. González-Lloret &amp; L. Ortega (Eds), Technology-mediated TBLT: Researching technology and tasks (pp. 239–262). Amsterdam: John Benjamins.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sauro, S. (2016). “I’m going to get online and I’m going to talk to people and learn English”: The informal language learning of a Sherlock fan. Paper presented at the International Conference on MOOCs, Informal Language Learning, and Mobility, Milton Keynes, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sauro, S., &amp; Chapelle, C. A. (in press). Toward langua-technocultural competence. In C. A. Chapelle &amp; S. Sauro (Eds.), The handbook of technology and second language teaching and learning (pp. 459-472). Oxford: Wiley-Blackwell.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sauro, S., &amp; Sundmark, B. (2016). Report from Middle Earth: Fan fiction tasks in the EFL classroom. ELT Journal, 70(4), 414–423. https://doi.org/10.1093/elt/ccv075</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sauro, S., &amp; Zourou, K. (2017). CALL for papers for CALL in the Digital Wilds special issue. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 21(1), 186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundqvist, P., &amp; Sylvén, L. K. (2014). Language-related computer use: Focus on young L2 English learners in Sweden. ReCALL, 26(1), 3–20. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0958344013000232</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Suto, I. (2013). 21st century skills: Ancient, ubiquitous, enigmatic? Research Matters. A Cambridge Assessment Publication,15, 2–8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thomas, E. E., &amp; Stornaiuolo, A. (2016). Restorying the self: Bending toward textual justice. Harvard Educational Review, 86(3), 313–338. https://doi.org/10.17763/1943-5045-86.3.313</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thorne, S. L., &amp; Black, R. W. (2011). Identity and interaction in internet-mediated contexts. In C. Higgins (Ed.), Identity formation in globalizing contexts: Language learning in the new millenium (pp. 257–278). New York: Mouton de Gruyter. https://doi.org/10.1515/9783110267280.257</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thorne, S. L., Sauro, S., &amp; Smith, B. (2015). Technologies, identities, and expressive activity. Annual Review of Applied Linguistics, 35, 215–233. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0267190514000257</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tosenberger, C. (2008). “Oh my God, the Fan fiction!”: Dumbledore’s outing and the online Harry Potter fandom. Children’s Literature Association Quarterly, 33(2), 200–206. https://doi.org/10.1353/chq.0.0015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Valero-Porras, M.-J., &amp; Cassany, Y. (2015). Multimodality and language learning in a scanlation community. Procedia – Social and Behavioral Sciences, 212 (2), 9–15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sbspro.2015.11.291</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Valero-Porras, M.-J., &amp; Cassany, Y. (2016). “Traducción por fans para fans”: organización y prácticas en una comunidad hispania de scanlation. BiD: Textos Universitaris de Biblioteconomia i Documentació, 37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Tonder, L. C. (2015). Fansubbing and creative subtitling – How amateur approaches can help improve professional products. South African Translators’ Institute – second triennial conference: The changing face of translation and interpreting, Kempton Park, South Africa.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Williams, K. L. (2006). The impact of popular culture fandom on perceptions of Japanese language and culture learning: The case of student anime fans. (Doctoral dissertation). Retrieved from ProQuest Dissertations &amp; Theses (UMI 3245796).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, L. T., &amp; Cassany, D. (2016). Fansubbing del español al chino: Organización, roles y normas en las escritura colaborativa. BiD: Textos Universitaris de Biblioteconomia i Documentació, 37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
