<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26956201</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Offshore Wind Resource Assessment in Rhode Island Waters</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Grilli</surname>
                  <given-names>Annette R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Spaulding</surname>
                  <given-names>Malcolm L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">37</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26956197</issue-id>
         <fpage>579</fpage>
         <lpage>594</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26956201"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The validity and accuracy of the Weibull distribution to represent wind speed distributions and estimate the wind power resource is assessed for Southern New England coastal waters. Excellent agreement is found between Weibull-derived and measured mean power resource estimates, confirming the validity of the two-parameter Weibull distribution in the study area. The mean power resource and its spatial variability are assessed and mapped in terms of <italic>theoretical</italic> and <italic>technical</italic> power estimates. Finally, a sensitivity study is performed to assess the impact on power estimates at hub height of a hypothetical wind turbine, of uncertainties of three main controlling factors : (1) mean wind speed, (2) Weibull shape parameter, and (3) shear coefficient of the lower atmospheric boundary layer. Results are presented in terms of expected mean theoretical and technical power, and confidence interval, at a hypothetical 110 meters hub height, on a high resolution grid (10 arc-seconds) based on stochastic estimations.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>[1]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">AWS Truepower cited 2007. Wind speed data for Southern New England.[contact online at www.awstruepower.com].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>[2]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Barthelmie R.J., M.S. Courtney, J. Hojstrup, and S.E. Larsen 1996. Meteorological aspects of offshore wind energy. Observations from Vindeby wind farm. J. Wind Eng. Ind. Arerod., 62, 191-211.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>[3]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Brower, M. 2007. Wind Speed Data for Southern New England. CD-ROM. AWS TruePower.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>[4]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bailey B., and J. Freedman 2008. A regional assessment of the U.S. offshore wind energy resource through the use of mesoscale modeling. Marine Tech. Soc. J., 42, 8-18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>[5]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">CapeWind 2007. Comparison of Cape Wind Scientific Data Tower Wind Speed Data with ISO New England List of Top Ten Electric Demand Days. [Available online at http://www.capewind.org/downloads/CWReport.pdf].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>[6]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Conradsen K. and L.B. Nielsen 1984. Review of Weibull statistics for estimation of wind speed distribution. J. Climatol. Appl. Meteor., 23, 1173-1183.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>[7]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Charnock H. 1955. Wind stress on a water surface. Q. J. Roy. Meteor. Soc., 81, 639-640.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>[8]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">da Rosa A.V. 2009. Fundamentals of renewable energy processes. Elsevier. 844 pp.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>[9]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Garvine R.W. and W. Kempton 2008. Assessing the wind field over the continental shelf as a resource for electric power. J. Mar. Res., 66, 751-773.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>[10]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Grilli, A.R., T. Lado Insua and M.L. Spaulding 2012. A protocol to include ecosystem services constraints in a wind farm cost model. J. Environmental Engng. (in press).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>[11]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Hennessey, J.P. 1977. Some aspects of wind power statistics. J. Appl. Meteor., 16, 119-128.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>[12]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Morgan E.C., M. Lackner, R.M. Vogel, and L.G. Baise 2010. Probability distribution of offshore wind speeds. Energy Convers. Managment, 52, 15-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>[13]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Monahan, A.G. 2006a. The probability distribution of sea-surface wind speeds. Part I: Theory and SeaWinds observations. J. Climate, 19, 497-520.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>[14]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Monahan, A.G. 2006b. The probability distribution of sea-surface wind speeds. Part II: Data set Intercomparison and Seasonal Variability. J. Climate, 19, 521-534.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>[15]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">National Research Council 2011. Assessment of Marine and Hydrokinetic Energy Technology: Interim Letter Report. Washington, DC: The National Academies Press. http://www.nap.edu/ catalog.php?record_id=13202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>[16]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Ocean SAMP, 2010. Rhode Island Ocean Special Area Management Plan [Available online at http://seagrant.gso.uri.edu/ oceansamp].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>[17]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Pavia, E. G., and J.J. O’Brien 1986. Weibull Statistics over the ocean. J. Climatol. Appl. Meteor., 25, 1324-1332.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>[18]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Pimenta F., K. Willet, and R. W. Garvine 2008. Combining meteorological stations and satellite data to evaluate the offshore wind power resource of Southeastern Brazil. Renew. Energ., doi:10.1016/j.renene.2008.01.01210.16.1310/16/1310.16.13</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>[19]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Rinne, H. 2009. The Weibull distribution. A handbook. CRC Press, Chapman and Hall. 784 pp.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>[20]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Sedeflan, L. 1980. On the vertical extrapolation of mean wind power density. J. Appl. Meteor., 19, 488-493.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>[21]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Spaulding, M., A. Grilli, C. Damon and G. Fugate 2010: Application of Technology Development Index and Principal Component Analysis and Cluster Methods to Ocean Renewable Energy Facility Siting. Marine Tech. Soc J., 44, 5-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>[22]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Schwartz, M., D. Heimiller, S. Haynes, and W. Musial 2010. Assessment of offshore wind energy resources for the United States. Technical Report. National Research Laboratory (NREL). 104 p.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>[23]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Tackle, E.S. and J.M. Brown 1978. Note on the use of Weibull statistics to characterize wind speed data. J. Appl. Meteor., 17, 556-559.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>[24]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Tuller, S. E. and A.C. Brett 1984. The characteristics of wind velocity that favor the fitting of a Weibull Distribution in wind speed analysis. J. Climatol. Appl. Meteor., 23, 124-134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>[25]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Turk, M., Grigutsch, K., Emeis, S. 2008. The wind profile above the sea. Investigations basing on four years of Fino1 Data. DEWI Magazin, 33. [available online athttp://www.dewi.de/dewi/index.php?id = 74&amp;tx_ttnews%5Btt_news%5D = 67&amp;cHa sh = e7ebc06c1baa669b46391d69aadf0181].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>[26]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c26">U.S. Army Corps of Engineers 2010. Wave Information Studies (WIS) data.[Available online at http://frf.usace.army.mil/ wis2010/].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>[27]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c27">WeatherFlow Data Center 2009. Rhode Island Met-towers Wind data. [Contact online at http://www.weatherflow.com].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>SAMP area (red dashed line) and extension towards Massachussets. Measurement stations are represented by triangular symbols; square symbols mark the WIS virtual station locations.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Wind data sources (data station locations are mapped in Fig. 1) and shape coefficient value estimated from Weibull distributions. WF: Weather Flow Inc.; AWS: AWS True Wind Inc.; CO: Coastal Observatory (MVCO)-WHOI; z₁ is actual measurement height or virtual station (WIS) elevation</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Comparison between simulated power resource from Weibull distributions, using the Monte Carlo (MC) method (P<sub>MC</sub>), and the mean instantaneous power calculated at each station from a full time series (Pₒ).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Mean theoretical power in and around SAMP area, based on Eq. (5).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3b:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Mean usable power available at turbine hub height (z<sub>h</sub> = 110 m), assuming cut-in, cut off, and rated speeds of, u<sub>in</sub> = 3.5, u<sub>out</sub> = 27, and u<sub>R</sub> = 15 m/s, respectively.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3c:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Mean technical power available at turbine hub height (z<sub>h</sub> = 110 m), assuming cut-in, cut off, and rated speeds of, u<sub>in</sub> = 3.5, u<sub>out</sub> = 27, and u<sub>R</sub> = 15 m/s, respectively and the aerodynamic limitation due to Betz law (Eq. 3).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Power sensitivity to the shape parameter k, estimated as the ratio of the mean expected power to the mean expected power assuming a standard value k = 2. [For instance, assuming a shape factor of 2 instead of 2.1 would overestimate the expected power by about 5%].</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Sources of uncertainty in mean power resource at measurement level</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Sensitivity of mean expected power resource at hub height z₂ = 110 m, to shear coefficient value</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Theoretical Power resource sensitivity to the shear coefficient: BISC (blue) compared to standard profile, SOSC (green), and modeled profile, MOSC. (red). The red dot represent the power calculated from Eq. 9 using AWS wind speed data and shear coefficient value, MOSC. The blue dots are estimated using Eq. 9, and wind speed distributions and parameters calculated from measured data as well as BISC shear coefficient value.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Technical Power resource sensitivity to the shear coefficient; BI profile 95% confidence interval (BISC; dash blue) compared to standard profiles, SOSC (plain blue) and MOSC (plain red) (Table 3).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Uncertainties associated with wind power parameters: definition, associated statistics and resulting combined uncertainty for 2 expected elevations, assuming Block Island wind characteristics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
