<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica, Centre for Financial Assistance to African Countries</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">23027507</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>CREDIT CONTROL POLICIES FOR IMPROVED AGRICULTURAL FINANCING IN NIGERIA: PANACEA, PLACEBO OR STRUCTURAL BOTTLENECK?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>A.S.</given-names>
                  <surname>Olomola</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1991</year>
         </pub-date>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i23027504</issue-id>
         <fpage>23</fpage>
         <lpage>38</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23027507"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper undertakes an analysis of the credit control mechanisms vis-a-vis the targeting of loans for agricultural financing in Nigeria. Such controls include loan portfolio requirements, loan guarantees, interest ceiling, regulations on rural bank branching and the granting of moratorium. The rationale for these control measures and the underlying assumptions are critically reviewed both in theory and practice. Having examined the various effects of credit controls on channeling funds into agriculture, it is argued that the persistence of such controls is tantamount to the promotion of placebos rather than promoting farmers' accessibility to formal credit. In other words, some of the existing controls need to be relaxed or backed up with complementary policy actions if they are to contribute more meaningfully to the solution of agricultural finance problems in the country. In particular such bottlenecks as real negative rates of interest, high rates of loan default, low level of rural savings mobilization, leakage of credit funds to unintended beneficiaries etc.; arising directly or indirectly from credit controls will have to be eliminated. In conclusion, the paper contends that as the need for increased supply of agricultural credit rises so also will be the need for policy makers to weigh the favourable effects of credit controls on the agricultural sector against the unfavourable effects that may develop within the financial system. In other words, trade-offs between credit control and credit supply need to be balanced regularly in line with the dictates of economic realities to ensure that the agricultural sector derives the desired benefits.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d15e126a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e130" publication-type="other">
Brown, L. (1970) "Seeds of change", New York, Praeger.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e137a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e141" publication-type="other">
Central Bank of Nigeria (1979) Annual Report and Statement of Account, p. 57</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e148a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e152" publication-type="other">
(1986a) Sokoto State ACGSF Programmes Report Presented at the CBN 6th Annual Agricultural Credit Officers
Seminar held at Metropolitan Hotel, Calabar, 6 - 10 October, 1986</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e162a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e166" publication-type="other">
(1986b) Benue State ACGSF Programmes Report Presented at the CBN 6th Annual Agricultural Credit Officers
Seminar held at Metropolitan Hotel, Calabar, 6 - 10 October, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e177a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e181" publication-type="other">
Ewulu, J.N.J. "Problems of Rural Banking: Funding and Investment". A Paper Presented at the F.I.T.C. Course
on Effective Rural Branch Management, held at Hotel Presidential, Enugu, November, 20 - 21, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e191a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e195" publication-type="other">
John, F. and Kilby, P. (1975) Agricultural and Structural Transformation, Oxford University Press, p. 314.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e202a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e206" publication-type="other">
Mabawonku, A.F. and Olomola, A.S. (1988) "Monetary and Fiscal Policies in Nigeria, 1970-1985: Some Implica-
tions for Agricultural Development", Savings and Development Quarterly Review, XII(4): 343-362.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e216a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e220" publication-type="other">
Okorie, Aja (1988) "Agricultural Manpower Needs of the Rural Banks In Nigeria: A Case Study of Selected Bran-
ches In Bendel and Imo States" Paper Presented at the 1987/88 Conference of the Nigerian Association
of Agricultural Economists, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife. Jan. 26 - 28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e233a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e237" publication-type="other">
Schultz, T.W. (1964) Transforming Traditional Agriculture, New Haven, Yale University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
