<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437908</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Impact of Compulsory Competitive Tendering on Refuse Collection Services</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>STEFAN</given-names>
                  <surname>SZYMANSKI</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>1996</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">17</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437905</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>19</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 1996</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437908"/>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d29e162a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e169" publication-type="other">
Walsh (1991) reviewed the initial impact of CCT for the Department of the Environment on the management of
local authority services for a sample of 40 local authorities. More recently, a study by Escott and Whitfield (1995a)
has provided an important insight into employment policies following CCT but is again based on a relatively small
number of case studies. There are a small number of academic studies including Painter (1991), Shaw, Fenwick
and Foreman (1994) and Patterson and Pinch (1995), but they had limited data sources on which to draw. Milne
and McGee (1992) followed up the earlier work of Dornberger, Meadowcroft and Thompson (1987) on CCT in
the NHS.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e195a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e202" publication-type="other">
That is, 266 out of 328 authorities. For the second year after the tender was held, 259 out of 315 (82 per cent)
registered a fall in net expenditure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e212a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e219" publication-type="other">
A mote detailed analysis of these variations is provided in Szymanski (1995).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e226a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e233" publication-type="other">
The 1980 Local Government Planning and Land Act had already obliged authorities to hold competitive tenders
for most construction and maintenance work relating to highways.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e244a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e251" publication-type="other">
Services with a gross cost of less than £100,000 in the previous year were exempt.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e258a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e265" publication-type="other">
Although some critics have argued that this in itself demonstrates the inherent political bias of mainstream
economics — for example, Wilson and Game (1994) and Stewart (1993).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e275a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e282" publication-type="other">
The work of Williamson (for example, Williamson (1976)) pointed out that in situations where productive
efficiency requires long-term investments in activity-specific assets, the auctioning of time-limited contracts may
be inefficient since contractors will have no long-term incentive to invest. However, such problems are only likely
to arise in situations where complex or advanced technologies are used, or where human capital investments yield
benefits over the very long term. Neither of these conditions is likely to apply to a low-technology, low-skilled
activity such as refuse collection.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e305a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e312" publication-type="other">
See Walsh (1995) for a recent survey of the political debate.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e319a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e326" publication-type="other">
These figures are submitted annually on form R06A to the Department of the Environment, from which the
data were obtained.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e336a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e343" publication-type="other">
According to Escott and Whitfield (1995a), whose report was commissioned by the Equal Opportunities
Commission, there are hardly any women employed in refuse collection.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e354a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e361" publication-type="other">
Once it was clear the legislation on CCT would be passed, authorities were reluctant to reveal any information
that was considered commercially sensitive.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e371a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e378" publication-type="other">
Both pre- and post-CCT surveys asked for information on recycling but the effects of the Environmental
Protection Act mean that direct comparisons are not feasible. Data on wage and employment levels, even if
available, would not now be released on grounds of commercial sensitivity. Because CCT has meant that service
standards are now fixed contractually, the answers to the 1994 questionnaire were taken to apply to the service in
each year of the current contract (in virtually all cases, this was the first contract signed under 1988 Local
Government Act rules).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e401a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e408" publication-type="other">
More restrictive specifications, such as cost per household, did not produce significantly different results. Gross
expenditure is a misleading indicator since the expenditure of the local authority may be incurred specifically to
generate income. Net expenditure is therefore the major concern in assessing the cost-effectiveness of the authority.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e421a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e428" publication-type="other">
That is, Q = &lt;4L°W where Q is output proxied by the number of collection units and A is the vector of service
characteristics.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e438a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e445" publication-type="other">
The restriction of coefficient equality can be easily rejected.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e452a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e459" publication-type="other">
Members are the elected representatives who run each authority. The average number of members in authorities
awarding contracts to private contractors was 49, of whom 23 were Conservative and 11 were Labour. Where
contracts were awarded in-house, the average number of members was 48, of whom 18 were Conservative and 18
were Labour. The figures for political control were based on the post-May-election data in the 12-month period
before the award of the contract and were taken from the Municipal Yearbook.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e479a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e486" publication-type="other">
One explanation, suggested by a referee, is that where DSOs won, there may have been relatively few bids, so
that it is truly competition that matters, and DSO victories are proxies for lack of competition. Data on the number
of bids in each authority are not available.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e499a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e506" publication-type="other">
See Dornberger, Hall and Li (1995) for an interesting attempt to identify the relationship between competitive
tendering and ex-post quality in the Australian building cleaning industry.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e516a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e523" publication-type="other">
In Ihe probit regression of the sample selection model, the numbers of members belonging to the three main
parties were used as explanatory variables. The number of Labour members had a negative and statistically
significant coefficient, while the number of Conservative members had a positive and statistically significant
coefficient (both at the 5 per cent level).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e539a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e546" publication-type="other">
In any case, the restriction that the quality variables were not significantly different from zero was not accepted
by the data. The estimated coefficients were broadly similar to those reported by Dornberger, Meadowcroft and
Thompson ( 1986) and Szymanski and Wilkins ( 1993), with kerbside collection reducing costs by between 10 and
20 per cent (relative to back-door collection) and free provision of containers adding about 7.5 per cent to costs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e562a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e569" publication-type="other">
The regression output, not reported here, is available on request from the author.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e576a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e583" publication-type="other">
This issue is discussed in more detail in an earlier version of this paper.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d29e599a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e603" publication-type="other">
Audit Commission (1984), Securing Further Improvements in Refuse Collection: A Review by the
Audit Commission, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e613a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e617" publication-type="other">
— (1993), Realising the Benefits of Competition, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e624a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e628" publication-type="other">
Bello, H. (1994), 'An analysis of the changes in refuse collection methods and cost: the effect of
compulsory competitive tendering', MBA thesis, Imperial College Management School,
University of London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e641a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e645" publication-type="other">
BRMB (1995), CCT: The Private Sector View, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e653a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e657" publication-type="other">
CDC Research (1994), Contracts Handbook, London: CDC Publishing Limited.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e664a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e668" publication-type="other">
Consumers' Association (1995), 'Not a load of rubbish', Which?, June, pp. 28-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e675a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e679" publication-type="other">
Cubbin, J., Dornberger, S. and Meadowcroft, S. (1987), 'Competitive tendering and refuse collection:
identifying the source of efficiency gains', Fiscal Studies, vol. 8, no. 3, pp. 49-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e689a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e693" publication-type="other">
Demsetz, H. (1968), 'Why regulate utilities?', Journal of Law and Economics, vol. 11, pp. 55-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e700a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e704" publication-type="other">
Dornberger, S., Hall, C. and Li, E. (1995), 'The determinants of price and quality in competitively
tendered contracts', Economic Journal, vol. 105, pp. 1454-70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e714a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e718" publication-type="other">
—, Meadowcroft, S. and Thompson, D. (1986), 'Competitive tendering and efficiency: the case of
refuse collection', Fiscal Studies, vol. 7, no. 4, pp. 69-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e729a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e733" publication-type="other">
—, — and — ( 1987), 'The impact of competitive tendering on the costs of hospital domestic services',
Fiscal Studies, vol. 8, no. 4, pp. 39-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e743a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e747" publication-type="other">
— and Rimmer, S. (1994), 'Competitive tendering and contracting in the public sector: a survey',
International Journal of the Economics of Business, vol. 1, pp. 439-53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e757a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e761" publication-type="other">
Escott, K. and Whitfield, D. (1995a), The Gender Impact of Compulsory Competitive Tendering in
Local Government, Manchester: Equal Opportunities Commission.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e771a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e775" publication-type="other">
— and — ( 1995b), 'Calculation of the national costs and savings of CCT', Centre for Public Services
Research Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e785a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e789" publication-type="other">
Ganley, J. and Grahl, J. (1988), 'Competition and efficiency in refuse collection: a critical comment',
Fiscal Studies, vol. 9, no. 1, pp. 80-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e799a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e803" publication-type="other">
Kerr, A. and Radford, M. (1995), 'CCTchallenged', New Economy, vol. 2, pp. 36-41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e811a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e815" publication-type="other">
Laffont, J.-J. and Tirole, J. (1987), 'Auctioning incentive contracts', Journal of Political Economy,
vol. 95, pp. 921-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e825a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e829" publication-type="other">
LGMB (1993) CCT Information Service Survey Reports, nos. 6 and 7, London: Local Government
Management Board.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e839a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e843" publication-type="other">
McDavid, J. (1985), 'The Canadian experience with privatising residential solid waste collection
services', Public Administration Review, September / October, pp. 602-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e853a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e857" publication-type="other">
Milne, R. and McGee, M. (1992), 'Compulsory competitive tendering in the NHS: a new look at some
old estimates', Fiscal Studies, vol. 13, no. 3, pp. 96-111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e867a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e871" publication-type="other">
Painter, J. (1991), 'Compulsory competitive tendering in local government: the first round', Public
Administration, vol. 69, pp. 191-210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e881a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e885" publication-type="other">
Patterson, A. and Pinch, P. (1995), "'Hollowing out" the local state: compulsory competitive tendering
and the restructuring of British public sector services', Environment and Planning, vol. 27, pp.
1437-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e899a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e903" publication-type="other">
PSPRU (1992), Privatisation: Disaster for Quality, London: Public Services Privatisation Research
Unit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e913a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e917" publication-type="other">
Savas, E. (1977), The Organisation and Efficiency of Solid Waste Collection, Lexington.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e924a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e928" publication-type="other">
Shaw, K„ Fenwick, J. and Foreman, A. (1994), 'Compulsory competitive tendering for local
government services: the experiences of local authorities in the North of England 1988-1992',
Public Administration, vol. 72, pp. 201-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e941a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e945" publication-type="other">
Stevens, B. (1978), 'Scale, market structure and the cost of refuse collection', Review of Economics
and Statistics, vol. 60, pp. 438-48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e955a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e959" publication-type="other">
Stewart, J. (1991), 'The changing organisation and management of local authorities', in J. Stewart
and G. Stoker (eds), The Future of Local Government, London: Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e969a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e973" publication-type="other">
— ( 1993), 'The limitations of government by contract', Public Money and Management, vol. 13, no.
3, pp. 7-12.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e984a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e988" publication-type="other">
Szymanski, S. (1995), 'Compulsory competitive tendering of refuse collection services: accounting
for the cost reductions', mimeo, Imperial College Management School.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e998a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1002" publication-type="other">
—and Wilkins, S. (1993), 'Cheap rubbish? Refuse collection costs and collective tendering 1984-88',
Fiscal Studies, vol. 14, no. 3, pp. 109-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1012a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1016" publication-type="other">
Walsh, K. (1991), Competitive Tendering for Local Authority Services: Initial Experiences, London:
HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1026a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1030" publication-type="other">
— (1995), Public Services and Market Mechanisms, London: Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1037a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1041" publication-type="other">
— and Davis, H. (1993), Competition and Service: The Impact of the Local Government Act 1988,
London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1051a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1055" publication-type="other">
Williamson, O. (1976), 'Franchise bidding for natural monopolies — in general and with respect to
CATV', Bell Journal of Economics, vol. 7, pp. 73-104.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1066a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1070" publication-type="other">
Wilson, D. and Game, C. (eds) (1994), Local Government in the UK, London: Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
