<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277660</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Behavior of an IC Engine Turbocharger in Critical Conditions of Lubrication</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Galindo</surname>
                  <given-names>J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universitat Politècnica de València</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Serrano</surname>
                  <given-names>J.R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universitat Politècnica de València</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dolz</surname>
                  <given-names>V.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universitat Politècnica de València</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>López</surname>
                  <given-names>M. A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universitat Politècnica de València</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bouffaud</surname>
                  <given-names>F.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>RSA—Renault SA</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>797</fpage>
         <lpage>805</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277660"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Problems in the turbocharger lubrication system can cause serious deterioration in their overall performance and even their complete destruction. The paper describes several tests with different critical lubrication conditions, in order to determine the thresholds at which the operation may be appropriate. In an IC engine, these problems can be produced mainly by several factors: the decreasing in the supply pressure of the oil, a delay in the lubrication oil pressure and an intermittent lubrication interruption. A turbocharger test bench and an IC engine test bench has been used to test the turbocharger, in order to reproduce the conditions and cycles similar to the operation of the turbocharger in an IC engine (pressures, temperatures, mass flows, accelerations, etc..). Thermodynamic variables and mechanic variables measured in the tests help to identify some of the operating limits of lubrication in critical conditions. In addition, optical techniques have been combined with accelerometer measurements, in order to detect modifications in the movement of the turbocharger shaft. The main conclusions obtained from these tests are that accelerations from low rotational speed to 100krpm, without lubrication oil in the bearing system, don't cause significant problems in the turbocharger, for 20 sec. However, the accelerations to 150krpm can cause critical problems depending on the lubrication delay and the bearing configuration. Finally, higher acceleration rates to 200krpm, without lubrication, cause the turbocharger destruction in a few seconds. By other hand, a low oil inlet pressure given by an oil column, of about 1m in height, allows to the turbo survive during accelerations from low rotational speed to 150 krpm.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lecointe, B. and Monnier, G., “Downsizing a Gasoline Engine Using Turbocharging with Direct Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0542, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003- 01-0542.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eriksson L., “Modeling and Control of Turbocharged SI and CI Engines,” Oil and Gas Science and Technology - Rev IFP Volume 62, Number 4, July-August 2007IFP International Conference. New Trends on Engine Control, Simulation and Modeling, 06 December 2007, doi: 10.2516/ogst:2007042.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galindo J., Serrano J.R., Guardiola C., Cervelló C., “Surge limit definition in a specific test bench for the characterization of the automotive turbochargers”, Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science 30 (2006) 449-462, doi: 10.1016/j.expthermflusci.2005.06.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buratti Riccardo, Carlo Alesanddro, Lanfranco Enrico and Pisoni Alberto, “Di Diesel Engine with Variable Geometry Turbocharger (VGT): A Model Based Boost Pressure Control Strategy”, MECCANICA Volume 32, Number 5 (1997), 409-421, doi: 10.1023/A: 1004251615880.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cantemir, C., “Twin Turbo Strategy Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0666, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0666.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robert Keller A., “Turbocharger Lubrication System”, United States Patent, Patent number: 4,926,641 May 22, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Evans John W., “Pressurized Lubrication Assembly For The Center Bearing Of A Turbocharger”, United States Patent, Patent Number : 4,513, 705 Apr. 30, 1985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neuburger Martin, Schmidt Karl-Otto, Tsakiris Apostolos, “Method And Device Of A Start-Stop Control For An Internal Combustion Engine”, Patent Application Publication, Pub No: US 2011/0174255 A1, Jul. 21, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fulzele Asmita G., Arajpure V.G., Holay P.P., Patil N.M., Condition monitoring of shaft of single-phase induction motor using optical sensor. Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing 29 (2012) 428-435</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schweizer Bernhard, Total instability of turbocharger rotors-Physical explanation of the dynamic failure of rotors with full-floating ring bearings. Journal of sound and vibration 328 (2009) 156-190</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Günther P., Dreier F., Pfiser T., Czarske J., Haupt T., Hufenbach W., Measurement of radial expansion and tumbling motion of a high-speed rotor using an optical sensor system. Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing (2010) doi: 10.1016/j.ymssp.2010.08.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pastor JV, Serrano JR, Dolz V, López MA, Bouffaud F.. Study of turbocharger shaft motion by means of non-invasive optical techniques. Application to the behaviour analysis in turbocharger lubrication failures. Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing 32 (2012) 292-305. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ymssp.2012.04.020</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
