<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277955</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>3D Modeling of Particulate Matter from Spark Ignition Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sukegawa</surname>
                  <given-names>Yoshihiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Oryoji</surname>
                  <given-names>Kazuhiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Hitachi Ltd. Hitachi Research Laboratory</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>April 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277951</issue-id>
         <fpage>419</fpage>
         <lpage>425</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277955"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A 3D simulation technique to estimate density of particulate matter (PM) from spark ignition (SI) gasoline engines is proposed. The technique is based on a two-equation model consisting of coupled conservation equations of soot particle number and mass and fluid transportation equations.</p>
            <p>The nucleation rate of soot particles was obtained from a database built by simulation of elementary reaction with the proposed technique. Two approaches were explored to obtain the nucleation rate. One involves 0-dimensinal SI simulation and the other involves 1-dimensinal flame propagation simulation.</p>
            <p>The estimation results were verified with measurement data obtained with a single cylinder SI engine a homogeneous pre-mixed fuel was supplied. It was confirmed that appropriate results could be obtained with the 1-dimensional approach for the nucleation rate model.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carbonell D., Oliva A., and Perez-Segarra C. D., “Implementation of two-equation soot flamelet models for laminar diffusion flames”, Combustion and Flame, Vol. 156, Issue 3, pp.621-632 (2009).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wen Z., Yun S., Thomson M. J., and Lightstone M. F., “Modeling soot formation in turbulent kerosene/air jet diffusion flames”, Combustion and Flame, Vol. 135, Issue 3, pp.323-340 (2003).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Frenklach M. and Harris S. J., “Aerosol Dynamics Modeling Using the Method of Moments”, J. Colloid and Interface Science, Vol. 118, Issue 1, pp.252-261 (1987).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Frenklach M. and Wang H., “Detailed Mechanism and Modeling of Soot Particle Formation”, Soot Formation in Combustion Mechanisms and Models (Bockhorn H., Ed.), Springer Series in Chemical Physics, Vol. 59, Springer-Verlag, Berlin, pp.165-192 (1994).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akihama, K., Takatori, Y., Inagaki, K., Sasaki, S. et al., “Mechanism of the Smokeless Rich Diesel Combustion by Reducing Temperature,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0655, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gentry R. A., Martin R. E., and Daly B. J. “An Eulerian differencing method for unsteady compressible flow problems”, Journal of Computational Physics, Vol. 1, Issue 1, pp.87-118 (1966).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dukowicz J. K., “A Particle-Fluid Numerical Model for Liquid Sprays”, J. Comp. Physics, Vol. 35, Issue 2, pp.229-253 (1980).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Obokata T., Ishima T., Kato M., Yokota H., and Kaneko M., “Gas Flow Evaluation in the Cylinder of a 4-stroke Motored Engine by Means of LDA”, COMODIA 2008, pp.571-576 (2008).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yunoki K., Murota T., Miura K., Okazaki T., “Large Eddy Simulation of Coaxial Jet Cluster Burner for Gas Turbine Combustor”, Journal of the Combustion Society of Japan (in Japanese), Vol.56, No.177, pp.80-88 (2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inage S., Otsuka M., “A proposal for a New Turbulent Premixed Combustion Model and Its Evaluation (development of the Model)”, JSME International Journal, Series B, Vol. 39, No. 3, pp.640-646 (1996).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Metghalchi M. and Keck J. C., “Burning Velocities of Mixtures of Air with Methanol, Isooctane, and Indolene at High Pressure and Temperature”, Combustion and Flame Vol. 48, pp.191-210 (1982).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://web.stanford.edu/∼hpitsch/FlameMaster.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Slavinskaya N. A., Frank P., “A modelling study of aromatic soot precursors formation in laminar methane and ethene flames”, Combustion and Flame, Vol.156, Issue 9, pp.1705-1722 (2009).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marinov N.M., et al., “Aromatic and Polycyclic Aromatic Hydrocarbon Formation in a Laminar Premixed n-Butane Flame”, Combustion and Flame, Vol.114, Issues 1-2, pp.192-213 (1998).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://code.google.com/p/cantera/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
