<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023190</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Sales Taxes</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>SALES TAXES IN AN E-COMMERCE GENERATION</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Agrawal</surname>
                  <given-names>David R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Kentucky, Martin School of Public Policy and Department of Economics, Lexington, KY 40506-0027.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Fox</surname>
                  <given-names>William F.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Tennessee Center for Business &amp; Economic Research, 715 Stokely Management Center, Knoxville, Tennessee 37996-0570.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>47</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023190"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Rapid growth in e-commerce has altered the ability of U.S. states to enforce sales taxes on a destination basis. This results in different effective tax rates depending on the way in which goods and services are purchased and the characteristics of both the products and the sellers. We discuss how optimal tax research identifies conditions under which differential tax rates are preferred, but these are unlikely to defend low effective rates on e-commerce. This paper studies how recent technological changes, growth in online shopping and digital products, and decentralization of the commodity tax system might affect whether taxes should be collected at destination or origin. We discuss current institutional structures and analyze various approaches being considered to enforce the destination principle on online and digital purchases in the United States and relate these recent issues to countries utilizing Value Added Taxes.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>destination taxation</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>origin taxation</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>commodity taxes</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>online shopping</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>e-commerce</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>tax competition</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>digital products</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Agrawal, David R. 2014. “LOST in America: Evidence on Local Sales Taxes from National Panel Data,” Regional Science and Urban Economics, 49: 147-163.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Agrawal, David R. 2015a. “The Internet as a Tax Haven? The Effect of the Internet on Tax Competition,” SSRN Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Agrawal, David R. 2015b. “The Tax Gradient: Spatial Aspects of Fiscal Competition,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 7 (2): 1-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Agrawal, David R. and David Wildasin. 2014. “Sales Taxes, Agglomeration, and the Internet.” Work in Progress.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ainsworth, Richard. 2008. “Zappers and Phantom-ware: The Need for Fraud Prevention Technology,” Tax Notes International, June 23, p. 1017-1029.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alm, James and Mikhail I. Melnik. 2010. “Do eBay Sellers Comply with State Sales Taxes?” National Tax Journal, 63 (2): 215-236.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alm, James and Mikhail I. Melnik. 2012. “Cross-border Shopping and State Use Tax Liabilities: Evidence from eBay Transactions,” Public Budgeting &amp; Finance, 32(1): 5-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderson, John. 2014. “Paying the State Use Tax: Is a ‘Nudge’ Enough? Working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ballard, Charles L. and Jaimin Lee. 2007. “Internet Purchases, Cross-border Shopping and Sales Taxes,” National Tax Journal, 55 (4): 711-725.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baugh, Brian, Itzhak Ben-David and Hoonsuk Park. 2014. “The Amazon Tax: Empirical Evidence from Amazon and Main Street Retailers,” NBER Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Becker, Johannes and Clemens Fuest. 2012. “The Nexus of Corporate Income Taxation and Multinational Activity,” FinanzArchiv / Public Finance Analysis, 68 (2): 1-21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Behrens, Kristian, Jonathan Hamilton, Gianmarco Ottaviano, and Jacques-Francois Thisse. 2007. “Commodity Tax Harmonization and the Location of Industry,” Journal of International Economics, 72: 271-291.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Behrens, Kristian, Jonathan Hamilton, Gianmarco Ottaviano, and Jacques-Francois Thisse. 2009. “Commodity Tax Competition and Industry Location under the Destination and Origin Principle,” Regional Science and Urban Economics, 39: 422-433.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bird, Richard. 2012. “The GST/HST: Creating an Integrated Sales Tax in Federal Country,” SPP Research Papers, 5 (12): 1-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bird, Richard M. 2015. “Below the Salt: Decentralizing Value-Added Taxes,” in Ehtisham Ahmad and Georgio Brosio (eds.), Handbook of Multilateral Finance, Edward Elgar: Cheltenham UK, pp. 291-333.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bird, Richard M. and Pierre Pascal Gendron. 1998. “Dual VATs and Cross-Border Trade: Two Problems, One Solution?” International Tax and Public Finance, 5: 429-442.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bird, Richard M., Jack M. Mintz, and Thomas A. Wilson. 2006. “Coordinating Federal and Provincial Sales Taxes: Lessons from the Canadian Experience,” National Tax Journal, 59 (4): 889-903.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Black, Dan A. and William H. Hoyt. 1989. “Bidding for Firms,” American Economic Review, 79 (5): 1249-1256.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruce, Donald, and William F. Fox. 2013. “An Analysis of Internet Sales Taxation and the Small Seller Exception,” Office the Advocacy, Small Business Administration, November.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruce, Donald, William Fox and LeAnn Luna. 2015. “E-Tailer Sales Tax Nexus and State Tax Policies,” forthcoming, National Tax Journal.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruce, Donald, William Fox and LeAnn Luna. 2009. “State and Local Sales Tax Revenue Losses from E-commerce,” State Tax Notes, May 18, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruce, Donald, William Fox and Matthew Murray. 2003. “To Tax or Not to Tax: The Case of Electronic Commerce,” Contemporary Economic Policy, 21: 25-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bucovetsky, Sam and Andreas Haufler. 2007. “Preferential Tax Regimes with Asymmetric Countries,” National Tax Journal, 60 (4): 789-795.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burge, Gregory S. and Brian Piper. 2012. “Strategic Fiscal Interdependence: County and Municipal Adoptions of Local Option Sales Taxes,” National Tax Journal, 65 (2): 387-416.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burge, Gregory, and Cynthia Rogers. 2011. “Local Option Sales Taxes and Consumer Spending Patterns: Fiscal Interdependence Under Multi-tiered Local Taxation,” Regional Science and Urban Economics, 41: 46-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burge, Gregory S. and Cynthia Rogers. 2014. “Identifying Leaders and Followers in Models of Local Tax Competition,” University of Oklahoma Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burgess, Robin, Stephen Howes, and Nicholas Stern. 1995. “Value-added Tax Options for India,” International Tax and Public Finance, 2(1): 109-141.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diamond, Peter A. and James A. Mirrlees. 1971. “Optimal Taxation and Public Production I: Production Efficiency,” American Economic Review, 61 (1): 8-27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Due, John F. and John L. Mikesell. 1994. Sales Taxation: State and Local Structure and Administration, Second Edition, The Urban Institute Press: Washington DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Einav, Liran, Dan Knoepfle, Jonathan Levin, and Neel Sundaresan. 2014. “Sales Taxes and Internet Commerce,” American Economic Review, 104 (1): 1-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ellison, Glenn and Sara Fisher Ellison. 2009. “Tax Sensitivity and Home State Preferences in Internet Purchasing,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 1 (2): 53-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fox, William F. 2012. “Sales and Excise Taxes,” in Robert Ebel and John E. Petersen (eds.) Oxford Handbook on State and Local Finance, Oxford University Press: New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fox, William F., LeAnn Luna, and Georg Schaur. 2014. “Destination Taxation and Evasion: Evidence from U.S. Inter-state Commodity Flows,” Journal of Accounting and Economics, 57: 43-57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fox, William F. and Matthew Murray. 1997. “The Sales Tax and Electronic Commerce: So What’s New,” National Tax Journal, 50(3): 473-492.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fox, William F. and Zhou Yang. 2015. “Destination Taxation: Road to Economic Success?” Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gamage, David and Devin J. Heckman. 2012. “A Better Way Forward for State Taxation of e-Commerce,” Boston University Law Review 92: 483-534.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Genser, Bernd and Andreas Haufler. 1996. “Tax Competition, Tax Coordination and Tax Harmonization: The Effects of EMU,” Empirica, 23 (1): 59-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Genser, Bernd, Andreas Haufler, and Peter Birch Sørensesen. 1995. “Indirect Taxation in an Integrated Europe: Is There a Way of Avoiding Trade Distortions without Sacrificing National Tax Autonomy?” Journal of Economic Integration, 10 (2): 178-205.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gillitzer, Christian, Henrik Jacobsen Kleven, and Joel Slemrod. 2014. “A Characteristics Approach to Optimal Taxation: Line Drawing and Tax-Driven Product Innovation.” Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goolsbee, Austan. 2000. “In a World Without Borders: The Impact of Taxes on Internet Commerce,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 115 (2): 561-576.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goolsbee, Austan. 2001. “The Implications of Electronic Commerce for Fiscal Policy (and Vice Versa),” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 15 (1): 13-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goolsbee, Austan, Michael F. Lovenheim, and Joel Slemrod. 2010. “Playing with Fire: Cigarettes, Taxes and Competition from the Internet,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 2 (1): 131-154.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gorman, William M. 1980. “A Possible Procedure for Analysing Quality Differentiation in the Egg Market,” Review of Economic Studies, 47 (5): 843-856.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haufler, Andreas. 1996. “Tax Coordination with Different Preferences for Public Goods: Conflict or Harmony of Interest?” International Tax and Public Finance, 3 (1): 5-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haupt, Alexander and Wolfgang Peters. 2005. “Restricting Preferential Tax Regimes to Avoid Harmful Tax Competition,” Regional Science and Urban Economics, 35 (5): 493-507.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hatta, Tatsuo. 1986. “Welfare Effects of Changing Commodity Tax Rates Towards Uniformity,” Journal of Public Economics, 29: 99-112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hines, James R., Jr. 2010. “Treasure Islands,” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 24 (4): 103-126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoopes, Jeffrey L., Daniel H. Reck and Joel Slemrod. 2015. “Taxpayer Search for Information: Implication for Rational Attention,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoopes, Jeffrey L., Jacob R. Thornock and Braden M. Williams. 2015. “Is Use Tax Evasion a Competitive Advantage for E-tailers?” working paper, July 10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hortaçsu, Ali F., Asís Martínez-Jerez, and Jason Douglas. 2009. “The Geography of Trade in Online Transactions: Evidence from eBay and MercadoLibre,” American Economic Journal: Microeconomics, 1 (1): 53-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Janeba, Eckhard and Wolfgang Peters. 1999. “Tax Evasion, Tax Competition and the Gains from Nondiscrimination: The Case of Interest Taxation in Europe,” Economic Journal, 109 (452): 93-101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Janeba, Eckhard and Michael Smart. 2003. “Is Targeted Tax Competition Less Harmful than Its Remedies?” International Tax and Public Finance, 10 (3): 259-280.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johannesen, Niels. 2010. “Imperfect Tax Competition for Profits, Asymmetric Equilibrium, and Beneficial Tax Havens,” Journal of International Economics, 81 (2): 253-264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kanbur, Ravi and Michael Keen. 1993. “Jeux Sans Frontières: Tax Competition and Tax Coordination When Countries Differ in Size,” The American Economic Review, 83 (4): 877-892.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaplow, Louis. 1990. “Optimal Taxation with Costly Enforcement,” Journal of Public Economics 43: 221-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keen, Michael. 2001. “Preferential Regimes Can Make Tax Competition Less Harmful,” National Tax Journal, 54 (4): 757-762.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keen, Michael and Walter Hellerstein. 2010. “Interjurisdictional Issues in the Design of VAT,” Tax Law Review, 63 (2): 359-408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keen, Michael and Sajal Lahiri. 1998. “The Comparison Between Destination and Origin Principles Under Imperfect Competition,” Journal of International Economics, 45: 323-350.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keen, Michael, Sajal Lahiri, and Pascalis Raimondos-Møller. 2002. “Tax Principles and Tax Harmonization Under Imperfect Competition: A Cautionary Example,” European Economic Review, 46: 1559-1568.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keen, Michael and Stephen Smith. 1996. “The Future of Value Added Tax in the European Union,” Economic Policy, 11 (23): 373-420.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keen, Michael and David Wildasin. 2004. “Pareto-Efficient International Taxation,” American Economic Review, 94 (1): 259-275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kessing, Sebastian and Bernhard Koldert. 2013. “Cross-border Shopping and the Atkinson-Stiglitz Theorem,” International Tax and Public Finance, 20 (4): 618-630.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kleven, Henrik and Mazhar Waseem. 2013. “Using Notches to Uncover Optimization Frictions and Structural Elasticities: Theory and Evidence from Pakistan,” Quarterly Journal of Economics 128: 669-723.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lancaster, Kelvin J. 1966. “A New Approach to Consumer Theory,” Journal of Political Economy, 74 (2): 132-157.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lancaster, Kelvin, J. 1975. “Socially Optimal Product Differentiation,” American Economic Review, 65 (4): 567-585.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lockwood, Ben. 1993. “Commodity Tax Competition Under Destination and Origin Principles,” Journal of Public Economics, 52 (2): 141-162.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lockwood, Ben. 2001. “Tax Competition and Tax Coordination Under Destination and Origin Principles: A Synthesis,” Journal of Public Economics, 81: 279-319.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lockwood, Ben, David de Meza, and Gareth D. Myles. 1994. “When Are Origin and Destination Regimes Equivalent?” International Tax and Public Finance, 1: 5-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lopez-Garcia, Miguel-Angel. 1996. “The Origin Principle and the Welfare Gains from Indirect Tax Harmonization,” International Tax and Public Finance, 3: 83-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Luna, LeAnn. 2003. “Local Sales Tax Competition and the Effect on County Governments’ Tax Rates and Tax Bases,” Journal of American Taxation Association, 26 (1): 43-67,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref71">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Luna, LeAnn, Donald J. Bruce, and Richard R. Hawkins. 2007. “Maxing Out: An Analysis of Local Option Sales Tax Rate Increases,” National Tax Journal, LX (1): 45-63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref72">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manzi, Nina. 2012. “Use Tax Collection on Income Tax Returns in Other States,” Policy Brief, Minnesota Department of Representative, Research Department, April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref73">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mayshar, Joram. 1991. “Taxation with Costly Administration,” Scandinavian Journal of Economics, 93: 75-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref74">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mazerov, Michael. 2013. “States Should Embrace 21st Century Economy by Extending Sales Taxes to Digital Goods and Services,” State Tax Notes, 35-52, January 7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref75">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McLure, Charles E. 2000. “Implementing Subnational Value Added Taxes on Internal Trade: The Compensating VAT (CVAT),” International Tax and Public Finance, 7 (6): 723-740.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref76">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McLure, Charles E. 2003. “The Value Added Tax on Electronic Commerce in the European Union,” International Tax and Public Finance, 10: 753-762.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref77">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McLure, Charles E. 2005. “Coordinating State Sales Taxes with a Federal VAT: Opportunities, Risks and Challenges,” State Tax Notes, 36 (12).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref78">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mikesell, John L. 2010. “The Contribution of Local Sales and Income Taxes to Fiscal Autonomy,” In Ingram, Gregory K. and Yu-Hung Hong (eds.), Municipal Revenues and Land Policies, Lincoln Institute of Land Policy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref79">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mikesell, John. 2011. “State Sales Taxes in 2010: Collections Still in Recession,” State Tax Notes, June 6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref80">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mintz, Jack M. 1992. “Tax Assignment and Brazilian Fiscal Reform,” Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref81">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mintz, Jack M. 1995. “The Business Transfer Tax as a Consumption Tax,” Tax Notes International, 10(1): 75-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref82">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mintz, Jack and Henry Tulkens. 1986. “Commodity Tax Competition Between Member States of a Federation: Equilibrium and Efficiency,” Journal of Public Economics, 29, 133-172.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref83">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naritomi, Joana. 2014. “Consumers as Tax Auditors,” Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref84">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Paramonova, Yulia. 2014. “The Optimal Deterrence of Tax Evasion: The Trade-off Between Information Reporting and Audits,” University of Michigan Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref85">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">PriceWaterhouseCoopers. 2007. “Retail Sales Tax Compliance Costs: A National Study,” Joint Cost of Collection Study, June 1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref86">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sallee, James and Joel Slemrod. 2012. “Car Notches: Strategic Automaker Responses to Fuel Economy Policy,” Journal of Public Economics, (11-12): 981-999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref87">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sinn, Hans-Werner. 1990. “Tax Harmonization and Tax Competition in Europe,” European Economic Review, 34 (2-3): 489-504.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref88">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjoquist, David L, William Smith, Mary Beth Walker, and Sally Wallace. 2007. “An Analysis of the Time to Adoption of Local Sales Taxes: A Duration Model Approach,” Public Budgeting &amp; Finance, 27 (1): 20-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref89">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Slemrod, Joel. 1990. “Optimal Taxation and Optimal Tax Systems,” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 4: 157-178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref90">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Slemrod, Joel. 2007. “Cheating Ourselves: The Economics of Tax Evasion,” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 21 (1): 25-48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref91">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Slerod, Joel. 2013. “Buenas Notches: Lines and Notches in Tax System Design,” eJournal of Tax Research, 11 (3): 259-283.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref92">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Slemrod, Joel. 2015. “Tax Administration and Tax Systems,” IEB Working Paper 2015/13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref93">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Slemrod, Joel B., Brett Collins, Jeffrey L. Hoopes, Daniel H. Reck, and Michael Sebastiani. 2015. “Does Credit Card Information Reporting Improve Small-Business Tax Compliance,” working paper, June 16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref94">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Slemrod, Joel and John D. Wilson. 2009. “Tax Competition with Parasitic Tax Havens,” Journal of Public Economics, 93 (11-12): 1261-1270.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref95">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">State of Washington. 2010. “Department of Revenue Compliance Study,” Research Report No. 2010-4, August 20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref96">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tosun, Mehmet S. and Mark L. Skidmore. 2007. “Cross-Border Shopping and the Sales Tax: An Examination of Food Purchases in West Virginia,” The B.E. Journal of Economic Analysis &amp; Policy, 7(1): 1-18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref97">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Trandel, Gregory. 1992. “Evading the Use Tax on Cross-Border Sales: Pricing and Welfare Effects,” Journal of Public Economics, 49 (3): 313-331.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref98">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations. 1994. “Taxation of Interstate Mail Order Sales: 1994 Estimates,” SR-18, May.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref99">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wildasin, David E., 2001. “Sales Taxation in Kentucky: Problems and Prospects,” In: Wildasin, David E., Childress, Michael T., Hackbart, Merl, Lynch, Lawrence K., Martie, Charles W. (Eds.), Financing State and Local Government: Future Challenges and Opportunities. Kentucky Long Term Policy Research Center, pp. 27–38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref100">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yitzhaki, Shlomo. 1979. “A Note on Optimal Taxation and Administrative Costs,” American Economic Review 69 (3): 475-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref101">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zodrow, George. 2006. “Optimal Commodity Taxation of Traditional and Electronic Commerce,” National Tax Journal, 59, 7-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
