<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422636</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Evaluation of Different Turbocharger Configurations for a Heavy-Duty Partially Premixed Combustion Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Svensson</surname>
                  <given-names>Erik</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Yin</surname>
                  <given-names>Lianhao</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Tunestal</surname>
                  <given-names>Per</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Thern</surname>
                  <given-names>Marcus</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Tuner</surname>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Lund University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>December 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>5</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422609</issue-id>
         <fpage>2575</fpage>
         <lpage>2595</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422636"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The engine concept partially premixed combustion (PPC) has proved higher gross indicated efficiency compared to conventional diesel combustion engines. The relatively simple implementation of the concept is an advantage, however, high gas exchange losses has made its use challenging in multi-cylinder heavy duty engines. With high rates of exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) to dilute the charge and hence limit the combustion rate, the resulting exhaust temperatures are low. The selected boost system must therefore be efficient which could lead to large, complex and costly solutions.</p>
            <p>In the presented work experiments and modelling were combined to evaluate different turbocharger configurations for the PPC concept. Experiments were performed on a multi-cylinder engine. The engine was modified to incorporate long route EGR and a single-stage turbocharger, however, with compressed air from the building being optionally supplied to the compressor. Experimental combustion heat release rates and boundary conditions were used to validate a simulation model. This model was then used to compare three different turbochargers: two single-stage turbochargers and one two-stage. The whole speed and load range was covered in the simulations to determine the engine performance. The influence of high EGR rates as well as the effect of charge air and EGR cooler gas outlet temperatures were also investigated.</p>
            <p>The simulation results showed that the two-stage turbocharger was able to give the highest load over the whole speed range with a brake mean effective pressure of 25.6 bar, whereas the two single-stage turbochargers reached 22.2 and 23.1 bar respectively. The average brake efficiency was 39.3, 39.7 and 40.2 %. It was found that decreasing the inlet temperature is critical for obtaining high loads and system efficiencies. Finally, it was shown that the optimal amount of EGR was dependent on the turbocharger efficiency and cooler temperatures.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Risberg, P., and Ångström, H., "Partially Pre-Mixed Auto-Ignition of Gasoline to Attain Low Smoke and Low NOx at High Load in a Compression Ignition Engine and Comparison with a Diesel Fuel," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0006, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fridriksson, H., Sunden, B., Hajireza, S., and Tuner, M., "CFD Investigation of Heat Transfer in a Diesel Engine with Diesel and PPC Combustion Modes," SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1838, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1838.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Johansson, B., and Cannella, W., “Gasoline partially premixed combustion, the future of internal combustion engines?,” Int. J. Engine Res. 12(3):194-208, 2011, doi:10.1177/1468087411402441.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thring, R., "Homogeneous-Charge Compression-Ignition (HCCI) Engines," SAE Technical Paper 892068, 1989, doi:10.4271/892068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Johansson, B., and Einewall, P., "Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Using Isooctane, Ethanol and Natural Gas - A Comparison with Spark Ignition Operation," SAE Technical Paper 972874, 1997, doi:10.4271/972874.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J., Tunestål, P., and Johansson, B., "Closed-Loop Control of an HCCI Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1031, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Johansson, B., and Tunestal, P., "Partially Premixed Combustion at High Load using Gasoline and Ethanol, a Comparison with Diesel," SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0944, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0944.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lewander, M., Johansson, B., Tunestål, P., Keeler, N. et al., "Evaluation of the Operating Range of Partially Premixed Combustion in a Multi Cylinder Heavy Duty Engine with Extensive EGR," SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1127, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1127.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Johansson, B., Tunestal, P., and Cannella, W., "Influence of Inlet Pressure, EGR, Combustion Phasing, Speed and Pilot Ratio on High Load Gasoline Partially Premixed Combustion," SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1471, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1471.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Wissink, M., DelVescovo, D., and Reitz, R., "RCCI Engine Operation Towards 60% Thermal Efficiency," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0279, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0279.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, S., Hanson, R., Wagner, R., and Reitz, R., "Efficiency and Emissions Mapping of RCCI in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0289, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0289.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A., Curran, S., and Reitz, R., "Characterization of Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Using Premixed Gasoline and Direct-Injected Gasoline with a Cetane Improver on a Multi-Cylinder Engine," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(2):859-877, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0855.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Johansson, B., Amnéus, P., and Mauss, F., "Supercharged Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition," SAE Technical Paper 980787, 1998, doi:10.4271/980787.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noehre, C., Andersson, M., Johansson, B., and Hultqvist, A., "Characterization of Partially Premixed Combustion," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3412, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., "An Experimental Investigation of Fuel Reactivity Controlled PCCI Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Engine," SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):700-716, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0864.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shen, M., Tuner, M., Johansson, B., and Cannella, W., "Effects of EGR and Intake Pressure on PPC of Conventional Diesel, Gasoline and Ethanol in a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-2702, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2702.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shen, M., Tuner, M., and Johansson, B., "Close to Stoichiometric Partially Premixed Combustion -The Benefit of Ethanol in Comparison to Conventional Fuels," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0277, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0277.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, M., Reader, G.T., and Hawley, J.G., “Diesel engine exhaust gas recirculation--a review on advanced and novel concepts,” Energy Convers. Manag. 45(6):883-900, 2004, doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0196-8904(03)00194-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serrano, J., Piqueras, P., Angiolini, E., Meano, C. et al., "On Cooler and Mixing Condensation Phenomena in the Long-Route Exhaust Gas Recirculation Line," SAE Technical Paper 2015-24-2521, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-24-2521.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caton, J.A., “An Assessment of the Thermodynamics Associated With High-Efficiency Engines,” 301-317, 2010, doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1115/ICEF2010-35037.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caton, J., "Thermodynamic Advantages of Low Temperature Combustion (LTC) Engines Using Low Heat Rejection (LHR) Concepts," SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0312, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caton, J.A., “The thermodynamic characteristics of high efficiency, internal-combustion engines,” Energy Convers. Manag. 58:84-93, 2012, doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2012.01.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, J. and Caton, J.A., “Second law analysis of a low temperature combustion diesel engine: Effect of injection timing and exhaust gas recirculation,” Energy 38(1):78-84, 2012, doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2011.12.034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caton, J., "A Comparison of Lean Operation and Exhaust Gas Recirculation: Thermodynamic Reasons for the Increases of Efficiency," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0266, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chadwell, C., Alger, T., Roberts, C., and Arnold, S., "Boosting Simulation of High Efficiency Alternative Combustion Mode Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):375-393, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0358.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tuner, M., Johansson, B., Keller, P., and Becker, M., "Loss Analysis of a HD-PPC Engine with Two-Stage Turbocharging Operating in the European Stationary Cycle," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-2700, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2700.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ingesson, G., Yin, L., Johansson, R., and Tunestal, P., "Simultaneous Control of Combustion Timing and Ignition Delay in Multi-Cylinder Partially Premixed Combustion," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(5):2089-2098, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-24-2424.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yin, L., Ingesson, G., Tunestal, P., Johansson, R. et al., "An Experimental Investigation of a Multi-Cylinder Engine with Gasoline-Like Fuel towards a High Engine Efficiency," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0763, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0763.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Zander, C., Johansson, B., Tunestal, P. et al., "An Advanced Internal Combustion Engine Concept for Low Emissions and High Efficiency from Idle to Max Load Using Gasoline Partially Premixed Combustion," SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2198, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2198.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Svensson, E., “Engine layout.”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LLC., G.T., GT SUITE v2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tuner, M., "Potential ESC Performance of a Multi-Cylinder Heavy Duty PPC Truck Engine: System Simulations based on Single Cylinder Experiments," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0268, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0268.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T. and Keribar, R., "A Model for Predicting Spatially and Time Resolved Convective Heat Transfer in Bowl-in-Piston Combustion Chambers," SAE Technical Paper 850204, 1985, doi:10.4271/850204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kouremenos, D., Rakopoulos, C., Hountalas, D., and Zannis, T., "Development of a Detailed Friction Model to Predict Mechanical Losses at Elevated Maximum Combustion Pressures," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0333, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0333.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Watson, N. and Janota, M.S., “Turbocharging the internal combustion engine,” Macmillan ; Wiley London : New York, ISBN 0333242904 0471870722, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Avola, C., Copeland, C., Duda, T., Burke, R. et al., "Review of Turbocharger Mapping and 1D Modelling Inaccuracies with Specific Focus on Two-Stag Systems," SAE Technical Paper 2015-24-2523, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-24-2523.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals,” McGraw Hill Book Co.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Technologies, G., GT power help document, build V2017-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ettireddy, P., Kotrba, A., Boningari, T., and Smirniotis, P., "Low Temperature SCR Catalysts Optimized for Cold-Start and Low-Load Engine Exhaust Conditions," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1026, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1026.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zel’dovich, Y.B., “The Oxidation of Nitrogen in Combustion Explosions,” Acta Physicochim. U.S.S.R. 21:577-628, 1946.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
