<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">quarbankrevi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016167</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Quarterly Banking Review / רבעון לבנקאות</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>אגוד הבנקים בישראל</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">05571480</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">ג'</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">11</issue>
         <issue-id>i24010132</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24011976</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Recommendations of Committee Appointed to Enquire into Foreign Suppliers' Credits / המלצות הועדה לבדיקת בעיות אשראי של ספקים</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>1963</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>78</fpage>
         <lpage>80</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24011976"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The Committee was originally appointed to consider the economic and monetary effects of credits granted by foreign suppliers to importers in Israel. Such credits, though cheap relative to domestic interest rates, in the view of the Committee, stimulate local demand and increase foreign indebtedness. Later, the discussions were extended to cover the problems of credit for industry and of credit in general, in the light of Government policy aiming at continued economic stability in 1964. The maintenance of manufacturers' prices essential for this stability could in the opinion of the Committee be aided by cheapening industrial credit, both domestic and foreign. It was suggested that industrial credits in foreign currency granted out of foreign currency deposits be forbidden because of their adverse effect on the money supply and on demand. Exemptions should be made only in the following cases : a) for the import of industrial raw materials in bond, which shall be fully paid for when taken out of the bonded warehouse; b) for purchases which can be proved to be made more cheaply or efficiently in this way; c) in order to encourage imports of certain goods from countries with which Israel has clearing agreements. The Committee recommended that deposits at present required when importing raw materials should be abolished gradually. At the same time deposits made when importing unessential finished goods should be increased as a compensatory antiinflationary move. The reduction of interest rates for credits authorized by the Monetary Authorities was urged. Industries receiving special facilities with regard to working capital, should be required to give guarantees ensuring the reduction of credits granted to local customers. It was suggested that bill-brokerage be restricted and monies out of which such transactions are financed be made subject to liquidity regulations. Hence, the amount of authorized credits which represent 22% of deposits subject to liquidity regulations can be increased without expanding the total volume of credits made available from all sources. Stress was laid on the importance of requesting Government departments, municipalities and other public bodies to refrain from receiving credits which have not been provided for in their budgets and which give rise to inflationary pressures. Finally, it was pointed out that the growth of cheaper authorized credits would enable the Government to abolish the existing law governing the fixing of maximum interest rates. (Authorized bank-credits are granted at 9% and 10% p. a. which is below the legal maximum rate of 11%).</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>heb</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


