<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">36/49</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186568</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44438850</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Standardization Sought in Determining Hardenability of Steels: A Symposium</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Use of Hardenability Tests for Selection and Specification of Automotive Steels</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>A. L.</given-names>
                  <surname>BOEGEHOLD</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1941</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>266</fpage>
         <lpage>276</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44438850"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>THE fundamental relationship between cooling rate during quenching and hardness produced in steel is pointed out in this paper. The requirements for a hardenability test bar for determining this relationship for a wide variety of section sizes and steels are given. Some of the methods that have been suggested for testing hardenability are discussed briefly, pointing out that the end-quench specimen is best suited for obtaining this fundamental relationship between hardness and cooling rate. The use of the hardness-cooling rate curve for determining cooling rates in objects to be hardened and also for predicting hardnesses that will be obtained in such a part depending upon the steel used is described. A method of specifying hardenability of steels in terms of hardness cooling rate curves is described and the procedure outlined for determining what the hardenability limits should be. Application of this general procedure for selecting and specifying steels is illustrated in connection with a specific automobile part. A method of interpreting hardenability information obtained from various hardenability tests in terms of hardness cooling rate curves is explained. This translation of hardenability information from any test bar into terms of a hardness-cooling rate curve permits the. use of these various test bars for the purpose of predicting hardness in complicated shaped articles. The H-CR curve is the abbreviated name taken for convenience in referring to the hardness-cooling rate curve.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1254e272a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1254e279" publication-type="other">
Transactions of the American Society for Metals, Vol. XXVI,
1938, pp. 1-22: "Quantitative Hardenability; Proposed Standardization
Test," by J. L. Burns. T. L. Moore, and R. S. Archer.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1254e292a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1254e299" publication-type="other">
"Hardenability, Its Relation to Quenching and Some Quantitative
Data." by M. A. Grossmann. M. Asimow, and S. F. Urban, Symposium
en Hardenability of Alloy Steels. American Society for Metals, 1939.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1254e312a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1254e319" publication-type="other">
"Hardenability and Its Designation, the Hardenability Line,"
by B. R. Queneau and W. H. Mayo, Symposium on Hardenability of
Alloy Steels, American Society for Metals, 1939.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
  </back>
</article>


