<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277659</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental Evaluation of Advanced Turbocharger Performance on a Light Duty Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sun</surname>
                  <given-names>Harold</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hanna</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Niessen</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fulton</surname>
                  <given-names>Brien</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hu</surname>
                  <given-names>Liangjun</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ESI Group</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Curtis</surname>
                  <given-names>Eric</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yi</surname>
                  <given-names>Jianwen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>788</fpage>
         <lpage>796</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277659"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>For diesel engines to meet current and future emissions levels, the amount of EGR required to reach these levels has increased dramatically. This increased EGR has posed big challenges for conventional turbocharger technology to meet the higher emissions requirements while maintaining or improving other vehicle attributes, to the extent that some OEMs resort to multiple turbocharger configurations. These configurations can include parallel, series sequential, or parallel - series turbocharger systems, which would inevitably run into other issues, such as cost, packaging, and thermal loss, etc.</p>
            <p>This study, as part of a U.S. Department of Energy (USDoE) sponsored research program, is focused on the experimental evaluation of the emission and performance of a modern diesel engine with an advanced single stage turbocharger.</p>
            <p>A production IHI (Ishikawajima Harima Heavy Industries) turbocharger was selected as the base architecture for the turbocharger design with optimizations focused on compressor impeller and turbine wheel designs.</p>
            <p>An advanced impeller design was used on the compressor side to improve the efficiency and surge margin at low mass flow areas of the compressor map, allowing greater EGR flow while extending the flow capacity by using an active casing treatment on the compressor cover.</p>
            <p>Mixed flow turbine technology was used on the turbine side, due to its performance characteristics; particularly high efficiency at low speed ratios relative to the base conventional radial flow turbine. This characteristic is relevant to increased EGR operation required for future diesel applications.</p>
            <p>Both steady state and transient engine dynamometer testing of FTP transient cycles at Tier II Bin 5 emission levels show that the advanced turbocharger technology enables around 3% fuel economy improvement on the engine while meeting the same emissions level.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zellbeck Hans, Ross Tilo, Guhr Carsten, “New Methods for Proper Boosting Systems,” Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nitta, J., Minato, A., and Shimazaki, N., “Performance Evaluation of Three-Stage Turbocharging System for Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0374, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0374.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Uchida Hiroshi, Kashimoto Akinobu, Iwakiri Yuji, “Development of wide flow range compressor with variable inlet guide vane,” R&amp;D Review of Toyota CRDL, Vol. 41, No. 3, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fraser, N., Fleischer, T., Thornton, J., and Rueckauf, J., “Development of a Fully Variable Compressor Map Enhancer for Automotive Application,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1558, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-1558.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mohtar, H., Chesse, P., Yammine, A., and Hetet, J., “Variable Inlet Guide Vanes in a Turbocharger Centrifugal Compressor: Local and Global Study,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0301, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-0301.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nikpour Bahram, “Turbocharger compressor flow range improvement for future heavy duty diesel engines,” THIESEL 2004 Conference on Thermoand Fluid Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fisher, F., “Application of Map Width Enhancement Devices to Turbocharger Compressor Stages,” SAE Technical Paper 880794, 1988, doi: 10.4271/880794.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamaguchi S., Yamaguchi H., Goto S., Hakao H. and Nakamura F., “The development of effective casing treatment for turbocharger compressors,” IMechE, C602/008/2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sakaguchi Daisaku, Nagoshi Keiichi, Tanimura Motoki, Ishida Masahiro and Ueki Hironobu, “Effect of Guide Vane in Ring Groove Arrangement for a Small Turbocharger,” American Institute of Physics, The 10th Asian international conference on fluid machinery June 28, 2010 -- Volume 1225, pp. 47-54</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barton M. T., Mansour M. L., Liu J. S., and Palmer D. L., “Numerical optimization of a vaned shroud design for increased operability margin in modern centrifugal compressors,” Proceedings of ASME Turbo Expo 2004 Power for Land, Sea, and Air, June 14-17, 2004, Vienna, Austria, GT2004-54287</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sivagnanasundaram S, Spence S and Early J, Nikpour B, “Investigation of compressor map width enhancement and the inducer flow field using a shroud bleed slot,” 9th turbocharger conference, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun H., Hu L, Zhang J, Hanna D, Krivitzky E, Larosiliere L, Lai M-C, Yang C, “Switchable Dual-Port Casing Treatment Scheme for Enhanced Turbocharger Compressor Operating Range,” IMechE, Journal of Automobile Engineering, 2013 (to be published)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hu, L., Yang, C., Sun, H., Krivizky, E. et al., “Experimental and Computational Analysis of Impact of Self Recirculation Casing Treatment on Turbocharger Compressor,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1224, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1224.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hu Liangjun, Investigation of operability margin improvement in an advanced turbocharger centrifugal compressor for HCCI diesel engine. Ph.D Dissertation, Beijing Institute of Technology, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Watson N., and Janota R. S., Turbocharging the internal combustion engine, 1982, MacMillan, London</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Whitefield A. and Baines N.C., Design of Radial Machines, 1990, Longman, England</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wallace F. J., “A systematic approach to the design of radial inflow and mixed flow turbines,” NACA Report, No. CP 1180</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
