<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014688</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Foreign Language Learners’ Beliefs about CALL</article-title>
            <subtitle>The Case of a U.S. Midwestern University</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Sydorenko</surname>
                  <given-names>Tetyana</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Tetyana Sydorenko (Ph.D., Michigan State University) is an Assistant Professor of Applied Linguistics at Portland State University. Her research interests include teaching and acquisition of SL pragmatics, computer-assisted language learning, psycholinguistic processes in SL acquisition, and assessment. She is currently investigating the use of adaptive computer-simulated conversations in the teaching of SL pragmatics.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hsieh</surname>
                  <given-names>Ching-Ni</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Ching-Ni Hsieh is Research Project Manager II at the Center for English Language Learning and Assessment at the Educational Testing Service, Princeton, NJ. She manages and leads research projects related to language testing and assessment. Her current research focuses on young language learner assessments and test validation. Ching-Ni received her Ph.D. in Second Language Studies from Michigan State University and a Master’s in English Language Teaching from the University of Nottingham.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ahn</surname>
                  <given-names>Seongmee</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a3">
                  <sup>3</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Seongmee Ahn received her Ph.D. in Second Language Studies at Michigan State University. Her main area of research is second language acquisition through conversational interaction. Her research also spans a variety of topics, such as heritage language acquisition, second language pragmatic development, second language writing, as well as computer-assisted language learning.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Arnold</surname>
                  <given-names>Nike</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a4">
                  <sup>4</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Nike Arnold (Ph.D., the University of Texas at Austin) is Associate Professor of Applied Linguistics at Portland State University in Oregon, USA. Her research focuses on online collaboration in L2 learning and teacher education as well as the role of affective factors in L2 learning and teaching.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>1</sup>Portland State University, Portland, OR.</aff>
            <aff id="a2">
               <sup>2</sup>Educational Testing Service.</aff>
            <aff id="a3">
               <sup>3</sup>Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI.</aff>
            <aff id="a4">
               <sup>4</sup>Portland State University, Portland, OR.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>34</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014683</issue-id>
         <fpage>196</fpage>
         <lpage>218</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2017, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014688"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>A significant body of research has examined language learners’ attitudes toward particular technologies used in foreign language classrooms. However, literature is scarce on foreign language learners’ beliefs toward computer-assisted language learning (CALL) in general. To narrow this gap, we investigated the constructs that compose a system of language learners’ beliefs toward CALL at a large U.S. university and examined whether the amount of technology used and the target language (TL) play a role in shaping learners’ beliefs. The findings of this large-scale survey of 2,061 students studying nineteen different TLs indicate four factors comprising learners’ belief systems toward CALL in this context: efficacy of technology for language learning and its connection to motivation, satisfaction with technology used in the learners’ classes, specific benefits of technology, and the importance of computer skills and technical support. Learners’ CALL beliefs were more positive when they had had more exposure to technology in their classes, but this varied based on the TL. Higher use of technology outside of class resulted in more positive beliefs across the board, independent of the TL. The pedagogical implications are that greater exposure to effective and varied models of CALL might result in more positive beliefs toward it.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>foreign language learner beliefs about CALL</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>large-scale survey</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>principal component analysis</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alanen, R. (2003). A sociocultural approach to young language learners’ beliefs about language learning. In P. Kalaja &amp; A. M. F. Barcelos (Eds.), Beliefs about SLA: New research approaches (pp. 55–85). Dordrecht: Kluwer. http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4020-4751-0_3</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anyaegbu, R., Ting, W., &amp; Li, Y. (2012). Serious game motivation in an EFL classroom in Chinese primary school. TOJET, 11(1), 154–164. Retrieved from http://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/EJ976578.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnold, N. (2007). Technology-mediated learning 10 years later: Emphasizing pedagogical or utilitarian applications? Foreign Language Annals, 40(1), 161–181. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1944-9720.2007.tb02859.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnold, N., &amp; Ducate, L. (2015). Contextualized views of practices and competencies in CALL teacher education research. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 19(1), 1–9. Retrieved from http://llt.msu.edu/issues/february2015/commentary.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ayres, R. (2002). Learner attitudes towards the use of CALL. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 15(3), 241–249. http://dx.doi.org/10.1076/call.15.3.241.8189</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barcelos, A. M. F., &amp; Kalaja, P. (2011). Introduction to Beliefs about SLA Revisited. System, 39(3), 281–189. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.system.2011.07.001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barr, D. (2004). Students and ICT: An analysis of student reaction to the use of computer technology in language learning. IALLT Journal of Language Learning Technologies, 36(2), 19–38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bell, T. (2005). Behaviors and attitudes of effective foreign language teachers: Results of a questionnaire study. Foreign Language Annals, 38(2), 259–270. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1944-9720.2005.tb02490.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blake, R., Wilson, N. L., Cetto, M., &amp; Pardo-Ballester, C. (2008). Measuring oral proficiency in distance, face-to-face, and blended classrooms. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 12(3), 114–127. Retrieved from http://llt.msu.edu/vol12num3/blakeetal.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borg, S. (2003). Teacher cognition in language teaching: A review of research on what language teachers think, know, believe, and do. Language Teaching, 36, 81‒109. http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0261444803001903</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borg, S. (2011). The impact of in-service teacher education on language teachers’ beliefs. System, 39, 370–380. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.system.2011.07.009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown, A. V. (2009). Students’ and teachers’ perceptions of effective foreign language teaching: A comparison of ideals. The Modern Language Journal, 93, 46–60. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.2009.00827.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chapelle, C. (2010). Evaluating computer technology for language learning. TESL-Ontario, 36, 56–67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, J. J., &amp; Yang, S. C. (2014). Fostering foreign language learning through technology-enhanced intercultural projects. Language Learning &amp; Technology 18(1), 57–75. Retrieved from http://llt.msu.edu/issues/february2014/yangchen.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cohen, B. (2001). Explaining psychological statistics (2nd ed.). Hoboken, NJ: Wiley. Cohen, J. (1988). Statistical power analysis for the behavior sciences (2nd ed.). Hillsdale, NJ: Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cohen, A. D., &amp; Dornyei, Z. (2002). Focus on the language learner: Motivation, styles and strategies. In N. Schmitt (Ed.), An introduction to applied linguistics (pp. 170–190). London: Arnold.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diab, R. L. (2006). University students’ beliefs about learning English and French in Lebanon. System, 34(1), 80–96. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.system.2005.06.014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dornyei, Z. (2005). The psychology of the language learner: Individual differences in second language acquisition. Mahwah, NJ: Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fatemi Jahromi, S. A., &amp; Salimi, F. (2013). Exploring the human element of computer-assisted language learning: An Iranian context. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 26(2), 158–176. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2011.643411</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Field, A. (2009). Discovering statistics using SPSS (3rd ed.). London: Sage Publications.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gee, J. P. (2007). What video games have to teach us about learning and literacy. Basingstoke: Palgrave Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guichon, N., &amp; Hauck, M. (2011). Editorial: Teacher education research in CALL and CMC: More in demand than ever. ReCALL, 23, 187‒199. http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0958344011000139</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Horwitz, E. K. (1988). The beliefs about language learning of beginning university foreign language students. The Modern Language Journal, 72, 283–294. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.1988.tb04190.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Horwitz, E. K. (1999). Cultural and situational influences on foreign language learners’ beliefs about language learning: A review of BALLI studies. System, 27, 557–576. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0346-251X(99)00050-0</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalaja, P., &amp; Barcelos, A. M. F. (2003). Introduction. In P. Kalaja &amp; M. F. Barcelos (Eds.), Beliefs about SLA: New research approaches (pp. 1–4). Dordrecht: Kluwer. http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4020-4751-0</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lai, C. (2013). A framework for developing self-directed technology use for language learning. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 17(2), 100–122. Retrieved from http://llt.msu.edu/issues/june2013/lai.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lai, C., &amp; Gu, M. Y. (2011). Self-regulated out-of-class language learning with technology. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 24, 317–335. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2011.568417</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lai, C., &amp; Morrison, B. (2013). Towards an agenda for learner preparation in technology-enhanced language learning environments. CALICO Journal, 30(2), 154–162. http://dx.doi.org/10.11139/cj.30.2.154-162</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Loewen, S., Li, S., Fei, F., Thompson, A., Nakatsukasa, K., Ahn, S., &amp; Chen, X. (2009). Second language learners’ beliefs about grammar instruction and error correction. The Modern Language Journal, 93(1), 91–104. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.2009.00830.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu, J., Throssell, P., &amp; Jiang, H. (2013). Exploring the application of computer-assisted English learning in a Chinese mainland context: Based on students’ attitudes and behaviours. International Journal of English Linguistics, 3(3), 31–41. http://dx.doi.org/10.5539/ijel.v3n3p31</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Margaryan, A., Littlejohn, A., &amp; Vojt, G. (2011). Are digital natives a myth or reality? University students’ use of digital technologies. Computers &amp; Education, 56, 429–440. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2010.09.004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mori, Y. (1999). Epistemological beliefs and language learning beliefs: What do language learners believe about their learning? Language Learning, 49, 377–415. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/0023-8333.00094</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murday, K., Ushida, D., &amp; Chenoweth, N. A. (2008). Learners’ and teachers’ perspectives on language online. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 21(2), 125–142. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09588220801943718</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oz, H. (2015). Investigating the relationship between foreign language learning and CALL attitudes among EFL freshman students. Procedia – Social and Behavioral Sciences, 176, 1041–1049. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sbspro.2015.01.576</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reinders, H., &amp; Wattana, S. (2015). Affect and willingness to communicate in digital game-based learning. ReCALL, 27, 38–57. http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0958344014000226</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rivera, G. M., &amp; Matsuzawa, C. (2007). Multiple-language program assessment: Learners’ perspectives on first-year and second-year college foreign language programs and their implications for program improvement. Foreign Language Annals, 40, 569–583. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1944-9720.2007.tb02881.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scida, E. E., &amp; Saury, R. E. (2006). Hybrid courses and their impact on student and classroom performance: A case study at the University of Virginia. CALICO Journal, 23(3), 517–531. Retrieved from https://calico.org/html/article_104.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schulz, R. (1996). Focus on form in the foreign language classroom: Students’ and teachers’ views on error correction and the role of grammar. Foreign Language Annals, 17, 195–202. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1944-9720.1996.tb01247.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steel, C. H., &amp; Levy, M. (2013). Language students and their technologies: Charting the evolution 2006–2011. ReCALL, 25, 306–320. http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0958344013000128</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stevens, J. P. (1992). Applied multivariate statistics for the social sciences (2nd ed.). Hillsdale, NJ: Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stockwell, G. (2013). Technology and motivation in English language teaching and learning. In E. Ushioda (Ed.), International perspectives on motivation: Language learning and professional challenges (pp. 156–175). New York: Palgrave Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sydorenko, T. (2011). Exploring the potential of rehearsal via automatized structured tasks versus face-to-face pair work to facilitate pragmatic and oral development. (Doctoral dissertation) Michigan State University. Dissertation Abstracts International 3464977.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Compernolle, R. A., &amp; Williams, L. (2009). (Re)situating the role(s) of new technologies in world language teaching and learning. In R. Oxford &amp; J. Oxford (Eds.), Second language teaching and learning in the Net generation (pp. 9–21). Manoa, HI: National Foreign Language Resource Center.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, L., Ertmer, P.A., &amp; Newby, T.J. (2004). Increasing preservice teachers’ self-efficacy beliefs for technology integration. Journal of Research on Technology in Education, 36(3), 231–250. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15391523.2004.10782414</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wesely, P. M. (2012). Learner attitudes, perceptions, and beliefs in language learning. Foreign Language Annals, 45(s1), s98–s117. http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1944-9720.2012.01181.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Winke, P., Goertler, S., &amp; Amuzie, G. (2010). Commonly taught and less commonly taught language learners: Are they equally prepared for CALL and online language learning? Computer Assisted Language Learning, 23(3), 199–219. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2010.486576</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woods, D., 2003. The social construction of beliefs in the language classroom. In P. Kalaja &amp; A. M. F. Barcelos (Eds.), Beliefs about SLA: New research approaches (pp. 201–229). Dordrecht: Kluwer. http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4020-4751-0_9</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
