<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277941</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Numerical Investigation of the Relationship between Engine Performance and Turbocharger Speed of a Four Stroke Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Vichi</surname>
                  <given-names>Giovanni</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Florence</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Stiaccini</surname>
                  <given-names>Isacco</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Florence</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bellissima</surname>
                  <given-names>Alessandro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Yanmar R&amp;D Europe</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Minamino</surname>
                  <given-names>Ryota</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Yanmar Co. Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ferrari</surname>
                  <given-names>Lorenzo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Florence</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ferrara</surname>
                  <given-names>Giovanni</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Florence</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>January 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277910</issue-id>
         <fpage>288</fpage>
         <lpage>302</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International and Copyright © 2014 SAE Japan</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277941"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A condition monitoring activity consists in the analysis of several information from the engine and the subsequent data elaboration to assess its operating condition. By means of a continuous supervision of the operating conditions the internal combustion engine performance can be maintained at design-level in the long term.</p>
            <p>The growing use of turbocharger (TC) in automotive field suggests to use the TC speed as a possible feedback of engine operating condition. Indeed, the turbocharger behavior is influenced by the thermo and fluid-dynamic conditions in the cylinder exhaust port: this feature suggests that the TC speed could provide useful data about the engine cycle.</p>
            <p>In this study the authors describe a theoretical and numerical analysis focused on the TC speed in a four stroke turbo-diesel engine. The purpose of this study is to highlight whether the TC speed allows one to detect the variation of the engine parameters. In addition, when the TC speed alone is not sufficient to detect the variation in the engine operating conditions, the proper set of additional, easy-to-measure, engine parameters is studied to univocally identify the causes of the variation. The analysis was carried out numerically by using a commercial 1D code calibrated with experimental data on a four cylinders diesel engine coupled with a turbocharger.</p>
            <p>The numerical data was analyzed to estimate the optimal set of information required to identify the changed engine parameter that affects in particular the combustion process. By using the calibrated model, a sensitivity analysis of the detection parameter response, with particular attention to TC speed variations, was carried out by varying the operating conditions of the engine such as fuel mass flow rate, EGR rate and back pressure at the turbine outlet.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Citron, S., O'Higgins, J., and Chen, L., “Cylinder by Cylinder Engine Pressure and Pressure Torque Waveform Determination Utilizing Speed Fluctuations,” SAE Technical Paper 890486, 1989, doi:10.4271/890486.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rizzoni, G., “Diagnosis of individual Cylinder Misfires by Signature Analysis of Crankshaft Speed Fluctuations,” SAE Technical Paper 890884, 1989, doi:10.4271/890884.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Connolly, F.T. and Yagle, A.E., “Modeling and Identification of the Combustion Pressure Process in Internal Combustion Engines Using Engine Speed Fluctuations”, American Society of Mechanical Engineers, Dynamic Systems and Control Division, Anaheim, CA, 1992, pp. 191-206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moro. D., Cavina, N, and Ponti, F., “In-cylinder pressure reconstruction based on instantaneous engine speed signal”, J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power 124 (2002) 220-225.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Citron, S., O'Higgins, J., and Chen, L., “Cylinder by Cylinder Engine Pressure and Pressure Torque Waveform Determination Utilizing Speed Fluctuations,” SAE Technical Paper 890486, 1989, doi:10.4271/890486.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">lida, K., Akishino, K., and Kido, K., “IMEP Estimation from Instantaneous Crankshaft Torque Variation,” SAE Technical Paper 900617, 1990, doi:10.4271/900617.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown, T. and Neill, W., “Determination of Engine Cylinder Pressures from Crankshaft Speed Fluctuations,” SAE Technical Paper 920463, 1992, doi:10.4271/920463.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, S. and Chen, S., “Engine Diagnostics by Dynamic Shaft Measurement: A Progress Report,” SAE Technical Paper 932412, 1993, doi:10.4271/932412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ren, Y., “Detection of knocking combustion in diesel engines by inverse filtering of structural vibration signals”, Ph.D. Thesis, University of New South Wales, Australia, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Antoni, J., Daniere, J., Guillet, F. and Randall, R.b., “Effective vibration analysis of ICengines using cyclostationarity. Part II - new results on the reconstruction ofthe cylinder pressures”, Journal of Sound and Vibration 257 (5) (2002) 839-856.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnsson, R., “Cylinder pressure reconstruction based on complex radial biasis function networks from vibration and speed signals”, Mechanical Systems and signal Processing 20 (2006) 1923-1940.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barelli, L, Bidini, G, Buratti, C. and Mariani, R, “Diagnosis of internal combustion acoustic pressure non-intrusive measurements”, Applied Thermal Engineering 29 (2009) 1707- 1713.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
