<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24909671</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>It’s The Data, Stupid</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Akst</surname>
                  <given-names>George</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr George Akst is the Senior Analyst for the Marine Corps Combat Development Command (MCCDC), Quantico, VA. Dr Akst graduated cum laude from the City College of New York and received his PhD in mathematics from the University of Illinois in 1974. He served in the Corps of Engineers in the Army Reserve from 1970 through 1978, and graduated from the Engineer Officer Basic Course at Fort Belvoir in 1972. After receiving his PhD, Dr Akst was a professor of mathematics at New Mexico State University (1974-1976) and the California State University at San Bernardino (1976-1979).</p>
                  <p>In 1979, Dr Akst joined the Center for Naval Analyses (CNA), and entered the career of defense analysis and operations research. During his 19-year tenure, he was a research operations analyst and study director for numerous projects. He also served as the scientific analyst to Headquarters, Marine Corps (Plans, Policies, and Operations (PP&amp;O) and Programs and Resources (P&amp;R)), MCCDC, and the Navy Staff (Director of Assessments (N-81); and as the field representative to the Fleet Marine Force, Pacific</p>
                  <p>He entered the Federal service in 1998, as the Deputy Director of the Studies and Analysis Division, MCCDC. In this position, he represented the Marine Corps at the highest levels of Office of the Secretary of Defense (OSD) and the Joint Staff on analytical matters, and served on inter-service and international panels.</p>
                  <p>Dr Akst’s decorations include the Navy Superior Public Service Award, USMC Certificate of Commendation, and the CNA Phil E. DePoy Award for Analytical Excellence. He is a member of Phi Beta Kappa, Sigma Xi, and the Military Operations Research Society (MORS). He has a wife, Barbara, and two children.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2007</year>
            <string-date>December 2007</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>40</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e24909669</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>28</lpage>
         <page-range>1, 27-28</page-range>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2007, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24909671"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
