<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466821</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466828</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>What Happens in Nevada? Self-Selecting into Lax Law</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Michal</given-names>
                  <surname>Barzuza</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>David C.</given-names>
                  <surname>Smith</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>3593</fpage>
         <lpage>3627</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466828"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We find that Nevada, the second most popular state for out-of-state incorporations and a state with lax corporate law, attracts firms that are 30–40% more likely to report financial results that later require restatement than firms incorporated in other states, including Delaware. Our results suggest that firms favoring protections for insiders select Nevada as a corporate home, and these firms are prone to financial reporting failures. We provide some evidence that Nevada law also has a causal impact by increasing a Nevada firm's propensity to misreport financials after the firm has incorporated in Nevada.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d8e263a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e270" publication-type="other">
Research arguing that competition leads to a "race to the top" includes Easterbrook and Fischel (1991), Romano
(1985,1993a, 1993b, 2001), and Winter (1977). For race-to-the-bottom literature, see, for example, Cary (1974),
Bebchuk (1992), Bebchuk and Ferrell (2001), and Bar-Gill, Barzuza, and Bebchuk (2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e283a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e290" publication-type="other">
For instance, Michael J. Bonner, a Nevada attorney testifying before the Nevada legislature in favor of the 2001
amendments stated: "We have to recognize that... it is Delaware versus home state versus Nevada, if it is a tie,
if the corporate laws of these jurisdictions are equally favorable... typically, they are going to select Delaware.
... If Nevada can enhance the liability protection for [directors and officers] and strike the proper balance to not
protect those who have participated in criminal activity or fraud, the state will go a long way to making Nevada
an attractive place in which to incorporate." Nevada state senator Mark James followed on with the recognition
that "Directors are the ones who decide where to incorporate.... This will be a major incentive." See Bill Draft
Request 7-1547, introduced as Senate Bill 577, Hearing on S.B. 277 Before the Senate Comm. on the Judiciary,
2001 Leg., 71st Sess. (Nev. 2001 ), at 10-12.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e322a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e329" publication-type="other">
For the statement from the Nevada Secretary of State, see http://nvsos.gov/index.aspx?page=152 and
Lionel Sawyer and Collins Law Firm, "Legal Advantages: A Comparison with Delaware, Why
Nevada?" http://whynevada.com/commercialrecordingsAVhy.Nevada.Legal.Comparison.pdf. For examples of
online advertisements, see http://www.nevadal23.com/, http://www.nchinc.com/, and http://www.val-u-corp.
com/whynev.html, http://www.nevadal23.com/, respectively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e348a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e355" publication-type="other">
Plumlee and Yohn (2010) document a rise in aggregate restatements over the 2002-6 period and attribute the
rise to an increase in the complexity of audit rules following the adoption of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e366a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e373" publication-type="other">
Two concurrent papers provide additional evidence on the behavior of Nevada-incorporated firms. In an
examination of foreign firms that engage in "reverse mergers" through U.S. shell companies, Siegel and Wang
(2013) find that the choice of a Nevada-incorporate shell predicts a high likelihood for problematic restatements,
including restatements that correct for overstated income and restatements that lead to fraud or regulatory
investigations. Donelson and Yust (Forthcoming) examine the influence of the 2001 change to Nevada law and
find that the Nevada firm values, pay-for-performance sensitivity, and operating performance decline following
the 2001 law change.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e399a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e406" publication-type="other">
Efforts include "early and comprehensive case management, active judicial participation in settlement, priority
for hearing settings to avoid business disruption, and predictability of legal decisions in commercial matters."
See http://nvsos.gov/index.aspx?page=152. There is evidence that the Nevada business court still suffers from
deficiencies relative to the Delaware chancery court (Kahan and Kamar 2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e422a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e429" publication-type="other">
See the discussion by Warren Lowman and Dr. Paul Chalekian, Secretary of the State Response and
Implementation Plan, at http://nvsos.gov/Modules/ShowDocument.aspx?documentid=1282. Fees from public
incorporations are difficult to disentangle from overall fees from incorporations, including fees collected from
LLCs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e445a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e452" publication-type="other">
See Nevada Revised Statutes 78.138(7):7.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e459a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e466" publication-type="other">
Nevada corporate anti-takeover law is similarly more protective of managers than Delaware law (see Barzuza
2012). Panel B of Table Al provides a summary of the differences between Nevada and Delaware law in terms
of the standards they apply to management use of defensive tactics.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e479a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e486" publication-type="other">
Compustat reports only the most recent state of incorporation. It does not maintain a time series history of
incorporations. However, the Mergent database, available since 2000, does follow firms from state to state.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e497a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e504" publication-type="other">
For discussions of the severity of accounting misstatements and the consequences of their disclosure, see Plumlee
and Yohn (2010) and Files, Swanson, and Tse (2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e514a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e521" publication-type="other">
Consistent with these findings, Bar-Gill and Bebchuk (2002) develop a model demonstrating how compensation
could incentivize managers to misreport.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e531a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e538" publication-type="other">
See GMIRatings (2012) for an in-depth description of the AGR and its reliability for predicting cases of
accounting fraud or misleading activities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e548a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e555" publication-type="other">
For our performance regressions, in which Tobin's q is the dependent variable, we also use the natural logarithm
of total revenue (Log Sales) as a measure of size.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e565a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e572" publication-type="other">
Earlier versions of the paper have also reported results using a 1% cutoff in coding missing observations. The
results and inferences from the paper are unchanged when using the less restrictive cutoff.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e582a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e589" publication-type="other">
For the earlier part of the sample, Big-4 Auditor also equals one for clients that separately utilized PriceWaterhouse
and Coopers &amp; Lybrand (who merged in 1998) and Arthur Andersen (which ceased to exist in 2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e600a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e607" publication-type="other">
Multiple restatements within a year are treated the same as one restatement, so no weighting occurs within a year
for more than one restatement.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e617a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e624" publication-type="other">
Note that the average difference in matched restatement rates is still statistically different from zero when we
exclude two years in which the differences appear particularly large, 2006 (difference = 7.3 percentage points)
and 2010 (difference = 7.1 percentage points). If we drop both 2006 and 2010 from the sample, then the average
Nevada firm still restates an average of 2.42 percentage points more often than the average matched Delaware
firm (or at a rate that is 24% higher than the matched Delaware rate). This difference is still statistically significant
at the 5% level in a paired r-test (p-value = 0.041%).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e647a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e654" publication-type="other">
The post-2001 results could also be weaker because the sample size is small and young. The post-2001 IPO firms
have not been around as long to observe potential restatements of financial disclosures.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e664a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e671" publication-type="other">
Although we do not report the statistics in Table 8, tests for the "strength" of the headquarter proximity instrument
suggest that is a good instrument. Stock and Yogo (2005) tests reject the null hypothesis of weak instruments at all
simulated size levels, although this test is not well specified when errors are heteroscedastic. First-stage F-tests
and r-stats on the excluded variable that account for firm-level clustering of errors—a more robust test—also
easily reject the null hypothesis of weak instruments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e690a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e697" publication-type="other">
A third approach to studying the valuation consequences of incorporating in Nevada would be to examine the
long-term return performance of Nevada-incorporated firms along the lines of Gompers, Ishii, and Metrick (2003)
and Bebchuk, Cohen, and Ferrell (2009). We do not attempt such a study here. However, Torous (2013) shows
that firms scoring poorly on the GMIRatings AGR scale have long-term stock performance that is significantly
lower that firms with high AGR scores, suggesting that the long-term performance of Nevada firms might be
lower than their less aggressive peers in other states.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d8e729a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e733" publication-type="other">
Adams, R. B., B. E. Hermalin, and M. S. Weisbach. 2010. The role of boards of directors in corporate governance:
A conceptual framework and survey. Journal of Economic Literature 48:58-107.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e743a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e747" publication-type="other">
Anderson, K. L., and Yohn, T. L. 2002. The effect of 10K restatements on firm value, information asymmetries,
and investors' reliance on earnings. Working Paper, available at http://ssrn.com/abstract=332380.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e757a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e761" publication-type="other">
Arien, J. H., and W. J. Carney. 1992. Vicarious liability for fraud on securities market: Theory and evidence.
University of Illinois Law Review, 691-740.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e771a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e775" publication-type="other">
Baber, W. R., S.-H. Kang, L. Liang, and Z. Zhu. 2013. External corporate governance, and misreporting. Working
Paper, available at http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=760324.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e786a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e790" publication-type="other">
Bar-Gill, O., M. Barzuza, and L. A. Bebchuk. 2006. The market for corporate law. Journal of Institutional and
Theoretical Economics 162:134—71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e800a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e804" publication-type="other">
Bar-Gill, O., and L. A. Bebchuk. 2002. Misreporting corporate performance. Harvard Olin Discussion Paper
No. 400.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e814a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e818" publication-type="other">
Barzuza, M. 2009. The state of state antitakeover law. Virginia Law Review 95:1973-2052.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e825a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e829" publication-type="other">
. 2012. Market segmentation: The rise of Nevada as a liability-free jurisdiction. Virginia Law Review
98:935-1000.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e839a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e843" publication-type="other">
Bebchuk, L. A. 1992. Federalism and the corporation: The desirable limits on state competition in corporate law.
Harvard Law Review 105:1435-1510.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e853a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e857" publication-type="other">
Bebchuk, L. A., and A. Cohen. 2003. Firms' decisions where to incorporate. Journal of Law and Economics
46:383-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e868a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e872" publication-type="other">
Bebchuk, L. A., A. Cohen, and A. Ferrell. 2009. What matters in corporate governance? Review of Financial
Studies 22:783-827.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e882a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e886" publication-type="other">
Bebchuk, L. A., and A. Ferrell. 2001. Federalism and takeover law: The race to protect managers from takeovers.
In D. Esty and D. Geradin (Eds.), Regulatory competition and economic integration, 68-94. Oxford: Oxford
University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e899a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e903" publication-type="other">
Bebchuk, L. A., and A. Hamdani. 2002. Vigorous race or leisurely walk: Reconsidering the competition over
corporate charters. Yale Law Journal 112:553-615.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e913a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e917" publication-type="other">
Burns, N., and S. Kedia. 2006. The impact of performance-based compensation on misreporting. Journal of
Financial Economics 36:35-57.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e927a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e931" publication-type="other">
Cary, W. L. 1974. Federalism and corporate law: Reflections upon Delaware. Yale Law Journal 83:663-705.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e938a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e942" publication-type="other">
Coffee, J. C. 2005. A theory of corporate scandals: Why the U.S. and Europe differ. Oxford Review of Economic
Policy 21:198-211.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e953a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e957" publication-type="other">
Daines, R. M. 2001. Does Delaware law improve firm value? Journal of Financial Economics 62: 525-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e964a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e968" publication-type="other">
Donelson, D. C., and C. G Yust. Forthcoming. Litigation risk and agency costs: Evidence from Nevada corporate
law. Journal of Law and Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e978a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e982" publication-type="other">
Easterbrook, F. H., and D. R. Fischel. 1991. The economic structure of corporate law. Cambridge, MA: Harvard
University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e992a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e996" publication-type="other">
Efendi, J., A. Srivastava, and E. P. Swanson. 2007. Why do corporate managers misstate financial statements?
The role of option compensation and other factors. Journal of Financial Economics 85:667-708.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1006a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1010" publication-type="other">
Ettredge, M., K. R. Smith, S. Scholz, and L. Sun. 2010. How do misstatements begin? Evidence of Biased
financial reporting preceding misstatements. Journal of Business Finance and Accounting 37:332-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1020a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1024" publication-type="other">
Files, R., E. P. Swanson, and S. Y. Tse. 2009. Stealth disclosure of accounting statements. Accounting Review
84:1495-1520.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1035a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1039" publication-type="other">
GMIRatings. 2012. Eyes wide shut: Behind the masks of accounting fraud. Research Report, available at
http://www3.gmiratings.com/home/2012/ll/eyes-wide-shut-behind-the-masks-of-accounting-fraud-2/.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1049a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1053" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P., J. Ishii, and A. Metrick. 2003. Corporate governance and equity prices. Quarterly Journal of
Economics 107-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1063a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1067" publication-type="other">
Gordon, J. N. 2003. Governance failures of the enron board and the new information order of Sarbanes-Oxley.
Connecticut Law Review 35:1125-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1077a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1081" publication-type="other">
Heckman, J., H. Ichimura, J. Smith, and P. Todd. 1998. Characterizing selection bias using experimental data.
Econometrica 66:1017-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1091a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1095" publication-type="other">
Hermalin, B. E., and M. S. Weisbach. 1998. Endogenously chosen boards of directors and their monitoring of
the CEO. American Economic Review 88:96-118.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1105a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1109" publication-type="other">
. 2003. Boards of directors as an endogenously determined institution: A survey of the economic literature.
Economic Policy Review 9:7-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1120a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1124" publication-type="other">
Hribar, P., and N. T. Jenkins. 2004. The effect of accounting restatements on earnings revisions and the estimated
cost of capital. Review of Accounting Studies 9:337-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1134a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1138" publication-type="other">
Kahan, M., and E. Kamar. 2002. The myth of state competition in corporate law. Stanford Law Review
55:697-749.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1148a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1152" publication-type="other">
Palmrose, Z., V. Richardson, and S. Scholz, S. 2004. Determinants of market reactions to restatement
announcements. Journal of Accounting and Economics 37:59-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1162a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1166" publication-type="other">
Plumlee, M., and T. L. Yohn. 2010. An analysis of the underlying causes attributed to restatements. Accounting
Horizons 24:41-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1176a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1180" publication-type="other">
Ritter, J. 2013. Initial public offerings: Updated statistics. University of Florida, manuscript available at
http://bear.warrington.ufl.edu/ritter/IPOs2013Statistics.pdf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1190a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1194" publication-type="other">
Romano, R. 1985. Law as a product: Some pieces of the incorporation puzzle. Journal of Law, Economics, and
Organization 1:225-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1205a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1209" publication-type="other">
. 1993a. The genius of American corporate law. Washington, D.C.: AEI Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1216a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1220" publication-type="other">
1993b. Competition for corporate charters and the lesson of takeover statutes. Fordham Law Review
61:843-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1230a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1234" publication-type="other">
. 2001. The need for competition in international securities regulation. Theoretical Inquiries in Law
2:387-562.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1244a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1248" publication-type="other">
Rosenbaum, P. R., and D. B. Rubin. 1983. The central role of the propensity score in observational studies for
causal effects. Biometrika 70:41-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1258a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1262" publication-type="other">
Siegel, J. I., and Y. Wang. 2013. Cross-border reverse mergers: Causes and consequences. Harvard Business
School Strategy Unit Working Paper No. 12-089.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1272a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1276" publication-type="other">
Subramanian, G 2002. The influence of antitakeover statutes on incorporation choice: Evidence on the "race"
debate and antitakeover overreaching. University of Pennsylvania Law Review 150:1795-1873.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1287a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1291" publication-type="other">
. 2004. The disappearing Delaware effect. Journal of Law, Economics, and Organization 20:32-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1298a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1302" publication-type="other">
Stock, J. H., and M. Yogo. 2005. Testing for weak instruments in linear IV regression. In D. W. K. Andrews, J,
Stock, and T. Rothenberg (Eds.), Identification and inference for econometric models: Essays in honor of Thomas
Rothenberg, 80-108. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1319" publication-type="other">
Torous, W. 2013. The AGR anomaly: Corporate governance and the mispricing of U.S. stocks. UCLA Working
Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1329a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1333" publication-type="other">
Winter, R. K. 1977. Shareholder protection and the theory of the corporation. Journal of Legal Studies 6:251-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


