<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24438439</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Redistributive Effects of the Shift from Personal Income Taxes to Indirect Taxes: Belgium 1988–93</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>André</given-names>
                  <surname>Decoster</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Guy</given-names>
                  <surname>Van Camp</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2001</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24438400</issue-id>
         <fpage>79</fpage>
         <lpage>106</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2001</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24438439"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Between 1988 and 1993, the Belgian personal income tax system and the indirect tax system were reformed to a considerable extent. We use microsimulation models to investigate the impact of the reform on the liability progression and the redistributive effect of the combined tax system. The redistributive effect of personal income taxes decreased, notwithstanding an increase in liability progression. For indirect taxes, both the liability regressivity and the reverse redistributive effect have been enhanced. We use recently developed statistical tests to gauge the significance of the observed changes.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d29e236a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e243" publication-type="other">
These shares are also based on the results of simulations in Decoster et al. (1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e250a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e257" publication-type="other">
See Messere (1998, pp. 10-12) and Sommerhalder (1992).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e264a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e271" publication-type="other">
See Messere (1998, p. 8) and Giles and Johnson (1994).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e278a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e285" publication-type="other">
The general expectation at the time of the reform was that TRA86 would increase progressivity (see Pechman
(1987)), although the policy proposals themselves mentioned distributional neutrality (see the quote in McLure
and Zodrow (1987)). Indeed, many studies found that the reform enhanced progressivity. For a recent survey of
a broad range of studies, see Auerbach and Slemrod (1997) and the references therein. Yet the number of
studies that conclude that TRA86 decreased progressivity is not negligible (for example, see Bishop et al.
(1997)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e309a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e316" publication-type="other">
Many policy proposals contain prescriptions such as 'designing the tax reform as distributionally neutral',
notwithstanding the lack of a precise description of what is meant by this. TRA86, however, is one of the rare
exceptions that did specify this distributional neutrality — namely, as equal percentage reductions in tax
liabilities at all income levels (see McLure and Zodrow (1987, p. 44)). Clearly, this refers to keeping the
liability progression constant.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e335a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e342" publication-type="other">
See Bishop, Chow and Formby (1994) and Davidson and Duclos (1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e349a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e356" publication-type="other">
We sketch the major differences between the 1988 and 1993 PIT systems. Hence, so to speak, the reform
refers to all the measures that have been implemented between 1988 and 1993, although they have not been
realised by a single tax reform act. Note that if we refer to 1988 or 1993 for the PIT system, this implies
reference to the administrative tax years 1989 or 1994 respectively. Although we do not consider the benefit
part of the disposable income generation process, we do, of course, take into account any change in the tax
treatment of replacement incomes and benefits.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e379a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e386" publication-type="other">
The description 'exemptions from the bottom up' has been used in official texts in Belgium to distinguish this
basic allowance from ordinary exemptions and deductions on the one hand, and credits on the other hand.
Ordinary exemptions and deductions lead to a reduction in the tax liability, which is determined by the
marginal tax rate (hence 'at the top'). Exemptions 'from the bottom up' determine a tax credit by calculating
the tax liability on this exempted income, starting with the lowest marginal rates first (hence 'from the bottom
up'). This tax credit is then subtracted from the tax liability obtained from the taxation of the taxable income
without the exemption.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e412a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e419" publication-type="other">
Note that this system also applies for two-income-earner families if the marriage fraction produces a lower tax
liability than separate taxation does.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e429a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e436" publication-type="other">
See Standaert and Valenduc (1996) for more information on SIRe.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e444a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e451" publication-type="other">
Hence the reported income figures are expressed in 1993 prices.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e458a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e465" publication-type="other">
For some people, such as those receiving only replacement income, it is obvious that they will not have to pay
income taxes. After a number of years, these people no longer receive a tax form from the administration. They
only have to contact the administration if their income condition has changed. The parameters of the tax system
(and hence the rules used by the administration) determining which people do not receive a tax form did not
change in the period under consideration.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e484a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e491" publication-type="other">
To express nominal figures in the tax legislation of both systems at the same level, we used the change in the
consumption price index. This index increased from 100 to 115.8 between 1988 and 1993. See Ministerie van
Financiën (1994, p. IV.4). Between 1988 and 1993, the important parameters of the tax system, such as
brackets, allowances and deductions, were fully indexed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e507a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e514" publication-type="other">
See Decoster (1995) and Decoster, Delhaye and Van Camp (1996) for more information on ASTER.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e521a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e528" publication-type="other">
This amounts to assuming that the change in disposable income caused by the PIT reform is completely
absorbed into savings.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e538a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e545" publication-type="other">
The factor we use to inflate these figures is 1.404, which captures the nominal growth of national income in
the National Accounts between 1987-88 and 1993.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e556a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e563" publication-type="other">
On statistical matching, see, for example, Rodgers (1984).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e570a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e577" publication-type="other">
See, among others, Kakwani (1986), Pfähler (1987), Duclos (1993), Lambert (1993, Ch. 7) and Bishop et al.
(1997). In this section, we only assemble the elements from this literature that are relevant for the empirical
section. Our notation follows Lambert (1993) quite closely.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e590a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e597" publication-type="other">
The exact definition of IR(p) is the ordinate of the concentration curve of post-tax income minus the ordinate
of the Lorenz curve of pre-tax income.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e607a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e614" publication-type="other">
Since I Rip) is a comparison between a post-tax and a pre-tax distribution, it might also be interpreted as the
change in post-tax income inequality because of taxation. However, if there is reranking, it is well known that
IRip) provides a biased estimate of this change in inequality. See, for example, Lambert (1993, p. 185).
Reranking can be captured as the difference between the post-tax income concentration curve and the post-
tax income Lorenz curve (see Duclos (1993, p. 353) and Duclos (2000) for a possible interpretation of this
reranking measure). We could never reject the hypothesis that this difference is equal to zero (see Decoster and
Van Camp (2000b)). Therefore we can also use the IR(p)-alues to judge the impact of the different tax reforms
on inequality of post-tax incomes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e643a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e650" publication-type="other">
The exact definition of TR(p) is the ordinate of the Lorenz curve of pre-tax income minus the ordinate of the
concentration curve tax liabilities. In a progressive system, the lower income groups bear a share of the total tax
receipts that is smaller than their share in taxable income. Hence the 77?(p)-values for a progressive system are
positive.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e666a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e673" publication-type="other">
See Lambert (1993, pp. 183-4)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e681a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e688" publication-type="other">
See Formby, Smith and Thistle (1990) and Silber (1994) on this point.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e695a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e702" publication-type="other">
Bishop, Chow and Formby (1994) provide similar theorems, but they do not give an explicit expression for
the elements of the covariance matrix, which makes their results less accessible for empirical implementation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e712a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e719" publication-type="other">
Davidson and Duclos (1997) suggested estimating the quantile values within the covariance matrix, such as
E(Y Z = G(/?)), with the aid of a Kernel estimator. This is done only when the quantile values of
concentration curves are estimated. We use a Gaussian Kemel and determine the band width by means of
expression 3.28 on page 45 of Silverman (1986).
The use of the Kemel estimator only to estimate the quantile values of concentration curves, and not for the
values of the ordinates of the curves nor for the Lorenz curves, is, besides the appeal of simplicity, based on at
least two other arguments. First, it reflects the fact that the ordering variable (for example, Z) and the variable
of analysis (for example, T) converge differently from their true value. Second, one may assume that there is
more uncertainty when a point value has to be estimated (as is the case for a quantile value) instead of a sum of
these points (as is the case when ordinates are estimated).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e754a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e761" publication-type="other">
See Seber (1977, p. 131, Table 5.1).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e768a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e775" publication-type="other">
We do not use the pre-tax income concept from the fiscal dataset IPCAL, since some relevant income
components, such as family allowances, are not taxed and thus not available in IPCAL. Disposable income in
the budget survey covers all household income components, including transfers and non-earned income. Our
equivalised pre-tax income is therefore different from gross market income.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e791a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e798" publication-type="other">
In this scale, the first adult is given a value of 1, each subsequent adult gets a weight of 0.7 and each child
counts for 0.5. One is considered a child until the age of 13. Of course, we cannot exclude the possibility that
our results are sensitive to the choice of the scale.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e812a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e819" publication-type="other">
A two-sided test with or = 0.05 has been applied, the critical value being (°025 = 1.96.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e826a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e833" publication-type="other">
The numbers underlying Figures 2a and 2b can be found in Tables A.l and A.2 of the Appendix.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e840a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e847" publication-type="other">
See Duclos (1993).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e854a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e861" publication-type="other">
The detailed test results are given in columns 4, 8 and 12 of Table A.l in the Appendix.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e868a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e875" publication-type="other">
See column 4 of Table A.2 in the Appendix.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e882a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e889" publication-type="other">
The critical values for a two-sided test with a = 0.05 and five and six sub null hypotheses are 2.58 and 2.64
respectively. See Seber (1977, p. 131, Table 5.1).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e900a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e907" publication-type="other">
The numbers underlying Figures 3a and 3b can be found in Tables A.3 and A 4 of the Appendix.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e914a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e921" publication-type="other">
The critical value for a two-sided test with a - 0.05 and seven sub null hypotheses is 2.69. See Seber (1977,
p. 131, Table 5.1).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d29e940a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e944" publication-type="other">
Auerbach, A. J. and Slemrod, J. (1997), 'The economic effects of the Tax Reform Act of 1986',
Journal of Economic Literature, vol. 35, pp. 589-632.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e954a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e958" publication-type="other">
Beach, C. and Davidson, R. (1983), 'Distributional-free statistical inference with Lorenz curves
and income shares', Review of Economic Studies, vol. 50, pp. 723-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e968a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e972" publication-type="other">
Bishop, J., Chakraborti, S. and Thistle, P. (1989), 'Asymptotically distribution-free statistical
inference for generalized Lorenz curves', Review of Economics and Statistics, vol. 71, pp. 725-
7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e985a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e989" publication-type="other">
—, Chow, K. and Formby, J. (1994), 'Testing for marginal changes in income distributions with
Lorenz and concentration curves', International Economic Review, vol. 35, pp. 479-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1000a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1004" publication-type="other">
—, —, — and Ho, C. (1997), 'Did tax reform reduce actual US progressivity? Evidence from the
taxpayer compliance measurement program', International Tax and Public Finance, vol. 4, pp.
177-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1017a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1021" publication-type="other">
—, Formby, J. and Zheng, B. (1998), 'Inference tests for Gini-based tax progressivity indexes',
Journal of Business &amp; Economic Statistics, vol. 16, pp. 322-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1031a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1035" publication-type="other">
Davidson, R. and Duclos, J-Y. (1997), 'Statistical inference for the measurement of the incidence
of taxes and transfers', Econometrica, vol. 65, pp. 1453-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1045a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1049" publication-type="other">
Decoster, A. (1995), 'A microsimulation model for Belgian indirect taxes with a carbon-energy tax
illustration for Belgium', Tijdschrift voor Economie en Management, vol. 40, pp. 133-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1059a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1063" publication-type="other">
—, Delhaye, P. and Van Camp, G. (1996), 'Users guide for Aster: a microsimulation model for
indirect taxes version 2', Katholieke Universiteit Leuven, Centrum voor Economische Studien,
Public Economics Research Paper no. 48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1076a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1080" publication-type="other">
—, Standaert, I., Valenduc, C. and Van Camp, G. (1998), Evaluation of Simultaneous Reforms in
Personal Income Taxes and Indirect Taxes: Belgium 1988-1993, Final Report DWTC Project
PE/VA/07, Leuven: Centrum voor Economische Studien, Katholieke Universiteit Leuven.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1094a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1098" publication-type="other">
—, —, — and — (2000), 'What makes personal income taxes progressive', Katholieke Universiteit
Leuven, Centrum voor Economische Studien, Public Economics Research Paper no. DPS 00-
08.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1111a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1115" publication-type="other">
— and Van Camp, G. (2000a), 'The unit of analysis in microsimulation models for personal
income taxes: fiscal unit or household', in H. Sutherland, L. Mitton and M. Weeks (eds),
Microsimulation Modelling for Policy Analysis, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1128a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1132" publication-type="other">
— and — (2000b), 'Redistributive effects of the shift from personal income taxes to indirect taxes:
Belgium 1988-93', Katholieke Universiteit Leuven, Centrum voor Economische Studien,
Public Economics Research Paper no. DPS 00-07.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1145a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1149" publication-type="other">
Duclos, J-Y. (1993), 'Progressivity, redistribution, and equity, with application to the British tax
and benefit system', Public Finance /Finances Publiques, vol. 48, pp. 350-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1159a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1163" publication-type="other">
— (1997), 'The asymptotic distribution of linear indices of inequality, progressivity and
redistribution', Economics Letters, vol. 54, pp. 51-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1173a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1177" publication-type="other">
— (2000), 'Gini indices and the redistribution of income', International Tax and Public Finance,
vol. 7, no. 2, pp. 141-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1188a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1192" publication-type="other">
Formby, J., Smith, W. and Thistle, P. (1990), 'The average tax burden and the welfare implications
of global tax progressivity', Public Finance Quarterly, vol. 18, pp. 3-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1202a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1206" publication-type="other">
Giles, C. and Johnson, P. (1994), 'Tax reform in the UK and changes in the progressivity of the tax
system, 1985-95, Fiscal Studies, vol. 15, no. 3, pp. 64-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1216a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1220" publication-type="other">
Kakwani, N. (1977), 'Measurement of tax progressivity: an international comparison', Economic
Journal, vol. 87, pp. 71-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1230a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1234" publication-type="other">
— (1986), Analysing Redistribution Policies: A Study Using Australian Data, Cambridge:
Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1244a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1248" publication-type="other">
Lambert, P. (1993), The Distribution and Redistribution of Income: A Mathematical Analysis,
second edition, Manchester: Manchester University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1258a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1262" publication-type="other">
McLure, C. E., Jr and Zodrow, G. R. (1987), 'Treasury I and the Tax Reform Act of 1986: the
economics and politics of tax reform', Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 1, pp. 37-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1273a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1277" publication-type="other">
Messere, K. (1998), The Tax System in Industrialized Countries, New York: Oxford University
Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1287a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1291" publication-type="other">
Ministerie van Financiën (1994), Conjunctuurnota, Brussels: Studie- en Documentatiedienst van
het Ministerie van Financiën.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1301a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1305" publication-type="other">
Pechman, J. (1987), 'Tax reform: theory and practice', Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 1,
pp. 11-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1315a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1319" publication-type="other">
Pfähler, W. (1987), 'Redistributive effects of tax progressivity: evaluating a general class of
aggregate measures', Public Finance/Finances Publiques, vol. 42, pp. 1-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1329a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1333" publication-type="other">
Reynolds, M. and Smolensky, E. (1977), Public Expenditures, Taxes, and the Distribution of
Income: The United States, 1950, 1961, 1970, New York: Academic Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1343a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1347" publication-type="other">
Rodgers, W. (1984), 'An evaluation of statistical matching', Journal of Business &amp; Economic
Statistics, vol. 2, pp. 91-102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1358a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1362" publication-type="other">
Seber, G. (1977), Linear Regression Analysis, New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1369a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1373" publication-type="other">
Silber, J. (1994), 'Income redistribution, tax structure, and the measurement of tax progressivity',
Public Finance Quarterly, vol. 22, pp. 86-102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1383a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1387" publication-type="other">
Silverman, B. (1986), Density Estimation: for Statistics and Data Analysis, London: Chapman and
Hall.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1397a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1401" publication-type="other">
Sommerhaider, R. (1992), 'Dutch tax simplification: unique in an international setting?', Journal
of Economic Psychology, vol. 13, pp. 597-607.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1411a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1415" publication-type="other">
Standaert, I. and Valenduc, C. (1996), Het Micro-SimulatieModel van de PersonenBelasting in
België: SIRe, Research Paper no. 1, Brussels: Studie- en Documentatiedjenst van het Ministerie
van Financiën.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1428a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1432" publication-type="other">
Staline, M. and Ury, H. (1979), 'Tables of the studentized maximum modulus distribution and an
application to multiple comparisons among means', Technometrics, vol. 21, pp. 87-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
