<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830674</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830680</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>IMPACT OF FINANCE ON POVERTY REDUCTION AND SOCIAL CAPITAL FORMATION: A REVIEW AND SYNTHESIS OF EMPIRICAL EVIDENCE / IMPACTS POSITIFS DE LA MICROFINANCE SUR LA RÉDUCTION DE LA PAUVRETÉ ET SUR LE CAPITAL SOCIAL - UNE REVUE ET SYNTHÈSE DE L'ÉVIDENCE EMPIRIQUE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Gertrud</given-names>
                  <surname>Schrieder</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Manohar</given-names>
                  <surname>Sharma</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1999</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>67</fpage>
         <lpage>93</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830680"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Poverty in developing countries is often tied to imperfections of the enabling socio-economic environment, specifically financial market imperfections. However, financial markets are thin in most low-income regions of developing countries. Conditions are changing, nevertheless, more so for Asia and Latin America than for Sub-Saharan Africa. Financial innovations associated with microfinance appear to greatly reduce the cost of financial intermediation at the agent and client level. But while strong claims are made for the ability of microfinance interventions to reduce poverty, this effect cannot be taken for granted. Often, however, the assumption that microfinance has a positive impact on welfare is adopted if a microfinance intermediary appears to be financially sustainable. Based on a comprehensive literature review, this paper discusses and analyses empirical studies that research the question whether the poor's access to and participation in microfinance interventions lead to positive welfare changes. It is not the purpose of this paper to critically discuss the methodologies of the impact studies reviewed. This is done elsewhere. Because the findings of an impact analysis at the client level of microfinance should always be fed back to improve the design and implementation of the intervention at the agent level, the most important performance indicators of microfinance are reviewed as well. The paper concludes with policy and research implications. La pauvreté dans les pays en voie de développement (PVD) est souvent mise en rapport avec les imperfections de l'environnement socio-économique et plus particulièrement les imperfections du marché financier, embryonnaire dans les régions défavorisées de ces pays. Les conditions changent même si l'évolution n'est pas la même en Asie et en Amérique Latine qu'en Afrique au Sud du Sahara. Les innovations dans le domaine de la microfinance réduiraient considérablement le coût de l'intermédiation financière au niveau de l'agent et du client. Mais malgré tous les plaidoyers pour la microfinance réductrice de la pauvreté, ce résultat n'est pas une évidence. Souvent l'hypothèse que la microfinance aurait un impact positif sur le bienêtre n'est acceptée que dans les conditions d'une intermédiation financièrement durable. Cet article, basé sur une revue de littérature, discute et analyse des études empiriques qui ont abordé la question de savoir si l'accès et la participation des pauvres aux interventions dans le domaine de la microfinance améliore le bien-être. L'objectif du papier n'est pas de critiquer les méthodologies utilisées; cet aspect est abordé ailleurs. Les principaux indicateurs de la performance de la microfinance sont également passés en revue parce que les résultats d'une analyse d'impact au niveau du client doivent être transmis à l'agent afin d'améliorer la conception et la mise en œuvre des interventions à son niveau. Les implications en matière de politique et de recherche sont formulées en conclusion.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d22e156a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e163" publication-type="other">
Chung etal., 1997</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e169" publication-type="other">
The World Bank (1990</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e175" publication-type="other">
1993)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e182a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e189" publication-type="other">
Malawi, 1995.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e196a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e203" publication-type="other">
Zeller, Diagne and Mataya (1997)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d22e219a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e223" publication-type="other">
Berger, M. 1989. Giving women credit: The strengths and limitations of credit as a tool for alleviating poverty.
World Development 17 (7): 1017-1032.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e233a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e237" publication-type="other">
BMZ. 1994. Sektorkonzept Finanzsystementwicklung - F~rderung von Sparen und Kredit. Bonn, Deutschland:
Bundesministerium fur wirtschaftliche Entwicklung (BMZ).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e247a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e251" publication-type="other">
Braun, J. von, Johm, K., Kinteh, S., and D. Puetz. 1990. Structural adjustment, agriculture and nutrition: Po-
licy options in The Gambia. IFPRI Working Paper on Commercialization of Agriculture and Nutrition No.
4. Washington, D.C., USA: International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e264a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e268" publication-type="other">
CGAP. 1997. Policy Document: A Policy Framework for The Consultative Group to Assist the Poorest (CGAP)
- A Microfinance program -. Washington, D.C.: World Bank, Consultative Group to Assist the Poorest
(CGAP), http://www.worldbank.org/ html/cgap/policy.htm.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e282a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e286" publication-type="other">
Christen, R. P., Rhyne, E., Vogel, R. C, and C. McKean. 1995. Maximizing the outreach of microenterprise fi-
nance: An analysis of successful microfinance programs. USAID Program and Operations Assessment
Report No. 10. Washington: IMCC and United States Agency for International Development (USAID).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e299a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e303" publication-type="other">
Chung, K., Haddad, L, Ramakrishna, J., and F. Riely. 1997. Identifying the food insecure: The application of
mixed-method approaches in India. Occasional Paper. Washington, D.C., USA: International Food Po-
licy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e316a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e320" publication-type="other">
Desai, B. M., and J. W. Mellor. 1993. Institutional finance for agricultural development. Food Policy Review 1.
Washington, D.C., USA: International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e330a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e334" publication-type="other">
Diagne, A. 1998. Impact of access to credit on income and food security in Malawi. FCND Discussion Paper
No. 46. Washington, D.C., USA: International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e344a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e348" publication-type="other">
Eswaran, M., and A. Kotwal. 1990. Implications of credit constraints in farmers' decision making: A reinterpre-
tation. Oxford Economic Papers 42: 473-482.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e358a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e362" publication-type="other">
GTZ. 1997. Orientierungsrahmen fur die finanzsystemgerechte Handhabung von Kreditfonds. Eschborn:
Deutsche Gesellschaft fur Technische Zusammenarbeit (GTZ).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e373a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e377" publication-type="other">
Hashemi, S. M., Schuler S. R., and A. P. Riley. 1996. rural credit programs and women's empowerment in
Bangladesh. World Development 24 (4): 635-653.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e387a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e391" publication-type="other">
Islam, H. 1997. Moving toward institutional sustainability, Shakti Foundation. Countdown 2005 - The Newslet-
ter of the Microcredit Summit Campaign 1 (2): 3-4.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e401a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e405" publication-type="other">
Jahangir, A. S. M., and M. Zeller. 1995. Overview paper on rural finance programs for the poor in Bangladesh.
A review of five major programs. Washington, D.C., USA: International Food Policy Research Institute
(IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e418a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e422" publication-type="other">
Jansen, A. 1995. Linking microenterprise development and the environment. Gemini Issues Paper. Washington,
D.C., USA: U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), Microenterprise Development Office.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e432a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e436" publication-type="other">
Johnson, S., and B. Rogaly. 1997. Microfinance and poverty reduction. Oxford, UK: Oxfam.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e443a1310">
          
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e449" publication-type="other">
Khandker, M. 1998. Socio-economic and psychological dynamics of empowerment of Grameen Bank and
BRAC borrowers. PRUS Working Paper No. 3. Workshop proceedings "Recent research on micro-finan-
ce: Implications for policy". 43-56, Matin, I., Sinha, S., with P. Alexander (eds.). Brighton, Sussex, UK:
University of Sussex, Poverty Research Unit at Sussex (PRUS).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e466a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e470" publication-type="other">
Lund, S.M. 1995. Informal credit, insurance networks, and risk-sharing: Empirical evidence form the Philippi-
nes. Stanford, CA, USA: Stanford University, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e480a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e484" publication-type="other">
Mahajan, V., and B. G. Ramola. 1996. Financial services for the rural poor and women in India: Access and
sustainability. Journal of International Developments (March-April): 211-226.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e494a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e498" publication-type="other">
McNelly, B., and Ch. Dunford. 1998. Impact of credit with education on mothers' and their young children's nu-
trition: Lower Pra Rural Bank Credit with Education Program in Ghana. Davis, CA, USA: Freedom from
Hunger.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e511a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e515" publication-type="other">
Morduch, J. 1998. Does microfinance really help the poor? Unobserved heterogeneity and average impacts
of credit in Bangladesh. Cambridge, MA, USA: Harvard University, Department of Economics and HMD,
mimeo.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e528a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e532" publication-type="other">
Mosley, P., and D. Hulme. 1998. Micro-enterprise finance: Is there a trade-off between growth and poverty al-
leviation. PRUS Working Paper No. 3. Workshop proceedings "Recent research on micro-finance: Impli-
cations for policy". 1-12, Matin, I., Sinha, S., with P. Alexander (eds.). Brighton, Sussex, UK: University of
Sussex, Poverty Research Unit at Sussex (PRUS).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e548a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e552" publication-type="other">
Nguyen, T.-D.-P. G. 1998. Food insecurity and the evolution of indigenous risk-sharing institutions in the
Sahel. Ph.D. Thesis. Columbus, OH, USA: The Ohio State University (OSU), Department of Agricultural
Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e566a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e570" publication-type="other">
Osmani, L. N. K. 1998. Credit and relative well-being of women: The experience of the Grameen Bank, Ban-
gladesh. PRUS Working Paper No. 3. Workshop proceedings "Recent research on micro-finance: Impli-
cations for policy". 21-28, Matin, I., Sinha, S., with P. Alexander (eds.). Brighton, Sussex, UK: University
of Sussex, Poverty Research Unit at Sussex (PRUS).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e586a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e590" publication-type="other">
Otero, M., and E. Rhyne, eds. 1994. The new world of microenterprise finance: Building healthy financial insti-
tutions for the poor. West Hartford, CN, USA: Kumarian Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e600a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e604" publication-type="other">
Pallen, D. 1997. Environmental source book for micro-finance institutions. Hull, Quebec, Canada: Canadian Inter-
national Development Agency (CIDA), Asia Branch, http://www.soc.titech.ac.jp/icm/environ /environ.html.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e614a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e618" publication-type="other">
Pitt, M. M., and S. R. Khandker. 1997. The impact of group-based credit programs on poor households in
Bangladesh: Does the gender of participants matter? Journal of Political Economy 106 (5).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e628a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e632" publication-type="other">
Pitt, M. M., and S. R. Khandker. 1996. Household and intrahousehold impact of the Grameen Bank and simi-
lar targeted credit programs in Bangladesh. World Bank Discussion Papers No. 320. Washington, D.C.,
USA: World Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e645a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e649" publication-type="other">
Quinion, M. B. 1998. Topical words: Welfare, http://www.clever.net/quinion/words/n-wel1.htm: World Wide
Words.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e660a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e664" publication-type="other">
Schneider, H., ed. 1997. Microfinance for the poor. Rome, Italy and Paris, France: I FAD and OECD.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e671a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e675" publication-type="other">
Schrieder, G. 1998. Orientierungsrahmen fur Kleinkreditprogramme. Bonn, Deutschland: Deutsche Welthun-
gerhilfe (DWHH).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e685a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e689" publication-type="other">
Schrieder, G. 1996. The role of rural finance for food security of the poor in Cameroon. Frankfurt, Germany:
Lang Verlag.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e699a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e703" publication-type="other">
Schrieder, G., and K. Pfaff. 1997. Mise en place d'un reseau de caisses d'epargne villageoises au Niger.
Working Paper 28. Stuttgart, Germany: University of Hohenheim, Development Theory and Policy
(490a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e716a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e720" publication-type="other">
Schrieder, G., and F. Heidhues. 1993. Credit for the rural poor: Cameroon country case. Part 3 of the Final
Report to the GTZ. Washington, D.C., USA: International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e730a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e734" publication-type="other">
Schuler, S. R., Hashemi, S. M., and A. P. Riley. 1997. The influence of women's changing roles and status in
Bangladesh's fertility transition: Evidence from a study of credit programs and contraceptive use. World
Development 25 (4): 563-575.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e748a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e752" publication-type="other">
Srinivas, S. 1997. Self-employed Women's Association (SEWA) of India. Paving the way for women's econo-
mic progress. Bhadra, Ahmedabad, India: Self-employed Women's Association (SEWA), http://pw2.net-
com.com/~aikya/sewa.html.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e765a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e769" publication-type="other">
Srinivas, H., and D. Pallen. 1998. The environmental colors of microfinance. http://www.soc.titech.ac.jp/icm
/environ/environ.html.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e779a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e783" publication-type="other">
Sebstad, J., Neill, C, Barnes, C, and G. Chen. 1995. Assessing the impacts of microenterprise interventions:
A framework for analysis. Washington, DC, USA: USAID / Global Bureau / Office of Microenterprise De-
velopment.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e796a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e800" publication-type="other">
UNDP. 1997. Report on human development in Bangladesh: Empowerment of women. Dhaka, Bangladesh:
United Nations Development Program (UNDP).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e810a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e814" publication-type="other">
Waas, E. 1991. Urban waste, multiple waste: Introductory notes. African Environments (29-30): 1-2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e821a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e825" publication-type="other">
World Bank. 1990. World Development Report 1990: Poverty. New York, NY, USA: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e833a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e837" publication-type="other">
World Bank. 1993. World Development Report 1993. New York, NY, USA: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e844a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e848" publication-type="other">
Yaron, J. 1991. Successful rural finance institutions. Washington, D.C., USA: World Bank, Agricultural Policies
Department.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e858a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e862" publication-type="other">
Zaman, H. 1998. BRAC's impact on poverty and empowerment: A summary of findings from Matlab. PRUS
Working Paper No. 3. Workshop proceedings "Recent research on micro-finance: Implications for po-
licy". 13-20, Matin, I., Sinha, S., with P. Alexander (eds.). Brighton, Sussex, UK: University of Sussex,
Poverty Research Unit at Sussex (PRUS).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e878a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e882" publication-type="other">
Zeller, M. 1993. Credit policies for food security for the poor: Country case Madagascar. Part 2 of the Final
Report to the GTZ. Washington, D.C., USA: International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e892a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e896" publication-type="other">
Zeller, M., and M. Sharma. 1998. Rural finance and poverty alleviation. Washington, D.C., USA: International
Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e906a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e910" publication-type="other">
Zeller, M., Lapenu, C, Minten, B., Ralison, E., Randrianaivo, D., and C. Randrianarisoa. 1998. Rural develop-
ment in Madagascar: Quo vadis? Towards a better understanding of the critical triangle between econo-
mic growth, poverty alleviation and environmental sustainability. Washington, D.C., USA and Antananari-
vo, Madagascar: International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI) and Ministry of Scientific Research.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e927a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e931" publication-type="other">
Zeller, M., Diagne, A., and Ch. Mataya. 1997. Market access by smallholder farmers in Malawi: Implications
for technology adoption, agricultural productivity, and crop income. FCND Discussion Paper No. 35. Wa-
shington, D.C., USA: International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e944a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e948" publication-type="other">
Zeller, M., Broca, S., and M. Sharma. 1996. Financial services for the rural poor: A multicountry synthesis and
implications for policy and future research. Final report to the German Agency for Technical Cooperation
(GTZ). Washington, D.C., USA: International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e961a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e965" publication-type="other">
Zeller, M., Ahmed, A. Babu, S., Broca, S., Diagne, A., and M. Sharma. 1996. Rural financial policies for food
security of the poor: Methodologies for a multicountry research project. FCND Discussion Paper No. 11.
Washington, D.C., USA: International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e978a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e982" publication-type="other">
Zeller, M., Braun, J. von, Johm, K., and D. Putz. 1994. Sources and terms of credit of the rural poor in The
Gambia. Savings and Development.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


