<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26812208</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Public Sector Benefits: Funding , Behavior &amp; Objectives From the Perspectives of Governments and Taxpayers</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Role of Economic, Fiscal, and Financial Shocks in the Evolution of Public Sector Pension Funding</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Triest</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhao</surname>
                  <given-names>Bo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">107</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26812141</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>25</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26812208"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Many studies have documented the pervasive underfunding of public sector pension plans in the United States in recent years. The deterioration of the funded status of public pension plans coincided with severe fiscal crises that state and local governments experienced in the 2000s. This development has led to a suspicion that state and local governments have decreased employer pension contributions as a backdoor means of running fiscal deficits. In this paper, the authors investigate the extent to which this phenomenon has occurred.</p> 
            <p>They estimate panel data regressions using the Boston College Center for Retirement Research’s Public Plans Database, which provides data for 2001 through 2010. The authors find that contrary to popular belief, plan sponsors do not reduce their contributions in response to negative fiscal or economic shocks. In contrast, plan sponsors’ contributions to their pension plans increase in response to growth in their unfunded liabilities.</p> 
            <p>The authors document that the public pension underfunding crisis during the 2000s developed largely as a consequence of portfolio returns that fell short of expectations. Public pension plans’ assets portfolios have a relatively high share of equities and other risky assets, leaving the plans’ funded status vulnerable to asset price fluctuations. Although plan sponsors increased their contributions in response to the growth of unfunded liabilities, they did not do so by enough to fully counteract the effect of the subpar portfolio returns. This finding holds across the spectrum of plans ranked in terms of funded status in 2010.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Andonov, Aleksandar, Rob Bauer, and Martijin Cremers. 2013. “Pension Fund Asset Allocation and Liability Discount Rates: Camouflage and Reckless Risk Taking by U.S. Public Plans?” Working Paper. Available at SSRN: http://ssrn.com/abstract=2070054 or http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2070054</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Arellano, Manuel, and Stephen Bond. 1991. “Some Tests of Specification for Panel Data: Monte Carlo Evidence and an Application to Employment Equations.” Review of Economic Studies 58(2): 277-297.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Blundell, Richard, and Stephen Bond. 1998. “Initial Conditions and Moment Restrictions in Dynamic Panel Data Models.” Journal of Econometrics 87(1): 115-143.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bohn, Henning. 2011. “Should Public Retirement Plans Be Fully Funded?” Journal of Pension Economics and Finance 10(2): 195-219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Brown, Jeffrey R., and David W. Wilcox. 2009. “Discounting State and Local Pension Liabilities.” American Economic Review 99(2): 538-542.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Chaney, Barbara A., Paul A. Copley, and Mary S. Stone. 2002. “The Effect of Fiscal Stress and Balanced Budget Requirements on the Funding and Measurement of State Pension Obligations.” Journal of Accounting and Public Policy 21(4): 287-313.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Clark, Robert L., Lee A. Craig, and John Sabelhaus, 2011. State and Local Retirement Plans in the United States. Cheltenham, UK: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Coggburn, Jerrell D., and Richard C. Kearney. 2010. “Trouble Keeping Promises? An Analysis of Underfunding in State Retiree Benefits.” Public Administration Review 70(1): 97-108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Government Accountability Office. 2007. State and Local Government Retiree Benefits: Current Status of Benefit Structures, Protections, and Fiscal Outlook for Funding Future Costs. GAO-07-1156. Washington, DC: Government Accountability Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Hess, Federick M., and Juliet P. Squire. 2010. “‘But the Pension Fund Was Just SITTING There…’: The Politics of Teacher Retirement Plans.” Education Finance and Policy 5(4): 587-616.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Munnell, Alicia H., Jean-Pierre Aubry, and Laura Quinby. 2011. “Public Pension Funding in Practice.” Journal of Pension Economics and Finance 10(02): 247-268.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Munnell, Alicia H., Jean-Pierre Aubry, Josh Hurwitz, Madeline Medenica, and Laura Quinby. 2011. “The Funding of State and Local Pensions in 2010.” State and Local Pension Plan Brief 17. Chestnut Hill, MA: Center for Retirement Research at Boston College.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Munnell, Alicia H., 2012. State and Local Pensions: What Now? Washington, DC: Brookings Institution Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Novy-Marx, Robert, and Joshua D. Rauh. 2009. “The Liabilities and Risks of State-Sponsored Pension Plans.” Journal of Economic Perspectives 23(4): 191-210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Pew Center on the States. 2010. The Trillion Dollar Gap: Underfunded State Retirement Systems and the Roads to Reform. Washington, DC: Pew Charitable Trusts. Available at http://www.pewstates.org/uploadedFiles/PCS_Assets/2010/Trillion_Dollar_Gap_Underfunded_State_Retirement_Systems_and_the_Roads_to_Reform.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Pew Center on the States. 2012. The Widening Gap Update, Washington, DC: Pew Charitable Trusts. Available at http://www.pewstates.org/uploadedFiles/PCS_Assets/2012/Pew_Pensions_Update.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Poterba, James M. 1994. “State Responses to Fiscal Crises: The Effects of Budgetary Institutions and Politics.” Journal of Political Economy 102(2): 799-821.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">St. Clair, Travis. 2013. “The Impact of Budget Stabilization Funds on State Pension Contributions.” Public Budgeting &amp; Finance 33(3): 55-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>SUMMARY STATISTICS</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>REGRESSION RESULTS</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>COMPARISON BY QUARTILE OF FUNDED RATIO IN 2010</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Distributions of Funded Ratio</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>APPENDIX TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Regression Results with 10-Year Average Payroll</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>APPENDIX TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Regression Results Based on the Full Sample</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>APPENDIX TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Transitions of Public Pension Plans Between Funded Ratio Quartiles</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
