<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014699</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Student Teachers and CALL</article-title>
            <subtitle>Personal and Pedagogical Uses and Beliefs</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hlas</surname>
                  <given-names>Anne Cummings</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Anne Cummings Hlas is a professor of Spanish at the University of Wisconsin–Eau Claire. Her research interests include second language teacher knowledge, teacher use of technology, and teacher target language use.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Conroy</surname>
                  <given-names>Kelly</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Kelly Conroy teaches Spanish at Metropolitan State University of Denver. Her research interests include second language teacher licensure, teacher target language use, and student use of technology.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hildebrandt</surname>
                  <given-names>Susan A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a3">
                  <sup>3</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Susan A. Hildebrandt is an associate professor of applied linguistics and Spanish at Illinois State University. Her research interests include second language teacher education, professionalization, and evaluation.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>1</sup>University of Wisconsin Eau Claire.</aff>
            <aff id="a2">
               <sup>2</sup>Metropolitan State University of Denver.</aff>
            <aff id="a3">
               <sup>3</sup>Illinois State University.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>34</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014695</issue-id>
         <fpage>336</fpage>
         <lpage>354</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2017, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014699"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>The student teaching semester affords teacher candidates the chance to apply what they have learned during their teacher preparation coursework. Therefore, it can be a prime opportunity for student teachers to use technology for their own language learning and to implement computer assisted language learning (CALL) in their instruction. This study explores United States K–12 foreign language (FL) student teachers’ use of and beliefs about CALL technologies. Four research questions guide this study: (a) How are FL student teachers using CALL for personal language learning (if at all)? (b) What do FL student teachers report they believe about their own personal language learning using CALL? (c) How are FL student teachers using CALL pedagogically (if at all)? (d) What do FL student teachers report they believe about their teacher preparation in CALL? Data from 71 respondents suggest FL student teachers do not feel well prepared to use CALL technologies pedagogically and that they have a limited repertoire of technology resources. Approximately 87.5% of these student teachers self-report their knowledge of CALL technologies as novice or intermediate. This article examines the virtues and shortcomings of FL student teachers’ preparation and use of CALL, offering suggestions for FL teacher education.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>technological pedagogical content knowledge</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>student teachers</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>technology</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>teacher beliefs</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bax, S. (2003). CALL—past, present, and future. System, 31, 13–28. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0346-251X(02)00071-4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beatty, K. (2013). Teaching and researching: Computer-Assisted Language Learning. London: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chambers, A., &amp; Bax, S. (2006). Making CALL work: Toward normalization. System, 34, 465–479. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.system.2006.08.001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Corbin, J. M., &amp; Strauss, A. (2007). Basics of qualitative research: Techniques and procedures for developing grounded theory (3rd ed.). London: Sage Publications.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Creswell, J. W. (2013). Research designs: Qualitative, quantitative, and mixed methods approaches. London: Sage Publications.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cutrim Schmid, E., &amp; Hegelheimer, V. (2014). Collaborative research projects in the technology‐enhanced language classroom: Pre‐service and in‐service teachers exchange knowledge about technology. ReCALL, 26, 315–332. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0958344014000135</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dörnyei, Z. (2003). Questionnaires in second language research: Construction, administration, and processing. New Jersey: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Egbert, J., Paulus, T., &amp; Nakamichi, Y. (2002). The impact of CALL instruction on classroom computer use: A foundation for rethinking technology in teacher education. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 6(3), 108–126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Egbert, J., &amp; Thomas, M. (2001). The new frontier: A case study in applying instructional design for distance teacher education. Journal of Technology and Teacher Education, 9(3), 391–405.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Felix, U. (2005). Analysing recent CALL effectiveness research—Towards a common agenda. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 18(1 &amp; 2), 1–32. https://doi.org/10.1080/09588220500132274</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fleming, L., Motamedi, V., &amp; May, L. (2007). Predicting preservice teacher competence in computer technology: Modeling and application in training environments. Journal of Technology and Teacher Education, 15(2), 207–231.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galloway, J. P. (1997). How teachers use and learn to use computers. Technology and Teacher Education Annual, 857–859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goertler, S., &amp; Winke, P (2008). The effectiveness of technology-enhanced foreign language teaching. In S. Goertler &amp; P. Winke (Eds.), Opening doors through distance Education: Principles, perspectives, and practices (pp. 233-260). CALICO Monograph Series 7. San Marcos, TX: CALICO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hammond, M., Reynolds, L., &amp; Ingram, J. (2011). How and why do student teachers use ICT? Journal of Computer Assisted Learning, 27, 191–203. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2729.2010.00389.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hargrave, C., &amp; Hsu, Y. (2000). Survey of instructional technology courses for preservice teachers. Journal of Technology and Teacher Education, 8(4), 303–314.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hegelheimer, V. (2006). When the technology course is required. In P. Hubbard &amp; M. Levy (Eds.), Teacher education and CALL (pp. 117–133). Philadelphia: John Benjamins. https://doi.org/10.1075/lllt.14.12heg</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hildebrandt, S., Hlas, A. C., &amp; Conroy, K. (2013). A comparison of nine world language teacher preparation programs within and across three states. Northeast Conference on the Teaching of Foreign Languages Review, 72, 15-44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hirschel, R. (2012). Moodle: Students’ perspectives on forums, glossaries and quizzes. JALT CALL Journal, 8, 95–112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hlas, A. C., &amp; Hildebrandt, S. A. (2010). Demonstrations of pedagogical content knowledge: Spanish Liberal Arts and Spanish Education majors’ writing. L2 Journal, 2(10), 1-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hong, K. H. (2010). CALL teacher education as an impetus for L2 teachers in integrating technology. ReCALL, 22(1), 53–69. https://doi.org/10.1017/S095834400999019X</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hubbard, P., &amp; Levy, M. (2006a). Introduction. In P. Hubbard &amp; M. Levy (Eds.), Teacher Education and CALL (pp. ix–xi). Philadelphia: John Benjamins. https://doi.org/10.1075/lllt.14</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hubbard, P., &amp; Levy, M. (2006b). The scope of CALL education. In P. Hubbard &amp; M. Levy (Eds.), Teacher Education and CALL (pp. 3–20). Philadelphia: John Benjamins. https://doi.org/10.1075/lllt.14.04hub</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jones, E. (2013). First year teachers’ technology use: Perceptions of factors affecting technology integration (Doctoral Dissertation). University of Kansas.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kay, R. H. (2006). Evaluating strategies used to incorporate technology into preservice education: A review of the literature. Journal of Research on Technology in Education, 38, 385–410. https://doi.org/10.1080/15391523.2006.10782466</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kessler, G. (2006). Assessing CALL teacher training: What are we doing and what could we do better? In P. Hubbard &amp; M. Levy (Eds.), Teacher Education in CALL (pp. 23–44). Philadelphia: John Benjamins. https://doi.org/10.1075/lllt.14.05kes</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kessler, G. (2007). Formal and informal CALL preparation and teacher attitude toward technology. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 20(2), 173–188. https://doi.org/10.1080/09588220701331394</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kessler, G. (2010). When they talk about CALL: Discourse in a required CALL class. CALICO Journal, 27(2), 376–392. https://doi.org/10.11139/cj.27.2.376-392</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lam, Y. (2000). Technophilia vs. technophobia: A preliminary look at why second language teachers do or do not use technology in their classroom. The Canadian Modern Language Review, 56, 389–420. https://doi.org/10.3138/cmlr.56.3.389</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Levy, M. (1997). A rationale for teacher education and CALL: The holistic view and its implications. Computers and the Humanities, 30, 293–302.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lord, G., &amp; Lomicka, L. (2011). Calling on educators: Paving the way for the future of technology and CALL. In N. Arnold &amp; L. Ducate (Eds.), Present and future promises of CALL: From theory and research to new directions in language teaching (pp. 441–469). San Marcos, TX: CALICO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Luke, C. L., &amp; Britten, J. S. (2007). The expanding role of technology in foreign language teacher education programs. CALICO Journal, 24(2), 253–267.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mishra, P., &amp; Koehler, M. J. (2006). Technological pedagogical content knowledge: A framework for teacher knowledge. Teachers College Record, 108(6), 1017–1054. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9620.2006.00684.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marseden, E., Mackey, A., &amp; Plonsky, L (2016). The IRIS Repository: Advancing research practice and methodology. In A. Mackey &amp; E. Marsden (Eds.), Advancing methodology and practice: the IRIS Repository of Instruments for Research into Second Languages (pp. 1–21). New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merriam, S. B. (2009). Qualitative research: A guide to design and implementation. San Francisco, CA: Jossey-Bass.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patton, M. Q. (2002). Qualitative research and evaluation methods (3rd ed.). Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peters, M. (2006). Developing computer competencies for preservice teachers: Is one course enough? In P. Hubbard &amp; M. Levy (Eds.), Teacher Education and CALL (pp. 153–165). Philadelphia: John Benjamins. https://doi.org/10.1075/lllt.14.14pet</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Puentedura, R. R. (2009). As we may teach: Educational technology, from theory into practice [Blog post]. Retrieved from: http://www.hippasus.com/rrpweblog/archives/000025.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Raschio, R., &amp; Raymond, R. L. (2003). Where are we with technology? What teachers of Spanish and Portuguese have to say about the presence of technology in their teaching. Hispania, 86(1), 88–96. https://doi.org/10.2307/20062817</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Richardson, V. (1996). The role of attitudes and beliefs in learning to teach. In J. Sikula, T. J. Buttery, &amp; E. Guyton (Eds.), Handbook of research on teacher education (2nd ed., pp. 102–119). New York: Simon &amp; Schuster Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shulman, L. S. (1987). Knowledge and teaching: Foundations of the new reform. Harvard Educational Review, 57(1), 1–23. https://doi.org/10.17763/haer.57.1.j463w79r56455411</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smerdon, B., Cronen, S., Lanahan, L., Anderson, J., Iannotti, N., &amp; Angeles, J. (2000). Teachers’ tools for the 21st century: A report on teachers’ use of technology. Washington, DC: National Center for Education Statistics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stuhlmann, J., &amp; Taylor, H. (1999). Preparing technically competent student teachers: A three year study of interventions and experiences. Journal of Technology and Teacher Education, 7(4), 333–350.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swanson, P. (2013). Identifying and recruiting language teachers: A research-based approach. Charlotte, NC: Information Age Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Williams, L., Abraham, L., &amp; Bostelmann, E. (2014). A discourse-based approach to CALL training and professional development. Foreign Language Annals, 47(4), 614–629. https://doi.org/10.1111/flan.12119</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
