<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169249</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Influence of Feature Lines of Vehicle Hood Styling on Headform Kinematics and Injury Evaluation in Car-to-Pedestrian Impact Simulations</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nie</surname>
                  <given-names>Bingbing</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tsinghua Univ., Univ. of Virginia</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhou</surname>
                  <given-names>Qing</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tsinghua Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Xia</surname>
                  <given-names>Yong</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tsinghua Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tang</surname>
                  <given-names>Jisi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tsinghua Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>April 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169238</issue-id>
         <fpage>182</fpage>
         <lpage>189</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169249"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Vehicle hood styling has significant influence on headform kinematics in assessment tests of pedestrian impact protection performance. Pedestrian headform kinematics on vehicle front-end models with different hood styling characteristics is analyzed based on finite element modeling. More elevated feature lines near hood boundary and the following continuous hood surface towards fender will result in a different headform motion. It can lead to larger deformation space, more rotation and earlier rebound of the headform impactor, which will benefit the head impact protection performance. In addition, hood geometry characteristics such as hood angle and curvature have effects on structural stiffness. Therefore, inclusion of considerations on pedestrian head protection into the vehicle hood styling design stage may lead to a more effective and efficient engineering design process on headform impact analysis.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, G., Cao, L., Hu, J., and Yang, K. H., “A Field Data Analysis of Risk Factors Affecting the Injury Risks in Vehicle-to-Pedestrian Crashes,” Proceedings of 52nd Annual Proceedings of Association for the Advancement of Automotive Medicine (2008): 199-214, San Diego, US.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Traffic Safety Data and Analysis Group. IRTAD Road safety 2009 Annual Report, www.irtad.net, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Traffic Management Bureau of the Ministry of Public Security of China. Traffic Accident Annual Report, http://www.mps.gov.cn, 2004-2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhou, Q., Du, H. L. and Kong, F. Z., “Recent Progress in Pedestrian Impact Protection,” The 8th China International Conference of Automotive Safety Technology, Beijing, China, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alexander, B., Markus, E., Thomas, E. B., “Estimation of Benefits Resulting from Impactor-Testing for Pedestrian Protection,” The 18th International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles (ESV), Paper Number 142, Nagoya, Japan, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, J. K., “Injury Biomechanics and Protective Systems in Carto- Pedestrian Collisions,” Journal of Hunan University (Natural Science Edition). 28(3): 69-78, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EEVC WG17, “Improved Test Methods to Evaluate Pedestrian Protection Afforded by Passenger Cars,” Report, December 1998, updates Sept. 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Euro NCAP. Pedestrian Testing Protocol 6.1. www.euroncap.com, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kerkeling, C., Schäfer, J., Thompson, G., “Structural Hood and Hinge Concepts for Pedestrian Protection,” The 19th International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles (ESV), Paper Number 05-0304, Washington D.C., US, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ikeda, K. and Ishitobi, H., “Development of Aluminum Hood Structure for Pedestrian Protection,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-2793, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-2793.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Q., “Study of Pedestrian Friendly Vehicle Hood Concepts and Implementation,” Ph.D. thesis, Tsinghua University, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kerrigan, J., Arregui-Dalmases, C., Crandall, J., “Assessment of Pedestrian Head Impact Dynamics in Small Sedan and Large SUV Collisions,” International Journal of Crashworthiness, iFirst 2012: 1-16, 2012, doi:10.1080/13588265.2011.648517.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hu, J., Klinich, K. Toward Designing Pedestrian-Friendly Vehicles. Technical Report, UMTRI -2012-19, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shen, Z., Huang, J., Nie, B., “Investigation of the Effect of Vehicle Front-end Styling on Pedestrian Protection,” The 2010 China International Conference of Automotive Safety Technology, Chongqing, China, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Q., Xia, Y., Zhou, Q. and Wang, J. T., “Design Analysis of a Sandwich Hood Structure for Pedestrian Protection,” The 21st International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles Conference (ESV), Paper Number 09-0356, Stuttgart, Germany, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lissner, H. R., Lebow, M., and Evans, F. G., “Experimental Studies on the Relation between Acceleration and Intracranial Pressure Changes in Man,” Surg Gynecol Obstet., 111: 329-338, 1960.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takhounts E., Hasija V., Ridella S., et al. Kinematic Rotational Brain Injury Criterion (BRIC). The 22nd International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles (ESV), Paper Number 11-0263, Washington, D.C., United States, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Watanabe R., Miyazaki H., Kitagawa Y., Tsuyoshi Yasuki., “Research of Collision Speed Dependency Of Pedestrian Head and Chest Injuries Using Human Fe Model (Thums Version4),” The 22nd International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles (ESV), Paper Number 11-0043, Washington, D.C., United States, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruan, J. S., Khalil, T. B., and King, A. I., “Dynamic Response of the Human Head to Impact by Three-Dimensional Finite Element Analysis,” Journal of Biomechanical Engineering, 116: 44-50, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhou, C., Khalil, T., and King, A., “Shear Stress Distribution in the Porcine Brain due to Rotational Impact,” SAE Technical Paper 942214, 1994, doi:10.4271/942214.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bandak, F. and Eppinger, R., “A Three-Dimensional Finite Element Analysis of the Human Brain Under Combined Rotational and Translational Accelerations,” SAE Technical Paper 942215, 1994, doi:10.4271/942215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
