<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275488</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental Investigation of the Interaction of MultipleGDI Injections using Laser Diagnostics</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Martin</surname>
                  <given-names>Diana</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Institute of Heat and Mass Transfer, RWTH Aachen University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Stratmann</surname>
                  <given-names>Jochen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Institute of Heat and Mass Transfer, RWTH Aachen University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pischke</surname>
                  <given-names>Philipp</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Institute of Heat and Mass Transfer, RWTH Aachen University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kneer</surname>
                  <given-names>Reinhold</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Institute of Heat and Mass Transfer, RWTH Aachen University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lai</surname>
                  <given-names>Ming-Chia</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Wayne State University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>372</fpage>
         <lpage>388</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275488"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In present GDI engines, multiple injection strategies are often employed for engine cold start mixture formation. In the future, these strategies may also be used to control the combustion process, and to prevent misfiring or high emission levels. While the processes occurring during individual injections of GDI injectors have been investigated by a number of researchers, this paper concentrates on the interactions of multiple injection events. Even though multiple injection strategies are already applied in most GDI engines, the impact of the first injection event on the second injection event has not been analyzed in detail yet.</p>
            <p>Different optical measurement techniques are used in order to investigate the interaction of the two closely timed injection events, as well as the effect of dwell time and the in-cylinder conditions. The injector investigated is a GDI piezo injector with an outwardly opening needle. The laser diagnostics applied include measurement of the spray injection velocity profile close to the nozzle exit by Laser Correlation Velocimetry (LCV) and the droplet velocities at nozzle distances between 10 to 15 mm by Phase Doppler Anemometry (PDA). The penetration length and the overall spray shape, including the spray fingers and toroidal vortices, are compared using light scattering and laser light sheet measurements. A comparison of the spray structures shows that as well in-cylinder temperature and pressure as the dwell time have a significant impact on the intensity of the interaction.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Luttermann, C., Missy, S., Schwarz, C., and Klauer, N., “High Precision Injection in Verbindung mit Aufladung am Beispiel des neuen BMW Twin Turbo Ottomotors,” presented at 15th Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug- und Motorentechnik 2008, Germany, October, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schwarz, C., Missy, S., Steyer, H., Durst, B., Schünemann, E., Kern, W., and Witt, A., “Die neuen Vierund Sechszylinder-Ottomotoren von BMW mit Schichtbrennverfahren,” MTZ: 05/2007, Jahrgang 68, May 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reckers, W., Befrui, B., and Corbinelli, G., “Investigation of High Pressure GDi Conical Spray Atomization for Spray Guided Combustion Systems,” presented at 8th International Symposium on Combustion Diagnostics 2008, Germany, June 10-11, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Warncke, V., Achleitner, E., and Bäcker, H., “Entwicklungsstand des Siemens VDO Piezo- Einspritzsystems für strahlgeführte Brennverfahren,” presented at 27th Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium 2006, Austria, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Befrui, B., Corbinelli, G., Robart, D., Reckers, W. et al., “LES Simulation of the Internal Flow and Near-Field Spray Structure of an Outward -Opening GDi Injector and Comparison with Imaging Data,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0137, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prosperi, B., Delay, G., Bazile, R., Hélie, J., and Nuglish, H. J., “FPIV study of gas entrainment by a hollow cone spray submitted to variable,” Experiments in Fluids, 43:2-3, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gavaises, M., Tonini, S., Marchi, A., Theodorakakos, A., Bouris, D., and Matteucci, L., “Modelling of internal and near-nozzle flow of a pintle-type outwards-opening gasoline piezo-injector,” International Journal of Engine Research 7, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prosperi, B., Hélie, J., and Bazile, R., “PIV Measurement of Injection Pressure Influence on Gas Entrainement in GDI Engines,” presented at ILASS Europe, 21st Annual Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray System 2007, Turkey, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chaves, H., Knapp, M., Kubitzek, A., and Obermeier, F., “High speed flow measurements within an injection nozzle,” presented at 5th Int. Conf. Laser Anemometry Advances and Applications, SPIE 2052 Bellingham, USA, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schugger, C., “Experimentelle Untersuchung des primären Strahlterfalls bei der motorischen Hochdruckeinspritzung,” Ph.D. thesis, Institute of Heat and Mass Transfer, RWTH Aachen University, Germany, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stratmann, J., “Droplet-Wall and Spray-Wall Interaction at Increased Ambient Pressure and Wall Temperature,” Ph.D. thesis, Institute of Heat and Mass Transfer, RWTH Aachen University, Germany, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
