<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="other"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">3663798</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/323511</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB750109</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Doctoral Dissertations Accepted, 2000–2001</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>01</month>
            <year>2002</year>
            <string-date>January 2002</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>75</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2002.75.issue-1</issue-id>
         <fpage>203</fpage>
         <lpage>210</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/323511"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <title>Accounting</title>
         <p>Ira Wendell Bates. Arkansas. “An Analysis of the Elements of Difficulty in an Introductory Accounting Course.”</p>
         <p>Allen D. Blay. Univ. Florida. “Perceived Risks and the Auditor's Decision Process.”</p>
         <p>Qi Chen. Chicago. “Cooperation in the Budgeting Process.”</p>
         <p>Frank D. Hodge. Indiana. “Hyperlinking Unaudited Information to Audited Financial Statements: Effects on Investor Judgments.”</p>
         <p>Arthur Kraft. Chicago. “Account‐Based and Market‐Based Trading Strategies.”</p>
         <p>Qiang Li. Washington Univ. “Characteristics of Quarterly Earnings Time Series and Information Processing in Shareholder Lawsuits.”</p>
         <p>Teresa Lightner. Univ. Georgia. “An Analysis of the Tax‐Rate Differential between Ordinary and Capital Gains Tax Rates and Its Effect on the Structure of Corporate Payouts.”</p>
         <p>Kanogporn Narktabtee. Arkansas. “The Implication of Accounting Information in the Thai Capital Market.”</p>
         <p>David W. Randolph. Indiana. “Tax‐Motivated Income Shifting in the Property‐Casualty Industry.”</p>
         <p>Nathan V. Stuart. Indiana. “The Influence of Corporate Strategy, Maturity, and Change in the Competitive Environment on Executive Compensation Contracts: Evidence from the Pharmaceutical Industry.”</p>
         <p>Weimin Wang. Washington Univ. “Discretionary Choices of Accounting Methods and Value Relevance: The Case of R&amp;D Accounting in the Software Industry.”</p>
         <p>Donna D. Wei. California, Berkeley. “Studies in the Theory of Fixed Cost Allocation.”</p>
         <p>Ira Weiss. Chicago. “Managerial Responses to a Transitory Earnings Shock: Strategic Manipulation between the Core and Non‐core Components of Earning.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <title>Banking and Public Finance</title>
         <p>Michael Richard McAvoy. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Essays in Country Banking: Case Studies of the First National Bank of Bloomington (Illinois).”</p>
         <p>Brian Keith Weikel. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Essays on Semiparametric Methods in Finance.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <title>Business Economics and Economics</title>
         <p>Tiago Vanderlei de Vasconcelo Cavalcanti. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Essays on Macroeconomics and Informal Economies.”</p>
         <p>Paul Cowgill. Univ. Georgia. “A Productivity and Efficiency Study of Post‐reform China.”</p>
         <p>Christopher S. Decker. Indiana. “Corporate Environmentalism and Regulatory Responsiveness.”</p>
         <p>GiSeung Kim. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Markov‐Based Analysis of Life‐Cycle Employment Profiles.”</p>
         <p>Ryan Berry Lee. Univ. Georgia. “Financial Economics of Life Insurer Mergers.”</p>
         <p>Lars Lefgren. Chicago. “Are Educational Peer Effects Real? Evidence from the Chicago Public Schools.”</p>
         <p>Sonia Daryanani Marciano. Chicago. “Pricing Policies and Oligopoly with Product Differentiation: The Case of Cellular Telephony.”</p>
         <p>Christopher Reid Pope. Indiana. “The Professional Sports Owner and the Search for Revenue: Analyzing the Impact of New Stadiums on Team Quality, Owner Strategy, and Consumer Cost.”</p>
         <p>Ronald Lee Rainey. Arkansas. “Impacts of 1996 FAIR Act on Arkansas Agricultural Land Agreements.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <title>Business Education</title>
         <p>Harry Costin. Boston Univ. “An Empirical Study of Strategy‐Structure‐Performance Relationships of Graduate Business Schools and AACSB‐Accredited MBA Programs.”</p>
         <p>George L. Langelett. Nebraska—Lincoln. “Human Capital and Economic Growth in the Open Economy: An Appeal to Robustness.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc5">
         <title>Business Finance and Investments</title>
         <p>Il Yung Chung. Boston Univ. “Interest Rate Risk Management: Hedging Misspecification in Interest Rate Swaps.”</p>
         <p>Darin Clay. Chicago. “Institutional Ownership, CEO Incentives, and Firm Values.”</p>
         <p>Arthur Brent Comstock. Lehigh. “The Post‐privatization Financial Performances of Former State‐Owned Enterprises.”</p>
         <p>Hazem Daouk. Indiana. “Two Essays on the Response of Volatility to Returns.”</p>
         <p>Ming Dong. Ohio State. “A General Model of Stock Valuation: Theory and Applications.”</p>
         <p>Benjamin Lloyd Dow III. Arkansas. “Market Power as a Motive for Horizontal Acquisitions and Mergers.”</p>
         <p>Jeffrey M. Gropp. West Virginia. “Mean Reversion in U.S. Stock Prices: A Panel Approach.”</p>
         <p>Peter Hecht. Chicago. “The Cross‐Section of Expected Firm (Not Equity) Returns Design of Executive Compensation Contracts.”</p>
         <p>Byung‐Ju Kim. Lehigh. “The Regulatory and Procedural Effects on the Underpricing of Initial Public Offerings in Korea.”</p>
         <p>Jorg Kukies. Chicago. (1) “The Effect of Introducing New Equity Markets on the IPO Process”; (2) “Stock Markets for High‐Technology Firms and Venture Capital Financing: Evidence from Europe.”</p>
         <p>Leonard L. Lundstrum. Indiana. “Empirical Essays in Corporate Finance: Testing Theories of Market Imperfections and Costly Contracting.”</p>
         <p>Lionel Maretellini. California, Berkeley. “Three Essays in Asset Pricing Theory.”</p>
         <p>Mark Legge Muzere. Washington Univ. “Essays in Financial Economics.”</p>
         <p>Didit A. Ratam. Boston Univ. “Valuation and Hedging of Commodity‐Linked Interest Rate Swaps and Swaption.”</p>
         <p>Mark Allen Taranto. California, Berkeley. “Essays on Capital Structure and Dividend Policy.”</p>
         <p>Andrew C. Waisburd. Indiana. “Essays in Financial Market Automation.”</p>
         <p>Yu Wang. Washington Univ. “Essays in Asset Pricing and Corporate Finance.”</p>
         <p>Kehong Wen. California, Berkeley. “Essays on the Equilibrium Valuation of IPOs and Bonds.”</p>
         <p>Nicholas Xerxes Wonder. California, Berkeley. “Essays in Finance.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc6">
         <title>Industrial and Regional Studies</title>
         <p>Vladimir Starkov. West Virginia. “Essays on the Restructuring of the Electricity Industry in the United States.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc7">
         <title>Information Systems</title>
         <p>Michael Chilton. Arkansas. “Person‐Environment Fit and Paradigm Shifts: A Model of Behavioral Results Using Object‐Oriented Technology.”</p>
         <p>Charles Bryan Foltz. Arkansas. “The Impact of Deterrent Countermeasures upon Individual Intent to Commit Misuse: A Behavioral Approach.”</p>
         <p>Lee A. Freeman. Indiana. “The Effects of Concept Mapping on Shared Understanding during the Requirements Elicitation Phase of Information Systems Development.”</p>
         <p>Marc N. Haines. Univ. Georgia. “Effective Enterprise System Implementation: Aligning System Component Specialization with Organizational Strategy.”</p>
         <p>Hyokjin Kwak. Univ. Georgia. “Web‐Based Chatting: Consumer Communications and Commercial Communications.”</p>
         <p>Chi‐Hyon Lee. Boston Univ. “Information Technology Alliance Sourcing Efficacy: A Multi‐Method Comparison of Initial Value Distributions among Alliance Participants.”</p>
         <p>Christine Marie Lentz. Boston Univ. “From Comprehensiveness to Cohesiveness: An Organizational Capability for Achieving Value from Strategic IT Initiatives in the Life Insurance Industry.”</p>
         <p>Eleanor T. Loiacono. Univ. Georgia. “WebQual(tm): A Web Site Quality Instrument.”</p>
         <p>Sylnovie Spann Merchant. Arkansas. “The Influence of Individual Perceptions in the Diffusion of Technological Innovations: A Proposed Communication Adoption Model for Object‐Oriented Systems Development.”</p>
         <p>Lisa D. Murray. Indiana. “Digital Documents in the Workplace: An Empirical Investigation of Document Reuse and Information Technology Infrastructure.”</p>
         <p>Salvatore Parise. Boston Univ. “The Effects of Resource Exchange and Partner Roles on Alliance Performance.”</p>
         <p>Anne Louise Powell. Indiana. “Antecedents and Outcomes of Team Commitment in a Global, Virtual Environment.”</p>
         <p>Madhu T. Rao. Indiana. “Information Systems Management in Multinational Corporations: An Empirical Examination of the Factors Determining the Level and Form of Headquarters Control and Coordination over Subsidiary Information Systems Functions.”</p>
         <p>Andrew Urbaczewski. Indiana. “An Examination of the Effects of Electronic Monitoring of Employee Internet Usage.”</p>
         <p>Carlos Férran Urdaneta. Boston Univ. “The Effects of Videoconferencing on Persuasion.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc8">
         <title>Insurance</title>
         <p>Kevin C. Ahlgrim. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “The Effects of Multifactor Term Structure Models on Insurance Valuation.”</p>
         <p>Jaehyun Kim. Temple. “A Comparative Study on Productive Efficiency: Japan and the United States Non–Life Insurance Industries.”</p>
         <p>Kathleen A. McCullough. Univ. Georgia. “The Implications of Corporate Diversification and Focus: Evidence from Acquisitions in the Insurance Industry.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc9">
         <title>International Trade and Finance</title>
         <p>Andre Horta Barreto. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Essays on Internation Finance.”</p>
         <p>Ariaster B. Chimeli. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Environmental Quality and Economic Development.”</p>
         <p>Jeong Chul Ha. Temple. “Executive Compensation and Firm Performance: Domestic and Multinational Firms.”</p>
         <p>Mursaleena Islam. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Flood Plain Resource Management: An Economic Analysis of Policy Issues in Bangladesh.”</p>
         <p>Hyun‐A Kim. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Essays on Urban Economics.”</p>
         <p>Harsh Mishra. Temple. “Determinants of Cross‐National Knowledge Sourcing and Its Effect on Firm Innovation.”</p>
         <p>Erik Skaden. Nebraska—Lincoln. “Does Financial Development Robustly Confirm Economic Growth: A Time Series Empirical Approach.”</p>
         <p>Danchi Tan. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Managerial Limits to International Expansion by Acquisitions and Greenfields: An Empirical Examination of Japanese Direct Investments in the United States.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc10">
         <title>Management Organization Theory and Practice</title>
         <p>Sally Baack. USC. “Board Involvement in the Strategy Process: Antecedents and Consequences.”</p>
         <p>Calvin M. Bacon. Univ. Georgia. “The Determinants of New Venture Success: Venture Resources, Strategy, and Industry Structure.”</p>
         <p>S. Trevis Certo. Indiana. “Boards of Directors as Signals of Cooptation: A Study of Initial Public Offerings.”</p>
         <p>Wade M. Danis. Indiana. “Integration of Managerial Values, Practices, and Systems in International Cooperative Business Ventures: The Case of Hungary.”</p>
         <p>Lisa Epstein Dickstein. California, Berkeley. “Sharing Knowledge in Organizations: How People Use Media to Communicate.”</p>
         <p>Kent Stephen Faught. Arkansas. “Total Quality Management Systems: Construct Definition and Organizational‐Level Effects.”</p>
         <p>Peter Foreman. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Managing Identities in Managed Care: Top‐Management‐Team Responses to Organizational Complexity and Change.”</p>
         <p>April Corinne Gilbert. California, Berkeley. “Work Absorption: Causes among Highly Educated Workers and Consequences for Their Families.”</p>
         <p>Sheila Goins. Chicago. “Rival and Shareholder Influences in Corporate Layoff Decisions.”</p>
         <p>Yongliang Han. USC. “What Drives R &amp; D Alliances? Evidence from the Biotechnology Industry.”</p>
         <p>Kimberly Jaussi. USC. “The Relationship between Attitudinal Commitment and Organizational Performance: An Empirical Investigation.”</p>
         <p>Susanna Khavul. Boston Univ. “Money and Knowledge: Sources of Seed Capital and the Performance of High Technology Start‐Ups.”</p>
         <p>Hoe Jeong Kim. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Role of Institutions in Fiscal and Monetary Policies.”</p>
         <p>Yasemin Y. Kor. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Resource Deployment Strategies Following Initial Public Offerings: Connecting Resource‐Based, Upper Echelons, and Agency Perspectives.”</p>
         <p>Carter Lloyds. USC. “The Determinants of New Media Firm Foundings in the United States.”</p>
         <p>Ofer Meilich. USC. “Formalization and Organizational Performance: Determinants of Successful and Unsuccessful Bureaucratization.”</p>
         <p>Douglas Miller. Ohio State. “Corporate Diversification, Relatedness, and Performance.”</p>
         <p>Hettie Ann Richardson. Univ. Georgia. “Exploring the Mechanisms through Which High Involvement Work Processes Result in Group‐Level Performance Outcomes.”</p>
         <p>Eric Marshall Stark. Arkansas. “Team‐Related Attitude Change: A Conceptual Framework and Empirical Test.”</p>
         <p>Lynne Devnew Wolfe. Boston Univ. “Interpreting the Implications of the Internet: An Exploratory Study of CEOs in the Consumer Catalog Industry.”</p>
         <p>Anthea Zhang. USC. “Three Empirical Essays on CEO Succession: Multi‐theoretic Perspectives.”</p>
         <p>Kathrin Zoeller. Univ. Georgia. “Corporate Structure and Corporate Governance in Europe and the United States.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc11">
         <title>Marketing</title>
         <p>Michael J. Ahearne. Indiana. “An Examination of the Effects of Leadership Empowerment Behaviors and Organizational Citizenship Behaviors on Sales Team Performance.”</p>
         <p>Maria Tereza Cerqueira Alexandre. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Relationships between Firms' Sources of Technologies and Their Product Market Opportunities.”</p>
         <p>Suraj Commuri. Nebraska—Lincoln. “A Grounded Theory of Joint Consumption Decision Making.”</p>
         <p>Thomas Gerard Costello. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “The Role of Affect (Valence and Intensity) in Product Consumption.”</p>
         <p>Devon Delvecchio. Indiana. “When Does Price Promotion Decrease Subsequent Period Choice Probability? Testing the Assumptions Underlying Reference Price Theory.”</p>
         <p>Deborah June Evers. Arkansas. “Vegetarianism and Identity: The Politics of Eating.”</p>
         <p>Judith Garretson. Arkansas. “Brand Characteristics in Promotion: Their Role as Retrieval Cues.”</p>
         <p>Jeanie Han. USC. “The Effects of Explicitly vs. Implicitly Valued Incentive on Consumer Evaluation and Choice.”</p>
         <p>Heather Lee Honea. California, Berkeley. “Affect and Consumer Response to Promotions.”</p>
         <p>Maqbul Jamil. Indiana. “Consumer Response to Retail Assortment Reduction Strategies.”</p>
         <p>Joseph Johnson. USC. “Losers, Winners, and Hype: Consumer Choice under Uncertainty.”</p>
         <p>Velitchka Dimitrova Kaltcheva. Univ. Florida. “The Moderating Effect of Motivational Orientation on the Relationship between Activation and Pleasantness.”</p>
         <p>Jaehwan Kim. Ohio State. “Modeling Consumer Preference and Satiation for Complementary Characteristics.”</p>
         <p>Sylvia Long‐Tolbert. Ohio State. “A Conceptual Framework and Empirical Tests of the Antecedents and Consequences of Corporate Reputation: A Study of Consumer Markets.”</p>
         <p>Tom Meyvis. Univ. Florida. “Consumers' Beliefs in Product Benefits: The Effect of Irrelevant Product Information.”</p>
         <p>Rakesh Kumar Niraj. Washington Univ. “Essays in Distribution Channel Management under Demand Uncertainty.”</p>
         <p>Ramaprasad M. Unni. Indiana. “Relative Effectiveness of Electronic vs. Traditional Sources in Communicating Product Information.”</p>
         <p>Yun‐Oh Whang. USC. “Why Do Consumers Overspend? A Conceptual Framework for Consumer Choice Behavior under Budget Control.”</p>
         <p>John Wright. Chicago. “The Influence of Absolute Differences and Relative Differences on Unidimensional Difference Judgements.”</p>
         <p>Debra L. Zahay. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Aligning Strategy and Customer Information for Performance in Business Markets.”</p>
         <p>Ying Zhao. California, Berkeley. “Price Dispersion and Retailer Behavior.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc12">
         <title>Medical Economics and Health Administration</title>
         <p>Eric Wayne Christensen. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Quality, Cost, and Access Issues in Nursing Home Care.”</p>
         <p>Michael Jae Woo Lee. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “The Pricing of Pharmaceuticals by Online and Traditional Retailers: An Empirical Examination.”</p>
         <p>Sonya Butler Merrill. Temple. “An Investigation of the Relationship between a Measure of Hospital Reputation and Patient Volume.”</p>
         <p>Heather Radach Spang. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “The Impact of Hospital Consolidation: An Examination of Consolidating Hospitals and Their Rivals.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc13">
         <title>Operations Research and Management Science</title>
         <p>Elliot Bendoly. Indiana. “Supply and Demand Management in Clicks‐and‐Mortar Operations.”</p>
         <p>John Borse. Chicago. “Symbolic Optimization and the SyOpt System.”</p>
         <p>Chialin Chen. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Integrating Operations and Environmental Management: Focusing on Product and Process Innovation.”</p>
         <p>Mark A. Christobek. Temple. “A Comparison of the Effectiveness of Statistical Process Control Charts.”</p>
         <p>Thomas Frederic Gattiker. Univ. Georgia. “Enterprise Resource Planning Systems in Operations Management: A Model, an Instrument and an Empirical Test.”</p>
         <p>Sufeng Ma. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Long‐Term Agency Relationships and Human Capital Investment.”</p>
         <p>Kelly Beth Nichols. Indiana. “The Product Line Pricing and Positioning Problem: A Meta‐heuristic Approach.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc14">
         <title>Personnel and Industrial Relations</title>
         <p>David Jonathan Balan. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Three Essays in Personnel Economics.”</p>
         <p>Carol C. Cirka. Temple. “Compliance and Constructive Contributions in Organizations: Effects of Managerial Control Styles on Proactive Employee Behaviors.”</p>
         <p>Robert Lee Cross, Jr. Boston Univ. “A Relational View of Information Seeking Personal and Impersonal Source Employed in Intentional Search.”</p>
         <p>Kimberly‐Ann Eddleston. Connecticut. “What Managers Seek from Their Careers: Expanding the Traditional Model of Career Satisfaction.”</p>
         <p>Unnikammu Moideenkutty. Temple. “Correlates and Outcomes of Organizational Citizenship Behavior Directed toward the Organization, the Supervisor, and Co‐workers: A Social Exchange Perspective.”</p>
         <p>Guorong Zhu. Boston Univ. “Psychological Contract Alignment and Repatriation Success.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc15">
         <title>Production</title>
         <p>Michael H. Way. Indiana. “The Intra‐organizational Diffusion of Best Manufacturing Practice.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc16">
         <title>Public and Nonprofit Institutions</title>
         <p>Joshua B. Powers. Indiana. “Academic Entrepreneurship in Higher Education: Institutional Effects in Performance of University Technology Transfer.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc17">
         <title>Social Control and Business Law</title>
         <p>Bennet Andrew Zelner. California, Berkeley. “Political Institutions, Interest Group Competition and Investment Strategy: International and Domestic Applications to Electric Utilities.”</p>
         <p>Arvids Alexander Ziedonis. California, Berkeley. “The Commercialization of University Technology: Implications for Firm Strategy and Public Policy.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc18">
         <title>Statistics and Econometrics</title>
         <p>Xuezheng Bai. Chicago. “Efficiency of Variance Estimate Using High Frequency Financial Data.”</p>
         <p>Kevin L. Busby. Alabama. “Interpreting Out‐of‐Control Signals from Hotelling's T<sup>2</sup>Chart.”</p>
         <p>Yea‐Jane Chu. Chicago. (1) “Asymptotic Distributions of Some Portmanteau Statistics for Nonstationary Time Series”; (2) “Some Issues about Time Series and Decomposition and Seasonal Adjustment.”</p>
         <p>Mawia Kaddoura. Alabama. “Density Estimation through Kernel Estimation‐based Empirical Characteristic Function.”</p>
         <p>Grigorios Kordas. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Binary Regression Quantiles.”</p>
         <p>Sreelatha Meleth. Alabama. “Analyzing Data Sets with a Mixture of Mar and Ninr Data: Assessing the Impact of Sample Size and Proportion Missing on Estimates.”</p>
         <p>Hetti Arachchige Gamini Premaratne. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Time Series Models for Analyzing Financial Data.”</p>
         <p>Deepa Sridhar. Univ. Georgia. “Postsecondary Enrollment Effects of Merit‐Based Financial Aid: Evidence from Georgia's Hope Scholarship Program.”</p>
         <p>Teruko Takada. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Destiny Estimation for Robust Financial Econometrics.”</p>
         <p>Lei Wang. Alabama. “Longitudinal Ecologic Study with Temporal‐Spatially Correlated Data: Comparison of Alternate Methods.”</p>
         <p>Yuanjie Zhang. Chicago. “Econometric Modeling of High‐Frequency Financial Data with Applications to Market Microstructure.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc19">
         <title>Miscellaneous</title>
         <p>Murillo Netto Carneiro Campello. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Three Essays in Corporate Finance and Banking.”</p>
         <p>Carolyn A. Dehring. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Three Essays in Real Estate and Urban Economics.”</p>
      </sec>
   </body>
</article>
