<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278298</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effect of Tumble Flow on Efficiency for a Direct Injected Turbocharged Downsized Gasoline Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Berntsson</surname>
                  <given-names>Andreas W.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Josefsson</surname>
                  <given-names>Göran</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ekdahl</surname>
                  <given-names>Roy</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ogink</surname>
                  <given-names>Roy</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Grandin</surname>
                  <given-names>Börje</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Volvo Car Corporation</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278288</issue-id>
         <fpage>2298</fpage>
         <lpage>2311</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278298"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Direct gasoline injection combined with turbo charging and down sizing is a cost effective concept to meet future requirements for emission reduction as well as increased efficiency for passenger cars. It is well known that turbulence induced by in-cylinder air motion can influence efficiency. In this study, the intake-generated flow field was varied for a direct injected turbo charged concept, with the intent to evaluate if further increase in tumble potentially could lead to higher efficiency compared to the baseline. A single cylinder head with flow separating walls in the intake ports and different restriction plates was used to allow different levels of tumble to be experimentally evaluated in a single cylinder engine. The different levels of tumble were quantified by flow rig experiments.</p>
            <p>Two series of experiments were performed, one aiming to evaluate tumble in the region of low to medium load and engine speed, mainly focusing on efficiency, and one for the high load region to evaluate any negative consequences of increased tumble. The results indicate that tumble positively can influence the efficiency and emissions, however, the shape of the incoming flow dictate the level of impact significantly. Even for a relatively small change in tumble great differences in heat loss were seen. The efficiency increase seen originated mainly from lower heat loss through the exhaust gases. Additional gain came from lower in cylinder heat loss for the more favorable shape of the flow, where CFD indicates that the incoming air initially follows the cylinder head to a greater extent. Negative consequences are also associated with increased tumble. For instance, excessive pressure rise rates which can result in noise issues at higher loads. However, from a combustion perspective, the turbulence induced by the tumble positively effects the main parameters with reduced combustion duration, increased stability and increased exhaust gas recycling tolerance as well as increased combustion efficiency, features that are beneficial especially for a direct injected down sized turbo charged concept.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, F. Lai, M.-C. Harrington, D. L., “Automotive sparkignited direct-injection gasoline engines”, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, Volume 25, Pages 437-562 (1999).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wirth, M., Mayerhofer, U., Piock, W., and Fraidl, G., “Turbocharging the DI Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0251, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0251.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bandel, W., Fraidl, G., Kapus, P., Sikinger, H. et al., “The Turbocharged GDI Engine: Boosted Synergies for High Fuel Economy Plus Ultra-low Emission,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1266, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kasseris, E. and Heywood, J., “Comparative Analysis of Automotive Powertrain Choices for the Next 25 Years,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1605, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-1605.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kirwan, J., Shost, M., Roth, G., and Zizelman, J., “3- Cylinder Turbocharged Gasoline Direct Injection: A High Value Solution for Low CO2 and NOx Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):355-371, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0590.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ranini, A. and Monnier, G., “Turbocharging a Gasoline Direct Injection Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0736, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0736.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B. “Internal Combustion Engines Fundamentals” 1988, Singapore: McGraw-Hill Inc.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wakisaka, T. Shimamoto, Y., Isshiki, Y., Sumi, N., Tamura, K. and Modien, R. M., “Analysis of the Effects of In-Cylinder Flows during Intake Stroke on the Flow Characteristics near Compression TDC in Four-Stroke Cycle Engines”, International Symposium COMODIA, Volume 90, Pages 487-492 (1990).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arcoumanis, C., Hu, Z., Vafidis, C., and Whitelaw, J., “Tumbling Motion: A Mechanism for Turbulence Enhancement in Spark-Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 900060, 1990, doi: 10.4271/900060.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hadded, O. and Denbratt, I., “Turbulence Characteristics of Tumbling Air Motion in Four-Valve S.I. Engines and their Correlation with Combustion Parameters,” SAE Technical Paper 910478, 1991, doi: 10.4271/910478.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arcoumanis, C., Godwin, S., and Kim, J., “Effect of Tumble Strength on Combustion and Exhaust Emissions in a Single-Cylinder, Four-Valve, Spark-Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 981044, 1998, doi: 10.4271/981044.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kent, J., Mikulec, A., Rimal, L., Adamczyk, A. et al., “Observations on the Effects of Intake-Generated Swirl and Tumble on Combustion Duration,” SAE Technical Paper 892096, 1989, doi: 10.4271/892096.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hirooka, H., Mori, S., and Shimizu, R., “Effects of High Turbulence Flow on Knock Characteristics,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0977, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0977.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, Y., Selamet, A., Reese, R., Vick, R. et al., “Impact of Tumble on Combustion in SI Engines: Correlation between Flow and Engine Experiments,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4003, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-4003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wurms, R. Grigo, M., Hatz, W., “Audi FSI technology improved performance and reduced fuel consumption”, ATA, Volume 56 (2003).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wotton, C. R. N. “Ricardo Steady State Flowbench Port Performance Measurement and Analysis Techniques”, DP93/0704 (1993).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rouland, E., Trinité, M., Dionnet, F., Floch, A. et al., “Particle Image Velocimetry Measurements in a High Tumble Engine for In-Cylinder Flow Structure Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 972831, 1997, doi: 10.4271/972831.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hascher, H., Schock, H., Avanessian, O., and Novak, J., “A Comparison of Modeled and Measured 3-D In-Cylinder Charge Motion Throughout the Displacement of a Four- Valve SI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2799, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-2799.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
