<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">5</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465733</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465740</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Monotonicity of the Stochastic Discount Factor and Expected Option Returns</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ranadeb</given-names>
                  <surname>Chaudhuri</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Mark</given-names>
                  <surname>Schroder</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1462</fpage>
         <lpage>1505</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465740"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Evidence shows that the stochastic discount factor (SDF) is not always a downward-sloping function of S&amp;P 500 returns when estimated using options data. In contrast, our results suggest that SDFs as functions of individual stock returns are generally downward sloping. A simple jump-diffusion model can reconcile these empirical findings. The same model also implies a steeper implied-volatility curve for the index than for the typical stock, a well-known empirical fact from the options literature. Both the SDF and volatility-curve results can be explained by a common source of jump risk among stocks, together with diversification of Brownian risk in the index. We also devise novel empirical tests of SDF monotonicity based on average returns of option trading strategies, thus avoiding the estimation of the return density functions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d2157785e236a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e243" publication-type="other">
A bullish call spread is long a call at one strike price and short a call at a higher strike price, with both options
on the same stock and with the same expiration.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e253a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e260" publication-type="other">
Explanations for nonmonotonicity include nontraded income or state variables (Brown and Jackwerth 2004);
state dependence in the representative agent's utility (Brown and Jackwerth 2004); heterogeneous investor
beliefs (Ziegler 2007; Bakshi and Madan 2009; and Hens and Reichlin 2013); the influence of a latent state
variable (Chabi-Yo, Garcia, and Renault 2008); Epstein-Zin preferences and a persistent state variable subject to
jumps (Benzoni, Collin-Dufresne, and Goldstein 2011); negative variance risk premium (Christoffersen, Heston,
and Jacobs 2013); and investor sentiment (Han 2008). There is some contradictory evidence. For example,
Barone-Adesi and Dall'O (2012)'s findings support strict monotonicity.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e286a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e293" publication-type="other">
The "rate of compensation" in our context is defined as the market price of risk per unit return.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e300a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e307" publication-type="other">
More precisely, the left-hand and right-hand derivatives of ln(g()) (which exist by concavity) are strictly
decreasing. Concave functions are differentiable (the left and right-hand derivatives are the same) almost
everywhere.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e321a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e328" publication-type="other">
Although the case of butterfly spreads (as well as call options) suggests a link to skewness, we emphasize that a
(first-order dominance) shift to the right in payouts does not imply, nor is implied by, an increase in skewness.
For example, vanilla and binary put options both have log-concave payouts and, therefore, expected returns
increasing in strike, but the skewness of returns of both typically decreases as the strike increases.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e344a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e351" publication-type="other">
The proof can be provided upon request. It is essentially the same as the sufficiency part of the proof of Proposition
1 after replacing g'/g with ~pk/P-</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e361a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e368" publication-type="other">
More precisely, we follow the CBOE strike-increment rule and remove those stock-week combinations for which
the absolute difference between the current stock price and nearest strike is $2.5 or higher when current stock
prices are $25 or less, $5 or higher when the stock price is $25 through $200, and $10 or higher when the stock
price is over $200. There are 559 such cases (on average, less than one occurrence a week) which represents less
than 0.1 % of our final sample.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e387a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e394" publication-type="other">
If a particular option price is missing or does not satisfy the no-arbitrage restriction, then the associated return
differences are considered as missing. For example if the strike group 2 return for a stock on a particular week
is missing, then we assign the return differences "2— l"and "3-2" as missing.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e407a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e414" publication-type="other">
Rejection of monotonicity based on unconditional returns would imply rejection with conditional returns (a
conditional expectation cannot be a.s. positive if the expectation is negative). However, with sufficient data, a
stricter test of monotonicity could be designed when unconditional expectations are found to be strictly positive.
Nevertheless, in our jump-diffiision model, with returns modeled as a Levy process, the projected SDF and the
option-strategy returns do not depend on any state variables, and the "conditioning down" has no effect.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e433a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e440" publication-type="other">
Broadie et al. (2009) also argue that care must be taken when assessing the performance of option returns because
of their high skewness.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e451a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e458" publication-type="other">
As one indication, using her sorting rule, the average elasticity for her deep OTM calls is smaller than that for
the At-the-Money (ATM) group, even though Black-Scholes elasticities are monotonically increasing in strike,
ceteris paribus. One explanation for this is that her sorting rule results in assigning a disproportionate number of
low priced, and, consequently, significantly higher volatility stocks to higher strike groups. In the Black-Scholes
model, for example, the elasticity of a call option, and therefore the call-option expected return, decreases with
volatility. This causes her deep OTM calls to have lower average returns than those of the ATM calls. Detailed
tables illustrating these results can be provided upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e484a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e491" publication-type="other">
The assumption p &gt;0 is without loss of generality (we can always reverse the signs Bc) we assume a' &gt; 0 for
simplicity, so that each stock has positive per-unit-return market price of systematic Brownian risk.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e501a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e508" publication-type="other">
See also Das and Uppal (2004), who consider a common jump model in an international setting and its effect on
portfolio choice.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e518a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e525" publication-type="other">
In the Ito expansion of the state-price density, ln(X/A.) is the coefficient of dNt, and — rf is the coefficient of
dBf. Because the state-price density in this model is strictly positive, the model is arbitrage free.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e535a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e542" publication-type="other">
That is, there exist constants y,e&gt; 0 such that K -4tto(K)— &lt;yyfx for all r</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e549a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e556" publication-type="other">
If X &gt; A. but stock i's price increases at market crashes ({/1 &gt; 0), then Sl &gt; 0 necessarily holds because the positive
crash reward (instead of a negative Brownian reward) is associated with returns above yfr' /2.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e567a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e574" publication-type="other">
Bakshi and Wu (201 l)'s diffusion risk coefficient (which, in their setting, is the negative of the state-price-density
coefficient of dBf times the stock volatility) is estimated to be 1.82, which must be multiplied by a =0.30 to
obtain our rf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e587a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e594" publication-type="other">
See also Branger and others (2008). They show, using simulations, that diversification of the idiosyncratic
component of stochastic volatility produces steeper implied slopes for indexes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e604a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e611" publication-type="other">
The ATM slope for each stock is calculated by first finding the two strikes nearest to the money, and then
computing the ratio of the difference in the two implied volatilities to the difference in the two strikes. Our
results are insensitive to the normalization. We get similar results if we sort based on the slope measure n
instead.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e627a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e634" publication-type="other">
The betas, /?, and RMSE are estimated for each underlying stock and each month from the Fama-French and
Carhart 4-factor regression model using daily returns. Similar results are obtained using just the CAPM or
Fama-French 3 factor model</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e647a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e654" publication-type="other">
Stocks with market capitalization less than $1 billion are classified as small cap, $1 billion to $5 billion as
midcap, and greater than $5 billion as large cap. Market-to-book ratios are calculated using definitions provided
on Kenneth French's website, and we use trading volume of the underlying stock on the buying date of the option
strategy as a proxy for liquidity. Firms are classified as financials if their SIC codes are between 6000 and 6999.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e670a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e677" publication-type="other">
To apply the lemma, define Y=m{Sj), and the decreasing function f(Y)= 1 (K)^.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e685a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e692" publication-type="other">
As another example, if Jj = riy=i Vj where {Vj; j = 1,2,...) are i.i.d., then In J Ë (/{ j | =XË(V — 1).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e699a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e706" publication-type="other">
It is well known that put-call parity implies that the implied volatilities for European calls and puts are identical.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e713a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e720" publication-type="other">
Although, our focus is on testing monotonically increasing alternatives, this test, in principle, can be modified
to test other patterned alternatives (for example, U-shaped kernels).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e730a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e737" publication-type="other">
We take the average-return differences from our pairwise tests (Section 3.1 ) and, for each period, cumulate them
across strike groups to get an average return for each group. Strike group zero is assigned a zero average return;
average returns for all other groups are relative to strike group zero.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e750a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e757" publication-type="other">
Unlike the Spearman rank correlation test, the Page test allows dependence among each time-/ set of observations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e764a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e771" publication-type="other">
Equally likely ranks implies
Var(Lt)=-i-0:+l)2(fc —1),
which yields the classical Page statistic.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e785a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e792" publication-type="other">
A special case is if each permutation is equally likely (as in the classical Page test). Another special case is if the
distribution of the rank is symmetric under Hq in the sense that the distribution of (xj,...xf^ is the same as
the distribution ^xf,...xj^j, which includes the case of only two equally likely rankings: strictly ascending or
strictly descending.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e808a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e815" publication-type="other">
Closely related to Page is the test of Bathke (2009), which is Equation (Dl) but with X replaced by Y in the
definition of Lt, where (y^denotes the length-T k vector of ranks of the entire sample of average
returns across time and strikes (which is some permutation of {1,..., T • k}). That is, the Page test is based on the
per-period ranks of average returns, whereas the Bathke (2009) test is based on the overall average ranks. The
assumptions for asymptotic standard normality of B under the null are therefore stronger. In particular, Bathke
(2009) assumes that the average return vectors are i.i.d. over time. Heteroscedasticity is likely to be more of a
problem with the Bathke (2009) tests because, for example, increasing variance over time is likely to result in
more extreme ranks appearing later in the sample, giving more weight to those observations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157785e844a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157785e851" publication-type="other">
We thank Andrew Patton for providing the MATLAB code for the stationary bootstrap on his website.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d2157785e867a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e871" publication-type="other">
Ait-Sahalia, Y., and A. Lo. 2000. Nonparametric risk management and implied risk aversion. Journal of
Econometrics 94:9-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e881a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e885" publication-type="other">
Bakshi, G, N. Kapadia, and D. Madan. 2003. Stock return characteristics, skew laws, and the differential pricing
of individual equity options. The Review of Financial Studies 16:101-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e895a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e899" publication-type="other">
Bakshi, G, and D. Madan. 2009. Investor heterogeneity and the non-monotonicity of the aggregate marginal rate
of substitution in market index. Working Paper, University of Maryland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e909a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e913" publication-type="other">
Bakshi, G, D. Madan, and G Panayotov. 2010. Returns of claims on the upside and the viability of U-Shaped
Pricing Kernels. Journal of Financial Economics 97:130-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e924a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e928" publication-type="other">
Bakshi, G, and L. Wu. 2011. The behavior of risk and market prices of risk over the nasdaq bubble period.
Journal of Financial Economics 100:475-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e938a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e942" publication-type="other">
Barone-Adesi, G, and H. Dall'O. 2012. Is the price kernel monotone? ACRN Journal of Finance and Risk
Perspectives 1:43-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e952a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e956" publication-type="other">
Barone-Adesi, G, R. Engle, and L. Mancini. 2008. Garch options in incomplete markets. Review of Financial
Studies 21:1223-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e966a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e970" publication-type="other">
Bates, D. 2000. Post-'87 crash fears in the S&amp;P 500 futures option market. Journal of Econometrics
94:181-238.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e980a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e984" publication-type="other">
Bathke, A. 2009. A unified approach to nonparametric trend tests for dependent and independent samples. Metrika
69:17-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e994a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e998" publication-type="other">
Beare, B. 2011. Measure preserving derivatives and the pricing kernel puzzle. Journal of Mathematical Economics
47:689-697.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1009a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1013" publication-type="other">
Beare, B., and L. Schmidt. 2013. An empirical test of pricing kernel monotonicity. Journal of Applied
Econometrics. Forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1023a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1027" publication-type="other">
Benzoni, L., P. Collin-Dufresne, and R. Goldstein. 2011. Explaining asset pricing puzzles associated with the
1987 market crash. Journal of Financial Economics 101:552-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1037a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1041" publication-type="other">
Bernard, C., and P. Boyle. 2010. Explicit representation of cost-efficient strategies. Finance Meeting
EUROFIDAI - AFFI.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1051a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1055" publication-type="other">
Branger, N., and C. Schlag. 2004. Why is the index smile so steep? Review of Finance 8:109-127.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1062a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1066" publication-type="other">
Branger, N., H. Kraft, A. Mahayni, and C. Schlag. 2008. Reconciling smiles for index and stock options. Working
Paper, Goethe University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1076a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1080" publication-type="other">
Branger, N., A. Hansis, and C. Schlag. 2010. Expected option returns and the structure of jump risk premia.
Working Paper, Goethe University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1091a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1095" publication-type="other">
Breeden, D., and R. Litzenberger. 1978. Prices of state-contingent claims implicit in option prices. Journal of
Business 51:621-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1105a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1109" publication-type="other">
Broadie, M., M. Chernov, and M. Johannes. 2009. Understanding index option returns. Review of Financial
Studies 22:4493-529.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1119a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1123" publication-type="other">
Brown, D., and J. Jackwerth. 2004. The pricing kernel puzzle: reconciling index option data and economic theory.
Working Paper, University of Konstanz.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1133a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1137" publication-type="other">
Chabi-Yo, F., R. Garcia, and E. Renault. 2008. State dependence can explain the risk aversion puzzle. Review of
Financial Studies 21:973-1011.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1147a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1151" publication-type="other">
Chen, L. 1995. Testing the mean of skewed distributions. Journal of the American Statistical Association
90:767-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1161a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1165" publication-type="other">
Christoffersen, P., S. Heston, and K. Jacobs. 2013. Capturing option anomalies with a variance-dependent pricing
kernel. Review of Financial Studies 26:1962-2006.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1176a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1180" publication-type="other">
Constantinides, G, J. Jackwerth, and S. Perrakis. 2009. Mispricing of S&amp;P 500 index options. The Review of
Financial Studies 22:1247-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1190a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1194" publication-type="other">
Constantinides, G, and S. Perrakis. 2002. Stochastic dominance bounds on derivatives prices in a multiperiod
economy with proportional transaction costs. Journal of Economic Dynamics &amp; Control 26:1323-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1204a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1208" publication-type="other">
. 2006. Stochastic dominance bounds on American option prices in markets with frictions. Review of
Finance 10:1-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1218a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1222" publication-type="other">
Coval, J., and T. Shumway. 2001. Expected option returns. Journal of Finance 56:983-1009.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1229a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1233" publication-type="other">
Cox, J., S. Ross, and M. Rubinstein. 1979. Option pricing: A simplified approach. Journal of Financial Economics
7:229-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1243a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1247" publication-type="other">
Cremers, M., M. Hailing, and D. Weinbaum. 2014. Aggregate jump and volatility risk in the cross-section of
stock returns. Journal of Finance Forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1258a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1262" publication-type="other">
Das, S., and R. Uppal. 2004. Systemic risk and international portfolio choice. Journal of Finance
59:2809-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1272a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1276" publication-type="other">
Dennis, P., and S. Mayhew. 2002. Risk-neutral skewness: Evidence from stock options. Journal of Financial and
Quantitative Analysis 37:471-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1286a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1290" publication-type="other">
Duan, J., and J. Wei. 2009. Systematic risk and the price structure of individual equity options. The Review of
Financial Studies 22:1981-2006.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1300a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1304" publication-type="other">
Dybvig, P. 1988. Distributional analysis of portfolio choice. Journal of Business 61:369-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1311a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1315" publication-type="other">
Elkamhi, R., and C. Ornthanalai. 2010. Market jump risk and the price structure of individual equity options.
Working Paper, University of Iowa.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1325a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1329" publication-type="other">
Hall, P. 1983. Inverting an edgeworth expansion. The Annals of Statistics 11:569-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1337a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1341" publication-type="other">
Han, B. 2008. Investor sentiment and option prices. The Review of Financial Studies 21:387-414.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1348a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1352" publication-type="other">
Hansen, L., and K. Singleton. 1983. Stochastic consumption, risk aversion,and the temporal behavior of asset
returns. Journal of Political Economy 91:249-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1362a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1366" publication-type="other">
Hens, T., and C. Reichlin. 2013. Three solutions to the pricing kernel puzzle. Review of Finance
17:1065-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1376a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1380" publication-type="other">
Huang, C., and R. Litzenberger. 1988. Foundations for financial economics. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice
Hall.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1390a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1394" publication-type="other">
Jackwerth, J., and M. Rubinstein. 1996. Recovering probability distributions from option prices. Journal of
Finance 51:1611-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1404a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1408" publication-type="other">
Jackwerth, J. 2000. Recovering risk aversion from option prices and realized returns. Review of Financial Studies
13:433-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1419a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1423" publication-type="other">
Johnson, N. 1978. Modified t tests and confidence intervals for asymmetrical populations. Journal of the American
Statistical Association 73:536-44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1433a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1437" publication-type="other">
Ledoit, O., P. Santa-Clara, and S. Yan. 2002. Relative pricing of options with stochastic volatility. Working Paper,
Anderson Graduate School of Management, UCLA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1447a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1451" publication-type="other">
Levy, H. 1985. Upper and lower bounds of put and call option value: stochastic dominance approach. Journal
of Finance 40:1197-217.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1461a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1465" publication-type="other">
Li, S. 2013. Continuous beta, discontinuous beta, and the cross-section of expected stock returns. Working Paper,
Michigan State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1475a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1479" publication-type="other">
Ni, S. 2007. Stock option returns: A puzzle. Working paper, University of Illinois at Urbana-
Champaign.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1489a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1493" publication-type="other">
Pan, J. 2002. The jump-risk premia implicit in options: evidence from an integrated time-series study. Journal
of Financial Economics 63:3-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1504a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1508" publication-type="other">
Patton, A., and A. Timmermann. 2010. Monotonicity in asset returns: new tests with applications to the term
structure, the CAPM and portfolio sorts. Journal of Financial Evonomics 98:605-625.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1518a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1522" publication-type="other">
Perrakis, S., and P. Ryan. 1984. Option pricing bounds in discrete time. Journal of Finance
39:519-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1532a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1536" publication-type="other">
Politis, D., and J. Romano. 1994. The stationary bootstrap. Journal of the American Statistical Association
89:1303-13.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1546a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1550" publication-type="other">
Ritchken, P. 1985. On option pricing bounds. Journal of Finance 40:1219-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1557a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1561" publication-type="other">
Rosenberg, J., and R. Engle. 2002. Empirical pricing kernels. Journal of Financial Economics
64:341-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1571a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1575" publication-type="other">
Ross, S. 1976. The arbitrage theory of capital asset pricing. Journal of Economic Theory 13:341-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1583a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1587" publication-type="other">
Rubinstein, M. 1994. Implied binomial trees. Journal of Finance 49:771-818.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1594a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1598" publication-type="other">
Sutton, C. 1993. Computer-intensive methods for tests about the mean of an asymmetrical distribution. Journal
of the American Statistical Association 88:802-10.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1608a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1612" publication-type="other">
Yan, S. 2011. Jump risk, stock returns, and slope of implied volatility smile. Journal of Financial Economics
99:216-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157785e1622a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157785e1626" publication-type="other">
Ziegler, A. 2007. Why does implied risk aversion smile? Review of Financial Studies 20:859-904.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


