<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90007084</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Comparison of PI vs LPV Controllers for a Doubly-Fed Induction Generator in a Microgrid</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Vo</surname>
                  <given-names>T.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ravishankar</surname>
                  <given-names>J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Nurdin</surname>
                  <given-names>H. I.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Fletcher</surname>
                  <given-names>J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>School of Electrical Engineering and Telecommunications, the University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>39</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e90007075</issue-id>
         <fpage>479</fpage>
         <lpage>493</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90007084"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>State-space controllers have been central to modern control theory and are often preferred over classical controllers such as PI and lag-lead controllers. This is because they offer flexibility in design, such as being able to simultaneously incorporate performance and robustness requirements, and have a solid mathematical foundation. Recently, doubly-fed induction generators (DFIGs) for wind turbines have been modeled as linear parameter varying (LPV) systems, a special class of time-varying linear state-space systems, for which LPV state-space controllers can be designed. The LPV controllers have been introduced for DFIG mainly because of their novelty and that they can offer the typical advantages that come with state-space controllers. However, no comparison has yet been made regarding the control performance of LPV controllers versus more traditional PI controllers for DFIGs. In this paper, LPV controllers have been designed using linear matrix inequality (LMI) techniques and their performance is compared to PI controllers via simulation studies on a DFIG in a microgrid. Our study shows that if a mathematical model represents the DFIG accurately, then both controllers can be tuned to give comparable performance.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>induction machine</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>DFIG</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>control design</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>wind turbine</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>voltage oriented control (VOC)</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>LPV controllers</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>LMI techniques</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T. S. Ustun, C. Ozansoy and A. Zayegh, “Recent developments in microgrids and example cases around the world-A review,” Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, vol. 15, pp. 4030–4041, Oct. 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Muller, M. Deicke and R. W. De Doncker, “Doubly fed induction generator systems for wind turbines,” IEEE Industry Applications Magazine, vol. 8, pp. 26–33, May 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Akagi and H. Sato, “Control and performance of a doubly-fed induction machine intended for a flywheel energy storage system,” IEEE Transactions on Power Electronics, vol. 17, pp. 109–116, Jan. 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Popescu, Induction motor modelling for vector control purposes: Helsinki University of Technology, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">L. Xu, D. Zhi and B. W. Williams, “Predictive current control of doubly fed induction generators,” IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics, vol. 56, pp. 4143–4153, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. D. Lorenz, T. A. Lipo and D. W. Novotny, “Motion control with induction motors,” Proceedings of the IEEE, vol. 82, pp. 1215–1240, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Hu, Y. He, L. Xu and B. W. Williams, “Improved control of DFIG systems during network unbalance using PI-R current regulators,” IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics, Vol. 56, pp. 439–451, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Datta and V. T. Ranganathan, “Direct power control of grid-connected wound rotor induction machine without rotor position sensors,” IEEE Transactions on Power Electronics, vol. 16, pp. 390–399, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">X. Lie and P. Cartwright, “Direct active and reactive power control of DFIG for wind energy generation,” IEEE Transactions on Energy Conversion, vol. 21, pp. 750–758, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F. D. Bianchi, R. J. Mantz and C. F. Christiansen, “Gain scheduling control of variable-speed wind energy conversion systems using quasi-LPV models,” Control Engineering Practice, vol. 13, pp. 247–255, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. S. Shamma and M. Athans, “Guaranteed properties of gain scheduled control for linear parameter-varying plants,” Automatica, vol. 27, pp. 559–564, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Pena, J. C. Clare and G. M. Asher, “Doubly fed induction generator using back-to-back PWM converters and its application to variable-speed wind-energy generation,” IEE Proceedings Electric Power Applications, vol. 143, pp. 231–241, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. Tremblay, S. Atayde and A. Chandra, “Comparative study of control strategies for the doubly fed induction generator in wind energy conversion systems: A DSP-based implementation approach,” IEEE Transactions on Sustainable Energy, vol. 2, pp. 288–299, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C. Wang and G. Weiss, “Linear parameter varying control of a doubly fed induction generator based wind turbine with primary grid frequency support,” International Journal of Robust and Nonlinear Control, vol. 24, pp. 1927–1946, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>[15]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Iwanski and W. Koczara, “Sensorless direct voltage control of the stand-alone slip-ring induction generator,” IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics, vol. 54, pp. 1237–9, 04/2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>[16]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. H. Park, “Two-reaction theory of synchronous machines generalized method of analysis-part I,” American Institute of Electrical Engineers, Transactions of the, vol. 48, pp. 716–727, 1929.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>[17]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. C. Krause, O. Wasynczuk, S. D. Sudhoff and S. Pekarek, Analysis of electric machinery and drive systems vol. 75: John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>[18]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. S. Pena, G. M. Asher, J. C. Clare and R. Cardenas, “Constant frequency constant voltage variable speed stand alone wound rotor induction generator,” in Proceedings of the 1996 International Conference on Opportunities and Advances in International Electric Power Generation, March 18, 1996 - March 20, 1996, Durham, UK, 1996, pp. 111–114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>[19]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">X. Lie and W. Yi, “Dynamic modeling and control of DFIG-based wind turbines under unbalanced network conditions,” IEEE Transactions on Power Systems, vol. 22, pp. 314–23, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>[20]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Ziegler and N. Nichols, “Optimum settings for automatic controllers,” trans. ASME, Vol. 64, 1942.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>[21]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F. Haugen, “The Good Gain method for simple experimental tuning of PI controllers,” Modeling, Identification and Control, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>[22]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Zhou, J. C. Doyle, and K. Glover, Robust and Optimal Control: Prentice Hall, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>[23]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Packard, K. Zhou, P. Pandey, and G. Becker, “A collection of robust control problems leading to LMIs,” in Decision and Control, 1991., Proceedings of the 30th IEEE Conference on, 1991, pp. 1245–1250 Vol. 2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>[24]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. Gahinet and P. Apkarian, “A linear matrix inequality approach to H∞ control,” International Journal of Robust and Nonlinear Control, vol. 4, pp. 421–448, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>[25]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C. Scherer, P. Gahinet, and M. Chilali, “Multiobjective output-feedback control via LMI optimization,” Automatic Control, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 42, pp. 896–911, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>[26]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. Apkarian and R. J. Adams, “Advanced gain-scheduling techniques for uncertain systems,” Control Systems Technology, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 6, pp. 21–32, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>[27]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. Apkarian, J.-M. Biannic and P. Gahinet, “Self-scheduled H-infinity control of missile via linear matrix inequalities,” Journal of Guidance, Control, and Dynamics, vol. 18, pp. 532–538, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>[28]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C. Sloth, T. Esbensen and J. Stoustrup, “Active and passive fault-tolerant LPV control of wind turbines,” in American Control Conference (ACC), 2010, 2010, pp. 4640–4646.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>[29]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F. D. Adegas and J. Stoustrup, “Structured control of LPV systems with application to wind turbines,” in American Control Conference (ACC), 2012, pp. 756–761.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>[30]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Lofberg, “YALMIP: a toolbox for modeling and optimization in MATLAB,” in Computer Aided Control Systems Design, 2004 IEEE International Symposium on, 2004, pp. 284–289.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>[31]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Breen and D. Kay, “General decomposition theorems form-convex sets in the plane,” Israel Journal of Mathematics, vol. 24, pp. 217–233, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>[32]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“IEEE Standard Test Procedure for Polyphase Induction Motors and Generators,” IEEE Std 112–1996, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>[33]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Lanzon, “Weight selection in robust control: An optimisation approach,” PhD thesis, Cambridge University, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>[34]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Lanzon and M. Cantoni, “On the formulation and solution of robust performance problems,” Automatica, vol. 39, pp. 1707–1720, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>[35]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Osinuga, S. Patra, and A. Lanzon, “State-space solution to weight optimization problem in ℋ∞ loop-shaping control,” Automatica, vol. 48, pp. 505 513, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>[36]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T. Vo, J. Ravishankar, H. I. Nurdin, and J. Fletcher, “LPV controllers for a DFIG in a microgrid under unbalanced conditions,” to be presented at the IEEE International Conference on Environment and Electrical Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
