<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023193</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Building Tax Enforcement Capacity</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Rise of employees and growth in tax capacity</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Jensen</surname>
                  <given-names>Anders</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>London School of Economics</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>74</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023193"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper studies how the transition from self-employment to employee employment share over the development path can explain growth in personal income tax (PIT) capacity. Proxying for development using either 84 household surveys across countries today or 140 years of historical data within-US (1870-2010), I first establish two new stylized facts: 1) within-country, employee share is increasing in through the income-distribution, and the profile moves leftward with development; 2) the PIT exemption threshold moves down the income-distribution with development such that the employee share above the threshold is high and constant. These findings are consistent with a model in which high employee share is a necessary condition for taxation and the rise in third-party income through increases in employee shares drives growth in tax capacity. To provide more conclusive evidence, I use quasi-experimental variation in industry-subsidy policies in the U.S. in the 1940-60s that generated exogenous changes in employee share. I find that the exogenous increase in employee share is associated with a lower State PIT threshold. I find that an expansion of the State PIT base is associated with an increase in personal income tax revenue and a substitution away from 'distortive' taxes, including selective sales taxes. This last finding is consistent with the model where growth in employee mass lowers the marginal cost of funds of PIT and increases tax-reliance on PIT, and leads to substitution away from distortive tax-sources that have high marginal cost of funds. My model and empirical findings therefore address both the observed increase in PIT take and the observed variation in tax-mix over levels of development.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bachas, Pierre and Anders Jensen [2015]. “Tax administrations and size-based policies: a cross country database and study”, mimeo, London School of Economics and UC Berkeley.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Timothy, Besley and Torsten Persson [2009]. “The Origins of State Capacity: Property Rights, Taxation, and Politics,” American Economic Review, 99(4), 1218-44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Besley, Timothy and Torsten Persson [2011]. Pillars of Prosperity: The Political Economics of Development Clusters, Princeton: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Besley, Timmothy and Torsten Persson [2012]. “Taxation and Development,” in A. J. Auerbach and M. S. Feldstein, eds., Final Draft Chapter for the Handbook of Public Economics, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Besley, Timothy and Torsten Persson and Daniel M. Sturm [2010]. “Political Competition, Policy and Growth: Theory and Evidence from the US,” Review of Economic Studies, 1329-1352.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Best, Michael C. [2014]. “Salary Misreporting and the Role of Firms in Workers’ Responses to Taxes: Evidence From Pakistan,” mimeo, Stanford Institute for Economic Policy Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brockmeyer, Anne, Michael Best, Henrik Kleven, Johannes Spinnewijn, and Mazhar Waseem [2013]. “Production versus Revenue Efficiency with Limited Tax Capacity: Theory and Evidence from Pakistan,” mimeo, London School of Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carillo, Paul, Dina Pomeranz, and Monica Singhal [2014]. “Tax Me if You Can: Evidence on Firm Misreporting Behavior and Evasion Substitution,” mimeo, Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chetty, Raj [2009]. “Sufficient Statistics for Welfare Analysis: A Bridge Between Structural and Reduced-Form Methods” Annual Review of Economics 1: 451-488, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gordon, Roger H. and Wei Li [2009]. “Tax Structures in Developing Countries: Many Puzzles and a Possible Explanation,” Journal of Public Economics, 2009, 93 (7-8), 855866.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Tax Dialogue [2010]. “Revenue Administration in Sub-Saharan Africa,” ITD Comparative Information Series No.1</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johanessen, Niels and Gabriel Zucman [2012]. “The End of Bank Secrecy? An Evaluation of the G20 Tax Haven Crackdown,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khwaja, Munawer Sultan, Rajul Awasthi, and Jan Loeprick [2011]. “Risk-Based Tax Audits: Approaches and Country Experiences,” Directions in Development: Finance, The World Bank.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kopczuk, Wojciech and Joel Slemrod [2006]. “Putting Firms into Optimal Tax Theory,” The American Economic Review: Papers and Proceedings, 96 (2), 130-134</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>[15]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kleven, Henrik J. [2014]. “How Can Scandinavians Tax So Much?,” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 28(4), 77-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>[16]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kleven, Henrik J., Claus T. Kreiner, and Emmanuel Saez [2014]. “Why can Modern Governments Tax so Much? An Agency Model of Firms as Fiscal Intermediaries,” NBER Working Papers 15218, National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>[17]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kleven, Henrik J., Martin Knudsen, Claus T. Kreiner, Soren L. Pedersen, and Emmanuel Saez [2011]. “Unwilling or Unable to Cheat? Evidence from a Tax Audit Experiment in Denmark,” Econometrica, 79 (3), 651-692.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>[18]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kleven, Henrik J., and Mazhar Waseem [2013]. “Using Notches to Uncover Optimization Frictions and Structural Elasticities: Theory and Evidence from Pakistan,” Quarterly Journal of Economics 128, 669-723.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>[19]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kumler, Todd J., Eric A. Verhoogen, and Judith Frias [2012]. “Enlisting Workers in Monitoring Firms: Payroll Tax Compliance in Mexico,” Columbia University Department of Economics Discussion Papers, 96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>[20]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">le Maire, Daniel &amp; Schjerning, Bertel, 2013. “Tax bunching, income shifting and selfemployment,” Journal of Public Economics, pages 1-18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>[21]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Organisation for Economic Development and Co-Operation [2013]. “Tax Administration 2013: Comparative Information on OECD and Other Advanced and Emerging Economies,” OECD Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>[22]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pomeranz, Dina [2012]. “No Taxation without Information: Deterrence and Self-Enforcement in the Value Added Tax,” Harvard Business School Working Paper, 13-057.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>[23]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saez, Emmanuel [2010]. “Do Taxpayers Bunch at Kink Points?,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, American Economic Association, vol. 2(3), pages 180-212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>[24]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Munawer Sultan Khwaja, Rajul Awasthi, and Jan Loeprick [2011] “Risk-Based Tax Audits: Approaches and Country Experiences”, The World Bank Group.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article>
