<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284983</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Influence of Injector Location on Part-Load Performance Characteristics of Natural Gas Direct-Injection in a Spark Ignition Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sevik</surname>
                  <given-names>James</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Argonne National Laboratory</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pamminger</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Argonne National Laboratory</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wallner</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Argonne National Laboratory</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Scarcelli</surname>
                  <given-names>Riccardo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Argonne National Laboratory</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Boyer</surname>
                  <given-names>Brad</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wooldridge</surname>
                  <given-names>Steven</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hall</surname>
                  <given-names>Carrie</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Illinois Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Miers</surname>
                  <given-names>Scott</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan Technological Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>December 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284959</issue-id>
         <fpage>2262</fpage>
         <lpage>2271</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284983"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Interest in natural gas as an alternative fuel source to petroleum fuels for light-duty vehicle applications has increased due to its domestic availability and stable price compared to gasoline. With its higher hydrogen-to-carbon ratio, natural gas has the potential to reduce engine out carbon dioxide emissions, which has shown to be a strong greenhouse gas contributor. For part-load conditions, the lower flame speeds of natural gas can lead to an increased duration in the inflammation process with traditional port-injection. Direct-injection of natural gas can increase in-cylinder turbulence and has the potential to reduce problems typically associated with port-injection of natural gas, such as lower flame speeds and poor dilution tolerance.</p>
            <p>A study was designed and executed to investigate the effects of direct-injection of natural gas at part-load conditions. Steady-state tests were performed on a single-cylinder research engine representative of current gasoline direct-injection engines. Tests were performed with direct-injection in the central and side location. The start of injection was varied under stoichiometric conditions in order to study the effects on the mixture formation process. In addition, exhaust gas recirculation was introduced at select conditions in order to investigate the dilution tolerance. Relevant combustion metrics were then analyzed for each scenario.</p>
            <p>Experimental results suggest that regardless of the injector location, varying the start of injection has a strong impact on the mixture formation process. Delaying the start of injection from 300 to 120°CA BTDC can reduce the early flame development process by nearly 15°CA. While injecting into the cylinder after the intake valves have closed has shown to produce the fastest combustion process, this does not necessarily lead to the highest efficiency, due to increases in pumping and wall heat losses. When comparing the two injection configurations, the side location shows the best performance in terms of combustion metrics and efficiencies. For both systems, part-load dilution tolerance is affected by the injection timing, due to the induced turbulence from the gaseous injection event. CFD simulation results have shown that there is a fundamental difference in how the two injection locations affect the mixture formation process. Delayed injection timing increases the turbulence level in the cylinder at the time of the spark, but reduces the available time for proper mixing. Side injection delivers a gaseous jet that interacts more effectively with the intake induced flow field, and this improves the engine performance in terms of efficiency.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">"Fuel for Thought." : The First Natural Gas Vehicles. N.p., n.d. Web. 22 Apr. 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">"U.S. Energy Information Administration - EIA -Independent Statistics and Analysis." Short-Term Energy Outlook. N.p., n.d. Web. 22 Apr. 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Fuel Prices.” Alternative Fuels Data Center:. N.p., n.d. Web. 22 Apr. 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weber, C., Kramer, U., Klein, R., “CNG-Specific Downsizing - Potentials and Challenges”, Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bach, C., "CO2 Reduction and Cost Efficiency Potential of Natural Gas Hybrid Passenger Cars," SAE Int. J. Engines 4(2):2395-2404, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sevik, J., Pamminger, M., Wallner, T., Scarcelli, R. et al., "Performance, Efficiency and Emissions Assessment of Natural Gas Direct Injection compared to Gasoline and Natural Gas Port-Fuel Injection in an Automotive Engine," SAE Int. J. Engines 9(2):1130-1142, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0806.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mispreuve L., Magere E., Kermarrec S., Obiols J., Delpech V., Soleri D., “Development and Potential of the Renault CNG 2.0L Turbocharged Engine”, FISITA F2010-A-131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Delpech, V., Obiols, J., Soleri, D., Mispreuve, L. et al., "Towards an Innovative Combination of Natural Gas and Liquid Fuel Injection in Spark Ignition Engines," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(2):196-209, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1513.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderson, J., Miers, S., Wallner, T., Stutenberg, K. et al., "Performance and Efficiency Assessment of a Production CNG Vehicle Compared to Its Gasoline Counterpart," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-2694, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2694.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Husted, H., Karl, G., Schilling, S., Weber, C., “Direct Injection of CNG for Driving Performance with Low CO2,” 23rd Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technology 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Husted, H., Karl, G., Schilling, S., Weber, C., “Direct Injection of CNG for Driving Performance with Low CO2,” 23rd Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technology 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seboldt, D., Lejsek, D., Bargende, M., “Untersuchungen zum Einfluss von Einblasebeginn und Einblaserichtung auf die Gemischbildung und Verbrennung an einem λ = 1 betriebenen Ottomotor mit CNGDirekteinblasung,” 2015 IAV Conference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Alstine, D., Montgomery, D., Callahan, T., Florea, R., “ABILITY OF THE METHANE NUMBER INDEX OF A FUEL TO PREDICT RAPID COMBUSTION IN HEAVY DUTY DUAL FUEL ENGINES FOR NORTH AMERICAN LOCOMOTIVES”, ASME ICEF 2015, ICEF2015-1119.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kubesh, J., King, S., and Liss, W., "Effect of Gas Composition on Octane Number of Natural Gas Fuels," SAE Technical Paper 922359, 1992, doi:10.4271/922359.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Standard Test Method for Motor Octane Number of Spark-Ignition Engine Fuel, ASTM International D2700.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">"Fuel Quality Calculator." Cummins Westport. N.p., n.d. Web. 23 Oct. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., "Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals," McGraw- Hill Book.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">"Understanding Global Warming Potentials." US Environmental Protection Agency. N.p., n.d. Web. 18 Apr. 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“An introduction to combustion: concepts and applications,” Stephen R. Turns - WCB/McGraw-Hill - 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scarcelli, R., Wallner, T., Salazar, V., and Kaiser, S., "Modeling and Experiments on Mixture Formation in a Hydrogen Direct- Injection Research Engine," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):530-541, 2010, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0083.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scarcelli, R., Wallner, T., Matthias, N., Salazar, V. et al., "Mixture Formation in Direct Injection Hydrogen Engines: CFD and Optical Analysis of Single- and Multi-Hole Nozzles," SAE Int. J. Engines 4(2):2361-2375, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0096.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bartolucci, L., Scarcelli, R., Wallner, T., Swantek, A. et al., "CFD and X-Ray Analysis of Gaseous Direct Injection from an Outward Opening Injector," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0850, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016- 01-0850.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
