<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Wiley</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26604805</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Original Articles</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Recent Trends in the Size and the Distribution of Inherited Wealth in the UK</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Karagiannaki</surname>
                  <given-names>Eleni</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">36</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26604802</issue-id>
         <fpage>181</fpage>
         <lpage>213</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26604805"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>In this paper, we use HM Revenue and Customs (HMRC) estate statistics and micro data from four UK household surveys to examine changes in the size, the composition and the distribution of inherited wealth in the UK over the period 1985–2010. Our findings indicate that the period under examination is characterised by a substantial increase in the flow of inheritance. This increase, which was particularly marked in the early 2000s, was mainly driven by an increase in housing inheritance, which in turn reflected the rise in house prices and, to a lesser extent, the increase in the proportion of inheritances that included housing assets. The distribution of inheritance amongst recipients became more unequal over this period. However, the inequality-increasing effect from the greater dispersion in the distribution of inheritance was counterbalanced by the increase in the percentage of the population who received an inheritance, resulting in a small decrease in the inequality of inheritance for the population overall. Analysis of the distribution of inheritance by socio-economic status suggests a positive association between inheritance and socio-economic status, with some evidence suggesting that this association might have strengthened over time. Overall, however, the value of inheritance for most people is rather small and the differences across groups rather moderate.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Atkinson, A. B. (2013), ‘Wealth and inheritance in Britain from 1896 to the present’, Centre for Analysis of Social Exclusion (CASE), Discussion Paper no. 178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Becker, G. S. and Tomes, N. (1979), ‘An equilibrium theory of the distribution of income and intergenerational mobility’, Journal of Political Economy, vol. 87, pp. 1153-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Clark, G. and Cummins, N. (2012), ‘What is the true rate of social mobility? Surnames and social mobility, England 1800–2012’, UC Davis Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Davies, J. B. (1982), ‘The relative impact of inheritance and other factors on economic inequality’, Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 97, 471–98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Davies, J. B. and Shorrocks, A. F. (2000), ‘The distribution of wealth’, in A. B. Atkinson and F. Bourguignon (eds), Handbook of Income Distribution, vol. 1, pp. 605-75, Elsevier: Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">DeNardi, M. (2004), ‘Wealth inequality and intergenerational links’, Review of Economic Studies, vol. 71, pp. 743–68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Edlund, L. and Kopczuk, W. (2009), ‘Women, wealth and mobility’, American Economic Review, vol. 99, pp. 146–78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Gale, W. G. and Scholz, J. K. (1994), ‘Intergenerational transfers and the accumulation of wealth,’ Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 8, pp. 145-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Gokhale, J., Kotlikoff, L., Sefton, J. and Weale, M. (2001), ‘Simulating the transmission of wealth inequality via bequests’, Journal of Public Economics, vol. 79, pp. 93–128.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Hamnett, C. (1991), ‘A nation of inheritors? Housing inheritance, wealth and inequality in Britain’, Journal of Social Policy, vol. 20, pp. 509–36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Hamnett, C.(1992), ‘The geography of housing wealth and inheritance in Britain’, Geographical Journal, vol. 158, pp. 307–21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Hamnett, C., Harmer, M. and Williams, P. (1991), Safe as Houses: Housing Inheritance in Britain, London: Paul Chapman.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Harbury, C. D. (1962), ‘Inheritance and the distribution of wealth in Britain’, Economic Journal, vol. 72, pp. 845–68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Harbury, C. D. and Hitchens, D. M. W. N. (1976), ‘The inheritance of top wealth leavers: some further evidence’, Economic Journal, vol. 86, pp. 321–26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Harbury, C. D. and Hitchens, D. M. W. N. (1979), Inheritance and Wealth Inequality in Britain, London: George Allen and Unwin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Harbury, C. D. and McMahon, P. C. (1973), ‘Inheritance and the characteristics of top wealth leavers in Britain’, Economic Journal, vol. 83, pp. 810–33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">HM Revenue and Customs (2011), Description of inheritance tax, HM Revenue and Customs, http://www.hmrc.gov.uk/stats/inheritance_tax/description-of-tax.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Hood, A. and Joyce, R. (2013), ‘The economic circumstances of cohorts born between the 1940s and the 1970s’, Institute for Fiscal Studies (IFS), Report no. R89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Holmans, A. (1997), ‘Housing and inheritance revisited’, Housing Finance, vol. 33, pp. 14–23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Holmans, A. (2008), Prospects for UK Housing Wealth and Inheritance, London: Council of Mortgage Lenders.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Holmans, A. E. and Frosztega, M. (1994), House Property and Inheritance in the UK, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Kotlikoff, L. J. and Summers, L. H. (1981), ‘The role of intergenerational transfers in aggregate capital accumulation,’ Journal of Political Economy, vol. 89, pp. 706–32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Kotlikoff, L. J. and Summers, L. H. (1988), ‘The contribution of intergenerational transfers to total wealth: a reply’, in D. Kessler and A. Masson (eds), Modelling the Accumulation and Distribution of Wealth, pp. 53–67, Oxford: Clarendon Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Klevmarken, A. N. (2004), ‘On the wealth dynamics of Swedish families, 1984–98’, Review of Income and Wealth, vol. 50, p. 469–91.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Laitner, J. (1979a), ‘Household bequests, perfect expectations, and the national distribution of wealth’, Econometrica, vol. 47, pp. 1175-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Laitner, J. (1979b), ‘Household bequest behaviour and the national distribution of wealth’, Review of Economic Studies, vol. 46, 467-83.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Lloyd, J. (2008), Navigating the Age of Inheritance, London: International Longevity Centre.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Modigliani, F. (1988a), ‘Measuring the contribution of intergenerational transfers to total wealth: conceptual issues and empirical findings’, in D. Kessler and A. Masson (eds), Modelling the Accumulation and Distribution of Wealth, pp. 21–52, Oxford: Clarendon Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Modigliani, F. (1988b), ‘The role of intergenerational transfers and life cycle saving in the accumulation of wealth’, Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 2, pp. 15–40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Office for National Statistics (2009), Wealth in Great Britain: Main Results from the Wealth and Assets Survey 2006/08, Newport: Office for National Statistics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Office for National Statistics (2013), Social Survey Division, Wealth and Assets Survey, Waves 1–2, 2006–2010 [computer file], 2nd edition, Colchester, Essex: UK Data Archive [distributor], June 2013. SN: 7215 http://dx.doi.org/10.5255/UKDA-SN-7215-2).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Piketty, T. (2011), ‘On the long-run evolution of inheritance: France 1820–2050’, Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 126, pp. 1071–131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Ross, A., Lloyd, J. and Weinhardt, M. (2008), The Age of Inheritance, London: International Longevity Centre.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Rowlingson, K. and McKay, S. (2005), Attitudes to Inheritance in Britain, Bristol: The Policy Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Royal Commission on the Distribution of Income and Wealth (1977), Third Report on the Standing Reference, Report No. 5, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Smith, J. P. (1999), ‘Inheritances and bequests’, in J. P. Smith and R.Willis (eds.), Wealth, Work, and Health: Innovations in Measurement in the Social Sciences, Ann Arbor,MI: University of Michigan Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Stiglitz, J. (1969), ‘Distribution of income and wealth among individuals’, Econometrica, vol. 37, pp. 382–97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Tomes, N. (1981), ‘The family, inheritance, and the intergenerational transmission of inequality’, Journal of Political Economy, vol. 89, 928–58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Wolff, E. N. (2002), ‘Bequests, savings and wealth inequality’, American Economic Association, Paper and Proceedings, vol. 2, pp. 260–64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Wolff, E. N. and Gittleman, M. (2011), ‘Inheritances and the distribution of wealth or whatever happened to the great inheritance boom? Results from the SCF and PSID’, National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER), Working Paper no. 16840.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Wedgwood, J. (1928), ‘The influence of inheritance on the distribution of wealth’, Economic Journal, vol. 38, pp. 38–55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Wedgwood, J. (1929), The Economics of Inheritance, London: George Routledge &amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Statistics on estates passing on death by year of death, UK, all estates and by type of asset</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Statistics on estates passing on death 1984/85–2005/06</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Total value of estates excluding inter-spousal transfers by year of death, UK</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Per cent of the adult population that inherit in each year and the mean value of inheritance, 1986–2005 (excluding inter-spousal inheritance)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Statistics describing the distribution of inheritances in the UK for individuals (2005 prices and current prices for the WAS)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Percentage of individuals who received inheritances of any financial value and mean and median values of inheritance by various characteristics (excluding inter-spousal inheritances)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Probit marginal effects of the association between socio-economic status and the probability of inheriting</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>OLS estimates of the association between the logarithm of inheritances and socio-economic status</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Probit marginal effects and OLS estimates of the change in the association between socio-economic status and inheritance: probit and OLS interaction models</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
