<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007470</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">jinsuissu</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Journal of Insurance Issues</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15316076</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23324244</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Western Risk and Insurance Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26910015</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>ARTICLES</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A New Measure of Insurer Franchise Value</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ren</surname>
                  <given-names>Yayuan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2020</year>
            <string-date>SPRING 2020</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">43</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26910012</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>21</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2020 by the Western Risk and Insurance Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26910015"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Franchise value has been defined as “the present value of the future profits that a firm is expected to earn as a going concern” (Demsetz, Saidenberg, and Strahan, 1996), and is most often measured as Tobin’s q. It has been of particular interest in recent periods as researchers and policy makers try to understand influences on risky investment decisions. Our ability to measure it, however, is hampered by the relatively small number of insurers traded on the public market, a requirement to use Tobin’s q. To address this current limitation, we develop a franchise value measure that does not rely on stock-value-based data. Our measure incorporates eight variables representing sources of insurer franchise value. We then assess the measurement quality of the measure and compare it to the traditional market-to-book value (Tobin’s q) and two other proxies proposed by Gan (2004) and Yu, Lin, Oppenheimer, and Chen (2008). The results show that our measure significantly improves the measurement quality of franchise value compared to the other proxies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Babbel, D. F. and C. Merrill (2005) “Real and Illusory Value Creation by Insurance Companies,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 72: 1–22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Baker, M. and J. Wurgler (2006) “Investor Sentiment and the Cross-Section of Stock Returns,” Journal of Finance 61: 1645–1680.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Berger, A. N. (1995) “The Profit-Structure Relationship in Banking—Tests of Market-Power and Efficient-Structure Hypotheses,” Journal of Money, Credit and Banking 27: 404–431.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bongaerts, D., F. De Jong, and J. Driessen (2011) “Derivative Pricing with Liquidity Risk: Theory and Evidence from the Credit Default Swap Market,” Journal of Finance 66: 203–240.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Demsetz, R. S., M. R. Saidenberg, and P. E. Strahan (1996) “Banks with Something to Lose: The Disciplinary Role of Franchise Value,” Economic Policy Review 2: 1-14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Deng, Y., J. T. Leverty, and G. H. Zanjani (2017) “Market Discipline and Government Guarantees: Evidence from the Insurance Industry,” available at SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=2736397</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Epermanis, K. and S. E. Harrington (2006) “Market Discipline in Property/Casualty Insurance: Evidence from Premium Growth Surrounding Changes in Financial Strength Ratings,” Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking 38: 1515–1544.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Erickson, T. and T. M. Whited (2002) “Two-Step GMM Estimation of the Errors-in-Variables Model Using High-Order Moments,” Econometric Theory 18: 776–799.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Erickson, T. and T. M. Whited (2006) “On the Accuracy of Different Measures of Q,” Financial Management 35: 5–33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Flury, B. (1997) A First Course in Multivariate Statistics, New York: Springer.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Gan, J. (2004) “Banking Market Structure and Financial Stability: Evidence from the Texas Real Estate Crisis in the 1980s,” Journal of Financial Economics 73: 567–601.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Hess, E. (2006) The Road to Organic Growth: How Great Companies Consistently Grow Market Share from Within, McGraw Hill Professional.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Holmstrom, B. and P. Milgrom (1991) “Multitask Principal-Agent Analyses: Incentive Contracts, Asset Ownership, and Job Design,” Journal of Law, Economics and Organization 7: 24–52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Hubert M., P. J. Rousseeuw, and K. V. Branden (2005) “ROBPCA: A New Approach to Robust Principal Component Analysis,” Technometrics 47: 64–79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Leibowitz, M. and S. Kogelman (1991) “The Franchise Factor for Leveraged Firms,”Financial Analysts Journal 47: 29–43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Lopez, R. A., A. M. Azzam, and C. Lirón-España (2002) “Market Power and/or Efficiency: A Structural Approach,” Review of Industrial Organization 20: 115–126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Martin, S. (1988) “Market Power and/or Efficiency?” Review of Economics and Statistics 60: 331–335.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Pearson, K. (1901) “On Lines and Planes of Closest Fit to Systems of Points in Space,” The Philosophical Magazine 2: 559–572.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Ren, Y. and J. Schmit (2008) “Franchise Value, Competition and Insurer Risk Taking,” working paper available at SSRN: https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1230422</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Rencher, A. C. and W. Christensen (2012) Methods of Multivariate Analysis, 3rd edition, Wiley.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Shepherd, W. G. (1983) “Economies of Scale and Monopoly Profits,” in Industrial Organization, Antitrust, and Public Policy, Springer, Dordrecht, 165–204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Staking, K. B., and D. F. Babbel (1995) “The Relationship between Capital Structure, Interest Rate Sensitivity, and Market Value in the Property-Liability Insurance Industry,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 62: 690–718.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Stigler, G. J. (1964) “A Theory of Oligopoly,” Journal of Political Economy 72: 44–61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Yu, T., B. Lin, H. R. Oppenheimer, and X. Chen (2008) “Intangible Assets and Firm Asset Risk Taking: An Analysis of Property and Liability Insurance,” Risk Management and Insurance Review 11: 157–178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Descriptive Statistics of the Variables in the PCA (2006–2014)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Descriptive Statistics of FVINDEX</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Descriptive Statistics of Variables Used in the Assessment Model</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>GMM Estimates of Measurement Quality</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
