<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">reviespafinacont</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50009991</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Revista Española de Financiación y Contabilidad</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administarción de Empresas</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">02102412</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">38</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">141</issue>
         <issue-id>i24717601</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24718071</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Spatial effects in the productivity convergence of Spanish industrial SME's / Efectos espaciales en la convergencia de la productividad de las Pymes españolas</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>MariLuz Maté Sánchez</given-names>
                  <surname>Val</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Domingo García Pérez</given-names>
                  <surname>de Lema</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Fernando A. López</given-names>
                  <surname>Hernández</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>13</fpage>
         <lpage>36</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2001 Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administración de Empresas</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24718071"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper analyses the spatial effects influence on the convergence process in Spanish industrial SME's productivity. In order to do this: 1. We use an absolute convergence model considering the technological intensity of each sector; 2. From a statistical point of view, we determine the existence and composition of convergence clubs in productivity levels; 3. Finally, we test if the convergence clubs are affecting to the convergence process. To do this, we use accounting information with a microdata source composed by 35.042 firms over the period 1996-2004. The results show that there is a regional convergence process in firms belonging to high and low technological intensity. Moreover, in high technology sector there is not a spatial structure while this structure is evident in low technology sector. In this last case the spatial structure is influencing on the convergence process. Este trabajo analiza la influencia de los efectos espaciales en el proceso de convergencia regional en la productividad de las Pymes industriales españolas. Para ello utilizamos un modelo de convergencia absoluta, determinamos estadísticamente la existencia y composición de clubes de convergencia en niveles de productividad, y finalmente, contrastamos si existen diferencias en el proceso de convergencia determinadas por la existencia de los clubes detectados. En estudio trabajamos con la información contable de una muestra compuesta por 35.042 empresas para el periodo 1996-2004. Los resultados obtenidos indican, que existe un proceso de convergencia en la productividad de empresas con alta y baja intensidad tecnológica. Además, en alta intensidad tecnológica no existe una estructura espacial claramente definida, mientras que en baja intensidad detectamos un patrón espacial compuesto por dos clubes de convergencia, para los cuales existen diferencias significativas en el proceso analizado.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1793e227a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1793e234" publication-type="other">
Solow, 1956</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1793e241a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1793e248" publication-type="other">
Barro and Sala-i-Martin, 1991</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1793e254" publication-type="other">
Optimal Consumption Model of Ramsey (1928)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1793e260" publication-type="other">
Cass (1965)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1793e267" publication-type="other">
Koopmans (1965).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1793e273" publication-type="other">
Cabrera-Castellanos and Garcia Alamilla, 2003</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1793e280a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1793e287" publication-type="other">
Hendry
(1993)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1793e297a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1793e304" publication-type="other">
Anselin y Florax, 1995</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d1793e320a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e324" publication-type="other">
Aguayo, E.; Expósito, P.; Rodríguez, X. A., and Vázquez, E. 2000. Human capital and other factors of the
total productivity in Spanish Regions, Economic Development 45. University of Santiago de Composte-
la, Faculty of Economics and Business, Econometrics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e337a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e341" publication-type="other">
Anselin, L., and Florax, R. 1995. New Directions in Spatial Econometrics. Berlin: Springer.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e348a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e352" publication-type="other">
Audretscii, D. B. 2001. Research issues relating to structure, competition, and performance of small
technology-based firms. Small Business Economics 16: 37-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e362a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e366" publication-type="other">
Baiuío, R. J., and Sala-I-Martin, X. 1991. Convergence Across States and Regions. Brookings Papers on
Economic Activity 1:107-182.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e377a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e381" publication-type="other">
Barro, R. J., and Sala-I-Martin, X. 1991. Convergence, Journal of Political Economy 100: 223-251.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e388a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e392" publication-type="other">
Barro, R. J., and Sala-I-Martin, X. 1995. Economics Growth. New York: McGraw Hill.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e399a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e403" publication-type="other">
Baumont, C. 1998. Croissance endogene et croissance des regions: vers une théorie de la croissance
endogene spatialisée. Document de travail 9408. Dijon: LATEC.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e413a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e417" publication-type="other">
Baumont, C.; Erthur, C, and Le Gallo, J. 2003. Spatial Convergence Clubs and the European regional
Growth Process, 1980-1995, in Fingleton, B. (Eds.): European Regional Growth: Berlin et al. Springer:
131-158.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e430a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e434" publication-type="other">
Cabrera-Castellanos, I.., and Garcia Alamilla, B. 2003. Regional Convergence in Latin America: 1980-
2000. Anuario de la DCSEA 2:157-168.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e444a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e448" publication-type="other">
Camagni, R. 2005. Economía Urbana. Barcelona: Bosch.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e456a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e460" publication-type="other">
Carrington, A. 2003. Regional Convergence in the European Union: A Stochastic Dominance Approach.
International Regional Science Review 29(1): 64-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e470a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e474" publication-type="other">
Cass, D. 1965. Optimum Growth in an Aggregative Model of Capital Accumulation. Review of Econo-
mics Studies 32: 233-240.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e484a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e488" publication-type="other">
Ceukkol, P. 2003. Productivity patterns in the U.S. food and kindred products industries, a plant level
analysis, 1972-1995. The Pennsylvania State University Document.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e498a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e502" publication-type="other">
Chasco, C. 2003. Econometría espacial aplicada a la predicción-extrapolación de datos microterrito-
riales. Madrid: Consejería de Economía e Innovación Tecnológica de la Comunidad de Madrid.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e512a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e516" publication-type="other">
Comisión Europea. 2001. The European Observatory for SMEs. First Report.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e523a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e527" publication-type="other">
Correa, A.; González, A. L., and Acosta, M. 2002. Crecimiento y Pyme. Un estudio empírico. Revista
Europea de Dirección y Economía de la Empresa 11(3): 76-102.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e538a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e542" publication-type="other">
Cuadrado-Roura, J. 1998. Divergencia versus convergencia de las disparidades regionales en España.
EURE 24(72), 5-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e552a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e556" publication-type="other">
Cuadrado-Roura, J.; Garrido, R., and Mancha, T. 1999. Disparidades regionales y crecimiento en España-
1980-1995, Revista de Estudios Regionales, 55,109-137.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e566a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e570" publication-type="other">
Dall'erba, S. 2005. Productivity convergence and spatial dependence among Spanish regions. Journal
Geography System 7: 207-227.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e580a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e584" publication-type="other">
Durlauf, S., and Johnson, P. 1995. Multiple Regimes and Cross Country Growth Behaviour. Journal of
Applied Econometrics 10 (4): 365-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e594a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e598" publication-type="other">
Englmann, F. C., and Walz, U. 1995. Industrial Centers and Regional Growth in the Presence of Local
Inputs. Journal of Regional Science 35(1): 3-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e608a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e612" publication-type="other">
Ertur, C.; LeGallo, J., and Baumont, C. 2006. The European Regional Convergence Process, 1980-1995:
Do Spatial Regimes and Spatial Dependence Matter? International Regional Science Review 29(1):
3-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e626a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e630" publication-type="other">
Escribá, J. F., and Murgui, M. J. 2001. Tecnología, cambio estructural y convergencia en las regiones
españolas (1980-1995). Investigaciones económicas 25(2): 335-358.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e640a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e644" publication-type="other">
Espinosa, C., and Boceta, V. 2005. 75 años de política Económica Española. Información Comercial
Española: 825.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e654a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e658" publication-type="other">
Esteban, J. 1994. La desigualdad interregional en Europa y en España: descripción y análisis en: Cre-
cimiento y convergencia regional en España y Europa. Bellaterra: Institut d'Anälisi Económica.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e668a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e672" publication-type="other">
Estrada García, A. and López Salido, J. 2004. Sectoral and aggregate technology growth in Spain. Spa-
nish economic review 6(1): 3-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e682a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e686" publication-type="other">
Ezcurra, R.; Pascual, P., and Rapún, M. 2003. Movilidad y desigualdad regional en la Unión Europea.
Investigaciones Regionales 2: 5-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e696a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e700" publication-type="other">
Fischer, M., and Stirböck, C. 2006. Convergencia Regional en Europa. Papeles de economía española
10: 30-44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e711a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e715" publication-type="other">
Funke, M., and Niebuhr, A. 2005. Regional Geographie Research and Development Spillovers and Eco-
nomic Growth: Evidence from West Germany. Regional Studies 39(1): 143-153.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e725a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e729" publication-type="other">
García, A.; Merino, F., and Rubio, D. 2002. Financiación de la Pequeña y Mediana Empresa en Espa-
ña: Evolución reciente de los principales instrumentos públicos de apoyo. Boletín Económico del ICE
2.734.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e742a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e746" publication-type="other">
Getis, A., and Ord, J. K. 1992. The Analysis of spatial association by use of distance statistics, Geogra-
phical Analysis, 26,169-178.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e756a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e760" publication-type="other">
González Pérez, A. L. 1997. La rentabilidad empresarial: evaluación empírica de sus factores determi-
nantes. Tesis Doctoral. Ed. Colegio de Registradores de la Propiedad y Mercantiles de España, Madrid,
Centro de Estudios Regístrales.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e773a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e777" publication-type="other">
Hair, J. F.; Anderson, R. E.; Tatham, R. L, and Black, W. C. 1999. Análisis multivariante. Quinta edición:
Madrid: Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e787a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e791" publication-type="other">
Hendry, D. 1995. Dynamic Econometrics. Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e799a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e803" publication-type="other">
Huergo, E., and Jaumandreu, J. 2004. Firms age, process innovation and productivity growth. Interna-
tional Journal of Industrial Organization 22: 541-559.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e813a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e817" publication-type="other">
Hulten, C. 2001. Total Factor Productivity. A Short Biography. In Hulten. Dean y Harper (Eds.).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e824a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e828" publication-type="other">
Hulten, C.; Dean, E., and Harper, M. 2001. New Developments in Productivity Analysis. University of
Chicago Press for the National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e838a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e842" publication-type="other">
Kok, J.; Fris, P., and Brouwer, P. 2006. On the relationship between firm age and productivity growth.
Scientific Analysis of Entrepreneurship and SMEs.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e852a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e856" publication-type="other">
Koopmans, T. C. 1965. On the Concept of Optimal Economic Growth. Cowles Foundation Discussion.
Papers from Cowles Foundation. Yale University 163.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e866a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e870" publication-type="other">
Kösfeld, R.; Ecke, H„ and Greger, C. 2002. Regional convergence in unified Germany: A spatial econo-
metric perspective. Nomos-Press Series Edition 19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e881a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e885" publication-type="other">
Kubo, Y. 1995. Scale economies, regional externalities and the possibility of uneven regional develop-
ment. Journal of Regional Science 35(1): 29-42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e895a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e899" publication-type="other">
López-Bazo, E.; Vayá, A.; Mora, and Suriñach, J. 1999. Regional economic dynamics and convergence in
the European Union. Annals of Regional Science 33(3): 343-370.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e909a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e913" publication-type="other">
Martín Marcos, A., and Jaumandreu, J. 2004. Entry, exit and productivity growth: Spanish manufactu-
ring during the eighties. Spanish economic review 6(3): 211-226.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e923a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e927" publication-type="other">
Martin, P., and Octavtano, G. 1996. Growth and Agglomeration. CEPR Discusión Paper Series 1529.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e934a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e938" publication-type="other">
Moreno, R.; López-Bazo, E.; Vaya, E., and Arti's, M. 2004. Externalities, Public Capital and Costs of
Production, in Anselin, L.; Florax, R., and Rey, S., Advances in Spatial Econometrics (Eds.): Springer-
Verlag: 297-317.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e951a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e955" publication-type="other">
Mur, J.; López, F., and Angulo, A. 2008. Inestabilidad y convergencia entre las regiones europeas. Fun-
dación de las Cajas de Ahorros. Documento de trabajo 367.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e966a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e970" publication-type="other">
OECD/Eurostat. 2001. The measurement of scientific and technological activities, Proposed guidelines
for collecting and interpreting technological innovation data, Organisation for Economic Co-operation
and Development (OECD) and Eurostat, Paris.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e983a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e987" publication-type="other">
Ocaña, C.; Salas, V., and Valles, J. 1994. Un análisis empírico de la financiación de la pequeña y media-
na empresa manufacturera española: 1983-1989. Moneda y Crédito 199: 57-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e997a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1001" publication-type="other">
Ord, J. K„ and Getis, A. 1995. Local Spatial Autocorrelation Statistics: Distributional Issues and an
application. Geographical Analysis 27: 286-306.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e1011a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1015" publication-type="other">
Peña, A. 2005. El sistema de información contable en las pequeñas y medianas empresas. Un estudio
evaluativo en el área metropolitana de Venezuela. Actualidad Contable. FACES 11: 67-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e1025a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1029" publication-type="other">
Poutziouris, P.; Chittenden, F.; Michaelas, N., and Oakey, R. 2000. Taxation and the performance of tech-
nology-based small firms in the U.K. Small Business Economics 14:11-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e1039a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1043" publication-type="other">
Quah, D. 1997. Empirics for Growth and Distribution: Stratification, Polarization, and Convergence
Clubs. Journal of Economic Growth 2(1): 27-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e1054a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1058" publication-type="other">
Ramsey, F. 1928. A Mathematical Theory of Saving. Economic Journal 38: 543-559.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e1065a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1069" publication-type="other">
Rey, S. J., and Montouri, B. D. 1999. US Regional Income Convergence: A Spatial Econometric Pers-
pective. The Journal of the Regional Studies Association 33(2): 143-156.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e1079a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1083" publication-type="other">
Saia-i-Martín, X. 1994. Apuntes de crecimiento económico. Barcelona, Bosch.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e1090a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1094" publication-type="other">
Segarra, A. 1999. Las disparidades regionales de la productividad industrial, 1978-1992. Economía
Industrial 317: 21-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e1104a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1108" publication-type="other">
Solow, R. M. 1956. A Contribution to the Theory of Economic Growth. The Quarterly Journal of Eco-
nomics 70: 65-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e1118a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1122" publication-type="other">
Taymaz, E. 2002. Are small firms really less productive? An analysis of productivity differentials and
firms dynamics. Small Business Economics 25: 429-445.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e1133a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1137" publication-type="other">
Trullén, J. 2007. La nueva política industrial española: innovación, economías externas y productivas.
Economía industrial 363:17-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e1147a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1151" publication-type="other">
Vallés, J. 2006. Balance de dos años de gestión económica y orientación hacia un nuevo modelo.
Fundación Jaime Vera.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e1161a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1165" publication-type="other">
Villaverde, J., and Sánchez Robles, B. 1998. Convergencia regional en España y Unión Monetaria: un
nuevo enfoque. Revista Asturiana de Economía. Asturias 13:113-130.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1793e1175a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1793e1179" publication-type="other">
Zozaya, N. 2007. La productividad empresarial en España, Madrid: Dirección General de Política de la
pequeña y mediana empresa.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


