<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275495</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effect of Post Injections on In-Cylinder and Exhaust Soot for Low-Temperature Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bobba</surname>
                  <given-names>Mohan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Musculus</surname>
                  <given-names>Mark</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Neel</surname>
                  <given-names>Wiley</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Stanford Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>496</fpage>
         <lpage>516</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275495"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Multiple fuel-injections during a single engine cycle can reduce combustion noise and improve pollutant emissions tradeoffs. Various hypotheses have been proposed in the literature regarding the in-cylinder processes responsible for the pollutant emissions improvements. This paper provides a brief overview of these hypotheses along with an investigation exploring which of these mechanisms are important for post injections under low-temperature combustion (LTC) conditions in a heavy-duty diesel engine. In-cylinder soot and exhaust smoke are measured by 2-color soot thermometry and filter paper blackening, respectively. The evolution and interaction of soot regions from each of the injections is visualized using high-speed imaging of soot luminosity, both in the piston bowl and in the squish regions. Results for early main-injection (−18°after top dead center command start of injection) conditions show an abrupt reduction in exhaust soot as the post injection is delayed to timings where the post-injection jet starts to enter the squish volume. At these conditions, the post injection in the squish volume produces no soot of its own, and it does not interact with soot from the main injection, which remains in the piston bowl. Reduction in soot for this case is primarily due to fuel in the post injection burning soot-free in the squish volume. In contrast, for a late main-injection (2°after top dead center), the exhaust soot decreases to levels below “main-injection-only” values as the post injection is retarded. With late main-injection, significant soot from the main injection remains in the squish volume, so that strong interaction between the main and post jets is evident. The retarded post injection conditions have higher late-cycle soot temperature and faster oxidation of main-injection soot remaining in the squish volume. Finally, for either main-injection timing, the optimal post-injection timing is at roughly the same crank angle position. Hence, for these LTC post-injection conditions, the absolute crank angle position of the post injection appears more important for soot reduction than the dwell between injections, though the dwell also could play a role in soot reduction, especially when using a late main injection.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hardy, W.L. and Reitz, R.D., “An Experimental Investigation of Partially Premixed Combustion Strategies Using Multiple Injections in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0917, SAE Transactions 115(3), 514-531, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nehmer, D.A. and Reitz, R.D., “Measurement of the Effect of Injection Rate and Split Injections on Diesel Engine Soot and NOx Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 940668, SAE Transactions 103(3), 1031-1041, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mendez, S. and Thirouard, B., “Using Multiple Injection Strategies in Diesel Combustion: Potential to Improve Emissions, Noise and Fuel Economy Trade-Off in Low CR Engines,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):662-674, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, F., Benajes, J., Pastor, J.V., and Molina, S., “Influence of the Post-Injection Pattern on Performance, Soot and NOx Emissions in a HD Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0502, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Husberg, T., Denbratt, I., and Karlsson, A., “Analysis of Advanced Multiple Injection Strategies in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine using Optical Measurements and CFDSimulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1328, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dronniou, N., Lejeune, M., Balloul, I., and Higelin, P., “Combination of High EGR Rates and Multiple Injection Strategies to Reduce Pollutant Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3726, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tow, T.C., Pierpont, D.A., and Reitz, R.D., “Reducing Particulate and NOx Emissions by Using Multiple Injections in a Heavy Duty D.I. Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 940897, SAE Transactions 103(3), 1403-1417, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ojeda, W.D., Zoldak, P., Espinosa, R., and Kumar, R., “Development of a Fuel Injection Strategy for Partially Premixed Compression Ignition Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1473-1488, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamamoto, K., Takada, K., Kusaka, J., Kanno, Y. et al., “Influence of Diesel Post Injection Timing on HC Emissions and Catalytic Oxidation Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3442, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, S.K., “Simultaneous Reduction of NOx and Particulate Emissions by Using Multiple Injections in a Small Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-3084, SAE Transactions, Vol. 109(3), 2127-2136, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hotta, Y., Inayoshi, M., Nakakita, K., Fujiwara, K. et al., “Achieving Lower Exhaust Emissions and Better Performance in an HSDI Diesel Engine with Multiple Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0928, SAE Transactions 114(3), 883-898, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G. and Maligne, D., “Study of Mixing and Combustion Processes of Consecutive Short Double Diesel Injections,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1151-1169, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z., Uludogan, A., Hampson, G. J., and Reitz, R.D., “Mechanism of Soot and NOx Emission Reduction Using Multiple-Injection in a Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 960633, SAE Transactions 105(3), 837-852, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J., Arregle, J., Lopez, J. J., and Garcia, A., “A Comprehensive Study of Diesel Combustion and Emissions with Post-Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0915, SAE Transactions 116(3), 542-550, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E., “A Conceptual Model of D.I. Diesel Combustion Based on Laser-Sheet Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 970873, SAE Transactions 106(3), 1319-1348, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., Dec, J.E., and Tree, D.R., “Effects of Fuel Parameters and Diffusion Flame Lift-Off on Soot Formation in a Heavy-Duty DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0889, SAE Transactions 111(3), 1467-1489, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J.E., “An Investigation of the Relationship between Measured Intake Temperature, BDC Temperature, and Combustion Phasing for Premixed and DI HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1900, SAE Transactions 113(3), 1271-1286, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw-Hill, Inc., 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baratta, M., Catania, A. E., and Ferrari, A., “Hydraulic Circuit Design Keys to Remove the Dependence of the Injected Fuel Amount on Dwell Time in Multi-Jet C. R. Systems,” ASME IC Engine Spring Conference, ICES 2006-1426, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Helmantel, A., “Reduction in NOx Emissions from a Light Duty DI Diesel Engine in Medium Load Conditions with High EGR Rates,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0643, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Horibe, N., and Ishiyama, T., “Relations among NOx, Pressure Rise Rate, HC and CO in LTC Operation of a Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1443, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mueller, C. J. and Martin, G. C., “Effects of Oxygenated Compounds on Combustion and Soot Evolution in a DI Diesel Engine: Broadband Natural Luminosity Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1631, SAE Transactions 111(4), 518-527, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bobba, M.K., Genzale, C., and Musculus, M., “Effect of Ignition Delay on In-Cylinder Soot Characteristics of a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Operating at Low Temperature Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):911-924, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akihama, K., Takatori, Y., Inagaki, K., Sasaki, S. et al., “Mechanism of the Smokeless Rich Diesel Combustion by Reducing Temperature,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0655, SAE Transactions 110(3), 648-662, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., “On the Correlation between NOx Emissions and the Diesel Premixed Burn,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1401, SAE Transactions 113(4), 631-651, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J.M., Payri, R., Salvador, F.J., and Gimeno, J., “Measurements of Spray Momentum for the Study of Cavitation in Diesel Injection Nozzles,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0703, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
