<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">8</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466874</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466878</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Territorial Tax System Reform and Corporate Financial Policies</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Matteo P.</given-names>
                  <surname>Arena</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>George W.</given-names>
                  <surname>Kutner</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2250</fpage>
         <lpage>2280</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466878"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We examine the effect of a permanent change to a country corporate income repatriation tax system on corporate financial policies. In 2009, Japan and the United Kingdom switched from a worldwide system to a territorial system for the taxation of repatriated foreign earnings, effectively reducing the tax liabilities of most multinational firms when repatriating earnings. We find that after the change firms accumulate less cash, pay out larger amounts through dividends and share repurchases, and invest less abroad. We do not find that the tax system change has significantly affected domestic investments even when controlling for capital constraints.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d623286e245a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e252" publication-type="other">
See, for example, "More profits parked offshore," The Wall Street Journal, March 11,2013, "Corporate taxes, the
myths and facts," The Wall Street Journal, October 12, 2012, "Obama vs. Volcker, et al. The President's advisers
agree with Romney on a territorial tax reform," The Wall Street Journal, October 4,2012, "Why investors can't get
more cash out of U.S. companies," The Wall Street Journal, February 19, 2011, and "Escaping the shakedown,"
The Economist, July 4, 2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e271a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e278" publication-type="other">
In some territorial system countries, the exemption is set at 95% instead of being full.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e285a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e292" publication-type="other">
The foreign country also levies a withholding tax on dividends (earnings) transferred to the parent country.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e299a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e306" publication-type="other">
Tax Foundation Fiscal Fact No. 335.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e314a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e321" publication-type="other">
Houlder, V., "Tax move aims to check business exodus," Financial Times, December 10, 2008. Tax Foundation
Fiscal Fact No. 336.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e331a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e338" publication-type="other">
"WPP, publisher weigh end to tax exile from U.K.," The Wall Street Journal, March 25, 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e345a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e352" publication-type="other">
Source: Thomson Reuters Worldscope.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e359a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e366" publication-type="other">
As stated by the 2013 IMF Fiscal Monitor Report Survey, these tax avoidance techniques are implemented by
multinational firms in both advanced and developing economies. However, the problem is less acute in Japan
because Tax Heaven Counter Measure Laws effectively limit tax avoidance schemes via tax heavens.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e379a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e386" publication-type="other">
Let us consider a Japanese multinational firm with a cost of capital of 11%. This firm needs to repatriate cash
to invest in a project that will generate $150 M in cash flows next year and will require an investment of $100
M this year (the NPV is therefore $35.1 M). The cash could be repatriated from a Dutch subsidiary. The Dutch
subsidiary also has an investment opportunity that could generate $135 M next year and requires a $100 M
investment this year (the NPV is $21.6 M). In the absence of repatriation taxes, the cash would be repatriated
to invest in the more lucrative domestic project. Under the worldwide tax system, the foreign project would
be chosen instead. The statutory corporate tax in the Netherlands is 25.5%, whereas it is 40.69% in Japan. The
15.19% difference on the $ 100 M would be paid upon repatriation. Therefore, approximately $ 118 M would need
to be repatriated to have $100 M after tax to invest in the domestic project (118*( 1-0.1519) = 100). Effectively,
therefore, the domestic project requires an investment of $ 118 M, reducing the NPV to $ 17.1 M, which is lower
than the NPV of the foreign project. Hartman (1985) argues that under the worldwide system if the after-tax rate
of return abroad is higher (lower) than the domestic net rate of return, the firm would invest abroad and repatriate
in the following period (repatriate immediately and invest domestically). However, if there is an expectation of
a tax holiday or a territorial tax system reform in one of the following periods, the firm is more likely to reinvest
in foreign projects even when their returns are lower, consistent with our hypothesis and numerical example.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e437a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e444" publication-type="other">
Worldscope provides data about foreign assets, foreign capital expenditures, foreign income, and foreign income
taxes for firms with foreign operations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e455a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e462" publication-type="other">
We include these tax-credit firms in one of our robustness tests.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e469a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e476" publication-type="other">
We calculate the effective domestic tax rate by dividing domestic income taxes by pretax domestic income.
Foreign taxes include also any possible withholding taxes on dividends (earnings transferred to the domestic
country) levied by the subsidiary country.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e489a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e496" publication-type="other">
The proportion of U.K. dividend payer to nonpayer in our sample is 49:51.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e503a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e510" publication-type="other">
We report these aggregate figures purely for illustrative purposes. The reported numbers are affected by any
change in the number of multinational firms over the years and, most of all, changes in firm characteristics and
macroeconomic conditions during and after the recession.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e523a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e530" publication-type="other">
The only exception is the graph of foreign capital expenditures, which just reports the multinational firms' annual
median values.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e540a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e547" publication-type="other">
In unreported results, we also repeat all of our tests using a difference-in-differences (DID) estimation approach,
in which we compare changes in financial policy variables for a treated group of companies that are affected by
the tax law change (i.e., multinational firms) with a control group of companies that are not affected by the tax
change (i.e., purely domestic firms). The results are qualitatively identical.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e564a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e571" publication-type="other">
We check for the robustness of our results by scaling payouts by assets rather than by market values in regressions
that are presented in Table 10.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e581a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e588" publication-type="other">
Refer to Rau and Vermaelen (2002) for a detailed discussion of U.K. regulations on share repurchases.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e595a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e602" publication-type="other">
For the domestic firms in our sample, domestic capital expenditures coincide with consolidated capital
expenditures.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e612a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e619" publication-type="other">
When we include those firms in our sample, the results do not significantly change. These results are available
upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623286e629a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623286e636" publication-type="other">
The results of these tests are available upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d623286e652a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e656" publication-type="other">
Altshuler, R., and H. Grubert. 2002. Repatriation taxes, repatriation strategies and multinational financial policy.
Journal of Public Economics 87:73-107.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e666a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e670" publication-type="other">
Arena, M. R, and B. Julio. 2014. The effects of securities class action litigation on corporate liquidity and
investment policy. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis. Advance Access published March 14, 2014,
10.1017/S0022109014000076.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e683a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e687" publication-type="other">
Blouin, J., and L. Krull. 2009. Bringing it home: A study of the incentives surrounding the repatriation of foreign
earnings under the American Jobs Creation Act of 2004. Journal of Accounting Research 47:1027-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e697a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e701" publication-type="other">
Desai, M. A., C. F. Foley, and J. R. Jr. Hines. 2001. Repatriation taxes and dividend distortions. National tax
journal 54:829-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e712a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e716" publication-type="other">
Desai, M. A., C. F. Foley, and J. R. Jr. Hines. 2007. Dividend policy inside the multinational firm. Financial
Management 36:5-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e726a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e730" publication-type="other">
Dharmapala, D., C. F. Foley, and K. J. Forbes. 2011. Watch what I do, not what I say: The unintended consequences
of the homeland investment act. Journal of Finance 66:753-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e740a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e744" publication-type="other">
Faulkender, M., and M. Petersen. 2012. Investment and capital constraints: Repatriation under the American jobs
creation acts. Review of Financial Studies 25:3351-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e754a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e758" publication-type="other">
Foley, C. F., J. C. Hartzell, S. Titman, and G Twite. 2007. Why do firms hold so much cash? A tax-based
explanation. Journal of Financial Economics 86:579-607.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e768a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e772" publication-type="other">
Graham, J. R. 2008. Taxes and corporate finance. In Handbook of corporate finance. Ed. B. Espen Eckbo.
Amsterdam: North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e782a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e786" publication-type="other">
Graham, J. R., M. Hanlon, and T. Shevlin. 2011. Real effects of accounting rules: Evidence from multinational
firms investment location and profit repatriation decisions. Journal of Accounting Research 49:137-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e797a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e801" publication-type="other">
Grubert, H., and J. Mutti. 2001. Taxing international business income: Dividend exemption versus the current
system. Washington, DC: American Enterprise Institute Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e811a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e815" publication-type="other">
Grullon, G, B. Paye, S. Underwood, and J. P. Weston. 2011. Has the propensity to pay out declined? Journal of
Financial and Quantitative Analysis 46:1-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e825a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e829" publication-type="other">
Hanlon, M., R. Lester, and R. Verdi. Forthcoming. The effect of repatriation tax costs on U.S. multinational
investment. Journal of Financial Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e839a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e843" publication-type="other">
Hartman, D. G 1985. Tax policy and foreign direct investment. Journal of Public Economics 26:107-21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e850a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e854" publication-type="other">
Hoberg, G, and N. R. Prabhala. 2009. Disappearing dividends, catering, and risk. Review of Financial Studies
22:79-116.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e864a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e868" publication-type="other">
Honoré, B. E. 1992. Trimmed LAD and least squares estimation of truncated and censored regression models
with fixed effects. Econometrica 60:533-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e879a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e883" publication-type="other">
Landau, T., T. Tokuhiro, K. Muraoka, and S. Kobayashi. 2009. Japan issues proposed 2009 tax reforms. Journal
of International Taxation 20:15-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e893a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e897" publication-type="other">
Markle, K. 2013. A comparison of the tax-motivated income shifting of multinationals in territorial and worldwide
countries. Working Paper, University of Waterloo.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e907a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e911" publication-type="other">
Opler, T., L. Pinkowitz, R. Stulz, and R. Williamson. 1999. The determinants and implications of corporate cash
holdings. Journal of Finance 52:3-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e921a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e925" publication-type="other">
Rau, P. R., and T. Vermaelen. 2002. Regulation, taxes, and share repurchases in the United Kingdom. Journal of
Business 75:245-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623286e935a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623286e939" publication-type="other">
Skinner, D. J. 2008. The evolving relation between earnings, dividends, and stock repurchases. Journal of
Financial Economics 87:582-609.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


