<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422600</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental and Numerical Assessment of Multi-Event Injection Strategies in a Solenoid Common-Rail Injector</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Piano</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrea</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Torino</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Boccardo</surname>
                  <given-names>Giulio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Torino</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Millo</surname>
                  <given-names>Federico</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Torino</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Cavicchi</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrea</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Università degli Studi di Perugia</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Postrioti</surname>
                  <given-names>Lucio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Università degli Studi di Perugia</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Pesce</surname>
                  <given-names>Francesco Concetto</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors Global Propulsion Systems</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>October 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422530</issue-id>
         <fpage>2129</fpage>
         <lpage>2140</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422600"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Nowadays, injection rate shaping and multi-pilot events can help to improve fuel efficiency, combustion noise and pollutant emissions in diesel engine, providing high flexibility in the shape of the injection that allows combustion process control. Different strategies can be used in order to obtain the required flexibility in the rate, such as very close pilot injections with almost zero Dwell Time or boot shaped injections with optional pilot injections. Modern Common-Rail Fuel Injection Systems (FIS) should be able to provide these innovative patterns to control the combustion phases intensity for optimal tradeoff between fuel consumption and emission levels.</p>
            <p>In this work, a 1D-CFD model in GT-SUITE of a solenoid ballistic Common-Rail injector was firstly refined respect to the previous work [1] and then it was validated against an extensive experimental dataset of single injections, standard double pilot and multi-pilot injection patterns (up to 4 pilot events) with almost zero dwell time between two consecutive injection events. The experimental hydraulic test data used to validate the one-dimensional model were obtained by means of the UniPG Injection Analyzer based on the Zeuch’s method.</p>
            <p>The comparison between the experimental and simulated volumetric injection rates showed a more than satisfactory accuracy of the model in predicting the actual behavior of the ballistic injector for all the injection patterns tested, even for relatively complex injector command strategies, characterized by reduced Dwell Time values between consecutive injection events.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piano, A., Millo, F., Postrioti, L., Biscontini, G. et al., "Numerical and Experimental Assessment of a Solenoid Common-Rail Injector Operation with Advanced Injection Strategies," SAE Int. J. Engines 9(1):565-575, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0563.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blanco-Rodriguez, D., Vagnoni, G., and Holderbaum, B., “EU6 C-Segment Diesel vehicles, a challenging segment to meet RDE and WLTP requirements,” IFAC-PapersOnLine 49(11):649-656, 2016, doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ifacol.2016.08.094.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Minami, T., Takeuchi, K., and Shimazaki, N., "Reduction of Diesel Engine NOx Using Pilot Injection," SAE Technical Paper 950611, 1995, doi:10.4271/950611.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, L., "A Study of Pilot Injection in a DI Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3493, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3493.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schommers, J., Duvinage, F., Stotz, M., Peters, A. et al., “Potential of Common Rail Injection System for Passenger Car DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0944, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0944.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nehmer, D. and Reitz, R., "Measurement of the Effect of Injection Rate and Split Injections on Diesel Engine Soot and NOx Emissions," SAE Technical Paper 940668, 1994, doi:10.4271/940668.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bianchi, G., Falfari, S., Pelloni, P., Filicori, F. et al., "A Numerical and Experimental Study Towards Possible Improvements of Common Rail Injectors," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0500, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0500.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Imarisio, R., Ricco, M., and Rossi Sebastiano, G., “Multiple injection, a cost effective solution for emission reduction of common rail DI diesel engines,” Aachen Colloquium, Aachen, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hummel, K., Krieger, K., and Hansen, N., “Evolution of the Bosch common rail system for passenger cars,” The Future of Diesel Engine Technology for Passenger Cars, Porto Cervo, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Corcione, F., Vaglieco, B., Corcione, G., and Lavorgna, M., "Potential of Multiple Injection Strategy for Low Emission Diesel Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1150, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1150.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Corcione, F., Vaglieco, B., Corcione, G., Lavorgna, M. et al., "Study of the Combustion System of a New Small DI Diesel Engine with Advanced Common Rail Injection System," SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1782, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1782.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Badami, M., Mallamo, F., Millo, F., and Rossi, E., "Influence of Multiple Injection Strategies on Emissions, Combustion Noise and BSFC of a DI Common Rail Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0503, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0503.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ricaud, J.C. and Lavoisier, F., “Optimizing the Multiple Injection Settings on an HSDI Diesel Engine,” in: Whitelaw, J. H., Payri, F., Arcoumanis, C., and Desantes, J. M., eds., Thermo- and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines 2: Selected Papers from the THIESEL 2002 Conference, Valencia, Spain, 11--13 September 2002, Springer Berlin Heidelberg, Berlin, Heidelberg, doi:10.1007/978-3-662-10502-3_11.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H., “Advanced Direct Injection Combustion Engine Technologies and Development - Diesel Engines,” Cambridge: Woodhead Publishing, ISBN 9781439824757, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atzler, F., Kastner, O., Rotondi, R., and Weigand, A., "Multiple injection and rate shaping Part 1: Emissions reduction in passenger car Diesel engines," SAE Technical Paper 2009-24-0004, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boggavarapu, P. and Singh, S., "Computational Study of Injection Rate-Shaping for Emissions Control in Diesel Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2011-26-0081, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-26-0081.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Macian, V., Payri, R., Ruiz, S., Bardi, M. et al., “Experimental study of the relationship between injection rate shape and Diesel ignition using a novel piezo-actuated direct-acting injector,” Appl. Energy 118:100-113, 2014, doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2013.12.025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oki, M., Matsumoto, S., Toyoshima, Y., Ishisaka, K. et al., "180MPa Piezo Common Rail System," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0274, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0274.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matsumoto, S., Date, K., Taguchi, T., and Herrmann, O., “The New DENSO Common Rail Diesel Solenoid Injector,” MTZ Worldw. 44-48, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matsumoto, S., Klose, C., Schneider, J., Nakane, N. et al., “4th Generation Diesel Common Rail System: Realizing Ideal Structure Function for Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1590, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1590.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferrari, A., Paolicelli, F., and Pizzo, P., “The new-generation of solenoid injectors equipped with pressure-balanced pilot valves for energy saving and dynamic response improvement,” Appl. Energy 151:367-376, 2015, doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2015.03.074.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeuch, W., “Neue Verfahren zur Messung des Einspritzgesetzes und del Einspritzregelmassigkeit von Diesel Einspritzpumpen,” MTZ 344-349, 1961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Postrioti, L., Buitoni. G., Pesce, F.C. and Ciaravino, C., "Zeuch methodbased injection rate analysis of a common-rail system operated with advanced injection strategies," Fuel 128:188-198, 2014, http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2014.03.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GT-SUITE, Optimization Manual, 2017th ed.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deb, K. and Jain, H., “An evolutionary many-objective optimization algorithm using reference-point-based nondominated sorting approach, Part I: Solving problems with box constraints,” IEEE Trans. Evol. Comput. 18(4):577-601, 2014, doi:10.1109/TEVC.2013.2281535.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
