<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830828</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830833</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>VILLAGE BANKS FOR RURAL COMMUNITIES IN COSTA RICA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Mario</given-names>
                  <surname>Zappacosta</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2003</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>295</fpage>
         <lpage>316</lpage>
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830833"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Costa Rica has a long-term experience in financial services for small peasants. Immediately after the achievement of the independence in 1821, small producers of coffee started to manage loans proceeding from processing plants and import companies. At the beginning of the twentieth century, the central bank developed for the first time some special credit tools to support agriculture. For almost seventy years, Cajas rurales and Juntas de Crédito Agrícola financed the national production of both food and export crops. They were de facto operational until the end of the 1970s, when a rising inflation rate reduced drastically the availability of credit for small farmers. In these years, the Fundación Integral Campesina (FINCA), a local institution specialised in rural finance, began to promote the diffusion of an innovative form of financial intermediation called Bancomunales. Their structure and organisation are based on the Village Banking methodology, originally developed by the Foundation for International Community Assistance but then modified by FINCA to the national rural context. Costa Rican Bancomunales are a pioneer and successful experience in rural finance programs in Latin America. In fact, since their first establishment in 1984, the number of Bancomunales has continuously increased, reaching many rural and remote areas. This paper examines the interesting lesson of Costa Rican Bancomunales, analysing their structure, organisation and working mechanism. When addressing the reasons of their success, a special attention is given to methodology features and to the influence of the macroeconomic context. In conclusion, the paper proposes some methodological and institutional changes that may be useful to enhance Bancomunales future autonomy.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d15e126a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e133" publication-type="other">
http://www.villagebanking.org/village.htm</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e140a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e147" publication-type="other">
Molina. Palmer. 1997</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e153" publication-type="other">
Rosene. 1990</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e160a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e167" publication-type="other">
Paxton (1998)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e174a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e181" publication-type="other">
Garson 1996</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d15e197a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e201" publication-type="other">
Altenburg Tilman et al., El desafib economico de Costa Rica: desarrollo agroindustrial autocentrado como alter-
nativa, DEI, S. Jose, 1990.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e211a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e215" publication-type="other">
Bennett Lynn, Cuevas Carlos (eds.), "Sustainable banking with the poor", Journal of International Development,
special number, Vol.VIII, No. 2, 1996.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e225a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e229" publication-type="other">
Chaves Rodrigo, "Diseno institucional de organizaciones: el caso de los Bancomunales", in Gonzalez Vega
Claudio et al. (eds.), Financiamiento de la microempresa rural: FINCA - Costa Rica, Academia de Centroamerica,
S. Jose, 1993.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e242a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e246" publication-type="other">
Chavez Arroyo Fernando, "El credito subvencionado en el Banco Nacional de Costa Rica", in POSCAE (eds.), El
credito agncolo en el ambiente centroamericano, Editorial Guaymuras, Tegucigalpa, 1995.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e257a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e261" publication-type="other">
FAO/GTZ, Better practices in agricultural lending, Agricultural Finance Revisited n. 3, Rome, FAO, 1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e268a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e272" publication-type="other">
Fernandez Mario, "Agricultura de cambio y proletarizacion campesina en Costa Rica", in Mendizabal Ana, Weller
Jurgen (eds.), Exportaciones agrfcolas no tradicionales del istmo centroamericano: ipromesa o espejismo?, CADE-
SCA, Panama, 1992.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e285a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e289" publication-type="other">
Fonseca Elisabeth, Costa Rica colonial: la tierra y el hombre, Editorial Universitaria Centroamericana, San
Jose, 1997.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e299a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e303" publication-type="other">
Garson Jose, Microfinance and anti-poverty strategies for the poor. A donor perspective, United Nations
Development Fund, New York, 1996.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e313a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e317" publication-type="other">
Gonzalez Vega Claudio et al. (eds.), Financiamiento de la microempresa rural: FINCA - Costa Rica, Academia de
Centroamerica, S.Jose, 1993.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e327a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e331" publication-type="other">
Holt Sharon, "The village bank methodology: performance and prospects", in Otero Maria, Rhyne Elisabeth (eds.),
The new world of microenterprise finance: building healthy financial institutions for the poor, Kumarian Press, West
Hartford, 1994.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e345a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e349" publication-type="other">
Johnson Susan, "Microfinance North and South: contrasting current debates", Journal of International
Development, special number, Vol. VIII, No. 2, 1996.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e359a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e363" publication-type="other">
Ledgerwood Joanna, Microfinance Handbook. An Institutional and Financial Perspective, The World Bank,
Washington DC, 1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e373a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e377" publication-type="other">
Molina Ivan, Palmer Steven, Historia de Costa Rica, Editorial Universidad de Costa Rica, S. Jose, 1997.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e384a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e388" publication-type="other">
Morduch Jonathan, "The microfinance promise", Journal of Economic Literature, Vol. XXXVII, No. 4, 1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e395a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e399" publication-type="other">
Paxton Julia, Costa Rica FINCA - Village banking, Case Studies in Microfinance, The World Bank,
Washington DC, 1998.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e409a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e413" publication-type="other">
Quiros Rodolfo, Jimenez Ronulfo, "FINCA y el acceso al credito para pequenos productores rurales", in Gonzalez
Vega Claudio et al. (eds.), Financiamiento de la microempresa rural: FINCA - Costa Rica, Academia de Centroamerica,
S.Jose, 1993.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e427a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e431" publication-type="other">
Rodriguez Ennio, Costa Rica: policies and conditions for export diversification, Working Paper n.154, United
Nations University, WIDER, Helsinki, December, 1998.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e441a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e445" publication-type="other">
Rosene Chris, "Modernization and rural development in Costa Rica: a critical perspective", Canadian Journal of
Development Studies, Vol. XI, No. 2, 1990.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e455a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e459" publication-type="other">
UNDP, Human Development Report 1999, Oxford University Press, New York, 1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e466a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e470" publication-type="other">
UNDP, Human Development Report 2002, Oxford University Press, New York, 2002.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


