<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275545</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>An Investigation into the Effects of Fuel Properties and Engine Load on UHC and CO Emissions from a Light-Duty Optical Diesel Engine Operating in a Partially Premixed Combustion Regime</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Petersen</surname>
                  <given-names>Ben R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ekoto</surname>
                  <given-names>Isaac W.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Miles</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275542</issue-id>
         <fpage>38</fpage>
         <lpage>55</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275545"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The behavior of the engine-out UHC and CO emissions from a light-duty diesel optical engine operating at two PPCI conditions was investigated for fifteen different fuels, including diesel fuels, biofuel blends, n-heptane-iso-octane mixtures, and n-cetane-HMN mixtures. The two highly dilute (9-10% O ₂) early direct injection PPCI conditions included a low speed (1500 RPM) and load (3.0 bar IMEP) case-where the UHC and CO have been found to stem from overly-lean fuel-air mixtures-and a condition with a relatively higher speed (2000 RPM) and load (6.0 bar IMEP)-where globally richer mixtures may lead to different sources of UHC and CO. The main objectives of this work were to explore the general behavior of the UHC and CO emissions from early-injection PPCI combustion and to gain an understanding of how fuel properties and engine load affect the engine-out emissions.</p>
            <p>The UHC and CO emissions from an emissions certification diesel fuel and several soy- and palm-based biofuel blends were found to partially collapse when plotted as a function of the premixed burn duration for the low speed and load condition. Significant reductions in both UHC and CO were observed with the biofuel blends. The engine-out UHC and CO emissions and premixed burn duration, which directly correlates with the magnitude of the peak heat-release, were shown to depend on three general parameters: (1) the injection timing, which controls the targeting and the initial thermodynamic state of the ambient gases; (2) the mixing time between the fuel and ambient gases during the ignition delay period; and (3) the premixed combustion phasing, which controls the temperature, pressure, and mixture state during premixed combustion. In order to investigate the effects of ignition quality and volatility in greater detail, a controlled parametric study involving nine different fuels was conducted. The fuels were selected to provide an orthogonal fuel matrix in which ignition quality and volatility were varied independently. The advancement of the combustion phasing for fuels with higher ignition quality was found to significantly decrease the UHC and CO emissions, while fuel volatility was determined to have a much smaller effect on the engine-out emissions. The emissions from the higher speed and load condition were found to be mainly dependent on the injection timing and were less sensitive to fuel-type. This is consistent with previous studies that have attributed the behavior of the UHC and CO emissions at higher loads to bulk mixing processes controlled by the targeting of the injected fuel spray.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lapuerta, M., Armas, O., Rodriguez-Fernandez, J., “Effect of Biodiesel Fuels on Diesel Engine Emissions,” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci., Vol. 34, pp. 198-223, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graboski, M.S., McCormick, R.L., “Combustion of Fat and Vegetable Oil Derived Fuels in Diesel Engines,” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci., Vol. 24, pp. 125-164, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I.W., Colban, W.F., Miles, P.C., Park S. et al., “Sources of UHC Emissions from a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Operating in a Partially Premixed Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 1265-1289, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I.W., Colban, W.F., Miles, P.C., Park S.W. et al., “UHC and CO Emissions Sources from a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Undergoing Dilution-Controlled Low-Temperature Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):411-430, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I.W., Colban, W.F., Miles, P.C., Aronsson, U., Andersson, O., Park S.W., Foster, D.E., Reitz, R.D., Aronsson, U., Andersson, O., “UHC and CO Emissions Sources from a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Undergoing Late- Injection Low Temperature Combustion,” Proceedings of ASME ICEF2009, ICEF2009-14030, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, D., Ekoto, I, Colban, W.F., and Miles, P.C., “Incylinder CO and UHC Imaging in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine During PPCI Low-Temperature Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):933-956, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B.R., Ekoto, I.W., and Miles, P.C., “Optical Investigation of UHC and CO Sources from Biodiesel Blends in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Operating in a Partially Premixed Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1): 414-434, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0862.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murillo, S., Miguez, J., Porteiro, J., Granada, E., Moran, J., “Performance and Exhaust Emissions in the use of Biodiesel in Outboard Diesel Engines,” Fuel, Vol. 86, pp. 1765-1771, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Opat, R., Ra, Y., Gonzalez, M.A., Krieger, R. et al., “Investigation of Mixing and Temperature Effects on HC/CO Emissions for Highly Dilute Low Temperature Combustion in a Light Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0193, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koci, C.P., Ra, Y., Krieger, R., Andrie, M. et al., “Detailed Unburned Hydrocarbon Investigations in a Highly- Dilute Diesel Low Temperature Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):858-879, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colban, W.F., Miles, P.C., and Oh, S., “Effect of Intake Pressure on Performance and Emissions in an Automotive Diesel Engine Operating in Low Temperature Combustion Regimes,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4063, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colban, W.F., Kim, D., Miles, P.C., Oh, S. et al., “A Detailed Comparison of Emissions and Combustion Performance Between Optical and Metal Single-Cylinder Diesel Engines at Low Temperature Combustion Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):505-519, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bamgboye, A.I. and Hansen, A.C., “Prediction of Cetane Number of Biodiesel Fuel from the Fatty Acid Methyl Ester (FAME) Composition,” International Agrophysics, 22(1): 21-30, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murphy, M.J., Taylor, J.D., McCormick, R.L., “Compendium of Experimental Cetane Data”, National Renewable Energy Laboratory Report No. NREL/SR-540-36805; National Renewable Energy Laboratory: Golden, CO, September 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gallant, T., Franz, J.A., Alnajjar, M.S., Storey, J.M.E. et al., “Fuels for Advanced Combustion Engines Research Diesel Fuels: Analysis of Physical and Chemical Properties,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2 (2):262-272, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Ogawa, H., Muranaka, S. et al., “New Combustion Concept for Ultra-Clean and High- Efficiency Small DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3681, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Kitahara, Y., and Aiyoshizawa, E., “Ultra-Clean Combustion Technology Combining a Low- Temperature and Premixed Combustion Concept for Meeting Future Emission Standards,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0200, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
