<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278126</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental and Numerical Comparison of the Acoustic Performance of the Air Filter Box of a SI-ICE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Siano</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniela</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori CNR</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ferrara</surname>
                  <given-names>Giovanni</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Florence</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lenzi</surname>
                  <given-names>Giulio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Florence</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>D'Agostino</surname>
                  <given-names>Danilo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Naples</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fioravanti</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrea</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Florence</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>November 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278095</issue-id>
         <fpage>2368</fpage>
         <lpage>2378</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278126"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In an Internal Combustion Engine, the design of the intake system is a very critical aspect since it affects both the engine power output and noise emissions at the intake side. In particular, downsized VVA engines typically produce higher gas-dynamic noise levels since, due to the intake line de-throttling at part-load, a less effective attenuation of the pressure waves is realized. In this work, the acoustic performance of the intake air filter of a commercial VVA engine is numerically and experimentally analyzed. In particular, a FEM model of the system is realized in order to compute the Transmission Loss (TL) parameter of the base device. The numerical analysis accounts of fluid-structure interaction, which gives the possibility to determine the effect of structure participation on the TL profile. Contemporarily, the experimental tests are performed on an acoustic test bench based on the multi-microphone technique for the evaluation of the acoustic parameters. Numerical outcomes are compared with experimental findings, showing a very good correlation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Bellis, V., Bozza, F., Siano, D., and Gimelli, A., “Fuel Consumption Optimization and Noise Reduction in a Spark-Ignition Turbocharged VVA Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):1262-1274, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1625.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siano, D., Teodosio, L., De Bellis, V., and Bozza, F., “Analysis and Design of an Intake Filter Box for a Downsized VVA Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1693, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1693.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Munjal M. L., Acoustics of Ducts and Mufflers, John Wiley &amp; Sons, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siano, D., Bozza, F., Teodosio, L., and De Bellis, V., “A Comparison Between External and Internal Resonators Employment to Reduce the Gas-Dynamic Noise of a SI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(1):42-52, 2015, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2864.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferrara, G., ferrari, L., Vichi, G., Lenzi, G. et al., “Acoustic Characterization of Automotive Mufflers - Part I: Test Rig Design and Evaluation of Acoustic Properties,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0800, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0800.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fioravanti, A., Lenzi, G., Vichi, G., Ferrara, G. et al., “Assessment and Experimental Validation of a 3D Acoustic Model of a Motorcycle Muffler,” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(1):266-276, 2015, doi:10.4271/2014-32- 0122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ih J. G. and Jang S. H., “On the multiple microphone method for measuring in-duct acoustic properties in the presence of mean flow,” Journal of Acoustic Society of America, vol. 103, no. 3, pp. 1520-1526, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heuwinkel C., Enghardt L. and Röhle I., “Experimental Investigation of the Acoustic Damping of Perforated Liners With Bias Flow,” in 13th AIAA/CEAS Aeroacoustic Conference, Rome, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abom M., “Measurements of scattering matrix of acoustical two-port,” Mechanical System and Signal Processing, vol. 5, no. 2, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montenegro, G., Della Torre, A., Cerri, T., Lenzi, G. et al., “Fluid Dynamic and Acoustic Optimization Methodology of a Motorbike Intake Airbox Using Multilevel Numerical CFD Models and Experimental Validation Tests,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(3):1731-1744, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0070.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heuwinkel C., Enghardt L., Röhle, I., Muhlbauer B., Noll B., Aigner M. and Busse S., “Comparison of experimental and numerical results concerning the dumping of perforated liners with bias flow,” in ASME Turbo Expo 2008: Power for Land, Sea, and Air, Berlin, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stiaccini, I., Romani, L., Ferrari, L. and Ferrara, G., “A Hybrid Time- Frequency Domain Approach For Numerical Modeling Of Reciprocating Compressors”, Energy Procedia 00 (2013) 000-000, 69th Conference of the Italian Thermal Machines Engineering Association, ATI2014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kulik Y., “Transfer matrix of conical waveguides with any geometric parameters for increased precision in computer modeling,” Journal of Acoustic Society of America, vol. 122, no. 5, pp. EL179-EL184, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ISO 5136:2003 Acoustics - Determination of sound power radiated into a duct by fans and other air-moving devices - In- duct method</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Visual-Environment V. 10.5, esi Group</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fine/Acoustics Theoretical Manual, www.numeca.be</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zienkievicz O.C. and Taylor R.L.. The Finite Element Method, volume 1, The Basis. Butterworth-Heinemann, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seybert, A. F., Wu, T. W., Li, W. L. A Coupled FEM/BEM for Fluid- Structure Interaction Using Ritz Vectors and Eigenvectors, Lexington, KY 40506-0046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Felippa, C.A., Park, K.C., Farhat, C., Partitioned analysis of coupled mechanical systems, Computer methods in applied mechanics and engineering, 190 (2001) 3247-3270.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siano, D., Bozza, F., Auriemma, F., Acoustic and fluid-dynamic optimization of an automotive muffler, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering, ISSN: 09544070, doi:10.1177/0954407012465689, Vol. 227, Issue 5, May 2013, Pages 735-747.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siano D., Transmission loss and gas-dynamic noise analyses of a downsized spark ignition engine, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part C: Journal of Mechanical Engineering Science Volume 229, Issue 4, 15 March 2015, Pages 679-691, ISSN: 09544062, doi:10.1177/0954406214538953.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
