<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440107</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Did the National Minimum Wage Affect UK Prices?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Jonathan</given-names>
                  <surname>Wadsworth</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2010</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">31</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440103</issue-id>
         <fpage>81</fpage>
         <lpage>120</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2010</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440107"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>One potential channel through which the effects of the minimum wage could be directed is that firms that employ minimum-wage workers could have passed on any higher labour costs resulting from the minimum wage in the form of higher prices. This study looks at the effects of the minimum wage on the prices of UK goods and services by comparing prices of goods and services produced by industries in which UK minimum-wage workers make up a substantial share of total costs with prices of goods and services that make less use of minimum-wage labour. Using sectoral-level price data matched to Labour Force Survey data on the share of minimum-wage workers in each sector, it is hard to find much evidence of significant price changes in the months that correspond immediately to the uprating of the national minimum wage. However, over the longer term, prices in several minimum-wage sectors – notably, take-away food, canteen meals, hotel services and domestic services – do appear to have risen significantly faster than prices in non-minimum-wage sectors. These effects were particularly significant in the four years immediately after the introduction of the minimum wage.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d22e224a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e231" publication-type="other">
Submitted September 2008.
This work is based on an initial report for the Low Pay Commission. Thanks to Tim Butcher, Steve
Machin, David Metcalf and two anonymous referees for very helpful comments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e244a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e251" publication-type="other">
With an elasticity of price inflation with respect to the NMW of around 0.04.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e258a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e265" publication-type="other">
See Low Pay Commission (2008) for more details on the levels and history of the NMW.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e272a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e279" publication-type="other">
Any price index also follows a similar pattern to the inflation rate.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e287a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e294" publication-type="other">
These data on individual firms exist in principle, since prices for a sample of firms form the basis of
the retail price index (RP1) in the UK.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e304a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e311" publication-type="other">
The (mean shift) structural break techniques advocated by Bai and Perron (2003) are more suited to
sustained breaks in the series rather than the analysis of single pulses in the series.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e321a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e328" publication-type="other">
In the absence of disaggregated UK input-output data, it is not possible to track the minimum-wage
content of supply chains.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e338a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e345" publication-type="other">
Table 1 uses the LFS to estimate the NMW wage bill share. A table based on the use of ASHE to
estimate the wage bill share is available on request. See also Wadsworth (2009). The rankings do not
change much.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e358a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e365" publication-type="other">
The minimum-wage recipients in minicab services are typically office workers rather than (self-
employed) drivers.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e375a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e382" publication-type="other">
According to ASHE, the two largest minimum-wage sectors are bars (SIC 5540) and the primary
education sector (SIC 8010), which each accounted for some 15 per cent of all minimum-wage workers in
1999. Retail superstores accounted for a further 6 per cent of the total, despite not featuring in the top 10
rankings in Table 1. The LFS does not disaggregate the retail sector below two-digit level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e399a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e406" publication-type="other">
Around 20 per cent of all employees in the retail sector were paid at or below the NMW according to
the 1998-99 LFS.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e416a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e423" publication-type="other">
For example, the take-away food category in the RPI is currently based on weighted information of
15 different take-away items ranging from fish and chips to pizza to beefburgers, sandwiches, tea and
coffee.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e436a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e443" publication-type="other">
This point was made almost 100 years ago in the debate surrounding the introduction of the UK
Wages Councils; see Webb and Webb ( 1911, pp. 780-3).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e453a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e460" publication-type="other">
See Wadsworth (2007) for details on how to identify 'minimum-wage households'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e467a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e474" publication-type="other">
Housing accounts for around 15-20 per cent of total household spending over the sample period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e481a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e488" publication-type="other">
If the prices of all nine NMW goods and services in the table rose by 10 per cent, then real incomes
would fall by around 1 per cent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e499a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e506" publication-type="other">
The smaller October 2000 and 2002 NMW increases (2.8 per cent and 2.4 per cent respectively) are
not shown in Figure 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e516a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e523" publication-type="other">
"The price series were tested for stationarity with a deterministic trend against a non-stationary series
with drift for each of the minimum-wage goods that we identify. In each case, the null of a random walk
with drift cannot be rejected. Results available on request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e536a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e543" publication-type="other">
Not all the sectors are represented here in the item-level estimates because there is no consecutive
seven-year monthly price series for certain items spanning the requisite time periods. The hotel sector is
notably absent from these item-level regressions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e556a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e563" publication-type="other">
To allow for autocorrelation, the standard errors in the individual series regressions are adjusted
using a Newey-West correction factor of order 1. The standard errors in the pooled regressions are
adjusted using the fixed effects robust correction suggested by Wooldridge (2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e576a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e583" publication-type="other">
These results do not change significantly if we add another five minimum-wage items with at least
seven years of continuous data but not covering the period before the NMW was introduced. If retail food
items - a potential minimum-wage sector - are dropped from the list of non-minimum-wage goods in
column 3, the 'minimum wage on' dummy becomes significantly negative: -0.0017 (0.0007).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e599a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e606" publication-type="other">
We also used month of announcement rather than month of introduction of the NMW level to centre
the dummy variables in order to test whether there is any evidence of anticipation effects. The results,
available on request, show little sign of any price hikes in the month the NMW level is announced.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e620a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e627" publication-type="other">
These goods are soft drinks, alcohol off-sales, sweets, tobacco, books, furniture and gardening
products. These are not free of minimum-wage influences since many of them will be sold in shops
whose staff are covered by the NMW. A graph of their respective inflation rates is available on request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e640a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e647" publication-type="other">
Assuming an average NMW share in total costs of 20 per cent, then the 17 per cent rise in the NMW
observed between 1998 and 2003 on top of the estimated 20 per cent rise in wages generated by the
introduction of the NMW equates to an 8 per cent rise in total costs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e660a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e667" publication-type="other">
The set of estimated coefficients in column 1 indicate that the inflation rate for minimum-wage goods
was 3.9 per cent in the period after April 1999 compared with the retail price index average of 2.2 per
cent for the same period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e680a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e687" publication-type="other">
So prices of hairdressing services continued to rise faster than general prices (Min. wage, column 3),
but this price differential did not change significantly in the period after April 1999.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e697a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e704" publication-type="other">
The aggregate inflation rate was some 0.5 points higher in the period 2003-07 than between 1999
and 2003. The inflation rate among the basket of non-minimum-wage goods was little changed over the
same two time periods, which explains the general result. If we include seven interaction dummies (one
for each NMW period) rather than one, the estimated coefficients - available on request - confirm the
idea of a stronger price response in the earlier period, though larger price responses do not always follow
larger percentage rises in the NMW.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e727a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e734" publication-type="other">
The price data for these series begin in 1995 (hotels) and 1997 (hairdressing and dry-cleaning), so
estimates do not exist before these periods.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d22e753a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e757" publication-type="other">
Aaronson, D. (2001), 'Price pass-through and the minimum wage', Review of Economics and
Statistics, vol. 83, pp. 158-69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e767a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e771" publication-type="other">
— and French, E. (2007), 'Product market evidence on the employment effects of the
minimum wage', Journal of Labor Economics, vol. 25, pp. 167-200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e781a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e785" publication-type="other">
—, — and MacDonald, J. (2008), 'The minimum wage, restaurant prices and labor market
structure', Journal of Human Resources, vol. 43, pp. 688-720.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e795a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e799" publication-type="other">
Alvarez, L., Dhyne, E., Le Bihan, H., Veronese, G., Dias, D., Hoffman, J., Jonker, N.,
Lunnemann, P., Rumler, F. and Vilmunen, J. (2005), 'Sticky prices in the euro area: a
summary of new micro-evidence', Journal of the European Economic Association, vol. 4,
pp. 575-84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e816a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e820" publication-type="other">
Apel, M., Friberg, R. and Hallsten, K. (2005), 'Micro foundations of macroeconomic price
adjustment: survey evidence from Swedish firms', Journal of Money, Credit and Banking,
vol. 37, pp. 313-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e833a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e837" publication-type="other">
Bai, J. and Perron, P. (2003), 'Computation and analysis of multiple structural change
models', Journal of Applied Econometrics, vol. 18, pp. 1-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e847a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e851" publication-type="other">
Ball, L. and Mankiw, G. (1994), 'A sticky-price manifesto', Carnegie-Rochester Conference
Series on Public Policy, vol. 41, pp. 127-51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e861a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e865" publication-type="other">
Bils, M. and Klenow, P. (2004), 'Some evidence on the importance of sticky prices', Journal
of Political Economy, vol. 112, pp. 947-85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e875a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e879" publication-type="other">
Blanchard, O. (1989), 'A traditional interpretation of macroeconomic fluctuations', American
Economic Review, vol. 79, pp. 1146-64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e889a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e893" publication-type="other">
Caballero, R. and Engel, E. (2003), 'Adjustment is much slower than you think', Yale
University, Economic Growth Center, Discussion Paper no. 865.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e904a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e908" publication-type="other">
Caplin, A. and Spulber, D. (1987), 'Menu costs and the neutrality of money', Quarterly
Journal of Economics, vol. 102, pp. 703-25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e918a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e922" publication-type="other">
Card, D. and Krueger, A. (1994), 'Minimum wages and employment: a case study of the fast-
food industry in New Jersey and Pennsylvania', American Economic Review, vol. 84, pp.
772-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e935a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e939" publication-type="other">
— and — (1995), Myth and Measurement: The New Economics of the Minimum Wage,
Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e949a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e953" publication-type="other">
Carlton, D. ( 1986), 'The rigidity of prices', American Economic Review, vol. 76, pp. 637-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e960a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e964" publication-type="other">
Draca, M., Machin, S. and Van Reenen, J. (2005), The Impact of the National Minimum Wage
on Profits and Prices: Report for Low Pay Commission, http://www.lowpay.gov.uk/
lowpay/research/pdf/NMW_profits_and_prices.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e977a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e981" publication-type="other">
Gordon, R. (1981), 'Output fluctuations and gradual price adjustment', Journal of Economic
Literature, vol. 19, pp. 493-530.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e992a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e996" publication-type="other">
Hall, S., Walsh, M. and Yates, A. (2000), 'Are UK companies' prices sticky?', Oxford
Economic Papers, vol. 52, pp. 425-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1006a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1010" publication-type="other">
Hendry, D., Johansen, S. and Santos, C. (2006), 'Selecting a regression saturated by
indicators', University of Oxford, http://www.esg.ac.uk/papers/santos.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1020a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1024" publication-type="other">
Lach, S. and Tsiddon, D. (1992), 'The behavior of prices and inflation: an empirical analysis
of disaggregate price data', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 100, pp. 349-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1034a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1038" publication-type="other">
Lemos, S. (2008), 'A survey of the effects of the minimum wage on prices', Journal of
Economic Surveys, vol. 22, pp. 187-212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1048a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1052" publication-type="other">
Low Pay Commission (2001), The National Minimum Wage: Making a Difference, Third
Report of the Low Pay Commission, Cm. 5075, http://www.lowpay.gov.uk/lowpay/
report/pdf/report3.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1065a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1069" publication-type="other">
— (2008), The National Minimum Wage: Low Pay Commission Report 2008, Cm. 7333,
http://www.lowpay.gov.uk/lowpay/report/pdf/2008_min_wage.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1080a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1084" publication-type="other">
MacDonald, J. and Aaronson, D. (2006), 'How firms construct price changes: evidence from
restaurant responses to increased minimum wages', American Journal of Agricultural
Economics, vol. 88, pp. 292-307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1097a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1101" publication-type="other">
Nakamura, E. and Steinsson, J. (2008), 'Five facts about prices: a réévaluation of menu cost
models', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 123, pp. 1415-64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1111a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1115" publication-type="other">
Sheshinski, E. and Weiss, Y. (1993), Optimal Pricing, Inflation and the Cost of Price
Adjustment, Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1125a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1129" publication-type="other">
Stewart, M. (2004), 'The employment effects of the national minimum wage', Economic
Journal, vol. 114, pp. CI 10-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1139a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1143" publication-type="other">
— and Swaffield, J. (2008), 'The other margin: do minimum wages cause working hours
adjustments for low wage workers?', Economica, vol. 75, pp. 148-67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1153a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1157" publication-type="other">
Taylor, J. (1999), 'Staggered price and wage setting in macroeconomics', in J. Taylor and M.
Woodford (eds), Handbook of Macroeconomics, Amsterdam: Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1168a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1172" publication-type="other">
Wadsworth, J. (2007), Did the Minimum Wage Change Consumption Patterns? Report to
Low Pay Commission, http://www.lowpay.gov.uk/lowpay/research/pdf/t0Z96GK8.pdf.
— (2009), 'Did the national minimum wage affect UK prices?', Centre for Economic
Performance, Discussion Paper no. 947.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1188a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1192" publication-type="other">
Webb, B. and Webb, S. (1911), Industrial Democracy, London: Macmillan Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1199a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1203" publication-type="other">
Wooldridge, J. (2002), The Econometrics of Cross-Section and Panel Data, Cambridge, MA:
MIT Press</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
