<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24910681</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PROFESSIONAL FEATURES</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Practical VV&amp;A for DIME/PMESII Models</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hartley</surname>
                  <given-names>Dean S.</given-names>
                  <suffix>III</suffix>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dean S. Hartley III is the principal of Hartley Consulting. Previously he was a senior member of the research staff at the Department of Energy Oak Ridge Facilities. He received his PhD in piecewise linear topology from the University of Georgia. Hartley is a past Vice President of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS), a past Director of the Military Operations Research Society (MORS), past President of the Military Applications Society (MAS), and a member of the INFORMS Simulation Society (ISIM). He also serves as the Technical Advisor for Operations Research and Modeling to the International Psychopharmacology Algorithm Project (IPAP). Hartley is a Senior Fellow with the George Mason University School of Public Policy, a consulting resource for the Naval Postgraduate School (NPS), Modeling, Virtual Environments &amp; Simulation (MOVES) Institute, and a Research Fellow with the University of Alabama in Huntsville, Center for the Management of Science and Technology (CMOST). His expertise includes modeling of combat, DIME/PMESII (diplomatic, information, military, economic / political, military, economic, social, information, infrastructure) operations, verification, validation, and accreditation (VV&amp;A) of models, psychopharmacology modeling, and simulation. Hartley received the Koopman Prize for best publication in military operations research in 1994 and the Steinhardt Prize for lifetime achievement in operations research in 2013. His website is: http://dshartley3.home.comcast.net.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>March 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>48</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e24910667</issue-id>
         <fpage>33</fpage>
         <lpage>39</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24910681"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Appleget, J., Blais, C., Burks, R., Brown, R., Duong, D., Jaye, M., Perkins, T., and Thompson, M. 2011. Irregular Warfare (IW) Model Validation Best Practices Guide. TRADOC Analysis Center, Monterey, California.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Balci, O. 2001. Verification, Validation and Testing of Models. Encyclopedia of Operations Research and Management Science, Gass, S. I., and Harris, C. M., eds.. Kluwer Academic Publishers, Boston.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Department of Defense (DoD). 1996. DoD Modeling and Simulation (M&amp;S) Verification, Validation, Accreditation (VVA). DoD Instruction (DoDI) 5000.61 ( under revision).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Department of the Navy (DoN). 2004. Modeling and Simulation Verification, Validation, and Accreditation Implementation Handbook: Volume I VV&amp;A Framework (2004). Department of the Navy, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harmon, S. Y., and Youngblood, S. M. 2005. A Proposed Model for Simulation Validation Process Maturity. JDMS, Vol 2, No 4, 179-190.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hartley, D. S., III. 2014. “Chapter 5: DIME/PMESII Models,” Conflict and Complexity: Countering Terrorism, Insurgency, Ethnic and Regional Violence, P. Vos Fellman, Y. Bar- Yam, and A. Minai, eds. Springer.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hartley, D. S., III, and Lacy, L. W. 2011. Irregular Warfare (IW) Metrics Ontology Final Report, TRAC-H-TR-13-020, 29 July, Fort Leavenworth, Kansas.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hartley, D. S., III, and Lacy, L. W. 2013. Irregular Warfare (IW) Ontology Final Report, TRAC-TBD, 9 September 2013, Fort Leavenworth, Kansas.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hartley, D. S., III, Quillinan, J. D., and Kruse, K. L. 1990. Phase I Verification and Validation of SIMNET-T, Martin Marietta Energy Systems, Inc., Oak Ridge, TN, K/DSRD-116.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knepell, P. L., and Arangno, D. C. 1993. Simulation Validation: A Confidence Assessment Methodology. IEEE Computer Society Press, Los Alamitos, California.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
