<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90010046</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Original Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Damage mitigation techniques in wind turbine blades</article-title>
            <subtitle>A review</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Shohag</surname>
                  <given-names>Md Abu S</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hammel</surname>
                  <given-names>Emily C</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Olawale</surname>
                  <given-names>David O</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
               <x>
                  <sup>,</sup>
               </x>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Okoli</surname>
                  <given-names>Okenwa I</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>1</sup>High-Performance Materials Institute, FAMU – FSU College of Engineering, Tallahassee, FL, USA</aff>
            <aff id="a2">
               <sup>2</sup>Nanotechnology Patronas Group Inc., Tallahassee, FL, USA</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>June 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>41</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e90010041</issue-id>
         <fpage>185</fpage>
         <lpage>210</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© SAGE Publications Ltd, 2017</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90010046"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>Wind blades are major structural elements of wind turbines, but they are prone to damage like any other composite component. Blade damage can cause sudden structural failure and the associated costs to repair them are high. Therefore, it is important to identify the causation of damage to prevent defects during the manufacturing phase, transportation, and in operation. Generally, damage in wind blades can arise due to manufacturing defects, precipitation and debris, water ingress, variable loading due to wind, operational errors, lightning strikes, and fire. Early detection and mitigation techniques are required to avoid or reduce damage in costly wind turbine blades. This article provides an extensive review of viable solutions and approaches for damage mitigation in wind turbine blades.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label>
            <kwd>Wind energy</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>composite</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>wind turbine blade</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>damage</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>mitigation approaches</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">3M™ (2015) Leading edge protection. Available at: http://multimedia.3m.com/mws/media/800189O/3m-wind-erosion-solutions.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdussalam SR (2000) Damage and Fracture Mechanics of Composite Materials. Winnipeg, MB, Canada: University of Manitoba.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adams DOH and Bell SJ (1995) Compression strength reductions in composite laminates due to multiple-layer waviness. Composites Science and Technology 53: 207–212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">American Wind Energy Association (2013) Wind energy conserving water. Available at: http://www.awea.org/wind-and-water</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderson DN and Reich AD (1997) Tests of the Performance of Coatings for Low Ice Adhesion. Washington, DC: National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrawus J, Watson J, Kishk M, et al. (2006) The selection of a suitable maintenance strategy for wind turbines. Wind Engineering 30: 471–486.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ataya S and Ahmed MMZ (2013) Damages of wind turbine blade trailing edge: Forms, location, and root causes. Engineering Failure Analysis 35: 480–488.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Banea MD and Da Silva LFM (2009) Adhesively bonded joints in composite materials: An overview. Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part L: Journal of Materials Design and Applications 223: 1–18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battisti L and Fedrizzi R (2007) 2D numerical simulation of a wind turbine de-icing system, using cycled heating. Wind Engineering 31: 33–42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battisti L, Baggio P and Fedrizzi R (2006) Warm-air intermittent de-icing system for wind turbines. Wind Engineering 30: 361–374.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battisti L, Brighenti A, Dal Savio S, et al. (2005) Evaluation of anti-icing energy and power requirement for wind turbine rotors in cold climates. In: Proceedings of the BOREAS VII conference, Finnish Meteorological Institute (FMI), Saariselka, 7–8 March, p. 13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benzeggagh M and Kenane M (1996) Measurement of mixed-mode delamination fracture toughness of unidirectional glass/epoxy composites with mixed-mode bending apparatus. Composites Science and Technology 56: 439–449.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Black &amp; Veatch (2007) Twenty Percent Wind Energy Penetration in the United States: A Technical Analysis of the Energy Resource. Walnut Creek, CA: Black &amp; Veatch.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bogetti TA, Gillespie JW and Lamontia MA (1994) The influence of ply waviness with nonlinear shear on the stiffness and strength reduction of composite laminates. Journal of Thermoplastic Composite Materials 7: 76–90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boisseau A, Davies P and Thiebaud F (2012) Sea water ageing of composites for ocean energy conversion systems: Influence of glass fibre type on static behaviour. Applied Composite Materials 19: 459–473.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bolotin VV (1996) Delaminations in composite structures: Its origin, buckling, growth and stability. Composites Part B: Engineering 27: 129–145.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Botura G and Fisher K (2003) Development of ice protection system for wind turbine applications. In: Proceedings of the BOREAS VI conference, Finnish Meteorological Institute (FMI), Pyhatunturi, 9–11 April, p. 16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cairns DS, Riddle T and Nelson J (2011) Wind turbine composite blade manufacturing: The need for understanding defect origins, prevalence, implications and reliability. SANDIA report SAND2011-1094, February. Albuquerque, NM: Sandia National Laboratories.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caithness Windfarm Information Forum (2005) Wind turbine accident data to December 31st 2005. Available at: http://www.caithnesswindfarms.co.uk/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Camanho PP, Davila C and De Moura M (2003) Numerical simulation of mixed-mode progressive delamination in composite materials. Journal of Composite Materials 37: 1415–1438.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Canales AG (2008) Evaluation of Bondline Thickness on Wind Turbine Blade Subcomponents. Eindhoven: Sustainable Energy Technology Master Programme, Eindhoven University of Technology.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caselitz P and Giebhardt J (2005) Rotor condition monitoring for improved operational safety of offshore wind energy converters. Journal of Solar Energy Engineering: Transactions of the ASME 127: 253–261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang F-K and Chang K-Y (1987) A progressive damage model for laminated composites containing stress concentrations. Journal of Composite Materials 21: 834–855.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang F-K and Lessard LB (1991) Damage tolerance of laminated composites containing an open hole and subjected to compressive loadings: Part I—Analysis. Journal of Composite Materials 25: 2–43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ciang CC, Lee J-R and Bang H-J (2008) Structural health monitoring for a wind turbine system: A review of damage detection methods. Measurement Science &amp; Technology 19: 122001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cormier L and Joncas S (2010) Effects of cold temperature, moisture and freeze-thaw cycles on the mechanical properties of unidirectional glass fiber-epoxy composites. In: Proceedings of the 51st AIAA/ASME/ASCE/AHS/ASC structures, structural dynamics, and materials conference, Orlando, FL, 12–15 April. Reston, VA: American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Corten GP (2001) Flow separation on wind turbines blades. PhD dissertation, Utrecht University, Utrecht.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Corten GP and Veldkamp HF (2001a) Aerodynamics: Insects can halve wind-turbine power. Nature 412: 41–42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Corten GP and Veldkamp HF (2001b) Insects Cause Double Stall. Petten: Netherlands Energy Research Foundation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dalili N, Edrisy A and Carriveau R (2009) A review of surface engineering issues critical to wind turbine performance. Renewable &amp; Sustainable Energy Reviews 13: 428–438.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davidson BD, Gharibian SJ and Yu L (2000) Evaluation of energy release rate-based approaches for predicting delamination growth in laminated composites. International Journal of Fracture 105: 343–365.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dongsheng L, Siu-Chun MH, Gangbing S, et al. (2015) A review of damage detection methods for wind turbine blades. Smart Materials and Structures 24: 033001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eder MA and Bitsche RD (2015) Fracture analysis of adhesive joints in wind turbine blades. Wind Energy 18: 1007–1022.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eder MA, Bitsche RD, Nielsen M, et al. (2014) A practical approach to fracture analysis at the trailing edge of wind turbine rotor blades. Wind Energy 17: 483–497.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elisa P (2011) Virtual Crack Closure Technique and Finite Element Method for Predicting the Delamination Growth Initiation in Composite Structures. Rijeka: INTECH Open Access Publisher.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eric N and Bayrak M (2015) Wind turbine mass and aerodynamic imbalances determination. International Journal of Engineering Sciences &amp; Research Technology 4(2): 224–233.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eritech (2012) Lightning protection for wind turbine blades. Available at: http://www.chinawind.org.cn/CWP2016/uploadpdf/1141_English.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrar CR and Worden K (2007) An introduction to structural health monitoring. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London Series A: Mathematical, Physical and Engineering Sciences 365: 303–315.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fox TR (2016) Recycling Wind Turbine Blade Composite Material as Aggregate in Concrete. Ames, IA: Industrial and Manufacturing Systems Engineering, Iowa State University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Freebury G and Musial WD (2000) Determining Equivalent Damage Loading for Full-Scale Wind Turbine Blade Fatigue Tests. Golden, CO: National Renewable Energy Laboratory.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Garg AC (1988) Delamination—A damage mode in composite structures. Engineering Fracture Mechanics 29: 557–584.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GCube Insurance Services Inc. (2012) Top 5 wind energy claims. GCube Insurance Services Inc. Available at: http://www.gcubeinsurance.com</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giguere P and Selig MS (1999) Aerodynamic effects of leading-edge tape on airfoils at low Reynolds numbers. Wind Energy 2: 125–136.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Global Wind Energy Council (2014) Global wind report annual market update. Available at: http://www.gwec.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/GWEC_Global_Wind_2014_Report_LR.pdf (accessed June 2015).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gou J, Tang Y, Liang F, et al. (2010) Carbon nanofiber paper for lightning strike protection of composite materials. Composites Part B: Engineering 41: 192–198.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grande JA (2008) Wind power blades energize composites manufacturing. Plastics Technology. Available at: http://www.ptonline.com/articles/wind-power-blades-energize-composites-manufacturing</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Griffin DA and Ashwill TD (2003) Alternative composite materials for megawatt-scale wind turbine blades: Design considerations and recommended testing. Journal of Solar Energy Engineering: Transactions of the ASME 125: 515–521.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gurit (2014) WE Handbook-3- Structural Design. Available at: https://www.coursehero.com/file/p35jefc/Blades-3-Gurit-2014-WE-Handbook-3-Structural-Design-Online-Available/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gurit (2016) Guide to composites. Support Materials. Available at: http://www.gurit.com</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haag M (2013) Advances in leading edge protection of wind turbine blades. In: Proceedings of the EWEA, Vienna, 4–7 February.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hansen P and Martin R (1999) DCB, 4ENF and MMB delamination characterisation of S2/8552 and IM7/8552. DTIC Document. Available at: http://oai.dtic.mil/oai/oai?verb=getRecord&amp;metadataPrefix=html&amp;identifier=ADA368672</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harper PW and Hallett SR (2015) Advanced numerical modelling techniques for the structural design of composite tidal turbine blades. Ocean Engineering 96: 272–283.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hasson D and Hamm M (1992) Effects of Freeze/Thaw Cycles on Hydrostatically Conditioned E-Glass/J-2 Composite. Annapolis, MD: United States Naval Academy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hayman B (2007) Approaches to damage assessment and damage tolerance for FRP sandwich structures. Journal of Sandwich Structures &amp; Materials 9: 571–596.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hertzberg RW (1989) Deformation and Fracture Mechanics of Engineering Materials. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hogg P (2012) Durability of wind turbine materials in offshore environments. In: Proceedings of the SUPERGEN wind phase 2–4th training seminar, SUPERGEN Wind, Manchester, 1 March.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC) (2002) Wind turbine generator systems–Part 24: Lightning protection. IEC TR 61400-24. Geneva: IEC. Available at: https://webstore.iec.ch/p-preview/info_iec61400-24%7Bed0.0%7Den.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC) (2004) Wind Turbine Generator Systems—Part 1: Safety Requirements. Geneva: IEC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ireland B (2011) Preventive maintenance and troubleshooting techniques for wind turbines. Available at: http://ecmweb.com/content/wind-service</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacob GC, Hoevel B, Pham HQ, et al. (2009) Technical advances in epoxy technology for wind turbine blade composite fabrication. In: Proceedings of the SAMPE fall technical conference, Wichita, KS, 19–22 October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jasinski WJ, Noe SC, Selig MS, et al. (1998) Wind turbine performance under icing conditions. Journal of Solar Energy Engineering: Transactions of the ASME 120: 60–65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jiang WG, Hallett SR, Green BG, et al. (2007) A concise interface constitutive law for analysis of delamination and splitting in composite materials and its application to scaled notched tensile specimens. International Journal for Numerical Methods in Engineering 69: 1982–1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jilbert G and Field J (2000) Synergistic effects of rain and sand erosion. Wear 243: 6–17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johannesson T and Blikstad M (1984) A fractographic study of the delamination process. Technical report, Report from Linkoping Institute of Technology. Linkoping, Sweden.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jungert A (2008) Damage detection in wind turbine blades using two different acoustic techniques. The NDT Database &amp; Journal (NDT). Available at: http://www.ndt.net/article/v13n12/juengert.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karmouch R and Ross GG (2010) Superhydrophobic wind turbine blade surfaces obtained by a simple deposition of silica nanoparticles embedded in epoxy. Applied Surface Science 257: 665–669.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keegan MH, Nash D and Stack M (2013) On erosion issues associated with the leading edge of wind turbine blades. Journal of Physics D: Applied Physics 46: 383001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kelly ES, Ondercin RJ, Detrio JA, et al. (1997) Environmental testing of long-wavelength infrared (LWIR) windows. In: Proceedings of the SPIE 3060: Window and dome technologies and materials V, Orlando, FL, 21 April, pp. 68–75. Bellingham, WA: SPIE.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura S, Sato T and Kosugi K (2003) The effect of anti-icing paint on the adhesion force of ice accretion on a wind turbine blade. In: Proceedings of the BOREAS VI conference, Finnish Meteorological Institute (FMI), Pyhatunturi, 9–11 April, p. 9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kithil R (2008) Case Study of Lightning Damage to Wind Turbine Blade. Louisville, CO: National Lightning Safety Institute. Krueger R (2004) Virtual crack closure technique: History, approach, and applications. Applied Mechanics Reviews 57: 109–143.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref71">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krueger R (2006) Fracture mechanics for composites—State of the art and challenges. In: Proceedings of the NAFEMS Nordic seminar: Prediction and modelling of failure using FEA, Copenhagen; Roskilde, 31 May–1 June.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref72">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kusnick J, Adams DE and Griffith DT (2015) Wind turbine rotor imbalance detection using nacelle and blade measurements. Wind Energy 18: 267–276.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref73">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laakso T and Peltola E (2005) Review on blade heating technology and future prospects. In: Proceedings of the BOREAS VII conference, Saariselka, 7–8 March.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref74">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laakso T, Holttinen H, Ronsten G, et al. (2003) State-of-the-art of wind energy in cold climates. International Energy Agency (IEA) Wind Annex XIX, p. 53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref75">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laasko T, Ronsten G, Tallhaug L, et al. (2005) Wind energy projects in cold climates. International Energy Agency (IEA) Wind Annex XIX, p. 37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref76">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Larsen FM and Sorensen T (2003) New lightning qualification test procedure for large wind turbine blades. In: Proceedings of the international conference on lightning and static electricity, Blackpool, 16–19 September.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref77">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee J and Yee AF (2000) Role of inherent matrix toughness on fracture of glass bead filled epoxies. Polymer 41: 8375–8385.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref78">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee J and Yee AF (2001) Inorganic particle toughening I: Micro-mechanical deformations in the fracture of glass bead filled epoxies. Polymer 42: 577–588.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref79">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin K-F and Shieh Y-D (1998) Core-shell particles designed for toughening the epoxy resins. II. Core-shell-particle-toughened epoxy resins. Journal of Applied Polymer Science 70: 2313–2322.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref80">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lindenberg S (2009) 20% Wind Energy by 2030: Increasing Wind Energy’s Contribution to U.S. Electricity Supply. Collingdale, PA: DIANE Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref81">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lord HW and Dutta PK (1988) On the design of polymeric composite structures for cold regions applications. Journal of Reinforced Plastics and Composites 7: 435–458.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref82">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu X, McElroy MB and Kiviluoma J (2009) Global potential for wind-generated electricity. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 106: 10933–10938.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref83">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McGugan M, Pereira G, Sorensen BF, et al. (2015) Damage tolerance and structural monitoring for wind turbine blades. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London A: Mathematical, Physical and Engineering Sciences 373: 20140077.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref84">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Madsen S, Bertelsen K, Krogh T, et al. (2012) Proposal of new zoning concept considering lightning protection of wind turbine blades. Journal of Lightning Research 4: 108–117.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref85">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mahri Z and Rouabah M (2002) Fatigue estimation for a rotating blade of a wind turbine. Revue des energies renouvelables 5: 39–47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref86">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maissan JF (2002) Wind power development in sub-arctic conditions with severe rime icing. Northern Review 24: 174–183.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref87">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Makkonen L (2000) Models for the growth of rime, glaze, icicles and wet snow on structures. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London A: Mathematical, Physical and Engineering Sciences 358: 2913–2939.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref88">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mandell JF and Samborsky DD (1997) DOE/MSU Composite Material Fatigue Database: Test Methods, Materials, and Analysis. Albuquerque, NM: Sandia National Labs.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref89">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mandell JF, Samborsky DD and Cairns DS (2002) Fatigue of Composite Materials and Substructures for Wind Turbine Blades. Albuquerque, NM; Livermore, CA: Sandia National Labs.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref90">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mansson J (2004) Why de-icing of wind turbine blades. In: Proceedings of the global windpower, Chicago, IL, 28–31 March, p. 12. Washington, DC: American Wind Energy Association.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref91">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manwell JF, McGowan JG and Rogers AL (2010) Wind Energy Explained: Theory, Design and Application. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref92">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martin R (1998) Incorporating interlaminar fracture mechanics into design. In: Proceedings of the international conference on designing cost-effective composites, IMechE conference transactions, London, 15–16 September, pp. 83–92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref93">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mayer C (2007) Systeme electrothermique de degivrage pour une pale d’eolienne. Master’s Thesis, UQAR, Rimouski, QC, Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref94">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mayer C, Ilinca A, Fortin G, et al. (2007) Wind tunnel study of electrothermal de-icing of wind turbine blades. International Journal of Offshore and Polar Engineering 17: 182–188.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref95">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miner MA (1945) Cumulative damage in fatigue. Journal of Applied Mechanics 12: 159–164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref96">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naka T, Vasa NJ, Yokoyama S, et al. (2006) Experimental studies on lightning protection design for wind turbine blades. In: Proceedings of the European Wind Energy Association (EWEC), Athens, 27 February–2 March.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref97">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nelson JW, Cairns DS and Riddle TW (2011) Manufacturing defects common to composite wind turbine blades: Effects of defects. In: Proceedings of the AIAA aerospace science meeting, wind energy symposium, Orlando, FL, 4–7 January.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref98">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nelson J, Cairns D, Riddle T, et al. (2012) Composite wind turbine blade effects of defects: Part B—Progressive damage modeling of fiberglass/epoxy laminates with manufacturing induced flaws. In: Proceedings of the 53rd AIAA/ASME/ASCE/AHS/ASC structures, structural dynamics and materials conference, Honolulu, HI, 23–26 April. Reston, VA: American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref99">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NetComposites (2011) Polyurethane composite technology for wind turbine blades. Available at: http://netcomposites.com/news/2011/decemeber/13/polyurethane-composite-technology-for-wind-turbine-blades/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref100">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Niebsch J (2011) Determination of Rotor Imbalances. Rijeka: INTECH Open Access Publisher.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref101">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Niebsch J, Ramlau R and Nguyen TT (2010) Mass and aerodynamic imbalance estimates of wind turbines. Energies 3: 696–710.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref102">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Niezrecki C, Avitabile P, Chen J, et al. (2014) Inspection and monitoring of wind turbine blade-embedded wave defects during fatigue testing. Structural Health Monitoring 13: 629–643.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref103">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nijssen RPL and Brondsted P (2013) Chapter 6: Fatigue as a design driver for composite wind turbine blades. In: Nijssen RPL and Brondsted P (eds) Advances in Wind Turbine Blade Design and Materials. Cambridge: Woodhead Publishing, pp. 175–209.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref104">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nilsson J and Bertling L (2007) Maintenance management of wind power systems using condition monitoring systems—Life cycle cost analysis for two case studies. IEEE Transactions on Energy Conversion 22: 223–229.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref105">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O’Brien TK (1982) Characterization of delamination onset and growth in a composite laminate. Damage in Composite Materials, STP 775, January, pp. 140–167. West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref106">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O’Brien TK (1998) Interlaminar fracture toughness: The long and winding road to standardization. Composites Part B: Engineering 29: 57–62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref107">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Okamatsu T and Ochi M (2002) Effect on the toughness and adhesion properties of epoxy resin modified with silyl-crosslinked urethane microsphere. Polymer 43: 721–730.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref108">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pagano N and Schoeppner G (2000) Delamination of polymer matrix composites: Problems and assessment. Comprehensive Composite Materials 2: 433–528.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref109">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pallarol J, Sunden B and Wu Z (2014) On ice accretion for wind turbines and influence of some parameters. In: Amano RS and Sunden B (eds) Aerodynamics of Wind Turbines: Emerging Topics. Southampton: WIT Press, pp. 129–160.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref110">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parent O and Ilinca A (2011) Anti-icing and de-icing techniques for wind turbines: Critical review. Cold Regions Science and Technology 65: 88–96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref111">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patreau V, Morency F and Paraschivoiu I (1998) Analysis of thermal de-icing system for horizontal axis wind turbine blade. In: Proceedings of the BOREAS IV conference, Finnish Meteorological Institute (FMI), Hetta, pp. 222–235.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref112">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pearson RA and Yee AF (1986) Toughening mechanisms in elastomer-modified epoxies. Journal of Materials Science 21: 2475–2488.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref113">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peesapati V, Cotton I, Sorensen T, et al. (2011) Lightning protection of wind turbines—A comparison of measured data with required protection levels. IET Renewable Power Generation 5: 48–57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref114">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peltola E, Laakso T, Antikainen P, et al. (2003) Prevention of icing effects. In: Proceedings of the BOREAS VI conference, Finnish Meteorological Institute (FMI), Pyhatunturi, p. 9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref115">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peng C, Xing S, Yuan Z, et al. (2012) Preparation and anti-icing of superhydrophobic PVDF coating on a wind turbine blade. Applied Surface Science 259: 764–768.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref116">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Portal Energia (2014) Wind turbine accident compilation. Available at: http://www.portal-energia.com/downloads/resumo-acident-esaerogeradores-parques-eolicos.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref117">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Powell S (2011) 3M™ wind blade protection coating W4600. Industrial Marketing Presentation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref118">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rachidi F, Rubinstein M, Montanya J, et al. (2008) A review of current issues in lightning protection of new-generation wind-turbine blades. IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics 55: 2489–2496.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref119">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Radičević BM, Savić MS, Madsen SF, et al. (2012) Impact of wind turbine blade rotation on the lightning strike incidence—A theoretical and experimental study using a reduced-size model. Energy 45: 644–654.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref120">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ragheb M (2009) Fatigue loading wind turbines. Available at: http://mragheb.com/NPRE%20475%20Wind%20Power%20Systems/Fatigue%20Loading%20in%20Wind%20Turbines.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref121">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ramlau R and Niebsch J (2009) Imbalance estimation without test masses for wind turbines. Journal of Solar Energy Engineering: Transactions of the ASME 131: 011010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref122">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ray BC (2005) Freeze–Thaw response of glass–Polyester composites at different loading rates. Journal of Reinforced Plastics and Composites 24: 1771–1776.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref123">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Riddle TW, Cairns DS and Nelson JW (2011) Characterization of manufacturing defects common to composite wind turbine blades: Flaw characterization. In: Proceedings of the 52nd AIAA/ASME/ASCE/AHS/ASC structures, structural dynamics and materials conference, Denver, CO, 4–7 April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref124">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rybicki EF and Kanninen M (1977) A finite element calculation of stress intensity factors by a modified crack closure integral. Engineering Fracture Mechanics 9: 931–938.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref125">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sareen A, Sapre CA and Selig MS (2014) Effects of leading edge erosion on wind turbine blade performance. Wind Energy 17: 1531–1542.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref126">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmitt GF Jr (1968) Polyurethane Coatings for Rain Erosion Protection (DTIC document). Fort Belvoir, VA: Defense Technical Information Center.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref127">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmitt GF (1973) Advanced Rain Erosion Resistant Coating Materials, vol. 18 (Science of Advanced Materials and Process Engineering Series). Society for the Advancement of Material and Process Engineering, pp. 57–75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref128">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seifert H (2003) Technical requirements for rotor blades operating in cold climate. In: Proceedings of the BOREAS VI conference, p. 13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref129">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shohag MAS, Hammel EC, Olawale DO, et al. (2016) Adhesive bond failure monitoring with triboluminescent optical fiber sensor. In: Proceedings of the SPIE 9803: sensors and smart structures technologies for civil, mechanical, and aerospace systems, Las Vegas, NV, 20 March, paper no. 98034Y.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref130">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shokrieh MM and Rafiee R (2006) Simulation of fatigue failure in a full composite wind turbine blade. Composite Structures 74: 332–342.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref131">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Short W, Blair N, Heimiller D, et al. (2003) Modeling the Long-Term Market Penetration of Wind in the United States. Golden, CO: National Renewable Energy Laboratory.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref132">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Slot H, Gelinck E, Rentrop C, et al. (2015) Leading edge erosion of coated wind turbine blades: Review of coating life models. Renewable Energy 80: 837–848.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref133">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smith C (2014) Fires Are Major Cause of Wind Farm Failure, According to New Research (21 July 2014 edition). London: Imperial College London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref134">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Soltani MR, Birjandi AH and Seddighi Moorani M (2011) Effect of surface contamination on the performance of a section of a wind turbine blade. Scientia Iranica 18: 349–357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref135">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Song G, Li H, Gajic B, et al. (2013) Wind turbine blade health monitoring with piezoceramic-based wireless sensor network. International Journal of Smart and Nano Materials 4: 150–166.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref136">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sorensen BF, Jorgensen E, Debel CP, et al. (2004) Improved design of large wind turbine blade of fiber composites based on studies of scale effects (phase 1). Summary report, Riso-R-1390(EN), September. Roskilde: Riso National Laboratory.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref137">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spera D (1994) Wind Turbine Technology. New York: ASME Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref138">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Springer GS (1976) Erosion by Liquid Impact. New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref139">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Starr S (2010) Turbine fire protection. Wind Systems. Available at: http://www.windsystemsmag.com/article/detail/136/turbine-fire-protection</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref140">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sue HJ, Bertram JL, Garcia-Meitin EI, et al. (1994) Fracture behavior of core-shell rubber-modified crosslinkable epoxy thermoplastics. Colloid and Polymer Science 272: 456–466.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref141">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sultan JN and McGarry FJ (1973) Effect of rubber particle size on deformation mechanisms in glassy epoxy. Polymer Engineering and Science 13: 29–34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref142">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundaresan M, Schulz M and Ghoshal A (2002) Structural health monitoring static test of a wind turbine blade. Subcontract report NREL/SR-500-28719, March. Golden, CO: National Renewable Energy Laboratory.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref143">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sutherland HJ (1999) On the Fatigue Analysis of Wind Turbines. Livermore, CA; Albuquerque, NM: Sandia National Labs.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref144">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sutherland HJ and Mandell JF (2004) Effect of mean stress on the damage of wind turbine blades. Journal of Solar Energy Engineering: Transactions of the ASME 126: 1041–1049.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref145">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tammelin B and Santti K (1994) Effect of rime accretion on wind energy production in the top areas of fells. In: Proceedings of the II BOREAS conference, Finnish Meteorological Institute (FMI), Pyhatunturi, pp. 265–275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref146">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tammelin B, Bohringer A, Cavaliere M, et al. (2000) Wind energy production in cold climate (WECO). Final report, Finnish Meteorological Institute, Helsinki, 1 January 1996–31 December 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref147">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tay TE (2003) Characterization and analysis of delamination fracture in composites: An overview of developments from 1990 to 2001. Applied Mechanics Reviews 56: 1–32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref148">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tay TE, Tan VBC and Tan SHN (2005) Element-failure: An alternative to material property degradation method for progressive damage in composite structures. Journal of Composite Materials 39: 1659–1675.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref149">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Uadiale S, Urban E, Carvel R, et al. (2014) Overview of problems and solutions in fire protection engineering of wind turbines. Fire Safety Science 11: 983–995 (also published in Proceedings of the 11th symposium on International Association for Fire Safety Science).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref150">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">US Department of Energy (2015) Wind Vision: A New Era for Wind Power in the United States. Washington, DC: US Department of Energy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref151">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang L (2001) Effects of in-plane fiber waviness on the properties of composite materials. MS Thesis, Department of Chemical Engineering, Montana State University, Bozeman, MT.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref152">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weis TM and Maissan J (2003) The Effects of Black Blades on Surface Temperatures for Wind Turbines. Pembina Institute, Universite du Quebec a Rimouski.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref153">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wilcox B and White E (2015) Computational analysis of insect impingement patterns on wind turbine blades. Wind Energy19: 483–495.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref154">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">WindAction (2012) Industrial wind action. Available at: http://www.windaction.org/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref155">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yokoyama S (2013) Lightning protection of wind turbine blades. Electric Power Systems Research 94: 3–9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
