<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830853</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830857</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE POTENTIAL FOR FINANCIAL SAVINGS IN RURAL MOZAMBICAN HOUSEHOLDS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Oliveira</given-names>
                  <surname>Amimo</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Donald W.</given-names>
                  <surname>Larson</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Mauricio</given-names>
                  <surname>Bittencourt</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Douglas H.</given-names>
                  <surname>Graham</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2004</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>157</fpage>
         <lpage>178</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830857"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Many policy makers and businesses erroneously believe that rural populations, particularly in Africa, have no margin for savings over consumption needs. This study examines the potential for financial savings in rural Mozambican households by looking at the determinants of savings behavior. An econometric model for a household's saving behavior was estimated using data from 113 rural households from Nampula province in Mozambique. Results indicate that income, physical wealth, household size, and years of schooling affect a household's savings behavior. The results of this study show evidence of a high potential for household financial savings in rural areas of Mozambique. The study also finds that Mozambican rural households use their own grassroots associations for many financial services due to the lack of access to formal financial intermediaries. The study concludes that existing economic and financial policies have led to the neglect of the mobilization of savings in general and in rural areas in particular. More specifically, rural households do not have adequate opportunity to save with formal financial intermediaries. Financial policy reform is needed to increase domestic savings for development and to reduce the country's dependence on foreign donor funds.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d8e180a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e187" publication-type="other">
Amimo (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e194a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e201" publication-type="other">
Studenmund, 1985</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d8e217a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e221" publication-type="other">
Adams, D.W, D.H. Graham, and J.D. Von Pischke (1984). Undermining Rural Development with Cheap Credit.
Boulder, Colorado: Westview Press Inc.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e231a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e235" publication-type="other">
Amimo, O. (1999). "The Potential For Financial Savings In Rural Mozambican Households: Demand And Supply
Side Determinants." Unpublished M. S. Thesis. The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e245a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e249" publication-type="other">
Benfica, R. (1998). "Analysis of the Contribution of Micro and Small Enterprises to Rural Household Income in
Central and Northern Mozambique." Unpublished M. S. Thesis. Department of Agricultural Economics, Michigan State
University, East Lansing, Michigan.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e262a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e266" publication-type="other">
Berthelemy, J.C. and L. Soderling (2001). "The Role of Capital Accumulation, Adjustment and Structural Change for
Economic Take-Off: Empirical Evidence from African Growth Episodes." World Development. Vol. 29, No 2, pp. 323-344.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e277a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e281" publication-type="other">
Carboni, O.A. (2001). "Financial and Monetary Aspects in the Process of Economic Recovery: the Case of Mozambique."
African Review of Money Finance and Banking. A supplementary issue of Savings and Development, pp. 5-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e291a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e295" publication-type="other">
Charlier, F. and Charles N'cho oguie (2002). "The Impact of Interest Rate Liberalization: Empirical Evidence from
Sub-Saharan Africa." Savings and Development. Vol. XXVI, Issue 4, pp. 355-380.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e305a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e309" publication-type="other">
Chenery, H.B. and Eckstein, P. (1970). "Development Alternatives for Latin America." Key Problems of Economic
Policy in Latin America. Journal of Political Economy. Vol.78. No. 4, pp. 966-1006.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e319a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e323" publication-type="other">
Chidzero, A.M, C. F. Lassimo, H. Hunguana and C. Cuevas (1998). "Mozambique Microfinance Study",
Commissioned by INDER, Banco de Mozambique and Ministry of Plan and Finance, Maputo, Mozambique.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e333a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e337" publication-type="other">
DeH'Amore, G. (1977). "Household Propensity to Save: The Pre-Requisites." In Mobilization of Household Savings,
A Tool for Development. Arnaldo Mauri (ed.). Milan: Cassa di Risparmio delle Provincie Lombarde.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e347a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e351" publication-type="other">
Dellien, H. (1997). "Household Savings and Deposits in Rural Honduras." Unpublished M. S. Thesis. Department
of Agricultural Economics and Rural Sociology; The Ohio State University. Columbus, Ohio.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e362a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e366" publication-type="other">
Edwards, S. (1996). "Why are Latin America's Savings Rates So Low? An International Comparison." Journal of
Development Economics. Vol. 51, Issue 1, pp.5-44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e376a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e380" publication-type="other">
Faruqee, H. and A.M. Husain (1998). "Savings trends in Southeast Asia: A Cross Country Analysis." Asian
Economic Journal. Vol 12, Issue 3, September, pp.195-217.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e390a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e394" publication-type="other">
Fernando, N. A. (1991). "Mobilizing Rural Savings in Papua-New-Guinea - Myths, Realities, and Needed Policy
Reforms." Developing Economies. Vol. 29, No. 1, pp. 44-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e404a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e408" publication-type="other">
Fry, M. J. (1978). "Money and Capital of Financial Deepening in Economic Development." Journal of Money, Credit
and Banking. Vol.10, No.4, pp. 464-475.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e418a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e422" publication-type="other">
Gonzalez-Vega, C. (1984). "Credit Rationing Behavior of Agricultural Lenders. The Iron Law of Interest-Rate
Restrictions." In D. W. Adams, D. H. Graham and J. D. Von Pischke (eds.) Undermining Rural Development with Cheap
Credit, (pp. 78-95) Boulder: Westview Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e435a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e439" publication-type="other">
Graham, D. H. and A. A. Francisco da Silva (1993)." The Banco Popular de Desenvolvimento (BPD) and Formal-
Informal Financial Market Linkages in Maputo, Mozambique." Report to the USAID Maputo mission. The Ohio State
University, Columbus, Ohio.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e453a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e457" publication-type="other">
Kabongo, K. (1991). "Demand for Financial Services by Members of Credit Unions in Zaire." Unpublished M.S.
Thesis. Department of Agricultural Economics and Rural Sociology. The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e467a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e471" publication-type="other">
Khalily, A. B. (1987). "Determinants of Rural Deposit Behavior in Developing Countries: The Bangladesh Case."
Unpublished Master's Thesis, Department of Agricultural Economics and Rural Sociology, The Ohio State University,
Columbus, Ohio.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e484a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e488" publication-type="other">
Larson, D. W., F. Zaqueu and D. H. Graham. (1994). "Why Users Prefer Informal Financial Market Services: The
Case of Mozambique." Selected Paper Presented at the XXII Conference of the International Association of Agricultural
Economists (IAAE), Harare, Zimbabwe.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e501a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e505" publication-type="other">
Leite, S. P. and D. Makonnen. (1986). "Saving and Interest Rates in the BCEAO (West African Central Bank)
Countries: An Empirical Analysis." Savings and Development. Vol. 10, No.3, pp. 219-232.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e515a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e519" publication-type="other">
Mauri, A.(1977). "A Policy to Mobilize Rural Savings in Less Developed Countries." Savings and Development, Vol.
1. No. 1, pp. 14-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e529a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e533" publication-type="other">
Mauri, A.(1983). "The Potential for Savings and Financial Innovation in Africa." Savings and Development. Vol. 7.
No. 4, pp. 319-337.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e544a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e548" publication-type="other">
McKinnon, R. I. (1973). Money and Capital in Economic Development. Washington D.C.:The Brookings Institution.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e555a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e559" publication-type="other">
Meyer, R. and A. Alicbusan (1984). "The Farm-Household Heterogeneity and Rural Financial Markets: Insights
from Thailand." In D.W Adams, D. H. Graham and J.D. Von Pischke (eds.), Undermining Rural Development with Cheap
Credit, (pp. 22-35) Boulder, Colorado: Westview Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e572a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e576" publication-type="other">
Mikesell, R. J. and J. E. Zinser (1973). "The Nature of the Savings Function in Developing Countries: A Survey of
the Theoretical and Empirical Literature." The Journal of Economic Literature. Vol. 11, No.1, pp. 1-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e586a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e590" publication-type="other">
Mohsin, H. A. (2002). "The Impact of the Age Structure of Population on the Household Saving Rate in Pakistan:
a Cointegration Approach." Savings and Development. Vol. XXVI, Issue 3, pp. 289-300.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e600a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e604" publication-type="other">
Oladeji, S. I. and I. O Ogunrinola (2001). "Determinants of Informal Savings in South-Western Nigeria." Savings
and Development. Vol. XXV, Issue 2, pp. 225-235.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e614a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e618" publication-type="other">
Patten, R.H. and J.H. Rosengard (1991). Progress with Profits: The Development of Rural Banking in Indonesia.
San Francisco: International Center for Economic Growth and the Harvard Institute for International Development.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e629a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e633" publication-type="other">
Robinson, M.S. (1994). "Savings Mobilization and Microenterprise Finance: The Indonesian Experience." In The New
World of Microenterprise Finance. Maria Otero and Elisabeth Rhyne (edts.) West Hartford, Connecticut: Kumarian Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e643a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e647" publication-type="other">
Smith, D.(2001). "International Evidence on How Income Inequality and Credit Market Imperfections Affect Private
Savings Rates." Journal of Development Economics Vol 64, Issue 1, February, pp. 103-127.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e657a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e661" publication-type="other">
Studenmund, A.H. (1985). Using Econometrics: A Practical Guide. Occidental College: Harper Collins Publisher.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e668a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e672" publication-type="other">
Traore, N. (1989). "Demand for Deposit Services by Rural Households in Togo." Unpublished M.S. Thesis.
Department of Agricultural Economics and Rural Sociology. The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e682a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e686" publication-type="other">
Vasquez, A., (1986). "Determinants of Household Deposit Behavior in The Dominican Republic." Unpublished
M.S. Thesis, Department of Agricultural Economics and Rural Sociology. The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e696a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e700" publication-type="other">
Vogel, R.C., and P. Burkett. (1986). "Deposit Mobilization in Developing Countries: The Importance of Reciprocity
in Lending." The Journal of Developing Areas. Vol. 20, pp. 425-437.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e711a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e715" publication-type="other">
Wai, U.T. (1972). Financial Intermediaries by Individuals and National Savings in Developing Countries. New York:
Praeger Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e725a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e729" publication-type="other">
Ziorklui, Sam Q. and William Barbee, Jr. (2003). "Financial Sector Reform and Financial Savings in Sub-Saharan
Africa: The Case of Ghana." Savings and Development. Vol. XXVII, Issue 1, pp. 63-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


