<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26168963</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Electrical Bus Performance Modeling for Urban Environments</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Perrotta</surname>
                  <given-names>Deborah</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>MIT-Portugal</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Teixeira</surname>
                  <given-names>Alexandre</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>CEIIA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Silva</surname>
                  <given-names>Helena</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>CEIIA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ribeiro</surname>
                  <given-names>Bernardo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>CEIIA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Afonso</surname>
                  <given-names>Joao</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Minho</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>June 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26168958</issue-id>
         <fpage>34</fpage>
         <lpage>45</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26168963"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Electric vehicles are seen as a key driver to address the issue of global warming, mainly through their zero tailpipe emissions operation and energy efficiency improvements. However, this does not solve the problem of urban chaos, related to traffic congestion and parking space cluttering, which contribute to increase human stress and overall economic productivity decrease. To address all these issues, electric urban buses come as an obvious solution, and they also have the advantages of being quieter than regular buses and of promoting a better travel experience to passengers.</p>
            <p>Nowadays there are already electric buses operating in some parts of the world and one of the main concerns is their high weight, which is mainly due to the amount of batteries they carry in order to have an adequate range. Several strategies are possible and are being tested to provide buses with adequate operability in terms of range: battery swapping at central stations, battery charging at central stations on slow or fast charge rates and sizing the battery pack to the route of the electric bus using fast charge on bus stops.</p>
            <p>This paper intends to provide a mathematical model for the electric bus powertrain and its routes, based on a created driving cycle that simulates an acceleration and deceleration period between two stops of a bus. The main objective is to verify how much of the energy recovered from regenerative braking can be absorbed by lithium-ion batteries and to verify whether the supercapacitors can excel the batteries for this purpose. The intent is to reduce the amount of batteries carried, in the attempt to increase the bus efficiency by optimizing regenerative braking capabilities and possibly reduce overall system weight.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gee, G. C. and Takeuchi, D. T., “Traffic stress, vehicular burden and ell-being: a multilevel analysis.,” Social science &amp; medicine (1982), ol. 59, no. 2, pp. 405-414, Jul. 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gakenheimer, R., “Urban mobility in the developing world,” ransportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice, vol. 33, no. 7-8, p. 671-689, Nov. 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Eurostat - Motorisation Rate.” [Online]. Available: http://pp.eurostat.ec.europa.eu/tgm/table.do? ab=table&amp;init=1&amp;plugin=1&amp;language=en&amp;pcode=tsdpc340. [Accessed: 08-Sep-2011].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Unger, N. et al., “Attribution of climate forcing to economic sectors,” roceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of merica, vol. 107, no. 8, pp. 3382-7, Feb. 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pope, C. A., Ezzati, M., and Dockery, D. W., “Fine-particulate air ollution and life expectancy in the United States.,” The New England ournal of medicine, vol. 360, no. 4, pp. 376-86, Jan. 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Advantages, E. B., “Electric Buses : Green Public Transport or THE ublic Transport?,” Enviro: News and Business, p. 2, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sinautec,, “Sinautec Automobile Technologies L.L.C.” [Online]. vailable: http://www.sinautecus.com/index.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Altairnano,, “Altairnano.” [Online]. Available: http://ww.altairnano.com/. [Accessed: 29-Mar-2011].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Proterra,, “Proterra.” [Online]. Available: http://www.proterra.com/ndex.php. [Accessed: 31-Mar-2011].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cikanek, S. R. and Bailey, K. E., “Regenerative braking system for a ybrid electric vehicle,” Proceedings of the 2002 American Control onference (IEEE Cat. No.CH37301), pp. 3129-3134, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chu, A. and Braatz, P., “Comparison of commercial supercapacitors and igh-power lithium-ion batteries for power-assist applications in hybrid lectric vehicles I. Initial characterization,” Journal of Power Sources, ol. 112, no. 1, pp. 236-246, Oct. 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malcolm, E. M. D. Weiss, A., Heywood, John B. and Schafer, F. F. A. ndreas, “ON THE ROAD IN 2020 - A life-cycle analysis of new utomobile technologies,” 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. C. of M. of T. (ECMT) Organisation for Economic Co-operation and evelopment (OECD), “Speed Management,” 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. S. C. and A. G. N. Homero F. Oliveira, Gonçalves, Mirian B., “Development of a Computational System to Determine the Optimal us-stop Spacing in order to Minimize the Travel Time of All assengers,” in Logistics Dynamics - Second International Conference, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ehsani, M., Rahman, K. M., and Toliyat, H. a., “Propulsion system esign of electric and hybrid vehicles,” IEEE Transactions on Industrial lectronics, vol. 44, no. 1, pp. 19-27, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Larminie, J. and Lowry, J., Electric Vehicle Technology Explained. John iley &amp; Sons Ltd, 2003, pp. 62; 183-186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gillespie, T., “Fundamentals of Vehicle Dynamics,” SAE International, arrendale, PA, ISBN 978-1-56091-199-9, 1992. doi:10.4271/R-114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Maxwell Technologies.” [Online]. Available: http://ww.maxwell.com. [Accessed: 20-Sep-2011].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Conway, Brian E., Electrochemical supercapacitors: scientific undamentals and technological applications, 1st ed. Springer, 1999, p. 736.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnet, B. J. and Haines, L. P., “High power DC-to-DC converter for upercapacitors,” IEMDC 2001. IEEE International Electric Machines nd Drives Conference (Cat. No.01EX485), pp. 985-990, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Faggioli, E., Rena, P., Danel, V., Andrieu, X., Mallant, R., and Kahlen, ., “Supercapacitors for the energy management of electric vehicles,” ournal of Power Sources, vol. 84, no. 2, pp. 261-269, Dec. 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Camara, M. B., Gualous, H., Gustin, F., Berthon, A., and Dakyo, B., “DC / DC Converter Design for Supercapacitor and Battery Power anagement in Hybrid Vehicle Applications - Polynomial Control trategy,” vol. 57, no. 2, pp. 587-597, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grbovi, P. J., Member, S., Delarue, P., Le, P., and Member, M., “Modelling and Control of the Ultra-Capacitor Based Regenerative ontrolled Electric Drives,” 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“STCP - Sociedade de Transportes Colectivos do Porto, SA.” [Online]. vailable: http://www.stcp.pt. [Accessed: 25-Sep-2011].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
