<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277901</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Multi-Plane Airflow Measurements in the Cylinder of a Tumble Based Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pitcher</surname>
                  <given-names>Graham</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lotus Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>October 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277873</issue-id>
         <fpage>1945</fpage>
         <lpage>1952</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277901"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The tumble flow in modern spark ignition engines is assuming an evermore important role for fuel guiding, air/fuel mixing and the generation of turbulence kinetic energy to enhance the combustion process. This paper describes results obtained with laser Doppler anemometry in multiple vertical planes in the cylinder of a motored, tumble flow engine and looks at the post processed data in terms of tumble ratios and mean and turbulence kinetic energies.</p>
            <p>The tumble results indicate very different flow fields in parallel planes lying in the main tumble direction, showing the complex nature of the flows in the cylinder. A simple method of integrating the tumble ratios from the different planes is suggested, leading to a tumble ratio more in line with those expected from an integrated method of measuring tumble, albeit these results are crank angle dependent. The tumble in a perpendicular plane shows unexpected asymmetries and values for the tumble.</p>
            <p>The kinetic energy data shows evidence of a decaying mean kinetic energy contributing to the turbulence kinetic energy and is most obvious in plots of the percentage of total kinetic energy contained in the turbulence component of the energy. The mean kinetic energy also suggests that the asymmetries observed in the tumble in the cross tumble plane are likely to be due to the positions of the counter rotating vortices, rather than the magnitude of the velocities in these vortices.</p>
            <p>One of the major conclusions from this piece of work is that a simple integrated tumble ratio is unlikely to yield much information on the expected engine performance given the complex nature of the in-cylinder flows.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Middendorf H., Krebs R., Szengel R., Pott E., Fleiss M. and Hagelstein D., Volkswagen introduces the worlds first double charge direct injection petrol engine, 14th Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug- und Motorentechnik, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boccadoro Y., Tranchant O., Pionnier R. and Engelhardt H., The new Renault TCe 1.2l turbocharged gasoline engine, 28th Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boccadoro Y., Kermanc'h L., Siauve L. and Vincent J., The new Renault TCe 130 1.4l turbocharged gasoline engine, 30th Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Szengel R., Middendorf H., Pott E., Theobald J., Etzrodt T. and Krebs R., The TSI with 88kW - the expansion of the Volkswagen fanily of fuel-efficient gasoline engines, 28th Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pitcher G., Wigley G., Stansfield P. and Villatoro A., The Effect of Early Inlet Valve Closing on Combustion within a Direct Injection Spark Ignition Engine, 7th International Conference on Modeling and Diagnostics for Advanced Engine Systems, COMODIA, Sapporo, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stansfield P. The Control of an Unthrottled Homogeneous DISI Engine Through Reduced Intake Lift and Duration - A Study of the In-cylinder Flows and Charge Formation, Doctoral Thesis, Loughborough University, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kessler F., Sonntag E., Schopp J., Simionesco L., Keribin P. and Bordes F., The new family of small 4 cylinder engines from BMW/PSA co-operation, 15th Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug- und Motorentechnik, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pitcher G. and Wigley G., A Comparison between In-cylinder Steady Flow and Motored Engine Air Velocities Using LDA, 16th Int. Symp. on Applications of Laser Techniques to Fluid Mechanics Lisbon, Portugal, 09-12 July, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bücker, I., Karhoff, D., Klaas, M., and Schröder, W., “Engine In-Cylinder Flow Control via Variable Intake Valve Timing,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0055, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0055.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allen J., Simms A., Williams P., Hergrave G. and Wigley G., An Advanced Optically Accessed Single Cylinder Research and Development Engine for Fuel/Air Mixing and Combustion Diagnostics, JSAE 9935086, Seoul, Korea, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
