<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277837</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Secondary Fuel Injection Characterization of a Diesel Vaporizer for Active DPF Regeneration</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hein</surname>
                  <given-names>Eric</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kotrba</surname>
                  <given-names>Adam</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Inclan</surname>
                  <given-names>Tobias</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bright</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrew</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Tenneco</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>August 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277829</issue-id>
         <fpage>1228</fpage>
         <lpage>1234</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277837"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Secondary fuel injection is applied to facilitate active soot management of the particulate filter within diesel aftertreatment systems, avoiding concerns with fuel delivery via in-cylinder post-injection. System performance is dependent on the thermo-fluid interactions of the injected fuel with the exhaust stream, with the intent of having more fully vaporized fuel and a well-mixed air-fuel mixture at the inlet of the oxidation catalyst for uniform thermal distribution as it exothermically reacts. Pre-heating the fuel with a diesel vaporizer prior to its delivery into the exhaust enables improved system performance, reducing droplet sizes and mixing demands. A diesel vaporizer is applied within the exhaust of a medium duty truck application, and the response of the catalyst is characterized across a variety of conditions. Cross-sectional measurements at the catalyst and filter outlet are described, including gas velocity, temperature, and HC concentration, and the effect of poor fuel vaporization is demonstrated. The system is installed in a medium-duty truck with a 4.8L engine and characterized on a chassis dynamometer across various steady-state and transient conditions. Performance is measured while applying closed loop fuel dosing control algorithms, demonstrating control capabilities similar to injectors. Adequate thermal distribution is achieved with minimal HC slip, and recommendations are offered to further demonstrate system integration benefits and risks of diesel vaporizers.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T., “Vehicular Emissions in Review,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):699-715, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0538.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kotrba, A., Gardner, T., Bai, L., and Yetkin, A., “Passive Regeneration Response Characteristics of a DPF System,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0520, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0520.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kotrba, A., Bai, L., Yetkin, A., Shotwell, R. et al., “DPF Regeneration Response: Coupling Various DPFs with a Thermal Regeneration Unit to Assess System Behaviors,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-2200, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-2200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kotrba, A., Yetkin, A., Gough, B., Gundogan, A. et al., “Performance Characterization of a Thermal Regeneration Unit for Exhaust Emissions Controls Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2011- 01-2208, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-2208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sampath, M., Zheng, G., and Kotrba, A., “Integration of Diesel Burner for Large Engine Aftertreatment using CFD,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1946, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1946.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, Z., Zheng, G., Shan, X., and Kotrba, A., “CFD Modeling of Mini and Full Flow Burner Systems for Diesel Engine Aftertreatment under Low Temperature Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1949, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1949.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nickolas, S., White, A., Kotrba, A., and Yetkin, A., “Engine Tests of an Active Diesel Particulate Filter Regeneration System,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1089, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1089.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gardner, T., Yetkin, A., Shotwell, R., Kotrba, A. et al., “Evaluation of a DPF Regeneration System and DOC Performance Using Secondary Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2884, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2884.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nagar, N., He, X., Iyengar, V., Acharya, N. et al., “Real Time Implementation of DOC-DPF Models on a Production-Intent ECU for Controls and Diagnostics of a PM Emission Control System,” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 2(2):222-233, 2010, doi:10.4271/2009- 01-2904.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tschoeke, H., Braungarten, G., and Platze, U., “Oil Dilution of a Passenger Car Diesel Engine in Operation with blended Diesel Fuel B10,” Final Report Abstract, Institute of Mobile Systems - Chair of Reciprocating Machines, Magdeburg, Germany, June 4th, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kotrba, R., “Understanding the Post-Injection Problem,” Biodiesel Magazine, April 15, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kotrba, A., Brockman, A., Martin, S., Mikovits, A. et al., “Secondary Fuel Injection Layout Influences on DOC-DPF Active Regeneration Performance,” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 6(2):539-544, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2465.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salanta, G., Zheng, G., Kotrba, A., Rampazzo, R. et al., “Optimization of a Urea SCR System for On-Highway Truck Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1938, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1938.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martin, S., Gehrlein, J., Kotrba, A., and Lacin, F., “Urea SCR System Characterization through Unique Flow Bench Testing,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3471, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01- 3471.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leong, W., Savci, I., Hatton, A., and Scott, J., “On Using a CFD Based Global Kinetic Reaction Model to Simulate Catalyst Exotherm with Exhaust Fuel Dosing Device (Fuel Vaporizer),” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1290, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1290.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alano, E., Amon, B., and Jean, E., “Fuel Vaporizer: Alternative Solution for DPF Regeneration,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01- 0561, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0561.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chiew, L., Kroner, P., and Ranalli, M., “Diesel Vaporizer: An Innovative Technology for Reducing Complexity and Costs Associated with DPF Regeneration,” SAE Technical Paper 2005- 01-0671, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0671.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mayr, A., Klement, J., Ranalli, M., and Schmidt, S., “Diesel Fuel Vaporizer: a Way to Reliable DPF Regeneration,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Friedrich, Ch., Inclán, T., Wilmes, B., Brichzin, V. et al., “Dieselverdampfer zur Partikelfilterregeneration,” MTZ - Motortechnische Zeitschrift, Ausgabe 05/2009: 398-406, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salanta, G., Kotrba, A., Nunan, J., Jacques, J. et al., “A Dual - Reductant HC LNC Approach to Commercial Vehicle Tier 4 Final Solutions,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-2203, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-2203.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gough, B., Kotrba, A., Salanta, G., Popovich, J. et al., “Transient Performance of an HC LNC Aftertreatment System Applying Ethanol as the Reductant,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1957, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1957.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
