<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica, Centre for Financial Assistance to African Countries</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">23024727</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE MALIAN EXPERIENCE IN FINANCING THE CEREALS TRADE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Jonathan</given-names>
                  <surname>Coulter</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1993</year>
         </pub-date>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i23024723</issue-id>
         <fpage>27</fpage>
         <lpage>45</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23024727"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper describes Mali's pioneering attempt to provide financial assistance to the private cereals trade in support of market liberalisation. Since 1987, donor funds have been channelled through local banks to create credit schemes for traders and farmers, the latter organised into Associations Villageoises (or AVs), wishing to engage in procurement and interseasonal storage of cereals. Several mechanisms were used to ensure repayment, particularly obliging traders to pledge their stock by placing it in a licensed warehouse. Out of the five schemes, four for traders and one for AVs, only the AV scheme and that for "semi-wholesale traders" remained by 1992. Only in one year did the amounts loaned have a major impact on aggregate supply and demand. Nevertheless, in many areas the schemes substantially increased farm-gate prices in the immediate post-harvest period, and in certain surplus monoculture areas the AV loans were particularly beneficial to farmers. There have been many difficulties in administering the schemes, and some underlying problems are identified: The lack of mechanisms for managing the lending risk, difficulties in finding reliable warehouse operators, and weaknesses in the AVs. Several useful lessons can be drawn from the experience. Firstly, there is a good case for supporting farmer storage in some cases, but it should not be a generalised prescription. Careful consideration should be given to the needs of farmers assisted in each area, to the type of organisation supported, and to alternative ways of helping them solve their cash-flow problems. Secondly, schemes for funding traders can work where the Government is fully committed to their role in the trading system, but such assistance should be seen as part of a gradual process of marketing improvement. The commitment of participating banks and the existence of reliable warehouse operators are vital pre-conditions to success, and for this reason it is important to involve these parties in the design of the schemes. Cet article décrit la tentative innovative du Gouvernement du Mali dans le domaine d'assistance financière au commerce privé des céréales pour soutenir la libéralisation du marché. Dépuis 1987, des fonds de différents bailleurs ont été acheminé à travers des banques locales pour créer des lignes de crédit aux commerçants et aux paysans intéressés à s'engager dans l'achat et dans le stockage inter-saisonnier de céréales. Les paysans ont dû s'organiser en Associations Villageoises (AVs) pour obtenir les crédits. Des différents mécanismes ont été appliqués pour assurer le remboursement des crédits, surtout en utilisant un système de tierce-détention qui oblige les commerçants à nantir leurs stocks dans un magasin agréé. Parmi les cinq lignes de crédit, dont quatre pour les commerçants et une pour les AVs, en 1992 il n'en restait que deux, cela des AVs et cela des demi-grossistes. Les crédits octroyés ont eu un impact important sur l'ensemble de l'offre et de la demande de céréales seulement pendant une année (celle de 1988/89). Néanmoins, dans beaucoup de zones les projets ont augmenté considérablement les prix aux producteurs immédiatement après la récolte et dans certaines zones de monoculture excédentaire les crédits aux AVs ont été particulièrement bénéficiaires. Il y avait plusieurs difficultés dans la gestion des crédits et quelques problèmes inhérents out pu être identifiés: Le manque de mécanismes pour gérer le risque de prêt, des difficultés de trouver des tiers détenteurs efficaces et des faiblesses dans les AVs. Plusieurs conclusions utiles peuvent être dégagées de cette expérience. Premièrement, dans certains cas l'appui au stockage au niveau des paysans peut être avantageux mais il ne faut pas le prendre en tant que préscription générale. Il est important d'étudier à fond les besoins des villageois assistés, le type d'organisation soutenue et des chemins alternatifs de les aider à resoudre leurs problèmes de trésorerie. Deuxièmement, les lignes de crédit aux commerçants peuvent fonctionner dans le cas où le gouvernement a pris un engagement entier concernant son rôle dans le système de commercialisation. Toutefois, une telle assistance doit être vue dans le contexte d'une amélioration progressive du fonctionnement de la commercialisation. L'engagement des banques participantes et une gestion serieuse des tierce-détention sont des préalables d'un succès et pour cela il est important d'inclure ces agents dans la préparation d'un tel projet.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d43e153a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e157" publication-type="other">
Cebron, D. and Sanogo, O, (1991) Credits PRMC aupres des Groupements villageois et impact sur les marchés
céréaliers; Campagnes de commercialisation 1988/89 et 1989/90. Institut d'Economie Rurale, Bamako,
Mali, 44 pp.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e170a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e174" publication-type="other">
Berg, E (1989) The liberalisation of rice marketing in Madagascar. In: World Development, 17: 719-728.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e181a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e185" publication-type="other">
Coulter, J. and Golob, P (1991) Liberalisation of cereals marketing in Sub-Saharan Africa; implementation is-
sues. Report no. 2: Tanzania-a case study. NRI, Chatham, UK, 46 pp.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e195a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e199" publication-type="other">
Mehta, M. (1989) An analysis of the structure of the cereals market in Mali. Bamako: Secretariat Technique
de la CESA. 179 pp.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
