<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277577</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Wavelet Neural Network Method to Determine Diesel Engine Piston Heat Transfer Boundary Conditions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Du</surname>
                  <given-names>Juan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Wuhan University of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>December 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277559</issue-id>
         <fpage>1740</fpage>
         <lpage>1746</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277577"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper presents a method of calculating temperature field of the piston by using a wavelet neural network (WNN) to identify the unknown boundary conditions. Because of the complexity of the heat transfer and limitations of experimental conditions of heat transfer analysis of the piston in a diesel engine, boundary conditions of the piston temperature field were usually obtained empirically, and thus the result itself was uncertain. By employing the capability of resolution analysis from a wavelet neural network, the method obtains improved boundary heat transfer coefficients with a limited number of measured temperatures. Using FEA software iteratively, results show the proposed wavelet neural network analysis method improves the prediction of unknown boundary conditions and temperature distribution consistent with the experimental data with an acceptable error.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCE</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu, R.S., Lin, F.S., and Zhang, R., “Internal Combustion Engine Heat Transfer and the Heat Load,” Beijing, China, ISBN 7-114-00078-2, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, T.C., Tuan, P.C., “Input estimation method including finiteelement scheme for solving inverse heat conduction problems,” J. Numer. Heat Transfer: Part B: Fundam. 47(3): 277-290, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tseng, A. A., Zhao, F.Z., “Multidimensional inverse transient heat conduction problems by direct sensitivity coefficient method using a finite-element scheme,” J. Numer. Heat Transfer: Part B: Fundam. 29(3):365-380, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dowding, K.J., Beck, J.V., “A Sequential gradient method for the inverse heat conduction problem (IHCP),” J. Heat Transfer Trans. ASME (121): 1503-1517, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hung, C.H., Chen, C.W., “A boundary-element-based inverse problem of estimating boundary conditions in an irregular domain with statistical analysis,” J. Numer. Heat Transfer: Part B: Fundam. 33(2): 251-268, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, S.K., Daniel, I. M., “Solution to inverse heat conduction problem in nanoscale using sequential method,” J. Numer. Heat Transfer: Part B: Fundam. 44(5):439-456, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yusaf, T. Azman, MS, and Hussein, I, “Performance and emission investigation of a four-stroke liquefied petroleum gas spark-ignition engine generator used in a Malaysian night market,” J. Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers: Part A: J. Power and Energy. 224(3) :339-347, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Najafi, G, Ghobadian, B, Tavakoli, T, Buttsworth, DR, Yusaf, Y, and Faizollahnejaad, M. “Performance and exhaust emissions of a gasoline engine with ethanol blended gasoline fuels using artificial neural network,” J. Applied Energy. 86(5) :630-639, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, L.Q., “Artificial Neural Network Theory, Design and Application,” Beijing, China, ISBN 9787502595234, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deng, S., Hwang, Y., “Applying neural networks to the solution of forward and inverse heat conduction problems,” Int. J. Heat and Mass Transfer: 49(25) 4732-4750, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shun, Y.K., “Wavelet Analysis and its Application,” Beijing, China, ISBN 711115876, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qian, Z.Q., Wang, W. H., and Wang, S.D., “Experiment research on temperature measurement of diesel engine's cylinder head by the way of hardness plug,” J. Ship Eng., 27:59-61, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nie, Y.H., Song, Y.S. “Influence of boundary conditions on temperature distribution in the diesel piston,” J. of Jiangsu Univ. of Sci. and Technol. (Natural Science Edition), 23:47-50, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qian, Z.Q., Liu, H.H., Zhang, G.D., and Brown, D.J., “Temperature field estimation for the piston of diesel engine 4112,” J. Lecture Notes in Comput. Sci., 4251:1198-1205, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qian, L., Chen, N., “The experimental research for wall surface temperature effect on heat transfer in internal combustion engine cylinder,” J. Trans. of CSICE, 17: 91-95, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lv, C.Q., Su, T.X., “Effect of cooling oil-antrum position on intensity of diesel engine piston,” J. Intern. Combust. Eng., 1:4-9, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Zhong-Yu, “A Study on the Heat Transfer and the Thermal Intensity of Piston,” Chongqing University, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
