<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277800</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Probing Species Formed by Pilot Injection During Re-Compression in a Controlled Auto-Ignition Engine by H₂CO LIF and Chemiluminescence Imaging</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Huelser</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>RWTH Aachen Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schulz</surname>
                  <given-names>Christian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>RWTH Aachen Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Brands</surname>
                  <given-names>Thorsten</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>RWTH Aachen Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Grunefeld</surname>
                  <given-names>Gerd</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>RWTH Aachen Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Koss</surname>
                  <given-names>Hans-Jürgen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>RWTH Aachen Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Morcinkowski</surname>
                  <given-names>Bastian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>RWTH Aachen Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pischinger</surname>
                  <given-names>Stefan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>RWTH Aachen Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Adomeit</surname>
                  <given-names>Philipp</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277784</issue-id>
         <fpage>772</fpage>
         <lpage>789</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277800"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Pilot injection (PI) during the negative-valve-overlap (NVO) period is one method to improve control of combustion in gasoline controlled auto-ignition engines. This is generally attributed to both chemical and thermal effects. However, there are little experimental data on active species formed by the combusting PI and their effect on main combustion in real engines. Thus, it is the objective of the current study to apply and assess optical in-cylinder diagnostics for these species. Firstly, the occurrence and nature of combustion during the NVO period is investigated by spectrally-resolved multi-species flame luminescence measurements. OH*, CH*, HCO*, CO-continuum chemiluminescence, and soot luminosity are recorded. Secondly, spectrally-, spatially-, and cycle-resolved laser-induced fluorescence measurements of formaldehyde are conducted. It is attempted to find a cycle-resolved measure of the chemical effect of PI. However, not any noticeable correlation between the measured formaldehyde content of the charge and main combustion phasing is observed. This can be explained by the findings that the exhaust gas of the prior cycle and potentially pool fire contribute significantly to the measured formaldehyde content of the charge. Thus, formaldehyde is not a good indicator of the chemical effect of PI on main combustion under these conditions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H., “HCCI and CAI Engines for the Automotive Industry,” Crc Press, Woodhead Publishing Limited, Cambridge, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hübner, W., Gerke, U., Boulouchos, K., Peters, N. et al., “Influence of pilot injection on controlled auto-ignition combustion - A theoretical and experimental study,” Int. Conf. “The Spark Ignition Engine of the Future”, Straßburg, France, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aroonsrisopon, T., Nitz, D., Waldman, J., Foster, D. et al., “A Computational Analysis of Direct Fuel Injection During the Negative Valve Overlap Period in an Iso-Octane Fueled HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0227, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0227.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Waldman, J., Nitz, D., Aroonsrisopon, T., Foster, D. et al., “Experimental Investigation into the Effects of Direct Fuel Injection During the Negative Valve Overlap Period in an Gasoline Fueled HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0219, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berntsson, A. and Denbratt, I., “Optical study of HCCI Combustion using NVO and an SI Stratified Charge,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0012, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-24-0012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berntsson, A., Andersson, M., Dahl, D., and Denbratt, I., “A LIFstudy of OH in the Negative Valve Overlap of a Spark-assisted HCCI Combustion Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0037, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0037.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tongroon, M. and Zhao, H., “Combustion Characteristics of CAI Combustion with Alcohol Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01- 0843, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brassat, A., Thewes, M., Müther, M., Pischinger, S. et al., “Analysis of the Effects of Certain Alcohol and Furan-Based Biofuels on Controlled Auto Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1135, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urushihara, T., Hiraya, K., Kakuhou, A., and Itoh, T., “Expansion of HCCI Operating Region by the Combination of Direct Fuel Injection, Negative Valve Overlap and Internal Fuel Reformation,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0749, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01- 0749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Juretzka, A., “Steuerung der Selbstzündung bei Ottomotoren,” Ph.D. thesis (in German), University of Karlsruhe, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Albin, T., Zweigel, R., Heßeler, F., Morcinkowski, B. et al., “Controlling GCAI (Gasoline Controlled Auto Ignition) in an Extended Operating Map,” ECOSM12 513-520, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kosaka, H., Aizawa, T., and Kamimoto, T., “Two-dimensional imaging of ignition and soot formation processes in a diesel flame,” Int. J. Engine Res. 6(1):1-22, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schießl, R., Schubert, A., and Maas, U., “Temperature Fluctuations in the Unburned Mixture: Indirect Visualisation Based on LIF and Numerical Simulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3338, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3338.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Collin, R., Nygren, J., Richter, M., Aldén, M. et al., “Simultaneous OH- and Formaldehyde-LIF Measurements in an HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3218, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01- 3218.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graf, N., Gronki, J., Schulz, C., Baritaud, T. et al., “In-Cylinder Combustion Visualization in an Auto-Igniting Gasoline Engine using Fuel Tracer- and Formaldehyde-LIF Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1924, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1924.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H., Peng, Z., and Ma, T., “Investigation of the HCCI/CAI Combustion Process by 2-D PLIF Imaging of Formaldehyde,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1901, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1901.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hwang, W., Dec, J., and Sjöberg, M., “Spectroscopic and chemicalkinetic analysis of the phases of HCCI autoignition and combustion for single- and two-stage ignition fuels,” Combust. Flame 154:387- 409, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kohse-Höinghaus, K. and Jeffries, J. B., “Applied combustion diagnostics,” Taylor and Francis, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duret, P., “A New Generation of Two-Stroke Engines for the Future?” Proceedings of the International Seminar, Rueil- Malmaison, France, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brands, T., Hottenbach, P., Koss, H., Grunefeld, G. et al., “Effects of Mixture Stratification on Ignition and Combustion in a GCAI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):in press, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hunicz, J., “An experimental study of negative valve overlap injection effects and their impact on combustion in a gasoline HCCI engine,” Fuel 117:236-250, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2013.09.079.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steeper, R. and Davisson, M., “Analysis of Gasoline Negative- Valve-Overlap Fueling via Dump Sampling,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):in press, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peters, N., personal communication, ITV RWTH Aachen University, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martin, D., “Experimentelle Untersuchungen der innermotorischen Gemischbildung bei variabler Einspritzung,” Ph.D. thesis (in German), RWTH Aachen University, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martin, D., Stratmann, J., Pischke, P., Kneer, R. et al., “Experimental Investigation of the Interaction of MultipleGDI Injections using Laser Diagnostics,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):372- 388, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0596.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adomeit, P., Sehr, A., Weinowski, R., Stapf, K. et al., “Operation Strategies for Controlled Auto Ignition Gasoline Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):164-172, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0300.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cardenas, M., personal communication, WSA RWTH Aachen University, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brackmann, C., Nygren, J., Bai, X., Li, Z. et al., “Laser-induced Fluorescence of Formaldehyde in Combustion Using Third Harmonic Nd:YAG Laser excitation,” Spectrochim. Acta A 59:3347- 3356, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olofsson, J., Richter, M., Aldén, M., and Augé, M., “Development of High Temporally and Spatially (Three-Dimensional) Resolved Formaldehyde Measurements in Combustion Environments,” Rev. Sci. Instrum. 77:013104, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Metz, T., Bai, X., Ossler, F., and Alden, M., “Fluorescence Lifetimes of Formaldehyde (H2CO) in the A1A2 -&gt; X1A1 Band System at Elevated Temperature and Pressures,” Spectrochim. Acta A 60:1043-1053, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Snyder, J., Dronniou, N., Dec, J., and Hanson, R., “PLIF Measurements of Thermal Stratification in an HCCI Engine under Fired Operation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1669-1688, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1291.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thirouard, B., Cherel, J., and Knop, V., “Investigation of Mixture Quality Effect on CAI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01- 0141, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0141.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weikl, M., Beyrau, F., and Leipertz, A., “Simultaneous Temperature and Exhaust-Gas Recirculation-Measurements in a Homogeneous Charge-Compression Ignition Engine by Use of Pure Rotational Coherent Anti-Stokes Raman Spectroscopy,” Appl. Optics 45(15):3646-3651, 2006, doi:10.1364/AO.45.003646.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals,” McGraw-Hill, p. 92-99 and p. 572-577, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahnz, C. and Spicher, U., “Irregular combustion in supercharged spark ignition engines - pre-ignition and other phenomena,” Int. J. Engine Res. 11:485-498, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lemel, M., Hultqvist, A., Vressner, A., Nordgren, H. et al., “Quantification of the Formaldehyde Emissions from Different HCCI Engines Running on a Range of Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3724, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3724.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urata, Y., Awasaka, M., Takanashi, J., Kakinuma, T. et al., “A Study of Gasoline-fuelled HCCI Engine Equipped with an Electromagnetic Valve Train,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1898, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1898.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zigler, B., Keros, P., Helleberg, K., Fatouraie, M. et al., “An experimental investigation of the sensitivity of the ignition and combustion properties of a single-cylinder research engine to spark-assisted HCCI,” Int. J. Engine Res. 12(4):353-375, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anders, H., Christensen, M., Johansson, B., Franke, A. et al., “A Study of the Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Combustion Process by Chemiluminescence Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3680, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3680.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guethe, F., Guyot, D., Singla, G., Noiray, N. et al., “Chemiluminescence as diagnostic tool in the development of gas turbines,” Appl. Phys. B 107:619-636, 2012, doi:10.1007/s00340- 012-4984-y.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, J. and Santavicca, D., “Experimental Diagnostics for the Study of Combustion Instabilities in Lean Premixed Combustors,” J. Prop. Power 19(5):735-750, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smith, J. J., Schneider, G., Suslov, D., Oschwald, M. et al., “Steady-State High Pressure LOx/H2 Rocket Engine Combustion,” Aerosp. Sci. Technol. 11:39-47, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kojima, J., Ikeda, Y., and Nakajima, T., “Spatially resolved Measurement of OH*, CH*, and C2* Chemiluminescence in the Reaction Zone of laminar Methane/Air premixed Flames,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 28:1757-1767, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merola, S. S. and Vaglieco, B. M., “Optical Investigation of Fuel Deposition Burning in Ported Fuel Injection (PFI) Spark-Ignition (SI) Engine,” Energy 34:2108-2115, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, C., Zhao, H., and Megaritis, T., “In-Cylinder Studies of CAI Combustion with Negative Valve Overlap and Simultaneous Chemiluminescence Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01- 1103, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuwahara, K. and Ando, H., “Diagnostics of in-cylinder flow, mixing and combustion in gasoline engines,” Meas. Sci. Technol. 11:95- 111, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weiser, V. and Eisenreich, N., “Fast Emission Spectroscopy for a Better Understanding of Pyrotechnic Combustion Behavior,” Propell. Explos. Pyrot. 30 (1):67, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cheng, A. S. E., Fisher, B. T., Martin, G. C., and Mueller, C. J., “Effects of Fuel Volatility on Early Direct-Injection, Low- Temperature Combustion in an Optical Diesel Engine,” Energ. Fuel. 24:1538-1551, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cao, L., Zhao, H., and Jiang, X., “Investigation into Controlled Auto-Ignition Combustion in a GDI Engine with Single and Split Fuel Injections,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0211, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0211.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrews, G. E., Daham, B., Mmolawa, M. D., Boulter, S. et al., “FTIR Investigations of Toxic Gases in Air Starved Enclosed Fires,” Fire Safety Science - Proceedings of the Eighth International Symposium, Beijing, China, 1035-1046, (2005).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
