<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277551</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development and Validation of a Pt-Pd Diesel Oxidation Catalyst Model</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Watling</surname>
                  <given-names>Timothy C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ahmadinejad</surname>
                  <given-names>Mehrdad</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ţuţuianu</surname>
                  <given-names>Monica</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johansson</surname>
                  <given-names>Åsa</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Paterson</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael A.J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Johnson Matthey, Emission Control Technologies</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>1420</fpage>
         <lpage>1442</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277551"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The Diesel Oxidation Catalyst (DOC) is an important technology for the removal of CO and hydrocarbons (HC) from the exhaust of diesel engines, as well as for generating exotherms for active regeneration, and for producing NO₂ used by downstream components.</p>
            <p>This paper describes the development of a one-dimensional numerical model for a Pt-Pd DOC for use in designing aftertreatment systems. The model is based on kinetics developed from laboratory microreactor data. The model is a significant advance over previous DOC models we have developed. A much larger experimental matrix was used enabling the kinetics and inhibition effects to be much better defined. The experiments included rich conditions enabling the model to be used in NO<sub>X</sub>trap systems, where the exhaust becomes rich during regeneration. Reduction of NO₂ to NO by CO and HC has been included in the model. As well as converting NO₂ entering the DOC, this reaction prevents NO₂ formation while significant levels of CO and HC are present along the catalyst. The conversion of NO to NO₂ is observed to exhibit hysteresis when the temperature is ramped up and then down. This has been explained and successfully modelled in terms of the formation of an oxide layer on the surface of the catalyst, which is inactive for NO oxidation. Including both this effect and NO₂ reduction is important for obtaining a good prediction of the outlet NO₂ concentration, which in turn is crucial for the performance of any downstream model. The model has been successfully validated over both NEDC and FTP75 tests.</p>
            <p>Finally, it is demonstrated that this model, developed for an LDD catalyst, is readily adaptable to an HDD catalyst. The HDD version of the model has been extensively validated against engine test data for a range of tests (steady state light-off, transient light-off, HD-FTP, NRTC, WHTC).</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrauto, R.J., and Voss, K.E., “Monolithic diesel oxidation catalysts”, Appl. Catal B: Environ. 10(1-3):29-51, 1996, doi: 10.1016/0926-3373(96)00022-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DieselNet, “Diesel Oxidation Catalyst”, http://www.dieselnet.com/tech/cat_doc.html, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cooper, B. and Thoss, J., “Role of NO in Diesel Particulate Emission Control,” SAE Technical Paper 890404, 1989, doi: 10.4271/890404.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hawker, P., Hüthwohl, G., Henn, J., Koch, W. et al., “Effect of a Continuously Regenerating Diesel Particulate Filter on Non- Regulated Emissions and Particle Size Distribution,” SAE Technical Paper 980189, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allansson, R., Blakeman, P., Cooper, B., Hess, H. et al., “Optimising the Low Temperature Performance and Regeneration Efficiency of the Continuously Regenerating Diesel Particulate Filter (CR-DPF) System,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0428, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0428.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gieshoff, J., Schäfer-Sindlinger, A., Spurk, P., van den Tillaart, J. et al., “Improved SCR Systems for Heavy Duty Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0189, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Epling, W., Campbell, L.E., Yezerets, A., Currier, N.W., and Parks, J.E.II, “Overview of the Fundamental Reactions and Degradation Mechanisms of NOX Storage/Reduction Catalysts”, Catal. Rev. 46(2): 163-245, 2004, doi:10.1081/CR-200031932.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">York, A., Cox, J., Watling, T., Walker, A. et al., “Development and Validation of a One-Dimensional Computational Model of the Continuously Regenerating Diesel Particulate Filter (CR-DPF) System,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0954, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0954.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desai, M., Tutuianu, M., Ahmadinejad, M., Watling, T. et al., “Modeling of Non-Road Diesel Exhaust Aftertreatment Systems: Diesel Oxidation and Selective Catalytic Reduction Catalysts,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2092, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01- 2092.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Transport for London, “TRANSPORT FOR LONDON (TfL) LOW EMISSIONS CERTIFICATE (LEC) TECHNICAL REQUIREMENTS FOR APPROVAL OF LOW EMISSIONS ADAPTATIONS”, http://www.tfl.gov.uk/assets/downloads/roadusers/lez/lez/lec-technicalrequirements- for-manufacturers.pdf, Jul. 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DieselNet, “California ARB to re-introduce NO2 limit in retrofit equipment verification”, http://www.dieselnet.com/news/2005/02carb.php, Feb. 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DieselNet, “US EPA adopts NO2 limit from retrofit technologies”, http://www.dieselnet.com/news/2007/12epa2.php, Dec. 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DieselNet, “FOEN/Suva Filterlist”, http://www.dieselnet.com/tech/text/ch_filterliste.pdf, Dec. 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Katare, S., Patterson, J., and Laing, P., “Aged DOC is a Net Consumer of NO2: Analyses of Vehicle, Engine-dynamometer and Reactor Data,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-3984, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-3984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, L., and Fridell, E., “The Influence of Pt Oxide Formation and Pt Dispersion on the Reactions NO2 &lt;=&gt; NO + ½ O2 over Pt/Al2O3 and Pt/BaO/Al2O3”, J. Catal. 210(2):340-353, 2002, doi: 10.1006/jcat. 2002.3698.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Després, J., Elsener, M., Koebel, M., Kröcher, O., Schnyder, B., and Wokaun, A., “Catalytic oxidation of nitrogen monoxide over Pt/SiO2”, Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 50(2):73-82, 2004, doi: 10.1016/j.apcatb. 2003.12.020.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Forster, P., Ramaswamy, V., Artaxo, P., Berntsen, T., Betts, R., Fahey, D.W., Haywood, J., Lean, J., Lowe, D.C., Myhre, G., Nganga, J., Prinn, R., Raga, G., Schulz, M., and Van Dorland, R., “Changes in Atmospheric Constituents and in Radiative Forcing”, in: “Climate Change 2007: The Physical Science Basis. Contribution of Working Group I to the Fourth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change” [Solomon, S., Qin, D., Manning, M., Chen, Z., Marquis, M., Averyt, K.B., Tignor, M., and Miller, H.L. (eds.)], Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, UK, 2007, http://www.ipcc.ch/pdf/assessment-report/ar4/wg1/ar4-wg1-chapter2.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ahmadinejad, M., Desai, M.R., Watling, T.C., and York, A.P.E., “Simulation of Automotive Emission Control Systems,” Adv. Chem. Eng. 33:47-101, 2007, doi:10.1016/S0065-2377(07)33002-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chorkendorff, I., and Niemantsverdriet, J.W., “Concepts of Modern Catalysis and Kinetics”, Wiley-VCH Verlag, Weinheim, ISBN 3-527-30574-2:57-68, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burch, R., and Millington, P.J., “Selective reduction of nitrogen oxides by hydrocarbons under lean-burn conditions using supported platinum group metal catalysts”, Catal. Today 26(2):185-206, 1995, doi: 10.1016/0920-5861(95)00136-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hauff, K., Tuttlies, U., Eigenberger, G., and Nieken, U., “A global description of DOC kinetics for catalysts with different platinum loadings and aging status”, Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 100(1-2):10-18, 2010, doi: 10.1016/j.apcatb.2010.07.036.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Güthenke, A., Chatterjee, D., Weibel, M., Krutzsch, B., Koči, P., Marek, M., Nova, I., and Tronconi, E., “Current Status of Modeling Lean Exhaust Gas Aftertreatment Catalysts”, Adv. Chem. Eng. 33:103-211, 2007, doi:10.1016/S0065-2377(07)33003-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hauptmann, W., Votsmeier, M., Gieshoff, J., Drochner, A., and Vogel, H., “Inverse hysteresis during the NO oxidation on Pt under lean conditions”, Appl Catal. B: Environ. 93(1-2):22-29, 2009, doi: 10.1016/j.apcatb.2009.09.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Voltz, S.E., Morgan, C.R., Liederman, D., and Jacob, S.M., “Kinetic Study of Carbon Monoxide and Propylene Oxidation on Platinum Catalysts”, Ind. Eng. Chem. Prod. Res. Develop. 12(4):294-301, 1973, doi: 10.1021/i360048a006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yao, Y-F.Y., “The Oxidation of CO and Hydrocarbons over Noble Metal Catalysts”, J. Catal. 87(1):152-162, 1984, doi: 10.1016/0021-9517(84)90178-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yao, Y-F.Y., “Oxidation of Alkanes over Nobel Metal Catalysts”, Ind. Eng. Prod. Res. Dev. 19(3): 293-298, 1980, doi: 10.1021/i360075a003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burch, R., and Hayes, M.J, “C-H bond activation in hydrocarbon oxidation on solid catalysts”, J. Mol. Catal. A 100(1-3):13-33, 1995, doi: 10.1016/1381-1169(95)00133-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burch, R., Fornasiero, P., and Watling, T.C., “Kinetic and Mechanism of the Reduction of NO by n-Octane over Pt/Al2O3 Under Lean-Burn Conditions”, J. Catal. 176(1):204-214, 1998, doi: 10.1006/jcat. 1998.2024.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Erkfeldt, S., Jobson, E., and Larsson, M., “The effect of carbon monoxide and hydrocarbons on NOX storage at low temperature”, Topics Catal. 16/17(1-4):127-131, 2001, doi: 10.1023/A: 1016647217973.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, K., Seshan, K., and Lefferts, L., “Selective removal of NO2 in the presence of oxygen and NO over Pd/SiO2 catalysts”, Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 50(3):143-151, 2004, doi: 10.1016/j.apcatb.2004.01.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Irani, K., Epling, W.S., and Blint, R., “Effect of hydrocarbons on NO oxidation over diesel oxidation catalysts”, Appl. Catal. B:Environ. 92(3-4): 422-428, 2009, doi: 10.1016/j.apcatb.2009.08.022.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Henry, C., Currier, N., Ottinger, N., Yezerets, A. et al., “Decoupling the Interactions of Hydrocarbons and Oxides of Nitrogen Over Diesel Oxidation Catalysts,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1137, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1137.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salomons, S., Votsmeier, M., Hayes, R.E., Drochner, A., Vogel, H., and Gieshof, J., “CO and H2 oxidation on a platinum monolith diesel oxidation catalyst”, Catal. Today 117(4):491-497, 2006, doi: 10.1016/j.cattod.2006.06.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ansell, G.P., Bennett, P.S., Cox, J.P., Frost, J.C., Gray, P.G., Jones, A.- M., Rajaram, R.R., Walker, A.P., Litorell, and Smedler, G., “The development of a model capable of predicting diesel lean NOX catalyst performance under transient conditions”, Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 10(1-3):183-201, 1996, doi:10.1016/0926-3373(96)00030-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burch, R., and Watling, T.C., “The Difference Between Alkanes and Alkenes in the Reduction of NO by Hydrocarbons Over Pt Catalysts Under Lean-Burn Conditions”, Catal. Lett. 43(1-2):19-23, 1997, doi: 10.1023/A:1018974102756.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burch, R., and Watling, T.C., “Kinetics and Mechanism of the Reduction of NO by C3H8 Over Pt/Al2O3 Under Lean-Burn Conditions”, J. Catal. 169(1):45-54, 1997, doi: 10.1006/jcat.1997.1686.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burch, R., and Watling, T.C., “Kinetics of the Reduction of NO by C3H6 and C3H8 Over Pt Based Catalysts Under Lean-Burn Conditions”, Stud. Surf. Sci. Catal. 116: 199-211 (Catalysis and Automotive Pollution Control IV), 1998, doi:10.1016/S0167-2991(98)80877-X.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
