<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422602</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Numerical Investigation on the Effects of Different Thermal Insulation Strategies for a Passenger Car Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Caputo</surname>
                  <given-names>Sabino</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Torino</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Millo</surname>
                  <given-names>Federico</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Torino</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Cifali</surname>
                  <given-names>Giancarlo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors Global Propulsion Systems</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Pesce</surname>
                  <given-names>Francesco Concetto</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors Global Propulsion Systems</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>October 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422530</issue-id>
         <fpage>2154</fpage>
         <lpage>2165</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422602"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>One of the key technologies for the improvement of the diesel engine thermal efficiency is the reduction of the engine heat transfer through the thermal insulation of the combustion chamber. This paper presents a numerical investigation on the effects of the combustion chamber insulation on the heat transfer, thermal efficiency and exhaust temperatures of a 1.6 l passenger car, turbo-charged diesel engine. First, the complete insulation of the engine components, like pistons, liner, firedeck and valves, has been simulated. This analysis has showed that the piston is the component with the greatest potential for the in-cylinder heat transfer reduction and for Brake Specific Fuel Consumption (BSFC) reduction, followed by firedeck, liner and valves. Afterwards, the study has been focused on the impact of different piston Thermal Barrier Coatings (TBCs) on heat transfer, performance and wall temperatures. This analysis has been performed using a 1-D engine simulation code coupled with a lumped mass thermal model, representing the engine structure. A time-periodic wall conduction model has been used to calculate the wall temperature swings along the combustion chamber surface and within the engine cycle. Two different TBC materials, Yttria-Partially Stabilized Zirconia (Y-PSZ) and anodized aluminum, and different layer thicknesses have been simulated.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ICCT, “Vehicle technology costs: Estimates vs. reality,” http://www.theicct.org/blogs/staff/vehicle-technology-costs-estimates-vs-reality, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T., Fort, E., and Blumberg, P., "Effect of Insulation Strategy and Design Parameters on Diesel Engine Heat Rejection and Performance," SAE Technical Paper 850506, 1985, doi:10.4271/850506.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T., Keribar, R., Blumberg, P., and Fort, E., "Examination of Key Issues in Low Heat Rejection Engines," SAE Technical Paper 860316, 1986, doi:10.4271/860316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T., Wahiduzzaman, S., and Fort, E., "Heat Transfer Experiments in an Insulated Diesel," SAE Technical Paper 880186, 1988, doi:10.4271/880186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Assanis, D. and Heywood, J., "Development and Use of a Computer Simulation of the Turbocompounded Diesel System for Engine Performance and Component Heat Transfer Studies," SAE Technical Paper 860329, 1986, doi:10.4271/860329.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Afify, E. and Klett, D., "The Effect of Selective Insulation on the Performance, Combustion, and NO Emissions of a DI Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 960505, 1996, doi:10.4271/960505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tamilporai, P., Baluswamy, N., Jawahar, P., Subramaniyam, S. et al., "Simulation and Analysis of Combustion and Heat Transfer in Low Heat Rejection Diesel Engine Using Two Zone Combustion Model and Different Heat Transfer Models," SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1067, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1067.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pawar, A., Jajoo, B., and Nandgaonkar, M., "COMBUSTION ANALYSIS AND PERFORMANCE OF LOW HEAT REJECTION DIESEL ENGINE WITH DIFFERENT THERMAL INSULATION COATING," SAE Technical Paper 2004-28-0012, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-28-0012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miyairi, Y., "Computer Simulation of an LHR DI Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 880187, 1988, doi:10.4271/880187.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tovell, J., "The Reduction of Heat Losses to the Diesel Engine Cooling System," SAE Technical Paper 830316, 1983, doi:10.4271/830316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saad, D., Saad, P., Kamo, L., Mekari, M. et al., "Thermal Barrier Coatings for High Output Turbocharged Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1442, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1442.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderson, D., "The Effects of Ceramic Port Insulation on Cylinder Head Performance in a Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 961745, 1996, doi:10.4271/961745.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Paola, G., Rabeau, F., Knop, V., Willems, W. et al., “Modelling investigation of design approaches for Low Heat Rejection Diesel Engines,” SIA Powertrain, Rouen, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serrano, J., Arnau, F., Martin, J., Hernandez, M. et al., "Analysis of Engine Walls Thermal Insulation: Performance and Emissions," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1660, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1660.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kosaka, H., Wakisaka, Y., Nomura, Y., Hotta, Y. et al., "Concept of “Temperature Swing Heat Insulation” in Combustion Chamber Walls, and Appropriate Thermo-Physical Properties for Heat Insulation Coat," SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):142-149, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0274.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wakisaka, Y., Inayoshi, M., Fukui, K., Kosaka, H. et al., "Reduction of Heat Loss and Improvement of Thermal Efficiency by Application of “Temperature Swing” Insulation to Direct-Injection Diesel Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 9(3):1449-1459, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0661.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawaguchi, A., Iguma, H., Yamashita, H., Takada, N. et al., "Thermo-Swing Wall Insulation Technology; - A Novel Heat Loss Reduction Approach on Engine Combustion Chamber -," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-2333, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-2333.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kogo, T., Hamamura, Y., Nakatani, K., Toda, T. et al., "High Efficiency Diesel Engine with Low Heat Loss Combustion Concept - Toyota’s Inline 4-Cylinder 2.8-Liter ESTEC 1GD-FTV Engine -," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0658, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0658.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gamma Technologies, GT-SUITE Flow Theory Manual, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piano, A., Millo, F., Boccardo, G., Rafigh, M. et al., "Assessment of the Predictive Capabilities of a Combustion Model for a Modern Common Rail Automotive Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0547, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0547.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T. and Keribar, R., "A Model for Predicting Spatially and Time Resolved Convective Heat Transfer in Bowl-in-Piston Combustion Chambers," SAE Technical Paper 850204, 1985, doi:10.4271/850204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piano, A., Millo, F., Postrioti, L., Biscontini, G. et al., "Numerical and Experimental Assessment of a Solenoid Common-Rail Injector Operation with Advanced Injection Strategies," SAE Int. J. Engines 9(1):565-575, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0563.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zaccardi, J.M. and De Paola, G., “Fuel efficiency improvements for post-Euro 6 Diesel engines,” International Conference on Diesel Powertrains 3.0, Leipzig, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanaka, H., Fujita, M., Yamamoto, T., Muramatsu et al., “Anodizing method for aluminum alloy by using high-frequency switching electrolysis,” Jsae 2011-32, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-32-0645.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Durat, M., Kapsiz, M., Nart, E., Ficici, F. et al., “The effects of coating materials in spark ignition engine design,” Mater. Des. 36:540-545, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.matdes.2011.11.053.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G., "A Universally Applicable Equation for the Instantaneous Heat Transfer Coefficient in the Internal Combustion Engine," SAE Technical Paper 670931, 1967, doi:10.4271/670931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gamma Technologies, GT-SUITE Help Manual, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jennings, M. and Morel, T., "A Computational Study of Wall Temperature Effects on Engine Heat Transfer," SAE Technical Paper 910459, 1991, doi:10.4271/910459.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
