<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">9</issue>
         <issue-id>i40009568</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40247673</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="pub-doi">10.1093/rfs/hhp009</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Simulation-Based Estimation of Contingent-Claims Prices</article-title>
          </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Peter C. B.</given-names>
                  <surname>Phillips</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Jun</given-names>
                  <surname>Yu</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
          </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>3669</fpage>
         <lpage>3705</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2009 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40247673"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>A new methodology is proposed to estimate theoretical prices of financial contingent claims whose values are dependent on some other underlying financial assets. In the literature, the preferred choice of estimator is usually maximum likelihood (ML). ML has strong asymptotic justification but is not necessarily the best method in finite samples. This paper proposes a simulation-based method. When it is used in connection with ML, it can improve the finite-sample performance of the ML estimator while maintaining its good asymptotic properties. The method is implemented and evaluated here in the Black-Scholes option pricing model and in the Vasicek bond and bond option pricing model. It is especially favored when the bias in ML is large due to strong persistence in the data or strong nonlinearity in pricing functions. Monte Carlo studies show that the proposed procedures achieve bias reductions over ML estimation in pricing contingent claims when ML is biased. The bias reductions are sometimes accompanied by reductions in variance. Empirical applications to U. S. Treasury bills highlight the differences between the bond prices implied by the simulation-based approach and those delivered by ML. Some consequences for the statistical testing of contingent-claim pricing models are discussed.</p>
          </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>C11</kwd>
            <kwd>C15</kwd>
            <kwd>G12</kwd>
          </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
              <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
              <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
          </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
        
         <fn-group>
            <title>[Footnotes]</title>
            <fn id="d89e261a1310">
               <label>2</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d89e268" publication-type="other">
Aït-Sahalia and Kimmel (2007)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="d89e275a1310">
               <label>4</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d89e282" publication-type="other">
(Phillips and
Yu 2007).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="d89e292a1310">
               <label>5</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d89e299" publication-type="other">
Gourieroux, Monfort, and Renault (1993),</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="d89e306a1310">
               <label>8</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d89e313" publication-type="other">
Tang and Chen (2007)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      
        
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d89e329a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e333" publication-type="other">
Aït-Sahalia, Y. 1999. Transition Densities for Interest Rate and Other Non-linear Diffusions. Journal of Finance
54:1361-95.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e343a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e347" publication-type="other">
Aït-Sahalia, Y. 2002. Maximum Likelihood Estimation of Discretely Sampled Diffusion: A Closed-Form Ap-
proximation Approach. Econometrica 70:223-62.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e357a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e361" publication-type="other">
Aït-Sahalia, Y. 2008. Closed-Form Likelihood Expansions for Multivariate Diffusions. Annals of Statistics
36:906-37.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e371a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e375" publication-type="other">
Aït-Sahalia, Y, and R. Kimmel. 2005. Estimating Affine Multifactor Term Structure Models Using Closed-Form
Likelihood Expansion. Working Paper, Princeton University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e386a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e390" publication-type="other">
Aït-Sahalia, Y, and R. Kimmel. 2007. Maximum Likelihood Estimation of Stochastic Volatility Models. Journal
of Financial Economics 83:413-52.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e400a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e404" publication-type="other">
Aït-Sahalia, Y, and J. Yu. 2006. Saddlepoint Approximations for Continuous-Time Markov Processes. Journal
of Econometrics 134:507-51.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e414a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e418" publication-type="other">
Andersen, T., H. Chung, and B. Sorensen. 1999. Efficient Method of Moments Estimation of a Stochastic
Volatility Model: A Monte Carlo Study. Journal of Econometrics 91:61-87.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e428a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e432" publication-type="other">
Andrews, D. W. K. 1993. Exactly Median-Unbiased Estimation of First Order Autoregressive/Unit Root Models.
Econometrica 61:139-66.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e442a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e446" publication-type="other">
Bakshi, G., C. Cao, and Z. Chen. 1997. Empirical Performance of Alternative Option Pricing Models. Journal
of Finance 52:2003-49.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e456a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e460" publication-type="other">
Bakshi, G., N. Ju, and H. Ou-Yang. 2006. Estimation of Continuous-Time Models with an Application to Equity
Volatility Dynamics. Journal of Financial Economics 82:227-49.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e471a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e475" publication-type="other">
Ball, C. A., and W. N. Torous. 1984. The Maximum Likelihood Estimation of Security Price Volatility: Theory,
Evidence, and Application to Option Pricing. Journal of Business 57:97-112.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e485a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e489" publication-type="other">
Ball, C. A., and W. N. Torous. 1996. Unit Roots and the Estimation of Interest Rate Dynamics. Journal of
Empirical Finance 3:215-38.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e499a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e503" publication-type="other">
Black, F., and M. Scholes. 1973. The Pricing of Options and Corporate Liabilities. Journal of Political Economy
81:637-59.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e513a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e517" publication-type="other">
Boyle, P. P., and A. L. Ananthanarayanan. 1977. The Impact of Variance Estimation in Option Valuation Models.
Journal of Financial Economies 5:375-87.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e527a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e531" publication-type="other">
Brandt, M. W., and P. Santa-Clara. 2002. Simulated Likelihood Estimation of Diffusions with an Ap-
plication to Exchange Rate Dynamics in Incomplete Markets. Journal of Financial Economies 30:161-
210.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e544a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e548" publication-type="other">
Butler, J. S., and B. Schachter. 1986. Unbiased Estimation of the Black/Scholes Formula. Journal of Financial
Economies 15:341-57.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e559a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e563" publication-type="other">
Chan, K. C, G. A. Karolyi, F. A. Longstaff, and A. B. Sanders. 1992. An Empirical Comparison of Alternative
Models of Short Term Interest Rates. Journal of Finance 47: 1209-27.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e573a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e577" publication-type="other">
Chapman, D. A., and N. Pearson. 2000. Is the Short Rate Drift Actually Non-linear? Journal of Finance 55:355-
88.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e587a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e591" publication-type="other">
Chen, R. R., and L. Scott. 1992. Pricing Interest Rate Options in a Two-Factor Cox-Ingersoll-Ross Models of
the Term Structure. Review of Financial Studies 5:613-36.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e601a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e605" publication-type="other">
Chen, R. R., and L. Scott. 1993. Maximum Likelihood Estimation of a Multi-factor Equilibrium Model of the
Term Structure of Interest Rates. Journal of Fixed Income 3: 14-31.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e615a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e619" publication-type="other">
Cox, J., J. Ingersoll, and S. Ross. 1985. A Theory of the Term Structure of Interest Rates. Econometrica
53:385-407.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e629a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e633" publication-type="other">
Dai, Q., and K. J. Singleton. 2000. Specification Analysis of Affine Term Structure Models. Journal of Finance
55:1943-78.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e644a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e648" publication-type="other">
Dotsis, G., and R. N. Markellos. 2007. The Finite Sample Properties of the GARCH Option Pricing Models.
Journal of Futures Markets 17:599-615.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e658a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e662" publication-type="other">
Duan, J. 1995. The GARCH Option Pricing Model. Mathematical Finance 5:13-32.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e669a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e673" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., and R. Kan. 1996. A Yield-Factor Model of Interest Rate. Mathematical Finance 6:379-406.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e680a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e684" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., J. Pan, and K. J. Singleton. 2000. Transform Analysis and Asset Pricing for Affine Jump-Diffusions.
Econometrica 68: 1343-76.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e694a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e698" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., and K. J. Singleton. 1993. Simulated Moments Estimation of Markov Models of Asset Prices.
Econometrica 61:929-52.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e708a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e712" publication-type="other">
Durham, G., and A. R. Gallant. 2002. Numerical Techniques for Maximum Likelihood Estimation of Continuous-
Time Diffusion Processes. Journal of Business and Economic Statistics 20:297-316.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e723a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e727" publication-type="other">
Egorov, A. E., H. Li, and D. Ng. Forthcoming. A Tale of Two Yield Curves: Modeling the Joint Term Structure
of Dollar and Euro Interest Rates. Journal of Econometrics.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e737a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e741" publication-type="other">
Egorov, A. E., H. Li, and Y. Xu. 2003. Maximum Likelihood Estimation of Time-Inhomogeneous Diffusions.
Journal of Econometrics 114: 107-39.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e751a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e755" publication-type="other">
Gallant, A., and G. Tauchen. 1996. Which Moments to Match? Econometric Theory 12:657-81.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e762a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e766" publication-type="other">
Geyer, A., and S. Pichler. 1999. A State-space Approach to Estimate and Test Multifactor Cox-Ingersoll-Ross
Models of the Term Structure. Journal of Financial Research 22:107-30.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e776a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e780" publication-type="other">
Gouriéroux, C, A. Monfort, and E. Renault. 1993. Indirect Inference. Journal of Applied Econometrics 8:S85-
118.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e790a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e794" publication-type="other">
Gouriéroux, C, P. C. B. Phillips, and J. Yu. Forthcoming. Indirect Inference for Dynamic Panel Models. Journal
of Econometrics.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e805a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e809" publication-type="other">
Gouriéroux, C, E. Renault, and N. Touzi. 2000. Calibration by Simulation for Small Sample Bias Correction.
In R. S. Mariano, T. Schuermann, and M. Weeks (eds.), Simulation-Based Inference in Econometrics: Methods
and Applications, pp. 328-58. Cambridge, United Kingdom: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e822a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e826" publication-type="other">
Heston, S. L. 1993. A Closed-Form Solution for Options with Stochastic Volatility, with Applications to Bond
and Currency Options. Review of Financial Studies 6:327-43.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e836a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e840" publication-type="other">
Heston, S. L., and S. Nandi. 2000. A Closed-Form GARCH Option Valuation Model. Review of Financial Studies
13:585-625.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e850a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e854" publication-type="other">
Huber, P. J. 1967. The Behavior of Maximum Likelihood Estimates under Nonstandard Conditions. In L. M.
LeCam and J. Neyman (eds.), Proceedings of the Fifth Berkeley Symposium on Mathematics, Statistics, and
Probability, pp. 221-33. Berkeley: University of California Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e867a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e871" publication-type="other">
Hull, J. 2000. Options, Futures, and Other Derivatives, 2d ed. Old Tappan, NJ: Prentice-Hall.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e878a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e882" publication-type="other">
Hull, J., and A. White. 1987. The Pricing of Options on Assets with Stochastic Volatilities. Journal of Finance
42:281-300.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e893a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e897" publication-type="other">
Ingersoll, J. 1976. A Theoretical and Empirical Analysis of the Dual Purpose Fund. Journal of Financial
Economics 3:83-124.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e907a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e911" publication-type="other">
Jamshidian, F. 1989. An Exact Bond Option Formula. Journal of Finance 44:205-9.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e918a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e922" publication-type="other">
Jensen, B., and R. Poulsen. 2002. Transition Densities of Diffusion Processes: Numerical Comparison of Ap-
proximation Techniques. Journal of Derivatives 9:1-15.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e932a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e936" publication-type="other">
Kim, S., N. Shephard, and S. Chib. 1998. Stochastic Volatility: Likelihood Inference and Comparison with ARCH
Models. Review of Economic Studies 65:361-93.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e946a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e950" publication-type="other">
Knight, J. L., and S. E. Satchell. 1997. Existence of Unbiased Estimators of the Black/Scholes Option Price,
Other Derivatives, and Hedge Ratios. Econometric Theory 13:791-807.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e960a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e964" publication-type="other">
Lo, A. W. 1986. Statistical Tests of Contingent-Claims Asset-Pricing Models. Journal of Financial Economics
17:143-73.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e975a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e979" publication-type="other">
Lo, A. W. 1988. Maximum Likelihood Estimation of Generalized Itô Processes with Discretely Sampled Data.
Econometric Theory 4:231-47.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e989a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e993" publication-type="other">
MacKinnon, J. G., and A. A. Smith. 1998. Approximate Bias Correction in Econometrics. Journal of Economet-
rics 85:205-30.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1003a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1007" publication-type="other">
Merton, R. C. 1973. Theory of Rational Option Pricing. Bell Journal of Economics and Management Science
4:141-83.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1017a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1021" publication-type="other">
Monfardini, C. 1998. Estimating Stochastic Volatility Models through Indirect Inference. Econometrics Journal
1:C113-28.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1031a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1035" publication-type="other">
Monfort, A. 1996. A Reappraisal of Misspecified Econometric Models. Econometric Theory 12:597-619.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1042a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1046" publication-type="other">
Phillips, P. C. B. 1972. The Structural Estimation of Stochastic Differential Equation Systems. Econometrica
40:1021-41.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1057a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1061" publication-type="other">
Phillips, P. C. B., and J. Yu. 2005. Jackknifing Bond Option Prices. Review of Financial Studies 18:707-42.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1068a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1072" publication-type="other">
Phillips, P. C. B., and J. Yu. Forthcoming. A Two-Stage Realized Volatility Approach to Estimation of Diffusion
Processes with Discrete Data. Journal of Econometrics.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1082a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1086" publication-type="other">
Phillips, P. C. B., and J. Yu. Forthcoming. Maximum Likelihood and Gaussian Estimation of Continuous Time
Models in Finance. In T. G. Andersen, R. A. Davis, J. P. Kreiss, and T. Mikosch (eds.), Handbook of Financial
Time Series. New York: Springer.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1099a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1103" publication-type="other">
Pierce, J. L. 1984. Did Financial Innovation Hurt the Great Monetarist Experiment? American Economic Review
74:392-96.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1113a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1117" publication-type="other">
Skaug, H., and J. Yu. 2007. Automated Likelihood Based Inference for Stochastic Volatility Models. Working
Paper, Sim Kee Boon Institute for Financial Economics, Singapore Management University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1127a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1131" publication-type="other">
Smith, A. A. 1993. Estimating Nonlinear Time-Series Models Using Simulated Vector Autoregressions. Journal
of Applied Econometrics 8:S63-84.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1142a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1146" publication-type="other">
Tang, C. Y., and S. X. Chen. 2007. Parameter Estimation and Bias Correction for Diffusion Processes. Working
Paper, Department of Statistics, Iowa State University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1156a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1160" publication-type="other">
Thompson, S. 2008. Identifying Term Structure Volatility from the LIBOR-Swap Curve. Review of Financial
Studies 21:819-54.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1170a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1174" publication-type="other">
Vasicek, O. 1977. An Equilibrium Characterization of the Term Structure. Journal of Financial Economics
5:177-86.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1184a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1188" publication-type="other">
Yu, J. 2008. Bias in the Estimation of Mean Reversion Parameter in Continuous Time Models. Working Paper,
Sim Kee Boon Institute for Financial Economics, Singapore Management University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d89e1198a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d89e1202" publication-type="other">
Zehna, P. 1966. Invariance of Maximum Likelihood Estimation. Annals of Mathematical Statistics 37:744.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      </back>
</article>
