<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278013</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Innovative Hybrid Rare Earth and Barium Materials with Enhanced Properties for NOx Storage Applications</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ocampo</surname>
                  <given-names>Fabien</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Harle</surname>
                  <given-names>Virginie</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ohtake</surname>
                  <given-names>Naotaka</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rohe</surname>
                  <given-names>Renaud</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Southward</surname>
                  <given-names>Barry W.L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Solvay - Rare Earth Systems</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>June 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277995</issue-id>
         <fpage>1136</fpage>
         <lpage>1143</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278013"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The reduction of NOₓ to meet current diesel regulation standards has been achieved using two main technologies named NH₃-SCR and LNT. In the forthcoming years, the implementation of new and colder test cycles such as “real driving emissions” (RDE), combined with CO₂ targets (95 g/km is 2020 target in Europe) will require higher NOₓ storage capacity (NSC) in the low temperature region (120-350°C). On the other hand, lean-burn Gasoline vehicles, emitting exhaust gases at higher temperatures, will require improved NSC over a broader temperature range (200-500°C). Therefore, the development of more efficient NSC materials is an area of extensive study by original equipment manufacturers (OEMs), catalysts manufacturers, and raw materials suppliers. Today, ceria is a key component in the formulation of active NSC washcoats. It is often combined with barium in order to improve its high temperature NSC, but this also leads to a significant loss of specific surface area and thus a decrease in overall performance at low temperature. This paper reports recent progress made on NSC materials, with the aim to enlarge their operational temperature window. In this regard, Solvay has developed an innovative solution: rare earth and barium hybrid compounds as advanced NSC materials. synthetic gas bench tests performed on powder model catalysts show a significant increase in NSC at low temperatures and a very strong benefit in NSC at high temperatures, compared to current Solvay reference ‘High Stability Ceria’ or Ba-doped ceria.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berreta, A., Groppi, G., Forzatti, P., “Structured Catalysts and Reactors”, Cybulski M.D.A., (Ed.), New York, 121-148, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Willems, F., Cloudt, R., van den Eijnden, E., van Genderen, M. et al., “Is Closed-Loop SCR Control Required to Meet Future Emission Targets?,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1574, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1574.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rohart, E., Krocher, O., Casapu, M., Marques, R. et al., “Acidic Zirconia Mixed Oxides for NH3-SCR Catalysts for PC and HD Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1327, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1327.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hun Kwak, J., Tran, D., Burton, S.D., Szanyi J. et al., “Effects of hydrothermal aging on NH3-SCR reaction over Cu/zeolites”, Journal of Catalysis, 287, 203-209, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takahashi, N., Shinjoh, H., Iijima, T., Suzuki, T., Yamazaki, K. et al., “The new concept 3-way catalyst for automotive lean-burn engine: NOx storage and reduction catalyst”, Catalysis Today, 27, 63-69, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bellière-Baca, V., Harlé, V., Pitois, C., Rohart, E. et al., “Ceria Doped Ba-Alumina Oxides for Durable NOx-Storage Catalysts Efficient at Low Temperature,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1241, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1241.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T., “Review of Diesel Emissions and Control,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):16-29, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0301.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matsumoto, S., “DeNOx catalyst for automotive lean-burn engine”, Catalysis Today, 29, 43-45, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Theis, J., Ura, J., Goralski, C., Jen, H. et al., “The Effect of Ceria Content on the Performance of a NOx Trap,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1160, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1160.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ji, Y., Topps, T.J., Crocker, M., “Effect of Ceria on the Sulfation and Desulfation Characteristics of a Model Lean NOx Catalyst”, Catalysis Letters, 127, 55-62, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bernal, S., Calvino, J.J., Cauqui, M.A. et al., “Some recent results on metal/support interaction effects in NM/CeO2 (NM: noble metal) catalysts”, Catalysis Today, 50, 175-206, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nagai, Y., Hirabayashi, T., Dohmae, K. et al., “Sintering inhibition mechanism of platinum supported on ceria-based oxide and Pt-oxidesupport interaction”, Journal of Catalysis, 242, 103-109, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kwak, J., Kim, D., Szanyi, J. et al., “Excellent Sulfur Resistance of Pt/BaO/CeO2 Lean NOx Trap Catalysts”, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental, 84, 545-551, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ji, Y., Toops, T.J., Crocker, M., “Effect of Ceria on the Storage and Regeneration Behavior of a Model Lean NOx Trap Catalyst”, Catalysis Letters, 119, 257-264, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adams, K., Graham, G., “Impact of Redox Conditions on Thermal Deactivation of NOx Traps for Diesel”, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental, 80, 343-352, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacobs, G., Williams, L., Graham, U. et al., “Low Temperature Water- Gas Shift: In Situ DRIFTS-Reaction Study of Ceria Surface Area on the Evolution of Formates on Pt/CeO2 Processing Catalysts for Fuel Cell Applications”, Applied Catalysis A, 252, 107-118, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruix, A., Rodriguez, J.A., Ramirez, P.J. et al., “A New Type of Strong Metal-Support Interaction and the Production of H2 through the Transformation of Water on Pt/CeO2(111) and Pt/CeOx/TiO2(110) Catalysts”, Journal of the American Society,134, 8968-8974, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Z., Anderson, J., “Influence of Reductant on the Thermal Stability of Stored NOx in Pt/BaO/Al2O3 NOx Storage and Reduction Traps”, Journal of Catalysis, 224, 18-27, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Szailer, T., Kwak, J., Kim, D. et al., “Reduction of Stored NOx on Pt/Al2O3 and Pt/BaO/Al2O3 Catalysts with H2 and CO”, Journal of Catalysis, 239, 51-64, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ji, Y., Toops, T.J., Pihl, J.A. et al., “NOx Storage and Reduction in Model Lean NOx Trap Catalysts Studied by in situ DRIFTS”, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental, 91, 329-338, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Punke, A., Hilgendorff, M., Neubauer, T., Caudle, M. et al., (BASF) “Passenger Car Diesel meeting Euro 6c Legislation: The next Generation LNT Catalyst Systems”, MinNOx Conference, Berlin, June 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoyer, R., Utschig, T., Kreuz, J., Bremm, S. et al. (Umicore) Company, “NOx Storage Catalyst Development to Support Fuel Efficiency Ambitions of Future Combustion Engines”, MinNOx Conference, Berlin, June 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wylie, J., Bergeal, D., Hatcher, D., Phillips, P., (Johnson Matthey), “SCRF Systems for Eu6c”, MinNOx Conference, Berlin, June 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wittka, T., Weissner, M., Holderbaum, B., Körfer, T., (Volkswagen), “Potential of combined NSC + passive SCR system for diesel passenger car application”, MinNOx Conference, Berlin, June 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Köpf, J., Keber, A., Brüne, H.J., (BMW), “The second generation U.S. Diesel cars from BMW”, MinNOx Conference, Berlin, June 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
