<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26812160</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Issues in Property Taxation</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Paper Prepared for Presentation at the 106th Annual Conference on Taxation National Tax Association Tampa, Florida November 2013 Structural / Institutional Determinants of Variations in Household Property Tax Burdens Within and Across Local Governments</article-title>
            <subtitle>The Effect of the Great Recession and Beyond</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mikesell</surname>
                  <given-names>John L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mullins</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">107</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26812141</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>32</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26812160"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Approximately 13 million household observations from the Public Use Micro Samples of the 1990 and 2000 Census of Population and Housing and Annual Community Surveys from 2005 through 2011 are combined with Census Summary File Tables and spatial demographic / economic measures to evaluate the distribution of residential property tax burdens between communities and population groups across time and through the period of the Great Recession in all fifty states. Household property tax data are combined with institutional data on property tax administration and individual unit data on government revenues and expenditures from the Annual Surveys and Census of Governments and socioeconomic and demographic characteristics from a variety of sources to map individual household data to Public Use Microdata Areas in each state and summary file tables to counties. These data are then used to identify how property tax burdens have shifted across household income classes from 1990 through 2011, how burdens have shifted in states across those years, and how household, economic, and fiscal structures impact those burdens. Particular attention is given to changes with the Great Recession. Policy recommendation emerge to restructure this most durable of local tax instruments to improve both equity and efficiency effects, while maintaining the need for steady, robust yield.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations(ACIR), Significant Features of Fiscal Federalism, Volume 1(Washington, D.C.: U.S. Government Printing Office, 1990, 1992, 1994).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations. Annual. Changing Public Attitudes on Governments and Taxes Washington, D. C.: U. S. Government Printing Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Atkins, Chris (2007), Appropriation by Litigation: Estimating the Cost of Judicial Mandates for State and Local Education Spending, Tax Foundation Background Paper, Number 55 (July 2007).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Baer, David (2008), State Handbook of Economic, Demographic &amp; Fiscal Indicators, 7thEdition(Washington, DC: American Association of Retired Persons).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Chamberlain, Andrew. 2007. What Does America Think About Taxes? The 2007 Annual Survey of U. S. Attitudes on Taxes and Wealth, Tax Foundation Special Report No. 154. (April)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Lyons, Karen, Sarah Farkas and Nicholas Johnson (2007), The Property Tax Circuit Breaker: An Introduction and Survey of Current Programs(Washington, DC: Center on Budget and Policy Priorities, March).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Minnesota Taxpayers Association (2001), 50 State Property Tax Comparison Study 2000(St. Paul, MN: Minnesota Taxpayers Association).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Minnesota Taxpayers Association (2006), 50 State Property Tax Comparison Study 2005(St. Paul, MN: Minnesota Taxpayers Association).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Mikesell, John L. and Cheol Liu. Forthcoming. “Property Tax Stability: A Tax System Model of Base and Revenue Dynamics Through the Great Recession and Beyond,” Public Finance and Management.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Mikesell, John L. and Daniel R. Mullins(2009), Structural/Institutional Determinants of Variations in Household Property Burdens and Effective TaxRates Within and Across Local Governments: The Implications of Classification, Assessment Methods, Revenue Diversity and TELs,Proceedings of the 101stAnnual Conference on Taxation(Washington, D.C.: National Tax Association, 2009).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Mikesell, John L. and Daniel R. Mullins (2008) “The Impacts of Property and Household Characteristics and Property Tax Systems on Household PropertyTax Burdens: An Analysis from Individual Property Data,” State Tax Notes, vol. 47, no 7, February 18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Mullins, Daniel R. (2003), “Popular Processes and the Transformation of State and Local Government Finances,” in David L. Sjoquist, State and Local Finances Under Pressure(Northampton, MA: Edward Elgar), ch 5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Mullins, Daniel R. (2010) “Fiscal Limitations on Local Choice: The Imposition and Effects of Local Government Tax and Expenditure Limitations,” in Sally Wallace ed., State and Local Fiscal Policy: Thinking Outside the Box (Edward Elgar, April), ch 9, pp. 201-265.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Mullins, Daniel R. and Kimberly A. Cox (1995), Tax and Expenditure Limits on Local Governments, M-194, Washington, D.C.: Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Mullins, Daniel R. and John L. Mikesell (2010), “State and Local Revenue Yield and Stability in the Great Recession,” State Tax Notes, vol. 55, no. 4: 267-274, January 25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">NCSL (2002), A Guide to Property Taxes: Property Tax Relief(Washington, DC: National Conference of State Legislatures, November).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Richardson, Jesse J., Jr., Meghan Zimmerman Gough, and Robert Puentes (2003), Is Home Rule the Answer? Clarifying the Influence of Dillon’s Rule on Growth Management, Discussion Paper Prepared for the Brookings Institution Center on Urban and Metropolitan Policy, January, p. 18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">U.S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of Census, American Community Survey, Public Use Microdata Sample Files(PUMS), years 2000 through 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">U.S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of Census (1961-2011), Annual Survey of State and Local Government Finances and Census of Governments.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">U. S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of Census (1987 -2007)Census of Governments,machine readable files, various years.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">U.S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of Census (1990, 2000) Census of Population and Housing, 5 Percent Public Use Microdata Sample Files (PUMS), prepared various years.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">U.S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of Census (2011), County Business Patterns, 2011. Machine readable files, all fifty states.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">U.S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of the Census (2013), USA Counties, machine readable files, released March 2008, continuously updated.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Local Property, Individual Income and General Sales Tax Yield Relative to 4th Qtr 1988, Annualized by Quarter</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Real Local Property Tax Yield, Annualized by Quarter (1989-2013, 2009 dollars)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Local Property Tax Yield, as a Percent of Total Local Tax Revenue, Annualized by Quarter (1989-2013)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Local Property Tax as a Portion of Personal Income, Annualized by uarter (1989-2013)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Absolute Dollar Value of Residential Property Tax Burden by Income Decile and Coefficient of Variation Across States, 1990 &amp; 2001-2011</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Residential Property Tax Burden (as Percent of Household Income) by Income Decile and Coefficient of Variation Across States, 1990 &amp; 2000-2011</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Average Absolute Dollar Value of Residential Property Tax Burden by State, by Year, and Rate of Growth, 1990 &amp; 2001-2011</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Avarage Residential Property Tax Burden (as Percent of Household Income) by State, by Year, and Rate of Growth, 1990 &amp; 2000-2011</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5.</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Exploratory Model Results Determinants of Absolute and Relative Household Property Tax Burdens (Pooled cross-sectional fixed effect (state-year) unbalanbced panel models with state clustered standard errors estimated via generalized estimating equations (GEEs))</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
