<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830656</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830659</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>CHARACTERISTICS OF EMERGING CAPITAL MARKETS / LES CARACTÉRISTIQUES DES MARCHÉS DES CAPITAUX ÉMERGENTS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Nighat</given-names>
                  <surname>Bilgrami</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1998</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>279</fpage>
         <lpage>282</lpage>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830659"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The financial sector allows an efficient transfer of resources from savers to investors. It is comprised of banks and the non-bank financial institutions, money markets and capital markets. Hence allows efficient transfer of resources from savers to investors. The role becomes more important for the developing economies, and a more efficient financial sector can emerge. Capital markets, however, are not homogenous in their institutional, operational, informational and other characteristics which are studied in the paper. The critical analysis of the emerging capital markets of Asia suggests that the key characteristics of major markets are sufficiently different to have important implications for the application of asset pricing theories. The size of the market is small as most of the Asian markets are located in small national economies. It is found that the important reason for the existence of these is the institutional differences which reflects that the market being organized in the recent decades. Le secteur financier, qui consiste de banques et d'institutions non bancaires, de marchés monétaires et de marchés des capitaux, permet un trasfert de ressources de l'épargneur à l'investisseur plus dynamique. Son rôle est encore plus important pour les économies en développement où un secteur financier plus efficace peut être mis en place. Les marchés des capitaux, toutefois, ne sont pas homogènes sous plusieurs aspects, institutionnel, opérationnel, informatique, etc, qui sont analysés dans cet article. Une analyse critique des marchés des capitaux émergeants de l'Asie suggère que les charactéristiques clef des marchés les plus importants sont si différentes qu'elles ont des implications importantes pour l'application des théories sur la fixation del prix. Les dimensions des marchés sont généralement petites car la plupart des marchés asiatiques est localisée dans des économies nationales petites et les différences institutionnelles qui reflètent le fait que ces marchés ont été organisés dans ces dernières décennies semblent être une des raisons principales de leur existence.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


