<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422606</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Real Time Prediction of Particle Sizing at the Exhaust of a Diesel Engine by Using a Neural Network Model</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Taglialatela</surname>
                  <given-names>Ferdinando</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>STMicroelectronics</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Lavorgna</surname>
                  <given-names>Mario</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>STMicroelectronics</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Di Iorio</surname>
                  <given-names>Silvana</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori CNR</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Mancaruso</surname>
                  <given-names>Ezio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori CNR</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Vaglieco</surname>
                  <given-names>Bianca Maria</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori CNR</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>October 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422530</issue-id>
         <fpage>2202</fpage>
         <lpage>2208</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422606"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>In order to meet the increasingly strict emission regulations, several solutions for NOx and PM emissions reduction have been studied. Exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) technology has become one of the more used methods to accomplish the NOx emissions reduction. However, actual control strategies do not consider, in the definition of optimal EGR, its effect on particle size and density. These latter have a great importance both for the optimal functioning of after-treatment systems, but also for the adverse effects that small particles have on human health. Epidemiological studies, in fact, highlighted that the toxicity of particulate particles increases as the particle size decreases.</p>
            <p>The aim of this paper is to present a Neural Network model able to provide real time information about the characteristics of exhaust particles emitted by a Diesel engine. In particular, the model acts as a <italic>virtual sensor</italic> able to estimate the concentration of particles with a specific aerodynamic diameter on the basis of some engine parameters such as engine speed, engine load and EGR ratio.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ostro, B. D., “Air pollution and morbidity: a sensitivity analysis of alternative monitors, pollutants, and averaging times,” Sci Total Environ. 39(1-2):111-24, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Douglas, W., Dockery, C., Pope, A., Xu, X., et al., “An Association between Air Pollution and Mortality in Six U.S. Cities,” N Engl. J Med; 329:1753-1759, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, J., T., Son, J., Y., Kim, H., and Kim, S., Y., “Effect of air pollution on asthma-related hospital admissions for children by socioeconomic status associated with area of residence,” Archives of Environmental and Occupational Health; 61(3):123-130, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Donaldson, K., Li, X. Y., and MacNee, W., “Ultrafine (Nanometer) Particle Mediated Lung Injury,” J. Aerosol Sci. 29:553-560.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">REGULATION (EC) No. 715/2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, M., Reader, G.T., and Hawley, J.G., “Diesel engine exhaust gas recirculation: a review on advanced and novel concepts,” Energy Conversion &amp; Management 45: 883:900, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hong, K., S., Lee, K., S., Song, S., Chun, K., M., et al., “Parametric study on particle size and SOF effects on EGR cooler fouling,” Atmospheric Environment” 45: 5677-5683, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, H., and Choi, B., “Effect of ethanol-diesel blend fuels on emission and particle size distribution in a common-rail direct injection diesel engine with warm-up catalytic converter,” Renewable Energy 33:2222-2228, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qi, D., Lee, C., and Lin, Y., "Effect of Injection Parameters and EGR on the Particle Size Distributions and Exhaust Emissions for Diesel and Biodiesel Fuels in CRDI Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1612, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1612.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kreso, A., Johnson, J., Gratz, L., Bagley, S. et al., "A Study of the Effects of Exhaust Gas Recirculation on Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine Emissions," SAE Technical Paper 981422, 1998, doi:10.4271/981422.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsolakis, “Effects on Particle Size Distribution from the Diesel Engine Operating on RME-Biodiesel with EGR,” Energy &amp; Fuels 20: 1418-1424, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee. H., and Jeong, Y., “The effect of dynamic operating conditions on nano-particle emissions from a light-duty diesel engine applicable to prime and auxiliary machines on marine vessels,” Inter J. Nav. Archit. Oc. Engng. 4:403:411, 2012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tao, F., Liu, Y., RempelEwert, B., Foster, D. et al., "Modeling the Effects of EGR and Injection Pressure on Soot Formation in a High-Speed Direct-Injection (HSDI) Diesel Engine Using a Multi-Step Phenomenological Soot Model," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0121, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., "A Conceptual Model of DI Diesel Combustion Based on Laser-Sheet Imaging*," SAE Technical Paper 970873, 1997, doi:10.4271/970873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ning, Z., Cheung, C. S., and Liu, S. X., “Experimental Investigation of the Effect of Exhaust Gas Cooling on Diesel Particulate,” J. Aerosol Sci. 35:333-345, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ahlvik, P., Ntziachristos, L., Keskinen, J., and Virtanen, A., "Real Time Measurements of Diesel Particle Size Distribution with an Electrical Low Pressure Impactor," SAE Technical Paper 980410, 1998, doi:10.4271/980410.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B. Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals; McGraw-Hill: New York, 1988; ISBN 0-07-100499-8</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner, R., M., Green, J., B. Jr, Storey, J., M., and Daw, C., S., “Extending Exhaust Gas Recirculation Limits in Diesel Engines,” Oak Ridge National Laboratory.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, Y., Wang, Z., Xu, G. J., and. Li, M. D., “Impact of EGR on the surface functional groups of diesel engine particles based on NEXAFS,” RSC Adv., 6, 57363, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, H., Liu, Q., Wang, Q., Zhou. C., et al. “Experimental investigation of particle emissions under different EGR ratios on a diesel engine fueled by blends of diesel/gasoline/n-butanol,” Energy Conversion and Management 121:212-223, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoard, J., Abarham, M., Styles, D., Giuliano, J. et al., "Diesel EGR Cooler Fouling," SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):1234-1250, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2475.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, F. and van Nieuwstadt, M., "Adaptive EGR Cooler Pressure Drop Estimation," SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0624, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0624.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maing, S., Lee, K.S., Song, S., Chun, K.M., et al. “Simulation of the EGR Cooler Fouling Effect on NOx Emission of a Light Duty Diesel Engine,” KSAE07-F0035, pp. 214-220, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T., "Diesel Emission Control in Review," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):68-81, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0069.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tao, F., Liu, Y., RempelEwert, B., Foster, D. et al., "Modeling the Effects of EGR and Injection Pressure on Soot Formation in a High-Speed Direct-Injection (HSDI) Diesel Engine Using a Multi-Step Phenomenological Soot Model," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0121, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nascimento, C.A.O., Guardani, R. and Giulietti, M., “Use of neural networks in the analysis of particle size distributions by laser diffraction,” Powder Technology 90: 89-94, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sayin, C., Ertunc, H., M., Hosoz, M., Kilicaslan, I., et al. “Performance and exhaust emissions of a gasoline engine using artificial neural network” Appl. Therm. Eng. 27:46-54, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Canakci, M., Erdil, A. and Arcaklioglu, E., “Performance and exhaust emissions of a biodiesel engine,” Appl. Energy 83:594-605, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arcaklioglu, E. and Celikten, I., A., “Diesel engine’s performance and exhaust emissions” Appl Energy 80:11-22, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Celik, V., Arcaklioglu, E., “Performance maps of a diesel engine,” Applied Energy 81:247-59, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Golcu, M., Sekmen., Y, Erduranli, P. and Salman., S., “Artificial neural network based modeling of variable valve-timing in a spark ignition engine,” Applied Energy 81:187-97, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haykin, S. Neural networks: a comprehensive foundation. New York: Mac-Millan, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Najafi, G., Ghobadian, B., Yusaf, T. and Rahimi, H., “Combustion analysis of a CI engine performance using waste cooking biodiesel fuel with an artificial neural network,” American Journal of Applied Sciences 4(10):756-64, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, H., Liu, Q., Wang, Q., Zhou, C., et al. “Experimental investigation of particle emissions under different EGR ratios on a diesel engine fueled by blends of diesel/gasoline/n-butanol,” Energy Conversion and Management 121: 212-223, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Canale, S. and Scotton, R., “Calcolo della percentuale di EGR - Motori - Sistemi Diesel ed Emissioni”, Orbassano, January, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mörsch, O. and Sorsche, P., (DaimlerChrysler AG) “Investigation of Alternative Methods to Determine Particulate Mass Emissions” http://www.oica.net/htdocs/Main.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maricq M., Xu N. and Chase E., “Measuring particulate mass Emissions with the Electrical Low Pressure Impactor”, Aerosol Science and Technology, v.40, pp.68 - 79, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MacKay D. J. C., “Bayes interpolation”, Neural Computation, vol. 4, no. 3, pp. 415-447, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Foresee, F. D., and Hagan M. T., “Gauss-Newton approximation to Bayesian regularization”, Proceedings of the 1997 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks, pp. 1930-1935, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A., Finesso, R., and Spessa, E., "Real-Time Calculation of EGR Rate and Intake Charge Oxygen Concentration for Misfire Detection in Diesel Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0149, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alger, T., Gukelberger, R., Gingrich, J., and Mangold, B., "The Impact of Cooled EGR on Peak Cylinder Pressure in a Turbocharged, Spark Ignited Engine," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(2):455-463, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0744.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klein, P., Grüter, R., and Loffeld, O., "Real-Time Estimation of the Exhaust Gas Recirculation Ratio Based on Cylinder Pressure Signals," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0493, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0493.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
