<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284919</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Extension of the Phenomenological 3-Arrhenius Auto-Ignition Model for Six Surrogate Automotive Fuels</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Blomberg</surname>
                  <given-names>Christopher Kim</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ETH Zurich</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mitakos</surname>
                  <given-names>Dimitrios</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ETH Zurich</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bardi</surname>
                  <given-names>Michele</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ETH Zurich</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Boulouchos</surname>
                  <given-names>Konstantinos</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ETH Zurich</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wright</surname>
                  <given-names>Yuri M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ETH Zurich/Combustion+FlowSolutions GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Vandersickel</surname>
                  <given-names>Annelies</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Technische Universität München</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>September 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284904</issue-id>
         <fpage>1544</fpage>
         <lpage>1558</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284919"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>An existing three-stage ignition delay model which has seen successful application to Primary Reference Fuels (PRFs) has been extended to six surrogate fuels which constitute potential candidates for future Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) engines. The fuels include petroleum-derived and oxygenated components and can be divided into low, intermediate and high cetane number groups. A new methodology to obtain the model parameters is presented which relies jointly on simulation and experimental data: in a first step, constant volume adiabatic reactor simulations using chemical kinetic mechanisms are performed to generate ignition delays for a very wide range of conditions, namely variations in equivalence ratio, Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR), pressure and temperature. Based on this “virtual shock tube” data the 3-Arrhenius parameters for low- and high-temperature ignition delay and Negative Temperature Coefficient (NTC) regimes are determined by means of a genetic algorithm. In a second step, the parameterized 3-Arrhenius model is assessed by means of experimental auto-ignition delay data from a Rapid Compression Expansion Machine (RCEM). This data revealed a systematic over prediction of the low and high temperature ignition delays. A refinement of the pre-exponential parameters of the low and high ignition delay terms was carried out resulting in excellent agreement over a large range of operating conditions between model and measurements for all six fuels. The approach proposed in this study hence combines 1) the efficient generation of ‘numerical’ ignition delay data for surrogate fuels at different pressure, temperature, equivalence ratio and EGR levels for which the variations span much larger ranges than typically available from experiments, 2) the rapid parameterization of this dataset by means of genetic algorithms to derive “initial estimates” for the three-stage ignition model parameters, for which in 3) the final values are determined by retuning the pre-exponential parameters of the low and high ignition delay terms based on a wide range of measurements in a RCEM. To conclude the new methodology has successfully extended the application of the 3-Arrhenius model to Toluene Reference Fuels (TRFs), longer-chain alkanes and oxygenated fuels. The efficiency and robustness of the new methodology compared to the traditional usage of exclusively experimental data for model parameterization considerably extends its applicability to auto-ignition modeling for a variety of fuels. This will allow for broader use of such models for different fuels for HCCI engine calibration and control.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yao M., Zheng Z., and Liu H., “Progress and recent trends in homogeneous charge compression ignition (HCCI) engines,” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci., vol. 35, no. 5, pp. 398-437, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barroso G., “Chemical kinetic mechanism reduction, multi-zone and 3D- CRFD Modelling of homogeneous charge compression ignition engines,” ETH Zurich PhD Thesis, no. 16437, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aceves, S., Flowers, D., Westbrook, C., Smith, J. et al., "A Multi-Zone Model for Prediction of HCCI Combustion and Emissions," SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0327, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0327.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Visakhamoorthy S., Tzanetakis T., Haggith D., Sobiesiak A., and Wen J. Z., “Numerical study of a homogeneous charge compression ignition (HCCI) engine fueled with biogas,” Appl. Energy, vol. 92, pp. 437-446, Apr. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aceves, S., Flowers, D., Martinez-Frias, J., Espinosa-Loza, F. et al., "Analysis of the Effect of Geometry Generated Turbulence on HCCI Combustion by Multi-Zone Modeling," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01- 2134, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, J., Miller, D., and Cernansky, N., "A Global Reaction Model for the HCCI Combustion Process," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2950, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2950.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vandersickel A., Wright Y. M., and Boulouchos K., “Global reaction mechanism for the auto-ignition of full boiling range gasoline and kerosene fuels,” Combust. Theory Model., 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Voglsam S. and Winter F., “A global combustion model for simulation of n-heptane and iso-octane self ignition,” Chem. Eng. J., vol. 203, pp. 357-369, Sep. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gowdagiri S. and Oehlschlaeger M. A., “Global Reduced Model for Conventional and Alternative Jet and Diesel Fuel Autoignition,” Energy &amp; Fuels, vol. 28, no. 4, pp. 2795-2801, Apr. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang H., Yao M., and Reitz R. D., “Development of a Reduced Primary Reference Fuel Mechanism for Internal Combustion Engine Combustion Simulations,” Energy &amp; Fuels, vol. 27, no. 12, pp. 7843-7853, Nov. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brakora, J. and Reitz, R., "A Comprehensive Combustion Model for Biodiesel-Fueled Engine Simulations," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01- 1099, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1099.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsurushima T., “A new skeletal PRF kinetic model for HCCI combustion,” Proc. Combust. Inst., vol. 32, no. 2, pp. 2835-2841, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">PrinceJ. C., Williams F. A., and Ovando G. E., “A short mechanism for the low-temperature ignition of n-heptane at high pressures,” Fuel, vol. 149, pp. 138-142, Jun. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CurranH. J., Pitz W. J., Westbrook C. K., Callahan G. V, and Dryer F. L., “Oxidation of automotive primary reference fuels at elevated pressures,” Symp. Int. Combust., vol. 27, no. 1, pp. 379-387, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">WestbrookC. K., Pitz W. J., Herbinet O., Curran H. J., and Silke E. J., “A comprehensive detailed chemical kinetic reaction mechanism for combustion of n-alkane hydrocarbons from n-octane to n-hexadecane,” Combust. Flame, vol. 156, no. 1, pp. 181-199, Jan. 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saisirirat P., Togbé C., Chanchaona S., Foucher F., Mounaim-Rousselle C., and Dagaut P., “Auto-ignition and combustion characteristics in HCCI and JSR using 1-butanol/n-heptane and ethanol/n-heptane blends,” Proc. Combust. Inst., vol. 33, no. 2, pp. 3007-3014, Jan. 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehl M., Pitz W. J., Westbrook C. K., and Curran H. J., “Kinetic modeling of gasoline surrogate components and mixtures under engine conditions,” Proc. Combust. Inst., vol. 33, no. 1, pp. 193-200, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh S., Reitz R. D., Musculus M. P. B., and Lachaux T., “Validation of engine combustion models against detailed in-cylinder optical diagnostics data for a heavy-duty compression-ignition engine,” Int. J. Engine Res., vol. 8, no. 1, pp. 97-126, Feb. 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salehi F., Talei M., Hawkes E. R., Yoo C. S., Lucchini T., D’Errico G., and Kook S., “Conditional moment closure modelling for HCCI with temperature inhomogeneities,” Proc. Combust. Inst., vol. 35, no. 3, pp. 3087-3095, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bolla M., Farrace D., Wright Y. M., and Boulouchos K., “Modelling of soot formation in a heavy-duty diesel engine with conditional moment closure,” Fuel, vol. 117, pp. 309-325, Jan. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrace, D., Bolla, M., Wright, Y., and Boulouchos, K., "Numerical Study of the Influence of EGR on In-Cylinder Soot Characteristics in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine using CMC," SAE Int. J. Engines 7(1):256- 268, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhen X. and Wang Y., “Numerical analysis of knock during HCCI in a high compression ratio methanol engine based on LES with detailed chemical kinetics,” Energy Convers. Manag., vol. 96, pp. 188-196, May 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LuongM. B., Lu T., Chung S. H., and Yoo C. S., “Direct numerical simulations of the ignition of a lean biodiesel/air mixture with temperature and composition inhomogeneities at high pressure and intermediate temperature,” Combust. Flame, vol. 161, no. 11, pp. 2878- 2889, Nov. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sankaran R., Im H. G., Hawkes E. R., and Chen J. H., “The effects of non-uniform temperature distribution on the ignition of a lean homogeneous hydrogen-air mixture,” Proc. Combust. Inst., vol. 30, no. 1, pp. 875-882, Jan. 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bolla M., Schmitt M., Hawkes E. R., and Boulouchos K., “A DNS study of ignition characteristics of a lean H2/air mixture under HCCI conditions within an enclosed geometry including wall heat transfer,” in 15th International Conference on Numerical Combustion, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrell, J., Cernansky, N., Dryer, F., Law, C. et al., "Development of an Experimental Database and Kinetic Models for Surrogate Diesel Fuels," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0201, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0201.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pitz, W., Cernansky, N., Dryer, F., Egolfopoulos, F. et al., "Development of an Experimental Database and Chemical Kinetic Models for Surrogate Gasoline Fuels," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0175, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0175.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrae J. C. G. and Head R. A., “HCCI experiments with gasoline surrogate fuels modeled by a semidetailed chemical kinetic model,” Combust. Flame, vol. 156, no. 4, pp. 842-851, Apr. 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akih-Kumgeh B. and Bergthorson J. M., “Comparative Study of Methyl Butanoate and n-Heptane High Temperature Autoignition,” Energy &amp; Fuels, vol. 24, no. 4, pp. 2439-2448, Apr. 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DavidsonD. F. and Hanson R. K., “Interpreting shock tube ignition data,” Int. J. Chem. Kinet., vol. 36, no. 9, pp. 510-523, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BeckS. A., “Beschreibung des Zündverzuges von dieselähnlichen Kraftstoffen im HCCI-Betrieb,” Univ. Stuttgart PhD Thesis, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shahbakhti M. and Koch C. R., “Physics Based Control Oriented Model for HCCI Combustion Timing,” J. Dyn. Syst. Meas. Control, vol. 132, no. 2, p. 21010, Feb. 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">RausenD. J., Stefanopoulou A. G., J.-Kang M., Eng J. A., and Kuo T.-W., “A Mean-Value Model for Control of Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Engines,” J. Dyn. Syst. Meas. Control, vol. 127, no. 3, pp. 355-362, Aug. 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He X., Zigler B. T., Walton S. M., Wooldridge M. S., and Atreya A., “A rapid compression facility study of OH time histories during iso-octane ignition,” Combust. Flame, vol. 145, no. 3, pp. 552-570, May 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hernández J. J., Sanz-Argent J., Carot J. M., and Jabaloyes J. M., “Ignition delay time correlations for a diesel fuel with application to engine combustion modelling,” Int. J. Engine Res., vol. 11, no. 3, pp. 199-206, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yates A., Bell A., and Swarts A., “Insights relating to the autoignition characteristics of alcohol fuels,” Fuel, vol. 89, no. 1, pp. 83-93, Jan. 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GoldsboroughS. S., “A chemical kinetically based ignition delay correlation for iso-octane covering a wide range of conditions including the NTC region,” Combust. Flame, vol. 156, no. 6, pp. 1248-1262, Jun. 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steurs, K., Blomberg, C., and Boulouchos, K., "Formulation of a Knock Model for Ethanol and Iso-Octane under Specific Consideration of the Thermal Boundary Layer within the End-Gas," SAE Int. J. Engines 7(4):1752-1772, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2607.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weisser G. A., “Modelling of Combustion and Nitric Oxide Formation for Medium-Speed DI Diesel Engines: A comparative Evaluation of Zero- and Three-Dimensional Approaches,” ETH Zurich PhD Thesis, no. 14465, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Campbell M. F., Davidson D. F., and Hanson R. K., “Scaling relation for high-temperature biodiesel surrogate ignition delay times,” Fuel, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus M. P. B., Miles P. C., and Pickett L. M., “Conceptual models for partially premixed low-temperature diesel combustion,” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci., vol. 39, no. 2-3, pp. 246-283, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., Hwang, W., and Sjöberg, M., "An Investigation of Thermal Stratification in HCCI Engines Using Chemiluminescence Imaging," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1518, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1518.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmitt M., Frouzakis C. E., Tomboulides A. G., Wright Y. M., and Boulouchos K., “Direct numerical simulation of the effect of compression on the flow, temperature and composition under engine-like conditions,” Proc. Combust. Inst., Jul. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sherazi H. Iqbal and Li Y., “Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition engine: A technical review,” in Automation and Computing (ICAC), 2011 17th International Conference on, 2011, pp. 315-320.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herold, R., Krasselt, J., Foster, D., Ghandhi, J. et al., "Investigations into the Effects of Thermal and Compositional Stratification on HCCI Combustion - Part II: Optical Engine Results," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1034-1053, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goldsborough S. S., Banyon C., and Mittal G., “A computationally efficient, physics-based model for simulating heat loss during compression and the delay period in RCM experiments,” Combust. Flame, vol. 159, no. 12, pp. 3476-3492, Dec. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lim O. T. and Iida N., “The investigation about the effects of thermal stratification in combustion chamber on HCCI combustion fueled with DME/n-Butane using Rapid Compression Machine,” Exp. Therm. Fluid Sci., vol. 39, pp. 123-133, May 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stanglmaier, R. and Roberts, C., "Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI): Benefits, Compromises, and Future Engine Applications," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3682, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3682.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yu, R., Bai, X., Vressner, A., Hultqvist, A. et al., "Effect of Turbulence on HCCI Combustion," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0183, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0183.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saxena S. and Bedoya I. D., “Fundamental phenomena affecting low temperature combustion and HCCI engines, high load limits and strategies for extending these limits,” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci., vol. 39, no. 5, pp. 457-488, Oct. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanaka S., Ayala F., Keck J. C., and Heywood J. B., “Two-stage ignition in HCCI combustion and HCCI control by fuels and additives,” Combust. Flame, vol. 132, no. 1-2, pp. 219-239, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yao, M., Liu, H., Zhang, B., and Zheng, Z., "An Investigation on the Effects of Fuel Chemistry and Engine Operating Conditions on HCCI Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1660, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008- 01-1660.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vandersickel A., Hartmann M., Vogel K., Wright Y. M., Fikri M., Starke R., Schulz C., and Boulouchos K., “The autoignition of practical fuels at HCCI conditions: High-pressure shock tube experiments and phenomenological modeling,” Fuel, vol. 93, pp. 492-501, Mar. 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>54.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mitakos D. A., “Experimental Investigations for Phenomenological Modelling of Two-Stage Auto-Ignition under HCCI Conditions,” ETH Zurich PhD Thesis, no. 22323, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>55.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goldsborough, S., "Evaluating the Heat Losses from HCCI Combustion within a Rapid Compression Expansion Machine," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0870, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0870.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>56.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vandersickel A., “Two Approaches to Auto-ignition Modelling for HCCI Applications,” ETH Zurich PhD Thesis, no. 19965, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>57.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Livengood J. C. and Wu P. C., “Correlation of autoignition phenomena in internal combustion engines and rapid compression machines,” Symp. Combust., vol. 5, no. 1, pp. 347-356, Jan. 1955.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>58.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bardi M., Blomberg C., Mitakos D. A., Schneider B., Wright Y. M., and Boulouchos K., “Effect of fuel composition and in cylinder conditions on HCCI combustion in an optically accessible Rapid Compression Expansion Machine,” Prog.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>59.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schlatter, S., Schneider, B., Wright, Y., and Boulouchos, K., "Experimental Study of Ignition and Combustion Characteristics of a Diesel Pilot Spray in a Lean Premixed Methane/Air Charge using a Rapid Compression Expansion Machine," SAE Technical Paper 2012- 01-0825, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0825.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>60.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mitakos, D., Blomberg, C., Wright, Y., Obrecht, P. et al., "Integration of a Cool-Flame Heat Release Rate Model into a 3-Stage Ignition Model for HCCI Applications and Different Fuels," SAE Technical Paper 2014- 01-1268, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1268.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <label>61.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mitakos, D., Blomberg, C., Vandersickel, A., Wright, Y. et al., "Ignition Delays of Different Homogeneous Fuel-air Mixtures in a Rapid Compression Expansion Machine and Comparison with a 3-Stageignition Model Parameterized on Shock Tube Data," SAE Int. J. Engines 6(4):1934-1952, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2625.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <label>62.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grogan K. P., Goldsborough S. Scott, and Ihme M., “Ignition regimes in rapid compression machines,” Combust. Flame, vol. 162, no. 8, pp. 3071-3080, Aug. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <label>63.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmitt M., Frouzakis C. E., Wright Y. M., Tomboulides A. G., and Boulouchos K., “Investigation of wall heat transfer and thermal stratification under engine-relevant conditions using DNS,” Int. J. Engine Res., Jun. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <label>64.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmitt M., “Direct numerical simulations in engine-like geometries,” ETH Zurich PhD Thesis, no. 22284, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <label>65.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sung C.-J. and Curran H. J., “Using rapid compression machines for chemical kinetics studies,” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci., vol. 44, pp. 1-18, Oct. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
