<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308499</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Spray Pattern Optimization for the Duratec 3.5L EcoBoost Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Iyer</surname>
                  <given-names>Claudia O.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yi</surname>
                  <given-names>Jianwen</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>1679</fpage>
         <lpage>1689</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308499"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A systematic methodology has been employed to develop the Duratec 3.5L EcoBoost combustion system, with focus on the optimization of the combustion system including injector spray pattern, intake port design, piston geometry, cylinder head geometry. The development methodology was led by CFD (Computational Fluid Dynamics) modeling together with a testing program that uses optical, single-cylinder, and multi-cylinder engines. The current study shows the effect of several spray patterns on air-fuel mixing, in-cylinder flow development, surface wetting, and turbulence intensity. A few sets of injector spray patterns are studied; some that have a wide total cone angle, some that have a narrow cone angle and a couple of optimized injector spray patterns. The effect of the spray pattern at part load, full load and cold start operation was investigated and the methodology for choosing an optimized injector is presented. The preliminary dynamometer data obtained from a direct injection engine equipped with the optimized 6-hole injector indicated good mixing at part load and Wide-Open Throttle (WOT) operating conditions. Higher combustion efficiency and lower CO emissions at most operating points indicate better mixing for the DI engine than the baseline PFI engine. The optimized injector was able to demonstrate lower smoke emissions than the baseline injector.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Potteau, S., Lutz, P., Leroux, S., Moroz, S., and Tomas, E., Cooled EGR for a Turbo SI Engine to Reduce Knocking and Fuel Consumption, presented at SAE PT &amp; Fluid Sys. Conf, Rosemont, IL, SAE 2007-01-3978, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hancock, D., Fraser, N., Jeremy, M., Sykes, and R., Blaxill, H., New 3 Cylinder 1.2L Advanced Downsizing Technology Demonstrator Engine, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2008- 01-0611, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw-Hill, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lang, O., Habermann, K., Krebber-Hortmann, K., Sehr, A., Thewes, M., Kleeberg, H., and Tomazic, D., Potential of the Spray-Guided Combustion System in Combination with Turbocharging, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2008- 01-0139, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kleeberg, H., Tomazic, D., Lang, O., and Habermann, K., Future Potential and Development Methods for High Output Turbocharged Direct Injected Gasoline Engines, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2006-01-0046, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, A., Weaver, C., Wooldridge, S., Alger, T., Hilditch, J., McGee, J., Westrate, B., Xu, Z, Yi, J., Chen, X., Trigui, N., and Davis, G., Development of a New Light Stratified-Charge DISI Combustion System for a Family of Engines With Upfront CFD Coupling With Thermal and Optical Engine Experiments, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2004-01-0545, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wirth, M., Mayerhofer, U., Piock, W. F., and Fraidl, G.K., Turbocharging the DI Gasoline Engine, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2000- 01-0251, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noyori, T. and Inoue, H., Effects of Fuel Spray Characteristics on Smoke Emissions in a Small Displacement Spark-Ignition Direct Injection, SAE 2007-01-3492, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden, A.A., KIVA-3V: A Block-Structured KIVA Program for Engines with Vertical or Canted Valves. Los Alamos National Laboratory Report LA-13313- MS, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden, A.A., KIVA-3V, Release 2: Improvements to KIVA-3V. Los Alamos National Laboratory Report LA-13608-MS, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z. and Xu, Z., Wall Film Dynamics Modeling for Impinging Sprays in Engines, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2004-01-0099, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liang, L. and Reitz, R.D., Spark Ignition Engine Combustion Modeling Using a Level Set Method with Detailed Chemistry, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2006-01-0243, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liang, L., Reitz, R.D., Iyer, C.O., and Yi, J., Modeling Knock in Spark-Ignition Engines Using a G-equation Combustion Model Incorporating Detailed Chemical Kinetics, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2007-01-0165, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yi, J., Han, Z., Yang, J., Anderson, R., Trigui, N., and Boussarsar, R., Modeling of the Interaction of Intake Flow and Fuel Spray in DISI Engines, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2000-01-0656, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yi, J., Han, Z., and Trigui, N., Fuel-air Mixing Homogeneity and Performance Improvements of a Stratified-Charge DISI Combustion System, presented at SAE PT &amp; Fluid Sys. Conf, San Diego, CA, SAE 2002-01-2656, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yi, J., Han, Z., Xu, Z., and Stanley, L.E., Combustion Improvement of a Light Stratified-Charge Direct Injection Engine, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2004-01-0546, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z., Yi, J. and Trigui, N., Stratified Mixture Formation and Piston Surface Wetting in a DISI Engine, presented at SAE PT &amp; Fluid Sys. Conf, San Diego, CA, SAE 2002-01-2655, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">VanDerWege, B., Han, Z., Iyer, C.O., Munoz, R.H., and Yi, J., Development and Analysis of a Spray- Guided DISI Combustion System Concept, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2003- 01-3105, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iyer, C.O., Han, Z., and Yi, J., CFD Modeling of a Vortex-Induced Stratification Combustion (VISC) System, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2004-01-0550, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yi, J., Wooldridge, S., Coulson, G., Hilditch, J. et al., “Development and Optimization of the Ford 3.5L V6 EcoBoost Combustion System” SAE Int. J. Engines :1388-1407, 2009. 1 6 8 8 SAE Int. J. Engines | Volume 2 | Issue 1 2(1)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kapp, D., Schamel, A., Hinds, B., and Weaver, C., 3.5L V6 EcoBoost – Democratization of Sustainable Engine Technology, presented at the Aachen Colloquium, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iyer, C.O. and Yi, J., 3D CFD Upfront Optimization of the In-Cylinder Flow of the 3.5L V6 EcoBoost Engine, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2009-01-1492, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, Z., Yi, J., Wooldridge, S., Reiche, D. et al., “Modeling the Cold Start of the Ford 3.5L V6 EcoBoost Engine” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1367- 1387, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reiche, D., Wooldridge, S., Moilanen, P., and Davis, G., Experimental Optimization of the Cold Start for the EcoBoost Engine, presented at the SAE World Congress, SAE 2009-01-1491, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z and Reitz, R.D. (1995). Turbulence Modeling of Internal Combustion Engines Using RNG kmodels. Combust. Sci. Tech., 106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dai, W., Trigui, N., Lu, Y., Modeling of cyclic variations in spark-ignition engines, presented at SAE Int'l. Spring Fuels &amp; Lubs. Mtg., Paris, France, SAE-2000-01-2036, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yi, Y. and Reitz, R.D., Modeling the effect of primary atomization on Diesel engine emissions, SAE 2003- 01-1041.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
