<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Bergamo University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">32</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830963</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830969</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE ROLE OF NON-GOVERNMENT ORGANISATIONS IN MICROFINANCE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Barclay</given-names>
                  <surname>O'Brien</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2008</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>103</fpage>
         <lpage>115</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2008 Bergamo University Press</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830969"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper contends that international Non-Governmental Organisations (NGOs) have played a substantial role in developing financial services for the poor (or microfinance). Their influence has been greatest in: • Pursuing a broader common vision and mission, particularly towards the poorest; • Offering clients a larger range of products and services; • Better engaging with industry regulators; • Advocating for microfinance generally and conducting research. Furthermore, even in cases where the role of these NGO Networks is no greater than other microfinance network support organizations, it appears the former are more willing to subsidise the costs of these benefits, such as with respect to innovation and creativity. Secondly, the financial performance of the NGO networks and the NGO microfinance institutions themselves do not suffer as a result. Based on the available evidence, there is no significant variation in the performance of NGO MFIs around the world compared to the average for all MFIs. In Asia, the NGOs perform slightly worse than the average in three out of four indicators. Therefore, whilst the long-term trend is likely to see more formal and regulated financial institutions delivering microfinance, the NGO Networks themselves will retain a crucial role in the sector as a whole. Cet article présente l'idée que les organisations non gouvernementales (ONG) internationales ont joué un rôle substantiel dans le développement des services financiers pour le pauvres. Leur influence à été particulièrement importante dans la poursuite d'une vision et d'une mission plus amples et partagées vers les pauvres, dans l'offre d'une plus vaste gamme de produits et services, dans l'engagement des autorités de réglementation, supporter la microfinance et la recherche dans le secteur. En plus, même quand le rôle des ONG n'est pas plus important de ce des réseaux de microfinance, il paraît que les ONG soutiennent plus volontiers les coûts lié aux effets positifs, tels que l'innovation et la créativité. En outre, la performance ne souffre pas pour cela. Basé sur l'évidence empirique, il n'y a pas de variation significative dans la performance des intermédiaires de microfinance qui sont ONG par rapports aux autres intermédiaires de microfinance. In Asia, les ONG ont des indicateurs légèrement plus mauvais dans trois cas sur quatre. Il en descend que, même si les intermédiaires formels de microfinance auront une croissance, les réseaux de microfinance auront aussi un rôle crucial dans le secteur.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d15e152a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e159" publication-type="other">
www.themix.org.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e166a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e173" publication-type="other">
Sebstad and Cohen
(2000)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e183a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e190" publication-type="other">
CGAP (2004), page
6</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e200a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e207" publication-type="other">
Bedson and Renzaho (2006), page 43</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d15e223a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e227" publication-type="other">
Bedson J. and A. M. N. Renzaho, 2006, "Microfinance Good Practice and World Vi-
sion Australia: The Challenge of a Poverty Focus in an Evolving Industry", Work-
ing Paper, No. 2006/001PE, World Vision.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e240a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e244" publication-type="other">
CGAP, 2004, "What is a Network? The Diversity of Networks in Microfinance To-
day", Focus Note, No. 26, Washington, DC: CGAP.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e254a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e258" publication-type="other">
CGAP, 2004a, "Key Principles of Microfinance", principles endorsed by CGAP and its
31 member donors, and further endorsed by the Group of Eight leaders at the G8
Summit on 10 June 2004.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e271a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e275" publication-type="other">
Daley-Harris S., 2005, "State of the Microcredit Summit Campaign Report 2005", Mi-
crocredit Summit Campaign, Washington D.C.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e286a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e290" publication-type="other">
Dunford C, 1998, "Microfinance: A Means to What End?", presented to the Dialogue
on Microfinance and Human Development, 1-3 April 1998, Stockholm, Sweden:
available at 'www.gdrc.org/icm/dunford-ffh.htmr.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e303a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e307" publication-type="other">
Fernando N.A., 2004, Micro Success Story? Transformation of Nongovernment Organisa-
tions into Regulated Financial Institutions, Asian Development Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e317a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e321" publication-type="other">
Gonzalez A. and R. Rosenberg, 2006, The State of Microcredit - Outreach, Profitability,
and Poverty, presented in the conference "Access to Finance: Building Inclusive Fi-
nancial Systems" organized by the World Bank and Brookings Institution, March
2006, Washington D.C.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e337a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e341" publication-type="other">
Morduch ]., 2000, "The Microfinance Schism", World Development, Vol. 28, No. 4, pp.
617-629.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e351a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e355" publication-type="other">
Sebstab J. and M. Cohen, 2000, "Microfinance, Risk Management and Poverty", AIMS
paper, Office of Microenterprise Development, US AID, Washington D.C.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e365a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e369" publication-type="other">
Simanowitz A., 2002, Ensuring Impact: Reaching the Poorest while Building Financially
Self-Sufficient Institutions, and Showing Improvement in the Lives of the Poorest Women
and Their Families, Institute of Development Studies, UK, Bloomfield: Connecticut.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


