<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285101</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Significance of RON, MON, and LTHR for Knock Limits of Compositionally Dissimilar Gasoline Fuels in a DISI Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Vuilleumier</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Sjöberg</surname>
                  <given-names>Magnus</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>June 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285080</issue-id>
         <fpage>938</fpage>
         <lpage>950</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285101"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Spark-ignition (SI) engine efficiency is typically limited by fuel auto-ignition resistance, which is described in practice by the Research Octane Number (RON) and the Motor Octane Number (MON). The goal of this work is to assess whether fuel properties (i.e. RON, MON, and heat of vaporization) are sufficient to describe the antiknock behavior of varying gasoline formulations in modern engines. To this end, the auto-ignition resistance of three compositionally dissimilar gasoline-like fuels with identical RON values and varying or non-varying MON values were evaluated in a modern, prototype, 12:1 compression ratio, high-swirl (by nature of intake valve deactivation), directly injected spark ignition (DISI) engine at 1400 RPM. The three gasolines are an alkylate blend (RON=98, MON=97), a blend with high aromatic content (RON=98, MON=88), and a blend of 30% ethanol by volume with a gasoline BOB (RON=98, MON=87; see Table 2 for details).</p>
            <p>The preliminary findings of this work are that RON and MON, when coupled with latent heat of vaporization information, are sufficient to describe the auto-ignition resistance of a fuel to a degree such that knock-limited combustion phasing shows no measurable differences. While the tested fuels yielded no inconsistencies between their ratings (RON and MON) and properties (latent heat of vaporization) and their performance in a DISI engine, measurable differences were found among the three tested fuels. Specifically, the manner in which the fuels obtained knock-resistance varied, be it through thermal tolerance, charge cooling, or lack of charge-heating Low-Temperature Heat Release (LTHR). In addition, the fuels’ knock-limited combustion phasing responses to variations in intake pressure and intake temperature varied with their thermal tolerance and tendency towards LTHR. Yet these dissimilar behaviors combine to produce similar anti-knock qualities and engine performance for naturally-aspirated operation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw- Hill, New York, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Department of Energy, “Co-Optimization of Fuels &amp; Engines.” Department of Energy, Web. 12 Oct. 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM 2699, “Research Octane Number Test.” 2016, www.astm.org/Standards/D2699</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM 2700, “Motor Octane Number Test.” 2016, www.astm.org/Standards/D2700</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stein, R., Polovina, D., Roth, K., Foster, M. , "Effect of Heat of Vaporization, Chemical Octane, and Sensitivity on Knock Limit for Ethanol - Gasoline Blends," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(2):823–843, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1277.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stein, R., Anderson, J., and Wallington, T., "An Overview of the Effects of Ethanol-Gasoline Blends on SI Engine Performance, Fuel Efficiency, and Emissions," SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):470–487, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1635.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morganti, K., Abdullah, M., Alzubail, A., Viollet, Y. , "Improving the Efficiency of Conventional Spark-Ignition Engines Using Octane-on- Demand Combustion. Part I: Engine Studies," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0679, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0679.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., "Fuel Anti-Knock Quality - Part I. Engine Studies," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3584, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3584.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Nakata, K., and Mogi, K., "Octane Appetite Studies in Direct Injection Spark Ignition (DISI) Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0244, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0244.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Morganti, K., Algunaibet, I., Sarathy, M. , "Knock Prediction Using a Simple Model for Ignition Delay," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0702, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0702.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sluder, C., Szybist, J., McCormick, R., Ratcliff, M. , "Exploring the Relationship Between Octane Sensitivity and Heat-of-Vaporization," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 9(1):80–90, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0836.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeng, W., Sjöberg, M., and Reuss, D., "Using PIV Measurements to Determine the Role of the In-Cylinder Flow Field for Stratified DISI Engine Combustion," SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):615–632, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1237.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Zeng, W., Singleton, D., Sanders, J. , "Combined Effects of Multi-Pulse Transient Plasma Ignition and Intake Heating on Lean Limits of Well-Mixed E85 DISI Engine Operation," SAE Int. J. Engines 7(4):1781–1801, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2615.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">"Petroleum Products Research." SwRI Brochure. Southwest Research Institute, n.d. Web. 12 Oct. 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shahlari, A., Hocking, C., Kurtz, E., and Ghandhi, J., "Comparison of Compression Ignition Engine Noise Metrics in Low-Temperature Combustion Regimes," SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):541–552, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1659.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">"Gamma Technologies | Engine and Vehicle Simulation." Gamma Technologies. Gamma Technologies, n.d. Web. 12 Oct. 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bradley, D., Morley, C., and Walmsley, H., "Relevance of Research and Motor Octane Numbers to the Prediction of Engine Autoignition," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1970, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CRC Performance Committee, “Coordinating Research Council Report No. 660,” May 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehl, M., Pitz, W., Sjöberg, M., and Dec, J., "Detailed Kinetic Modeling of Low-Temperature Heat Release for PRF Fuels in an HCCI Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1806, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1806.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., "EGR and Intake Boost for Managing HCCI Low-Temperature Heat Release over Wide Ranges of Engine Speed," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0051, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0051.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, Henry J., "A comprehensive modeling study of n-heptane oxidation." Combustion and flame 114.1 (1998): 149–177.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sarathy, S. Mani, "Ignition of alkane-rich FACE gasoline fuels and their surrogate mixtures." Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 35.1 (2015): 249–257.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vuilleumier, D., Selim, H., Dibble, R., and Sarathy, M., "Exploration of Heat Release in a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine with Primary Reference Fuels," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-2622, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2622.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehl, Marco "An approach for formulating surrogates for gasoline with application toward a reduced surrogate mechanism for CFD engine modeling." Energy &amp; Fuels 25.11 (2011): 5215–5223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vuilleumier, D., “The Effect of Ethanol Addition to Gasoline on Lowand Intermediate-Temperature Heat Release under Boosted Conditions in Kinetically Controlled Engines,” Ph.D. Dissertation, Mechanical Engineering Department, University of California at Berkeley, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
