<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24438309</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Symposium on Welfare Reform under the Labour Government: Part I</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Social Security in the UK under New Labour: What Did the Third Way Mean for Welfare Reform?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>MIKE</given-names>
                  <surname>BREWER</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>TOM</given-names>
                  <surname>CLARK</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>MATTHEW</given-names>
                  <surname>WAKEFIELD</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2002</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24438303</issue-id>
         <fpage>505</fpage>
         <lpage>537</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2002</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24438309"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>In 1997, the Labour Party was elected in the UK with few explicitly articulated ideas about social security reforms. This paper reviews the large number of subsequent reforms to social security, and argues that some consistent themes have emerged. A commitment to keep to the tight spending plans of the previous, Conservative, administration left little scope for increases in benefit spending during the first two years in office. Since that time, increases in the generosity of some social security programmes have been directed towards achieving certain goals. An emphasis on encouraging paid work has been a consistent theme, whilst aims of reducing poverty rates for children and pensioners have been emphasised since 1999. Spending to achieve these goals has often been directed through means-tested programmes, and there has been a related weakening of the link between paid National Insurance contributions and benefit entitlements. It remains to be seen whether reforms to the process of income assessment will increase take-up.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d15e211a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e218" publication-type="other">
The most important reforms are listed in Appendix A.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e225a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e232" publication-type="other">
The 'tax credits' are listed in Appendix C, where the pension credit is listed as a means-tested benefit because
it falls into this category in our data on the cost of different types of social security programme.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e242a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e249" publication-type="other">
A notable exception is that we do not include the cost of the children's tax credit because it operates as part of
the tax system by reducing an individual's income tax liability. It is operative in 2001/02 and 2002/03 only and
costs around £2 billion annually.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e262a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e269" publication-type="other">
For more details on historical trends, see Department for Work and Pensions (2002c) or Clark and Dilnot
(2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e280a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e287" publication-type="other">
Or from approximately £19 billion to approximately £24 billion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e294a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e301" publication-type="other">
See Appendix C for a comprehensive list of non-means-tested, non-contributory benefits and for lists of which
benefits fall into each of the other groups considered in Figure 2.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e311a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e318" publication-type="other">
For more on the government's thinking at this early stage in the parliament, see HM Treasury (1997 and
1998b).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e328a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e335" publication-type="other">
There has been an almost continual programme of incremental changes to the conditions attached to receiving
out-of-work benefits, so few sources review them all. Many of the incremental reforms are described in chapter
4 of successive Budget documents. One of the main legislative changes was the Welfare Reform and Pensions
Act 1999 (see House of Commons Library (1999a)). Other sources are Department for Education and
Employment (2001a and 2001b) and HM Treasury and Department for Work and Pensions (2001) on
JobCentre Plus, and Bennett (2002) on joint claims for jobseeker's allowance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e358a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e365" publication-type="other">
A related strand of reforms have included a number of small changes to benefit administration that have
sought to ease the transition from non-employment to employment by reducing the financial insecurity that
occurs when claimants have to apply or re-apply for benefits as they move into or out of work; some of these
appear in Table Al.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e381a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e388" publication-type="other">
Alistair Darling, speaking to the Guardian, 16 May 1999, cited in Social Security Select Committee (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e396a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e403" publication-type="other">
Authors' calculations using Households Below Average Income data-set for 2000-01.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e410a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e417" publication-type="other">
Table 1 shows that these benefits have actually risen by fractionally more than prices during this period. The
difference is explained by the fact that benefit rates are rounded to the nearest 5p.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e427a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e434" publication-type="other">
The pension credit is outlined by the government in Department for Work and Pensions (2001) and analysed
in Clark (2002). The child tax credit and the working tax credit are outlined in HM Treasury (2002b) and
analysed in Brewer, Clark and Myck (2001) and Brewer (2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e447a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e454" publication-type="other">
Department for Work and Pensions / Department of Social Security, various b.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e461a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e468" publication-type="other">
Department for Work and Pensions / Department of Social Security, various a.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e475a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e482" publication-type="other">
See, for example, the quote from Alistair Darling quoted in Social Security Select Committee (2000, para.
90).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e493a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e500" publication-type="other">
Brown, 2000b.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e507a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e514" publication-type="other">
The government has managed this by omitting irrelevant questions, such as details of pension contributions
being made, but also by asking fewer questions: the questions relating to employment, for example, take up one
page rather than four.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e527a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e534" publication-type="other">
The children's tax credit claim form is three pages, the child tax credit form is 12 pages and the WFTC form
is 19 pages.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e544a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e551" publication-type="other">
In what follows, details are drawn from Department for Work and Pensions (2001) for the pension credit and
from HM Treasury (2002b) for the working tax credit and new child tax credit; they are discussed in Clark
(2002) and Brewer, Clark and Myck (2001 ) respectively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e564a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e571" publication-type="other">
See Appendix C for a comprehensive list of contributory benefits.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e578a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e585" publication-type="other">
lt is interesting to note that the flat-rate system envisaged by Beveridge (1942) did not involve different
people paying different amounts of contributions in return for different entitlements. This became a feature of
the UK National Insurance system later, especially after the introduction of SERPS in 1978. We do not
consider this further, but for some discussion of how contributory benefits evolved in the UK after the Second
World War, see Social Security Select Committee (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e605a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e612" publication-type="other">
Although there is currently a commitment to increase the value by at least 2.5 per cent a year, even if the
price-inflation rate is lower than this.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e622a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e631" publication-type="other">
The scheme introduced in April 2002 entitles contributors to a pension that is earnings related, but less
strongly so than was the case in SERPS. This should be made flat-rate if and when it is considered that
'stakeholder pensions have established themselves' (Department of Social Security, 1998b). For more on S2P,
see Agulnik (1999), Disney, Emmerson and Tanner (1999) and House of Commons Library (1999a).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e647a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e654" publication-type="other">
Figures are for the 2002/03 National Insurance system.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e661a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e668" publication-type="other">
Data series measuring this on a consistent basis have only been available since the early 1960s.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e675a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e682" publication-type="other">
For example, the target to reduce the number of children in poverty by at least a quarter by 2004 is to be
assessed against a 1998 baseline with poverty defined as living in a household with income below 60 per cent
of the median (Department of Social Security, 2000a). Much of the government's supporting analysis and
thinking also uses this definition (see HM Treasury (1999b)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e698a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e705" publication-type="other">
Authors' calculations using Households Below Average Income data-set.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e713a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e720" publication-type="other">
Net of direct taxes, benefits, credits and tax credits.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e727a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e734" publication-type="other">
The unit of observation is the household. Incomes are measured before housing costs are deducted and are
adjusted for household composition using the McClements scale (see Department for Work and Pensions
(2002a, appendix B)). The modelled effects are estimated using the IFS tax and benefit simulation model,
TAXBEN, using data from the 1999/2000 Family Resources Survey. The estimates therefore take no account
of changes in the structure of the population or in the underlying income distribution during the period in
which the modelled reforms took place.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e757a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e764" publication-type="other">
We do not model changes to employers' National Insurance, nor some of the reforms to bereavement benefits
and incapacity benefit, partly because data limitations make it difficult to model these benefits and partly
because the reforms affect new claimants only. We do not have the expertise to model tax changes that are not
formally incident on households.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e780a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e787" publication-type="other">
2000/01 is the latest year for which such data are available. Some of Labour's important tax and benefit
reforms were already effective by this date, but some, including a large increase in the minimum income
guarantee for pensioners and the new credits, were not.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e800a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e807" publication-type="other">
But note that the results from the extremes of the income distribution may partly reflect the way in which the
Households Below Average Income data-set is constructed: the bottom decile of the data-set contains a high
proportion of people whose reported income over the relevant period seems to be much lower than their usual
income (for example, durable ownership and reported income tax liabilities are higher in the bottom decile than
in the second decile — see Clark, Giles and Hall (1999) for more details on this); the incomes of the very rich
are also thought to be less reliable in this data-set, though they are adjusted in an attempt to make them more
accurate (see Department for Work and Pensions (2002a, p. 249)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e833a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e840" publication-type="other">
See Piachaud and Sutherland (2001), although the figure for children is confirmed by other studies cited in
Brewer, Clark and Goodman (2002a). The latter reference also discusses in more detail why earlier estimates of
the fall in child poverty under Labour were higher than the outcome.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e854a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e861" publication-type="other">
Total social security expenditure includes some items that are not benefits in the usual sense — for example,
Pensions Compensation Board funding. These will typically be included in the 'non-contributory, non-means-
tested' category. Statutory sick pay and statutory maternity pay are included with contributory benefits as they
are funded from the National Insurance Fund, although they are not, strictly speaking, dependent on National
Insurance contributions. The pre-1988 maternity grant should logically also have been counted as contributory,
but has usually been in the 'non-contributory, non-means-tested' category. Sure Start maternity grants are part
of the income-related Social Fund. See footnote 3 for the children's tax credit.
Source: Department for Work and Pensions, personal communication.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d15e899a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e903" publication-type="other">
Agulnik, P. (1999), 'The proposed State Second Pension', Fiscal Studies, vol. 20, pp. 409-21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e910a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e914" publication-type="other">
Assinder, N. (2000), 'Brown risks jobs row', BBC News Online, 29 February, news.bbc.co.uk/hi/
english/uk_politics/newsid_659000/659755.stm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e924a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e928" publication-type="other">
Atkinson, A. B. (1995), Incomes and the Welfare State: Essays on Britain and Europe, Cambridge:
Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e938a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e942" publication-type="other">
Bennett, F. (2002), 'Gender implications of current social security reforms', Fiscal Studies, vol. 23,
pp. 559-84 (this issue).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e953a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e957" publication-type="other">
Beveridge, W. (1942), Social Insurance and Allied Services, Beveridge Report, Cmd 6404,
London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e967a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e971" publication-type="other">
Blair, T. (1996), speech to Labour Party Conference, 1 October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e978a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e982" publication-type="other">
— (1997), speech on opening of Social Exclusion Unit, 8 December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e989a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e993" publication-type="other">
— (1999), 'Beveridge revisited: a welfare state for the 21SI century', in R. Walker (ed.), Ending
Child Poverty: Popular Welfare for the 21" Century, Bristol: Policy Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1003a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1007" publication-type="other">
— (2001), transcript of BBC Newsnight interview, 5 June, news.bbc.co.uk/hi/english/events/
newsnight/newsid_1372000/1372220.stm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1017a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1021" publication-type="other">
Brewer, M. (2002), 'Personal tax reforms: the child tax credit and the working tax credit', in A.
Dilnot, C. Emmerson and H. Simpson (eds), The IFS Green Budget: January 2002,
Commentary no. 87, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1035a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1039" publication-type="other">
— and Clark, T. (2002), 'The impact on incentives of five years of social security reforms in the
UK', Institute for Fiscal Studies, Working Paper no. 02/14, www.ifs.org.uk/workingpapers/
wp0214.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1052a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1056" publication-type="other">
—, — and Goodman, A. (2002a), The Government's Child Poverty Target: How Much Progress
Has Been Made?, Commentary no. 88, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1066a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1070" publication-type="other">
—, — and — (2002b), 'What really happened to child poverty in the UK under Labour's first
term?', mimeo, Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1080a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1084" publication-type="other">
—, — and Myck, M. (2001), Credit Where It's Due? An Assessment of the New Tax Credits,
Commentary no. 86, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1094a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1098" publication-type="other">
—, — and Wakefield, M. (2002), 'Social security under new Labour: what did the third way mean
for welfare reform?', paper presented at IFS conference on Labour's social security reforms, 22
May, www.ifs.org.uk/conferences/socsec/clark.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1111a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1115" publication-type="other">
— and Gregg, P. (2001), 'Eradicating child poverty in Britain: welfare reform and children since
1997', Institute for Fiscal Studies, Working Paper no. 01/08, www.ifs.org.uk/workingpapers/
wp0108.pdf; forthcoming in R. Walker and M. Wiseman (eds), The Welfare We Want, Bristol:
Policy Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1132a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1136" publication-type="other">
Brown, G. (1993), speech to Labour Party Conference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1143a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1147" publication-type="other">
— (2000a), speech to East London Partnership, 29 February.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1154a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1158" publication-type="other">
— (2000b), speech to National Council for One-Parent Families, 5 December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1165a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1169" publication-type="other">
Child Poverty Action Group (various a), Welfare Rights Handbook, London: CPAG.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1176a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1180" publication-type="other">
— (various b), National Welfare Benefits Handbook, London: CPAG.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1187a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1191" publication-type="other">
Clark, T. (2002), Rewarding Saving and Alleviating Poverty? The Final Pension Credit Proposals,
Institute for Fiscal Studies, Briefing Note no. 22, www.ifs.org.uk/pensions/bn22.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1202a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1206" publication-type="other">
— and Dilnot, A. (2001), Election Briefing 2001, Commentary no. 84, London: Institute for Fiscal
Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1216a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1220" publication-type="other">
— and — (2002), Long-Term Trends in British Taxation and Spending, Institute for Fiscal Studies,
Briefing Note no. 25, www.ifs.org.uk/public/bn25.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1230a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1234" publication-type="other">
—, Giles, C. and Hall, J. (1999), Does Council Tax Benefit Work?, London: Institute for Fiscal
Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1244a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1248" publication-type="other">
— and Goodman, A. (2001), 'Living standards under Labour', in T. Clark and A. Dilnot (eds),
Election Briefing 2001, Commentary no. 84, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1258a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1262" publication-type="other">
Department for Education and Employment (2001a), JobCentre Plus: Pathfinder Service Delivery
Vision, London: DfEE.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1272a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1276" publication-type="other">
— (2001b), Towards Full Employment in a Modern Society, Cm. 5084, London: The Stationery
Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1287a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1291" publication-type="other">
Department for Work and Pensions (2001), The Pension Credit: The Government's Proposals,
www.dwp.gov.uk/publications/dwp/2001/pencred/pencred.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1301a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1305" publication-type="other">
— (2002a), Households Below Average Income, 1994/5-2000/1, London: Government Statistical
Service.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1315a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1319" publication-type="other">
— (2002b), Measuring Child Poverty: A Consultation Document, London: DWP.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1326a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1330" publication-type="other">
— (2002c), Benefit Expenditure Tables, www.dwp.gov.uk/asd/asd4/expenditure.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1337a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1341" publication-type="other">
— (2002d), Building Choice and Responsibility: A Radical Agenda for Housing Benefit, London:
DWP.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1351a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1355" publication-type="other">
— / Department of Social Security (various a), Income Support Quarterly Statistical Enquiry,
London: DWP/DSS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1366a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1370" publication-type="other">
— /— (various b), Jobseeker's Allowance Quarterly Statistical Enquiry, London: DWP/DSS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1377a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1381" publication-type="other">
Department of Social Security (1998a), New Ambitions for Our Country: A New Contract for
Welfare, Cm. 3805, London: The Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1391a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1395" publication-type="other">
— (1998b), A New Contract for Welfare: Partnership in Pensions, Cm. 4179, London: DSS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1402a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1406" publication-type="other">
— (2000a), Public Service Agreement, 2001-2004: Technical Note, www.dss.gov.uk/publications/
dss/2000/psa_tech/psatech.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1416a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1420" publication-type="other">
— (2000b), The Pension Credit: A Consultation Paper, Cm. 4900, London: The Stationery Office
(www.dwp.gov.uk/consultations/consult/2000/pencred/index.htm).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1430a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1434" publication-type="other">
Dilnot, A., Emmerson, C. and Simpson, H. (eds), The IFS Green Budget: January 2002,
Commentary no. 87, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1445a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1449" publication-type="other">
Disney, R., Emmerson, C. and Tanner, S. (1999), Partnership in Pensions: An Assessment,
Commentary no. 78, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1459a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1463" publication-type="other">
Field, F. (1995), Making Welfare Work, London: Institute of Community Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1470a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1474" publication-type="other">
— (1997), Reforming Welfare, London: Social Market Foundation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1481a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1485" publication-type="other">
Goodman, A. (2001), Inequality and Living Standards in Great Britain: Some Facts, Institute for
Fiscal Studies, Briefing Note no. 19, www.ifs.org.uk/inequality/bnl9.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1495a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1499" publication-type="other">
Government Actuary's Department (2000), National Insurance Fund — Long-Term Financial
Estimates: Report by the Government Actuary on the Financial Effects on the National
Insurance Fund of the Child Support, Pensions and Social Security Bill 1999,
www.archive.official-documents.co.uk/document/cm45/4573/4573.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1515a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1519" publication-type="other">
Hills, J. (2002), 'Following or leading public opinion? Social security policy and public attitudes
since 1997', Fiscal Studies, vol. 23, pp. 539-58 (this issue).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1530a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1534" publication-type="other">
HM Treasury (1997), Employment Opportunity in a Changing Labour Market, The Modernisation
of Britain's Tax and Benefit System, no. 1, London: HM Treasury.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1544a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1548" publication-type="other">
— (1998a), New Ambitions for Britain, HC 620, London: The Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1555a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1559" publication-type="other">
— (1998b), Work Incentives: A Report by Martin Taylor, The Modernisation of Britain's Tax and
Benefit System, no. 2, London: HM Treasury.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1569a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1573" publication-type="other">
— (1998c), The Working Families' Tax Credit, The Modernisation of Britain's Tax and Benefit
System, no. 3, London: HM Treasury.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1583a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1587" publication-type="other">
— (1999a), Building a Stronger Economic Future for Britain, HC 298, London: The Stationery
Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1597a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1601" publication-type="other">
— (1999b), Supporting Children through the Tax and Benefit System, The Modernisation of
Britain's Tax and Benefit System, no. 5, London: HM Treasury.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1612a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1616" publication-type="other">
— (2000a), Pre-Budget Report 2000: Building Long-Term Prosperity for All, London: The
Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1626a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1630" publication-type="other">
— (2000b), Prudent for a Purpose: Working for a Stronger and Fairer Britain, London: The
Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1640a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1644" publication-type="other">
— (2001a), Saving and Assets for All, The Modernisation of Britain's Tax and Benefit System, no.
8, London: HM Treasury.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1654a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1658" publication-type="other">
— (2001b), Investing for the Long Term: Building Opportunity and Prosperity for All, London:
The Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1668a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1672" publication-type="other">
— (2002a), The Strength to Make Long-Term Decisions: Investing in an Enterprising, Fairer
Britain, HC 592, London: The Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1682a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1686" publication-type="other">
— (2002b), The Child and Working Tax Credits, The Modernisation of Britain's Tax and Benefit
System, no. 10, London: HM Treasury.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1697a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1701" publication-type="other">
— and Department for Work and Pensions (2001), The Changing Welfare State: Employment
Opportunity for All, London: HM Treasury and Department for Work and Pensions.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1711a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1715" publication-type="other">
House of Commons Library (1999a), 'Welfare Reform and Pensions Bill', Research Paper no.
99/19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1725a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1729" publication-type="other">
— (1999b), 'Child support provisions in the Child Support, Pensions and Social Security Bill',
Research Paper no. 99/110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1739a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1743" publication-type="other">
— (2002), 'The burden of taxation', Research Paper no. 02/43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1750a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1754" publication-type="other">
Inland Revenue (2001), New Tax Credits: Supporting Families, Making Work Pay and Tackling
Poverty, London: Inland Revenue.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1764a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1768" publication-type="other">
Labour Party (1992), It's Time to Get Britain Working Again, Labour Party election manifesto,
London: Labour Party.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1779a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1783" publication-type="other">
— (1997), Britain Deserves Better, Labour Party election manifesto, London: Labour Party.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1790a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1794" publication-type="other">
Lister, R. (2001a), 'Work for those who can, security for those who cannot: a third way in social
security reform or fractured social citizenship?', in R. Edwards and J. Glover (eds), Risk in
Citizenship: Key Issues in Welfare, London: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1807a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1811" publication-type="other">
— (2001b), 'New Labour: a study in ambiguity from a position of ambivalence', in Critical Social
Policy, vol. 21, no. 4, pp. 425-47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1821a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1825" publication-type="other">
Piachaud, D. and Sutherland, H. (2001), 'How effective is the British government's attempt to
reduce child poverty?', Economic Journal, vol. 111, pp. F85-101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1835a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1839" publication-type="other">
Social Security Select Committee (2000), The Contributory Principle, HC 56-1, London: The
Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1849a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1853" publication-type="other">
Timmins, N. (1995, revised 2001), The Five Giants: A Biography of the Welfare State, new
edition, London: HarperCollins Publishers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1864a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1868" publication-type="other">
Walker, R. (ed.) (2001), Ending Child Poverty: Popular Welfare for the 21s' Century, Bristol:
Policy Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1878a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1882" publication-type="other">
Watt, N. (2000), 'Brown tells jobless to fill jobs', Guardian, 28 February.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
