<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277830</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effects of Real-Fluid Thermodynamics on High-Pressure Fuel Injection Processes</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Oefelein</surname>
                  <given-names>Joseph</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lacaze</surname>
                  <given-names>Guilhem</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dahms</surname>
                  <given-names>Rainer</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ruiz</surname>
                  <given-names>Anthony</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Misdariis</surname>
                  <given-names>Antony</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Renault SAS</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>August 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277829</issue-id>
         <fpage>1125</fpage>
         <lpage>1136</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277830"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper first summarizes a new theoretical description that quantifies the effects of real-fluid thermodynamics on liquid fuel injection processes as a function of pressure at typical engine operating conditions. It then focuses on the implications this has on modeling such flows with emphasis on application of the Large Eddy Simulation (LES) technique. The theory explains and quantifies the major differences that occur in the jet dynamics compared to that described by classical spray theory in a manner consistent with experimental observations. In particular, the classical view of spray atomization as an appropriate model at some engine operating conditions is questionable. Instead, non-ideal real-fluid behavior must be taken into account using a multicomponent formulation that applies to hydrocarbon mixtures at high-pressure supercritical conditions. To highlight the implications and needs related to modeling, we present a series of studies using LES that focus on experiments being conducted in the high-pressure combustion vessel at Sandia National Laboratories. We extend LES studies performed previously to the Engine Combustion Network (www.sandia.gov/ECN) Spray-H and Spray-A injectors using n-heptane and n-dodecane as the respective fuels. The accompanying analysis reveals the structural characteristics associated with the inherent scalar mixing processes at conditions directly relevant to advanced Diesel engines.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oschwald M., Smith J., Branam R., Hussong J., Schik A., Chehroudi B., and Talley D.. Injection of fluids into supercritical environments. Combustion Science and Technology, 178(1-3):49- 100, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Habiballah M., Orain M., Grisch F., Vingert L., and Gicquel P.. Experimental studies of high-pressure cryogenic flames on the mascotte facility. Combustion Science and Technology, 178(1- 3):101-128, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin K.-C., Cox-Stouffer S., and Jackson T.. Structures and phase transition processes of supercritical methane/ethylene mixtures injected into a subcritical environment. Combustion Science and Technology, 178 (1-3):129-160, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Candel S., Juniper M., Singla G., Scouflaire P., and Rolon C.. Structure and dynamics of cryogenic flames at supercritical pressure. Combustion Science and Technology, 178(1-3):161-192, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zong N. and Yang V.. Cryogenic fluid jets and mixing layers in transcritical and supercritcal environments. Combustion Science and Technology, 178(1-3):193-228, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oefelein J. C.. Mixing and combustion of cryogenic oxygenhydrogen shear-coaxial jet flames at supercritical pressure. Combustion Science and Technology, 178(1-3): 229-252, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bellan J.. Theory, modeling and analysis of turbulent supercritical mixing. Combustion Science and Technology, 178(1-3):253-281, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Selle L. C., Okong'o N. A., Bellan J., and Harstad K. G.. Modelling of subgrid-scale phenomena in supercritical transitional mixing layers: An a priori study. Journal of Fluid Mechanics, 593:57-91, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ribert G., Zong N., Yang V., Pons L., Darabiha N., and Candel S.. Counterflow diffusion flames of general fluids: Oxygen/hydrogen mixtures. Combustion and Flame, 154: 319-330, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lacaze G., Cuenot B., Poinsot T., and Oschwald M.. Large eddy simulation of laser ignition and compressible reacting flow in a rocket-like configuration. Combustion and Flame, 156:1166-1180, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pons L., Darabiha N., Candel S., Ribert G., and Yang V.. Mass transfer and combustion in transcritical non-premixed counterflows. Combustion Theory and Modelling, 13:57-81, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmitt T., Méry Y., Boileau M., and Candel S.. Large-eddy simulation of oxygen/methane flames under transcritical conditions. Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 33:1383-1390, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahms R. N., Manin J., Pickett L. M., and Oefelein J. C.. Understanding high-pressure gas-liquid interface phenomena in diesel engines. Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 34:1667- 1675, 2013. doi:10.1016/j.proci.2012.06.169.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahms R. N. and Oefelein J. C.. On the transition between twophase and single-phase interface dynamics in multicomponent fluids at supercritical pressures. Physics of Fluids, 25(092103):1- 24, 2013. doi:10.1063/1.4820346.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett L. M.. Engine combustion network. www.sandia.gov/ECN, 2005-2014. Sandia National Laboratories, Combustion Research Facility, Livermore, California.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oefelein J. C.. Large eddy simulation of turbulent combustion processes in propulsion and power systems. Progress in Aerospace Sciences, 42(1):2-37, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oefelein J. C.. Thermophysical characteristics of LOX-H2 flames at supercritical pressure. Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 30:2929-2937, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oefelein J. C., Schefer R. W., and Barlow R. W.. Toward validation of LES for turbulent combustion. AIAA Journal, 44(3):418-433, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oefelein J. C., Sankaran V., and Drozda T. G.. Large eddy simulation of swirling particle-laden flow in a model axisymmetric combustor. Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 31:2291- 2299, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Williams T. C., Schefer R. W., Oefelein J. C., and Shaddix C. R.. Idealized gas turbine combustor for performance research and validation of large eddy simulations. Review of Scientific Instruments, 78(3).035114-1-9, 2007. doi:10.1063/1.27.12936.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oefelein J. C. and Lacaze G.. Low-temperature injection dynamics and turbulent flame structure in high-pressure supercritical flows. Proceedings of the 23rd International Colloquium on the Dynamics of Explosions and Reactive Systems, July 24-29 2011. Irvine, California.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oefelein, J., Dahms, R., and Lacaze, G., “Detailed Modeling and Simulation of High-Pressure Fuel Injection Processes in Diesel Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1410-1419, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1258.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oefelein J. C., Dahms R. N., Lacaze G., Manin J. L., and Pickett L. M.. Effects of pressure on the fundamental physics of fuel injection in diesel engines. Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems, September 2-6 2012. Heidelberg, Germany.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oefelein J. C.. Large eddy simulation of complex thermophysics in advanced propulsion and power systems. Proceedings of the 8th Joint Meeting of the US Sections of the Combustion Institute, Invited Plenary Presentation and Paper, May 19-22 2013. Park City, Utah.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Erlebacher G., Hussaini M. Y., Speziale C. G., and Zang T. A.. Toward the large eddy simulation of compressible turbulent flows. Journal of Fluid Mechanics, 238:155-185, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Speziale C. G.. Galilean invariance of subgrid-scale stress models in the large eddy simulation of turbulence. Journal of Fluid Mechanics, 156:55-62, 1985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Germano M., Piomelli U., Moin P., and Cabot W. H.. A dynamic subgrid-scale eddy viscosity model. Physics of Fluids, 3(7):1760- 1765, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moin P., Squires K., Cabot W., and Lee S.. A dynamic subgridscale model for compressible turbulence and scalar transport. Physics of Fluids, 3(11):2746-2757, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lilly D. K.. A proposed modification of the germano subgrid-scale closure method. Physics of Fluids, 3(11): 633-635, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zang Y., Street R. L., and Koseff J. R.. A dynamic mixed subgridscale model and its application to turbulent recirculating flows. Physics of Fluids, 5(12):3186-3195, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vreman B., Geurts B., and Kuerten H.. On the formulation of the dynamic mixed subgrid-scale model. Physics of Fluids, 6(12):4057- 4059, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smagorinsky J.. General circulation experiments with the primitive equations. I. The basic experiment. Monthly Weather Review, 91:99-164, 1963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leland T. W. and Chappelear P. S.. The corresponding states principle. A review of current theory and practice. Industrial and Engineering Chemistry Fundamentals, 60 (7):15-43, 1968.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rowlinson J. S. and Watson I. D.. The prediction of the thermodynamic properties of fluids and fluid mixtures-I. The principle of corresponding states and its extensions. Chemical Engineering Science, 24(8):1565-1574, 1969.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reid R. C., Prausnitz J. M., and Polling B. E.. The Properties of Liquids and Gases. McGraw-Hill, New York, New York, 4th edition, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">VanWylen G. J. and Sonntag R. E.. Fundamentals of Classical Thermodynamics. John Wiley and Sons, Incorporated, New York, New York, 3rd edition, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gordon S. and McBride B. J.. Computer program for calculation of complex chemical equilibrium compositions, rocket performance, incident and reflected shocks and Chapman-Jouguet detonations. Technical Report NASA SP-273, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, 1971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kee R. J., Rupley F. M., and Miller J. A.. Chemkin thermodynamic data base. Technical Report SAND87-8215B, Sandia National Laboratories, 1990. Supersedes SAND87-8215 dated April 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ely J. F. and Hanley H. J. M.. Prediction of transport properties. 1. Viscosity of fluids and mixtures. Industrial and Engineering Chemistry Fundamentals, 20(4): 323-332, 1981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ely J. F. and Hanley H. J. M.. Prediction of transport properties. 2. Thermal conductivity of pure fluids and mixtures. Industrial and Engineering Chemistry Fundamentals, 22(1):90-97, 1981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bird R. B., Stewart W. E., and Lightfoot E. N.. Transport Phenomena. John Wiley and Sons, Incorporated, New York, New York, 1960.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hirschfelder J. O., Curtiss C. F., and Bird R. B.. Molecular Theory of Gases and Liquids. John Wiley and Sons, Incorporated, New York, New York, 2nd edition, 1964.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takahashi S.. Preparation of a generalized chart for the diffusion coefficients of gases at high pressures. Journal of Chemical Engineering of Japan, 7(6):417-420, 1974.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett L. M., Genzal C. L., Manin J., Malbec L.-M., and Hermant L.. Measurement uncertainty of liquid penetration in evaporating diesel sprays. Proceedings of the 23rd Annual Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems, May 15-18 2011. Ventura, California.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
