<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284827</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Low Temperature Premixed Diesel Combustion with Blends of Ordinary Diesel Fuel and Normal Heptane</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ogawa</surname>
                  <given-names>Hideyuki</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sakane</surname>
                  <given-names>Yuhei</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Obe</surname>
                  <given-names>Tatsunori</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Arisawa</surname>
                  <given-names>Tatsuaki</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shibata</surname>
                  <given-names>Gen</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Hokkaido Univ.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284791</issue-id>
         <fpage>445</fpage>
         <lpage>451</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE Japan and Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284827"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Premixed diesel combustion blending high volatility fuels into diesel fuel were investigated in a modern diesel engine. First, various fractions of normal heptane and diesel fuel were examined to determine the influence of the blending of a highly ignitable and volatile fuel into diesel fuel. The indicated thermal efficiency improves almost linearly with increasing normal heptane fraction, particularly at advanced injection timings when the fuel is not injected directly into the piston cavity. This improvement is mainly due to decreases in the other losses,<italic>ϕ<sub>other</sub>
               </italic>which are calculated with the following equation based on the energy balance.</p>
            <p>
               <italic>ϕ<sub>other</sub>= η<sub>u</sub>− η<sub>i</sub>− ϕ<sub>ex</sub>
               </italic>
            </p>
            <p>
               <italic>η<sub>u</sub>
               </italic>: The combustion efficiency calculated from the exhaust gas compositions</p>
            <p>
               <italic>η<sub>i</sub>
               </italic>: The indicated thermal efficiency</p>
            <p>
               <italic>ϕ<sub>ex</sub>
               </italic>: The exhaust loss calculated from the enthalpy difference between intake and exhaust gas</p>
            <p>The decreases in the other losses with normal heptane blends are due to a reduction in the unburned fuel which does not reach the gas analyzer.</p>
            <p>Next, a blend of 50 vol% iso-octane and 50 vol% diesel fuel was examined to determine the influence of blending a low ignitability and high volatility fuel similar to gasoline into diesel fuel. With the iso-octane blend the range of premixed diesel combustion can be expanded to higher intake oxygen concentrations due to a longer premixing duration with increasing ignition delay, and smokeless combustion is possible at low intake oxygen concentrations. The unburned fuel arising from adhesion of fuel spray on the cylinder wall can be avoided with the high volatility fuel, resulting in higher efficiency.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kanda T et al., PCCI Operation with Fuel Injection Timing Set Close to TDC, SAE 2006 World Congress &amp; Exhibition, 2006-01-0920 (2006)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diwakar R and Singh S, NOX and soot reduction in diesel engine premixed charge compression ignition combustion: a computational investigation, int. J. Engine Res., vol.9, No.3 (2008)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu, Y. et al., Using Multiple Injection Strategies in Diesel PCCI Combustion: Potential to Extend Engine Load, Improve Trade-off of Emissions and Efficiency, SAE 2011 World Congress &amp; Exhibition, 2011-01-1396 (2011)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hou, D et al., Adaptive PCCI Combustion Using Micro-Variable Circular-Orifice (MVCO) Fuel Injector - Key Enabling Technologies for High Efficiency Clean Diesel Engines, SAE 2009 World Congress &amp; Exhibition, 2009-01-1528 (2009)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shimazaki N et al., New Combustion Concept of Premixed Compression Ignition Combustion with Fuel-injection near Top Dead Center : Effects of Fuel Ignitability and Volatility, Transactions of Society of Automotive Engneers of Japan, vol.37, No.2 (2006) in Japanese</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sakai A et al., Improvements in premixed charge compression ignition combustion and emissions with lower distillation temperature fuels, int. J. Engine Res., vol.6, No.5 (2005)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xiong, Q., Inaba, K., Ogawa, H., and Shibata, G., “Influence of Fuel Properties on Operational Range and Thermal Efficiency of Premixed Diesel Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(3):1005-1013, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xiong Q et al., Improvements in thermal efficiency of premixed diesel combustion with low distillation temperature fuels, SAE paper 2013-01- 2624 (2013)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, F et al., Combustion and Emission Characteristics of a PPCI Engine Fuelled with Dieseline, SAE 2012 World Congress &amp; Exhibition, 2012-01-1138 (2012)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang, J et al., Fuel Economy Potential of Partially Premixed Compression Ignition (PPCI) Combustion with Naphtha Fuel, SAE 2013 Int Powertrains, Fuels &amp; Lubricants, 2013-01-2701 (2013)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ogawa H et al., Improvements in thermal efficiency of premixed diesel combustion with optimization of combustion-related parameters and fuel volatilities, int. J. Engine Res., vol.16, No.1 (2014)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
