<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816587</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Avoiding Taxes (Accounting)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effect of Industrial Diversification on Firm Taxes</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wentland</surname>
                  <given-names>Kelly</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>49</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816587"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This study investigates whether there is an empirical basis for one predicted benefit from industrial diversification: whether conglomerate firms obtain greater tax savings than single industry firms. The results suggest that, on average, firms operating in multiple industries incur lower tax liabilities than stand-alone firms. However, whether a firm obtains these benefits is affected by the type of industry-based tax positions available to the firm, the firm’s demand for debt, and its overall risk strategy. For identification, the study uses a triple difference model based on two temporary tax law changes and an instrumental variables analysis from the diversification discount literature. Results from these tests are consistent with a tax advantage from diversification. Overall, the results in the study inform recurring debates in the media and between management and shareholders over the costs and benefits of diversification as a business strategy.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Amihud, Y. and Lev, B. 1981. Risk Reduction as a Managerial Motive for Conglomerate Mergers. Bell Journal of Economics 12: 605-617.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Ammann, M., Hoechle, D., and Schmid, M. 2012. Is there Really No Conglomerate Discount? Journal of Business Finance &amp; Accounting 39(1) &amp; (2):264-288.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Armstrong, C., Blouin, J., and Larcker, D. 2012. The incentives for tax planning. Journal of Accounting and Economics 53(1-2): 391-411.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Benoit, D. and Grind, K. August 9, 2015. Activist Investors’ Secret Ally: Big Mutual Funds: Large Investors quietly back campaigns to force change at U.S. companies. The Wall Street Journal. &lt; http://www.wsj.com/articles/activist-investors-secret-ally-big-mutual-funds-1439173910&gt;</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Berger, P. and Ofek, E. 1995. Diversification’s effect on firm value. Journal of Financial Economics 37: 39-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Bound, J., Jaeger, D., and Baker, R. 1995. Problems with Instrumental Variables Estimation when the Correlation between the Instruments and the Endogenous Explanatory Variable is Weak. Journal of the American Statistical Association 90(430): 443-450.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Campa, J. M. and Kedia, S. 2002. Explaining the Diversification Discount. Journal of Finance. 57(4): 1731-1762.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Chen, S., Chen, X., Cheng, Q., and Shevlin, T. 2010. Are family firms more tax aggressive than non-family firms? Journal of Financial Economics 95: 41-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Creal, D., Robinson, L, Rogers, J., and Zechman, S. 2014. The Multinational Advantage. University of Chicago working paper No. 11-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Devos, E., Kadapakkam, P.R. and Krishnamurthy, S. 2009. Review of Financial Studies 22(3): 1179-1211.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Dimitrov, V. and Tice, S. 2006. Corporate Diversification and Credit Constriants: Real Effects across the Business Cycle. Review of Financial Studies 19(4): 1465-1498.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Donohoe, M. 2015. The economic effects of financial derivatives on corporate tax avoidance. Journal of Accounting and Economics 59(1): 1-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Dyreng, S., Hanlon, M., and Maydew, E. 2008. Long-Run Corporate Tax Avoidance. The Accounting Review: 83(1): 61-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Dyreng, S. and Lindsey, B. 2009. Using Financial Accounting Data to Examine the Effect of Foreign Operations Located in Tax Havens and Other Countries on U.S. Multinational Firms’ Tax Rates. Journal of Accounting Research 47(5): 1283-1316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Fama, E. and French, K. 2002. Testing Trade-Off and Pecking Order Predictions About Dividends and Debt. Review of Financial Studies 15(1): 1-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Furrer, O. 2011. Corporate Level Strategy Theory and Applications. Routledge: New York, NY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Gallemore, J. and Labro, E. 2015. The Importance of the Internal Information Environment for Tax Avoidance. Journal of Accounting and Economics 60(1): 149-167.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Gertner, R., Scharfstein, D., and Stein, J. 1994. Internal versus External Capital Markets. Quarterly Journal of Economics 109(4): 1211-1230.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Goetz, M., Laeven, L., and Levine, R. 2013. The Valuation Effects of Geographical Diversification: Evidence from U.S. Banks. Review of Financial Studies 67(7): 1787-1823.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Gopalan, R. and Xie, K. 2011. Conglomerates and Industry Distress. Review of Financial Studies 24(11): 3642-3687.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Gopinath, S. and Sikka, K. Sept. 17, 2014. Activist investor Peltz pushes DuPont to split itself. Reuters. &lt; http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/09/17/us-e-i-du-pont-de-divestiture-idUSKBN0HC0C220140917&gt;</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Graham, J., Lemmon, M., and Wolf, J. 2002. Does Corporate Diversification Destroy Value? The Journal of Finance 57(2): 695-720.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Graham, J., and Smith, C. W. Jr. 1999. Tax Incentives to Hedge. Journal of Finance 54(6): 2241-2262.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Graham, J., and Rogers, D. 2002. Do Firms Hedge in Response to Tax Incentives? Journal of Finance 57(2): 815-839.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Gupta, S. and Newberry, K. 1997. Determinants of the variability in corporate effectives tax rates: Evidence from longitudinal data. Journal of Accounting and Public Policy 16(1): 1-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Hanlon, M. and Heitzman, S. 2010. A review of tax research. Journal of Accounting and Economics 50(2-3): 127-178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Hann, R., Ogneva, M., and Ozbas, O. 2013. Corporate Diversification and the Cost of Capital. Journal of Finance 68(5): 1961-1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Henry, E., and Sansing, R., 2015. Data Truncation Bias and the Mismeasurement of Corporate Tax Avoidance. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Hoechle, D. Schmid, M., Walter, I., and Yermack, D. 2012. How much of the diversification discount can be explained by poor corporate governance? Journal of Financial Economics 103(1): 41-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Hope, O., Ma, M., and Thomas, W. 2013. Tax avoidance and geographic earnings disclosure. Journal of Accounting and Economics 56: 170-189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Humphery-Jenner, M. 2013. Diversification in Private Equity Funds: On Knowledge Sharing and Limited Attention. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis. 48(5): 1545-1572.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Khorana, A., Shivdasani, A., Stendevad, C., and Sanzhar, S. 2011. Spin-offs: Tackling the Conglomerate Discount. Journal of Applied Corporate Finance. 23(4): 90-101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Klein, P. and Saidenberg, M. 2010. Organizational Structure and the Diversification Discount: Evidence from Commercial Banking. Journal of Industrial Economics 58(1): 127-155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Lachapelle, T. March 1, 2015. Buffett Critiques Breakup Ideas Even as Spinoffs Surge: Real M&amp;A. Bloomberg Press. &lt; http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2015-03-01/buffett-critiques-breakup-ideas-even-as-spinoffs-surge-real-m-a&gt;</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Laeven, L. and Levine, R. 2007. Is there a diversification discount in financial conglomerates? 85: 331-367.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Lang, L., and Stulz, R. 1994. Tobin’s Q, Corporate Diversification and Firm Performance. Journal of Political Economy. 1248-1280.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Leland, H. 1998. Agency costs, risk management, and capital structure. Journal of Finance 53: 1213-1243.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Law, K. and Mills, L. 2015. Taxes and Financial Constraints: Evidence from Linguistic Cues. Journal of Accounting Research 53(4): 777-819</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Lennox, C., Francis, J., and Wang, Z. 2012. Selection Models in Accounting Research. The Accounting Review 87(2): 589-616.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Lewellen, W. 1971. A Pure Financial Rationale for the Conglomerate Merger. Journal of Finance 26(2): 521-537.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Li, K. and Prabhala, N.R. 2007. “Self-Selection Models in Corporate Finance” in B. E. Eckbo (Ed.). Handbook of Corporate Finance: Empirical Corporate Finance. Vol. 1, Chapter 2, 37-86. Elsevier/North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Lin, J., Pantzalis, C., and Park, J. 2007. Corporate use of derivatives and excess value of diversification. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance 31: 889-913.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Lins, K. and Servaes, H. 1999. International Evidence on the Value of Corporate Diversification. Journal of Finance 54(6): 2215-2239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Lynch, P. and Rothchild, J. 2000. One up on Wall Street: How to Use What You Already Know to Make Money in the Market. 2nd edition. Simon and Schuster.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Majd, S. and Myers, S.C. 1987. Tax asymmetries and corporate income tax reform, in: M. Feldstein, ed., Effects of taxation on capital accumulation. University of Chicago Press, Chicago, IL.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Mann, T. April 13, 2015. Price of Selling GE Capital? Tax Breaks. The Wall Street Journal. &lt;http://www.wsj.com/articles/price-of-ge-capital-sale-tax-breaks-1428970045&gt;</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">May, D. 1995. Do Managerial Motives Influence Firm Risk Reduction Strategies? Journal of Finance 50(4): 1291-1308.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">McGuire, S., Omer, T., and Wang, D. 2012. Tax Avoidance: Does Tax-Specific Industry Expertise Make a Difference. The Accounting Review 87(3): 975-1003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Myers, S.C. 1984. The Capital Structure Puzzle. Journal of Finance 39(3): 574-592.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Ohlemacher, S. December 16, 2014. Senate Votes to Extend Tax Breaks through December. Huffington Post. &lt; http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2014/12/16/senate-tax-breaks_n_6337484.html&gt;</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Phillips, J. 2003. Corporate Tax-Planning Effectiveness: The Role of Compensation-Based Incentives. The Accounting Review 78(3): 847-874.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Rajan, R., Servaes, H., and Zingales, L. 2000. The Cost of Diversity: The Diversification Discount and Inefficient Investment. Journal of Finance 55(1): 35-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Rego, S. 2003. Tax-Avoidance Activities of U.S. Multinational Corporations. Contemporary Accounting Research 20(4): 805-833.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Robinson, J., Sikes, S., and Weaver, C. 2010. Performance Measurement of Corporate Tax Departments. The Accounting Review 85(3): 1035-1064.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Scharfstein, D. and Stein, J. 2000. The dark side of internal capital markets: Divisional reent-seeking and inefficient investment. Journal of Finance 55: 2537-2564.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Staiger, D. and Stock, J. 1997. Instrumental Variables Regression with Weak Instruments. Econometrica 65(3): 557-586.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Stulz, R. 1996. Rethinking risk management. Journal of Applied Corporate Finance 9: 8-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Teece, D. 1980. Economies of Scope and the Scope of the Enterprise. Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization 1(3): 223-247.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Tita, B. and Mattioli, D. January 25, 2016. Johnson Controls, Tyco to merge in Inversion Deal. The Wall Street Journal. &lt; http://www.wsj.com/articles/johnson-controls-tyco-to-merge-in-inversion-deal-1453724828&gt;</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Villalonga, B. 2004a. Diversification Discount or Premium? New Evidence from the Business Information Tracking Series. Journal of Finance 59(2): 479-506.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Villalonga, B. 2004b. Does diversification cause the ‘diversification discount’? Financial Management 33(2): 5-27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <mixed-citation id="c62">Wooldridge, J. 2002. Econometric Analysis of Cross Section and Panel Data. The MIT Press: Cambridge, MA; London, England.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Zheng, S. 2015. Firm Diversification Corporate Governance and Tax Avoidance. Working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Zimmerman, J. 1983. Taxes and firm size. Journal of Accounting and Economics 5: 119-149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Descriptive Statistics and Correlation Matrix</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>OLS Regressions of Tax on Different Diversification Measures</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Effect of Diversification on Firm Taxes with a Different Extent of R&amp;D Activity</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Effect of Diversification on Firm Taxes with Different Firm Financial Constraints</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Effect of Diversification on Firm Taxes with Different Firm Risk Preferences</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Triple Difference Analysis – Temporary Extensions of NOL Carryback Periods</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Comparing Instrumental Variables Approaches to the Primary Analysis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>APPENDIX I –</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>VARIABLE DESCRIPTIONS</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
