<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">26</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">11</issue>
         <issue-id>i24464772</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24464781</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Asset Pricing with Endogenous Disasters</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Cristian</given-names>
                  <surname>Tiu</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Uzi</given-names>
                  <surname>Yoeli</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2013</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2916</fpage>
         <lpage>2960</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24464781"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We develop a parsimonious model in which frictions in the labor market may turn small, continuous labor productivity declines into large drops in employment, endogenously causing disasters. Assuming one state variable and CRRA agents, we solve for prices in closed form, calibrate the model using labor market data, and show that this simple setting captures the high, countercyclical volatility and equity premium observed in the United States. Moreover, returns in our model are conditionally predicted by dividend yields. Finally, as in the data, in our setting the disasters are larger when the capital's share of income is higher.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d57e208a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e215" publication-type="other">
Some of the models incorporating disasters are also referred to as "peso models." The reason lies in the collapse
of the Mexican peso in 1994. The high peso premium observed prior to the collapse was explained by the small
probability of a huge out-of-sample devaluation, which was eventually observed (see Danthine and Donaldson
1999). Other models allow for disasters of magnitudes not yet observed in the data. Modeling large but never
observed catastrophes led Mehra and Prescott (1988) to criticize the early disaster models as ad hoc.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e234a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e241" publication-type="other">
For example, in Diamond (1982), laborers on a tropical island produce only coconuts, and a taboo prevents them
from consuming their own pick. To consume, Diamond's laborers need to find a trade partner (while incurring
a search cost), and exchange coconuts (at a coconut-for-coconut rate). In this way, while the model has one
consumption good, it exhibits similarities to an economy with a variety of goods in which producers need to sell
a portion of their output, being unable to consume it all.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e260a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e267" publication-type="other">
This is similar to having probabilities of disaster that are perfectly negatively correlated with consumption, as
in Gourio (2008a) or Wächter (2013). In contrast with their work, the probability of disaster in our model is
endogenous.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e280a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e287" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Barro's (2007) Figure 9.7.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e295a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e302" publication-type="other">
The steps to arrive at this functional form of the production functions are as follows. First, we start with a simple
Cobb-Douglas production function, Ftl(Ljt, Kit)=Lj~a K?t. This is the gross output of the firm. However, as
in Diamond (1982), each firm needs to find a trade partner (other firms) to whom it can sell its output. This is
possible to the extent that other firms are operating. We assume that this search cost is a fraction of the output of
the firm that is proportional with total employment in firms. We assume that the search cost is a fraction (1 - Lt )
of the gross output. This results in a net output equal to F^(Lit, ) = Lt L^~a K?t. To this we add an exogenous
productivity factor Ot (modeling the fact that sometimes the coconut trees make more coconuts for the same
amount of labor and capital invested in the tree) and thus obtain the production function of Equation (1).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e331a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e338" publication-type="other">
For example, Gomme and Greenwood (1995) cite this as a stylized fact about the labor's share of income. They
report a correlation of —0.37 between labor's share of income and GNP (both detrended using a Hodrick-Prescott
filter).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e351a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e360" publication-type="other">
Diamond (2011) states that "[...] production contributes to demand [...] when others are producing little, the
ability to sell is low, and so the incentive to produce is low. When others are producing much, the incentive
to produce is high." Furthermore, analyzing the same relationship between employment and output, in a Wall
Street Journal interview (on August 12,2011), economist Nouriel Robini alluded to such an externality, arguing
that the less companies hire, the less money flows into the hands of workers, and therefore the less companies
sell, and the more they are forced to lay off workers. Additionally, Roubini states that in an attempt to increase
productivity, companies might lay off labor, also causing less money to flow into the hands of workers, thereby
decreasing output and forcing even more unemployment. Although we do not model this particular feedback
cycle, doing so has the potential to make disasters more frequent and would result in a higher equity premium
and volatility.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e395a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e402" publication-type="other">
Note that our interpretation and calibration of the less capital-intensive sector is not one of a primitive economy,
although the "model itself could be interpreted that way. To calibrate to an extreme disaster state, we would have
to assume that the second economic sector uses solely raw labor in the production function and that its output
is drastically lower than in our calibration. This would result in much more severe disasters than our current
calibration implies and would be beyond the scope of this study.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e421a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e428" publication-type="other">
Total consumption C{t) is equal to the sum of dividends paid to the capital asset and wages. Wages are paid by
the capital-intensive firms (in proportion of Lt) and by the less capital-intensive sector (in proportion of 1 — Lt).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e438a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e445" publication-type="other">
We note that the model could be expanded to have partial unemployment as a possible equilibrium. This would
be the case if different laborers had different alternative wages. As productivity drops, the wages could drop
below the alternative wages for the first group (the group with the highest reservation wages). This would cause
this group of workers to shift to the alternative production sector. The search cost will then go up, causing a
further decline in aggregate output of the first sector. Wages will in turn drop (although labor share of output
will rise). If these lower wages are higher than the alternative wages of the second group, the spiraling will stop,
and we will have a partial unemployment. If these lower wages are below the alternative wages of the second
group, the downward spiral will continue. For the spiraling to stop, the difference in the reservation wages needs
to be relatively large, and/or the first group should be relatively small. As our intent is not to capture the political
science aspects of economic and financial crises, and by no means do we try to explain unemployment, we keep
the setting relatively simple, with only one alternative wage level and shifts from full employment to complete
unemployment (and vice versa) that result from this rather simplified setting.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e488a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e495" publication-type="other">
11 The normalizing factor % is chosen so that 9t &gt; ( 1 - a) 1 Zt if and only if Xt &gt; 0.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e502a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e509" publication-type="other">
The productivity has a volatility equal to a and the drift of productivity growth mean-reverts around the fixed
rate of /x+a2/2.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e519a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e526" publication-type="other">
Note that to accommodate the big push equilibrium, Proposition 1 can be readily modified: in this case, our
economy, once in a state of disaster, will remain in that state until the state variable Xt reaches a constant
threshold X^.This corresponds to the barrier of =0Qtexg.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e539a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e546" publication-type="other">
This is because dividends on the capital asset, as well as consumption, are linear functions of Zt. Because Zt grows
at a deterministic rate, for any security s and any times 0 &lt; t &lt; t' we have that Ps (t,Xt=x)=~^ Ps (t', Xtr =x).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e556a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e563" publication-type="other">
From Proposition 1, D(t,Xt)=a6t = — eAt when labor is employed in the capital intensive sector.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e570a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e577" publication-type="other">
For brevity, we wrote g(*) :=g(x-, &lt;5+(y — l)/x, y -1) and l(x) :=C(x\8+(y — l)/x).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e585a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e592" publication-type="other">
Specifically, the lower the value of the state variable Xt (and thus the lower the consumption), the higher the
probability of disaster when fc=0.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e602a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e609" publication-type="other">
Such a variable would furthermore be an additional state variable, and therefore, a model with exogenous disasters
attempting to match conditional moments of asset prices will have at least two state variables. This is in contrast
with our model, which can capture asset pricing dynamics with a single state variable.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e622a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e629" publication-type="other">
Aït-Sahalia, Parker, and Yogo (2004) argue that consumption of luxury goods is what should matter, because
equity holders are typically rich and satiated with the consumption of basic goods. They find that the volatility
of luxury goods consumption is an order of a magnitude higher than the volatility of overall consumption.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e642a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e649" publication-type="other">
In our model, the volatility of dividends equals volatility of consumption in our model. Similar to consumption
volatility, the volatility of dividends also varies in time. For example, it exceeds 10% for the entire available
series in the United States, whereas it is smaller at around 5% in the postwar period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e662a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e669" publication-type="other">
See Kydland and Prescott (1982).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e676a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e683" publication-type="other">
We note that this is also a much milder drop than if we calibrate the model assuming that the second sector was
a primitive economy. If that is the case, then the production function in the second economic sector should only
include raw labor, whose share of income is much lower. For example, in 1996, the raw labor's share of income
was 4.9%, according to data compiled by Krueger (1999). This implies a drop of consumption in a disaster that
is equal to 100—4.9% = 95.1%. Calibrating to such an extreme outcome is beyond the scope of this study.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e703a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e710" publication-type="other">
The power of these tests is, however, small given that the sample contains only twelve data points.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e717a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e724" publication-type="other">
To simulate paths for our economy, we could draw an initial value from the stable distribution of X, when X is
mean reverting (k &gt; 0). For the case of k=0, however, we must make an assumption about Xq, and we choose
the starting value of the U.S. observed economic path from a normal distribution centered at Xq.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e737a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e744" publication-type="other">
Credit and gratitude for pointing this out to us go to an anonymous referee. Traditional peso models assume
leverage to obtain this effect; by contrast, we do not need this assumption.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e754a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e761" publication-type="other">
As implied by the third part of Proposition 5.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e768a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e775" publication-type="other">
Note that we use the dividend yield D/P as a predictor, rather than log(D) — log(P). This is due to the fact that,
in our model, D=0 when the economy is in the disaster state.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e785a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e792" publication-type="other">
Such an assumption also has the potential to generate procyclical short-term rates. It is not surprising that disaster
models have the potential to resolve a multitude of bond pricing puzzles. For example, Gabaix (2009) shows that
different exogenous disaster specifications may solve a multitude of asset pricing puzzles. Bekaert, Hodrick, and
Marshall (2001) also show that some term structure anomalies may be explained by peso arguments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e809a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e816" publication-type="other">
The subscript equal to zero is meant to signify that these are the first observed collapses and recoveries on a path
started conventionally at time t=0.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d57e835a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e839" publication-type="other">
Abramowitz, M., and I. Stegun. 1964. Handbook of mathematical functions with formulas, graphs, and
mathematical tables. New York: Dover Publications.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e849a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e853" publication-type="other">
Aït-Sahalia, Y., J. A. Parker, and M. Yogo. 2004. Luxury goods and the equity premium. Journal of Finance
59:2959-3004.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e863a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e867" publication-type="other">
Azariadis, C. 1981. Self-fulfilling prophecies. Journal of Economic Theory 25:380-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e874a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e878" publication-type="other">
Balvers, R. J., and D. Huang. 2007. Productivity-based asset pricing: Theory and evidence. Journal of Financial
Economics 86:405-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e889a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e893" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., and A. Yaron. 2004. Risks for the long run: A potential resolution of asset pricing puzzles. Journal of
Finance 59:1481-509.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e903a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e907" publication-type="other">
Barro, R. 2006. Rare disasters and asset markets in the Twentieth Century. Quarterly Journal of Economics
121:823-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e917a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e921" publication-type="other">
. 2007. Macroeconomics: A modern approach, First Edition. Mason, OH: South-Western College Pub.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e928a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e932" publication-type="other">
Barro, R. J., and J. F. Ursua. 2008. Macroeconomic crises since 1870. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity
39:255-350.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e942a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e946" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, G, R. J. Hodrick, and D. A. Marshall. 2001. Peso problem explanations for term structure anomalies.
Journal of Monetary Economics 48:241-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e956a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e960" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, G, and G Wu. 2000. Asymmetric volatility and risk in equity markets. Review of Financial Studies
13:1-42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e971a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e975" publication-type="other">
Black, F. 1976. Studies of stock price volatility changes. Proceedings of the 1976 Meetings of the American
Statistical Association, Business and Economical Statistics Section 1976:177-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e985a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e989" publication-type="other">
Borodin, A. N., and P. Salminen. 1996. Handbook ofBrownian motion - Facts and formulae. Boston: Birkhuser.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e996a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1000" publication-type="other">
Brown, S. J., W. N. Goetzmann, and S. A. Ross. 1995. Survival. Journal of Finance 50:853-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1007a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1011" publication-type="other">
Brown, R. H., and S. M. Schaefer. 1994. The term structure of real interest rates and the Cox, Ingersoll, and Ross
model. Journal of Financial Economics 35:3-42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1021a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1025" publication-type="other">
Boudoukh, J., R. Michaely, M. Richardson, and M. R. Roberts. 2007. On the importance of measuring payout
yield: Implications for empirical asset pricing. Journal of Finance 62:877-915.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1035a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1039" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., and J. H. Cochrane. 1999. By force of habit: A consumption-based explanation of aggregate
stock market behavior. Journal of Political Economy 107:205-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1050a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1054" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., and L. Hentschel. 1992. No news is good news: An asymmetric model of changing volatility in
stock returns. Journal of Financial Economics 31:281-318.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1064a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1068" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., and R. J. Shiller. 1988. The dividend-price ratio and expectation of future dividends and discount
factors. Review of Financial Studies 1:195-228.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1078a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1082" publication-type="other">
Cass, D., and K. Shell. 1983. Do sunspots matter? Journal of Political Economy 91:193-227.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1089a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1093" publication-type="other">
Chapman, D. 2002. Does intrinsic habit formation actually resolve the equity premium puzzle? Review of
Economic Dynamics 5:618-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1103a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1107" publication-type="other">
Christie, A. A. 1982. The stochastic behavior of common stock variances - Value, leverage and interest rate
effects. Journal of Financial Economics 407-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1117a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1121" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. H. 1992. Explaining the variance of price-dividend ratios. Review of Financial Studies
5:243-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1132a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1136" publication-type="other">
Danthine, J. P., and J. Donaldson. 1999. Non-falsified expectations and general equilibrium asset pricing: The
power of the peso. Economic Journal 109:607-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1146a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1150" publication-type="other">
David, A., and P. Veronesi. Forthcoming. What ties return volatilities to price valuations and fundamentals?
Journal of Political Economy.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1160a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1164" publication-type="other">
Davies, B. 1985. Integral transforms and their applications, Second Edition. Berlin: Springer.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1171a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1175" publication-type="other">
Diamond, P. A. 1982. Aggregate demand management in search equilibrium. Journal of Political Economy
90:881-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1185a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1189" publication-type="other">
. 2011. Employment, vacancies, wages. American Economic Review 101:1045-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1196a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1200" publication-type="other">
Dickens, W. T., L. Goette, E. L. Groshen, S. Holden J. Messina, M. E. Schweitzer, J. Turunen, and M. Ward. 2007.
The interaction of labor markets and inflation: Analysis of micro data from the International Wage Flexibility
Project. Brookings Institution.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1214a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1218" publication-type="other">
Doob, J. L. 1942. The Brownian movement and stochastic equations. Annals of Mathematics 43:351-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1225a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1229" publication-type="other">
Evans, M. D. 1998. Real rates, expected inflation, and inflation risk premia. Journal of Finance 53:187-218.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1236a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1240" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and K. R. French. 1988. Dividend yields and expected stock returns. Journal of Financial Economics
22:3-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1250a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1254" publication-type="other">
. 2002. The equity premium. Journal of Finance 57:637-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1261a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1265" publication-type="other">
French, K. R., G W. Schwert, and R. F. Stambaugh. 1987. Expected stock returns and volatility. Journal of
Financial Economics 19:3-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1275a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1279" publication-type="other">
Gabaix, X. 2009. A simple, unified, exactly solved framework for ten puzzles in macrofinance. Working Paper,
New York University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1290a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1294" publication-type="other">
Glosten, L. R., R. Jagannathan, and D. E. Runkle. 1993. On the relation between the expected vlue and the
volatility of the nominal excess return on stocks. Journal of Finance 48:1779-801.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1304a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1308" publication-type="other">
Gollin, D. 2002. Getting income shares right. Journal of Political Economy 110:458-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1319" publication-type="other">
Gomme, P., and J. Greenwood. 1995. On the cyclical allocation of risk. Journal of Economic Dynamics and
Control 19:91-124.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1329a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1333" publication-type="other">
Gourio, F. 2008a. Time series predictability in the disaster model. Finance Research Letters 92:68-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1340a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1344" publication-type="other">
. 2008b. Disasters and recoveries. American Economic Review - Papers and Proceedings 98:68-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1351a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1355" publication-type="other">
Henkel, S. J., J. Spencer Martin, and F. Nardari. 2011. Time-varying short-horizon predictability. Journal of
Financial Economics 99:560-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1366a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1370" publication-type="other">
Hodrick, R. J. 1992. Dividend yields and expected stock returns: Alternative procedures for inference and
measurement. Review of Financial Studies 5:357-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1380a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1384" publication-type="other">
Hubbard, R. G, J. Skinner, and S. P. Zeldes. 1995. Precautionary saving and social insurance. Journal of Political
Economy 103:360-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1394a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1398" publication-type="other">
Julliard, C., and A. Ghosh. 2012. Can rare events explain the equity premium puzzle? Review of Financial Studies
25:3037-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1408a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1412" publication-type="other">
Kramarz, F. 2001. Rigid wages: What we have learnt from microeconometric studies. Advances in macroeconomic
theory, 194-216. Ed. J. Dreze. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1422a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1426" publication-type="other">
Keim, D. B., and R. F. Stambaugh. 1986. Predicting returns in the stock and bond markets. Journal of Financial
Economics 17:357-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1436a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1440" publication-type="other">
Kocherlakota, N. 1990. On the 'discount' factor in growth economies. Journal of Monetary Economics 25:43-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1448a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1452" publication-type="other">
Krueger, A. B. 1999. Measuring labor's share. Industrial Relations Section, Princeton University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1459a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1463" publication-type="other">
Kydland, F., and E. Prescott. 1982. Time to build and aggregate fluctuations, it Econometrica 50:1345-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1470a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1474" publication-type="other">
Le Roy, S., and R. Porter. 1981. The present value relation: Tests based on implied variance bounds. Econometrica
49:555-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1484a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1488" publication-type="other">
Lettau, M., and S. Ludvigson. 2001. Consumption, aggregate wealth, and expected stock returns. Journal of
Finance 56:815-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1498a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1502" publication-type="other">
Lettau, M., S. C. Ludvigson, and J. A. Wächter. 2004. The declining equity premium: What role does
macroeconomic risk play? Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1512a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1516" publication-type="other">
Lettau, M., and J. A. Wächter. 2007. Why is long-horizon equity less risky? A duration-based explanation of the
value premium. Journal of Finance 62:55-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1527a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1531" publication-type="other">
Lucas, R. E., Jr. 1978. Asset pricing in an exchange economy. Econometrica 46:1429^4-5.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1538a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1542" publication-type="other">
Matsuyama, K. 1991. Increasing returns, industrialization, and indeterminacy of equilibrium. Quarterly Journal
of Economics 106:617-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1552a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1556" publication-type="other">
Mehra, R., and E. C. Prescott. 1985. The equity premium: A puzzle. Journal of Monetary Economics 15:145-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1563a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1567" publication-type="other">
. 1988. The equity premium: A solution? Journal of Monetary Economics 22:133-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1574a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1578" publication-type="other">
Murphy, K. M., A. Shleifer, and R. W. Vishny. 1989. Industrialization and the big push. Journal of Political
Economy 97:1003-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1588a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1592" publication-type="other">
Nelson, C. R., and C. I. Plosser. 1982. Trends and random walks in macroeconomic time series: Some evidence
and implications. Journal of Monetary Economics 10:139-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1603a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1607" publication-type="other">
Nelson, D. B. 1991. Conditional heteroskedasticity in asset returns: A new approach. Econometrica 59:347-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1614a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1618" publication-type="other">
Nordhaus, W. 2005. The sources of the productivity rebound and the manufacturing employment puzzle. Working
Paper No. 11354, NBER.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1628a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1632" publication-type="other">
Pastor, L., and R. F. Stambaugh. 2001. The equity premium and structural breaks. Journal of Finance 56:1207-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1639a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1643" publication-type="other">
Rietz, T. A. 1988. The equity risk premium: A solution. Journal of Monetary Economics 22:117-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1650a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1654" publication-type="other">
Shiller, R. J. 1981. Do stock prices move too much to be justified by subsequent changes in dividends? American
Economic Review 71:421-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1664a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1668" publication-type="other">
Stambaugh, R. F. 1999. Predictive regressions. Journal of Financial Economics 54:375^421.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1676a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1680" publication-type="other">
Veronesi, P. 1999. Stock market overreaction to bad news in good times: A rational expectations equilibrium
model. Review of Financial Studies 12:975-1007.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1690a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1694" publication-type="other">
. 2004. The peso problem hypothesis and stock market returns: New implications from a rational expectations
equilibrium model. Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control 28:707-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1704a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1708" publication-type="other">
Wächter, J. 2013. Can time-varying risk of rare disasters explain aggregate stock market volatility? Journal of
Finance 68:987-1035.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1718a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1722" publication-type="other">
West, K. D. 1988. Dividend innovations and stock price volatility. Econometrica 56:37-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1729a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1733" publication-type="other">
Whitelaw, R. F. 1997. Time varying Sharpe ratios and market timing. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1740a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1744" publication-type="other">
. 2000. Stock market risk and return: An equilibrium approach. Review of Financial Studies 13:521-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


