<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016544</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">ctbuhj</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CTBUH Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19461186</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19461194</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Council on Tall Buildings and Urban Habitat</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26768116</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Research</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>IT/Computer Science/Software</article-title>
            <subtitle>Using AI to Simulate Urban Vertical Growth</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Perez</surname>
                  <given-names>Rafael Ivan Pazos</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Carballal</surname>
                  <given-names>Adrian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rabuñal</surname>
                  <given-names>Juan R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>García-Vidaurrázaga</surname>
                  <given-names>María D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib> 
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mures</surname>
                  <given-names>Omar A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2019</year>
            <string-date>2019</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26768106</issue-id>
         <fpage>44</fpage>
         <lpage>51</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26768116"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This research explores the use of artificial intelligence to simulate how cities will grow vertically. By learning how cities have evolved in the recent past, genetic algorithms can successfully simulate vertical urban growth. The research was applied to buildings 130 meters and taller in the Minato Ward of Tokyo in 2015. An evolutionary computer model was built from a standard genetic algorithm, using historical and economic data, which then simulated future growth for the 2016 to 2019 period. The results obtained matched the area of study’s real vertical growth for the study period, with a 85.7% accuracy for the number of buildings, 73.7% for their average heights, and 96.3% for the likelihood of new construction projects happening within a mapped area. By learning how a city evolved in the past, the model replicated the future vertical growth of a city center.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">AL-SAYED, K., AND TURNER, A. 2012. “Emergence and Self-organization in Urban Structures.” Proceedings of the AGILE’2012 International Conference on Geographic Information Science, Avignon, April, 24-27, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">BAKER, J. 1987. “Reducing Bias and Inefficiency in the Selection Algorithm.” Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Genetic Algorithms and their Application. Hillsdale, New Jersey: L. Erlbaum Associates: 14-21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">BURKS, A. W. 1960. “Computation, Behavior and Structure in Fixed and Growing Automata.” Yovits, M.C. and Cameron, S. Editors, Self-Organizing Systems, Pergamon Press, pag. 282-309, New York, USA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">THE SKYSCRAPER CENTER. Council on Tall Buildings and Urban Habitat. &lt;http://www.skyscrapercenter.com/&gt; (Accessed April 1, 2019)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">EMPORIS BUILDING DIRECTORY. 2017. “Emporis Building Map: Tokyo.” &lt;https://www.emporis.com/buildings/map&gt; (Accessed June 10th 2017).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">GOOGLE EARTH. 2015. “Google Maps: Tokyo, Japan.” &lt;https://www.google.co.jp/maps/@35.6471092,139.7591565,433a,35y,318.1h,72.57t/data=!3m1!1e3&gt; (Data downloaded August 08, 2015).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">HOLLAND, J. H. 1975. Adaptation in Natural and Artificial Systems: an Introductory Analysis with Applications to Biology, Control, and Artificial Intelligence. University of Michigan Press. USA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">HOLLAND, J. H. 1998. Emergence: From Chaos to Order. Massachusetts, Helix.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">JACOBS, J. 1961. The Death and Live of the Great American Cities. New York, Vintage.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">JOHNSON, S. 2001. Emergence: The connected lives of ants, brains, cities and software. New York, Touchtone.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">KOZA, J. R. 1989. “Hierarchical Genetic Algorithms operating on Populations of computer programs.” Proceedings of the 11th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence. 768-774. Morgan Kaufmann, San Mateo, California, USA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">KOZA, J. R. 1992. Genetic Programming: On the Programming of Computers by Means of Natural Selection (Vol. 1). Massachusetts Institute of Technology. MIT press. Cambridge, Massachusetts, USA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">MATHIAS, K., WHITLEY, L., STOCK, C., AND KUSUMA, T. 1994. “Staged Hybrid Genetic Search for Seismic Data Imaging.” International Conference on Evolutionary Computation. Orlando, USA, pp. 356-361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">PAZOS, R. I. 2014. “The Historical Development of the Tokyo Skyline: Timeline and Morphology.” Journal of Asian Architecture and Building Engineering. vol.13 no.3 September 2014. P 609-615.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">PAZOS, R. I., CARBALLAL, A., GARCÍA-VIDAURRÁZAGA, M. D., MURES, O. A. AND RABUÑAL, J. R. 2017. “Predicting Vertical Urban Growth Using Genetic Evolutionary Algorithms in Tokyo’s Minato Ward.” Journal of Urban Planning and Development. J. Urban Plann. Dev., 2018, 144(1): 04017024.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">SELFRIDGE, O. G. 1958. “Pandemonium: A Paradigm for learning.” Proceedings of the Symposium on Mechanization of Thought Processes. 511-529, Teddington, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">TURING, A. 1952. “The Chemical Basis of Morphogenesis. ” Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London. Series B, Biological Sciences, Vol.237, No. 641. (Aug. 14, 1952), pp. 37-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">WEAVER, V. 1958. “A Quarter-Century in the Natural Sciences.” Rockefeller Foundation, New York. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London. Series B, Biological Sciences, Vol. 237, No. 641. (Aug. 14, 1952), pp. 37-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">WORLD BANK. 2016. “The World Bank Data: Japan.” &lt;http://data.worldbank.org/country/japan&gt; (Accessed August 08, 2016)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Partial view of the Minato Ward skyline in 2015.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Minato Ward skyline renderings from a base photogrammetric 3D image (Google Earth 2015), post-edited and rendered.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig> 
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Probabilistic diagram mapping, correlating conditions to likelihood of high-rise construction.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig> 
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Probability of High-Rise Development, Minato Ward, Tokyo, 2016-2019 allocation diagram produced from overlapping all the diagrams in Figure 3. The darker gray areas show a higher probability of future high-rise developments.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5.</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Number of buildings 130 meters and higher built per year in Minato Ward from 1960 to 2015, combined with Japan’s Gross Domestic Product (GDP) growth rates and economic stimulus packages.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig> 
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Technical specifications of the algorithm proposed.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig> 
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6.</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Genetic algorithm predictions on a probabilistic grayscale. The darker gray shows the higher probability.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig> 
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Observed available data for future construction in Minato Ward versus predictions by the algorithm for the years 2016 to 2019.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7.</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Minato Ward buildings over 130 meters in 2015. The buildings are organized by height and by plan type.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
