<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">51</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186601</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44440307</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Use of PETROLEUM PRODUCTS in AIRCRAFT</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>FRANK D.</given-names>
                  <surname>KLEIN</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1943</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>305</fpage>
         <lpage>309</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44440307"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>DISCUSSING the meteorological conditions under which aircraft operate, and so the conditions that rule the specifications of fuels and lubricants, the author points out that aircraft are used under a wide range of atmospheric pressures. Pressure variations influence chiefly the vaporlocking tendencies of the fuel system. Solubility of the air in the hydraulic oil and in the aircraftengine lubricating oil also introduces problems, under wide fluctuations of atmospheric pressure. Greatest need in engine lubricating oil development is improved stability, with consequent reduction in engine deposits. Detergent-type oils are effective in improving engine cleanliness and reducing ring sticking. Most grease lubrication can be accomplished with only two grades – a high-temperature grease and a low-temperature grease. The low-temperature grease is used chiefly for intermittently operated units that are never subject to high temperatures. The high-temperature grease is used for continuously operated units, which are subject to low temperatures for only short periods and which normally are kept warm. Corrosion preventives for aircraft fall into two general classes: One for the protection of exterior surfaces of parts, and the other for interior protection of engines. They consist generally of a rust-inhibiting base incorporated in a liquid or solid vehicle, depending on the desired method of application and the type of protective film.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


