<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275578</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Study of Ignition Characteristics of an HCCI Engine Operating on a Two-component Fuel</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Saitou</surname>
                  <given-names>Kenji</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Iijima</surname>
                  <given-names>Akira</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Otagiri</surname>
                  <given-names>Yasuhiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yoshida</surname>
                  <given-names>Koji</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Takahashi</surname>
                  <given-names>Yusuke</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shoji</surname>
                  <given-names>Hideo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Nihon University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275542</issue-id>
         <fpage>529</fpage>
         <lpage>536</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International and Copyright © 2010 SAE Japan</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275578"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The Homogenous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) engine is positioned as a next-generation internal combustion engine and has been the focus of extensive research in recent years to develop a practical system. One reason is that this new combustion system achieves lower fuel consumption and simultaneous reductions of nitrogen oxide (NOx) and particulate matter (PM) emissions, which are major issues of internal combustion engines today. However, the characteristics of HCCI combustion can prevent suitable engine operation owing to the rapid combustion process that occurs accompanied by a steep pressure rise when the amount of fuel injected is increased to obtain higher power output. A major issue of HCCI is to control this rapid combustion so that the quantity of fuel injected can be increased for greater power. Controlling the ignition timing is also an issue because it is substantially influenced by the chemical reactions of the fuel. Various approaches are being researched for expanding the range of stable engine operation, including the application of turbocharging, the use of residual combustion gas, stratification of the fuel concentration, and the use of a blend of two types of fuel having widely different ignition characteristics.</p>
            <p>This study focused on the use of a mixture of two fuels with different ignition characteristics. Experiments were conducted using a blend of n-heptane (0 RON) as a readily autoignitable fuel and iso-octane (100 RON) as a fuel non-conducive to autoignition. The results showed that this approach enables the amount of fuel injected to be increased while controlling the ignition timing.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thiring, R. H., “Homogeneous Charge Compression- Ignition (HCCI) Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 892068, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Einewall, P. and Johansson, B., “Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Using Isooctane, Ethanol and Natural Gas-A Compression With Spark-Ignition Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 972874, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aoyama, T., Hattori, Y., Mizuta, Jo., and Sato, Y., “An Experimental Study on Premixed-Charge Compression- Ignition Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 960081, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Onishi, S., Jo, S. H., Shoda, K., Jo, D. P., and Kato, S., “Active Thermo-Atmosphere Combustion (ATAC) - A New Combustion Process for Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 790501, 1979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iida, N., “Combustion Analysis of Method-Fueled Active Thermo-Atmosphere Combustion (ATAC) Engine Using a Spectroscopic Observation,” SAE Technical Paper 940684, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishibashi, Y., and Asai, M., “Improving the Exhaust Emissions of Two -Stroke Engines by Applying the Activated Radical Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 960742, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iijima, A. and Shoji, H.: A Study on HCCI Combustion using Light Emission and Absorption Measurements, JSAE Transactions (in Japanese), Vol. 38, No. 6, pp. 83-88, (2007).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Katayama, T., Yamasaki, Y., Kasutya, H., Iijima, A. and Shoji, H.: A Study of Combustion Characteristics of an HCCI Engine using Internal EGR, Proceedings of the 2008 JSAE Annual Congress (in Japanese), No.124-08, p.15-18, (2008).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saitou, K., Katayama, T., Iijima, A. and Shoji, H.: A Study of Combustion Characteristics of an HCCI Engine using Spectroscopic Techniques, Proceedings of the 2009 JSAE Annual Congress (in Japanese), No.91-09, p.21-24, (2009).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaydon, A. G.: The Spectroscopy of Flame-2nd Edition, London, Chapman and Hall Ltd, 1974, 412p.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shoji, H., Saima, A. and Shiino, K.: Simultaneous Measurement of Light Absorption Behavior of Unburned Gas During Knocking Operation, SAE 1993 Transactions, Section-4, Vol. 102. p. 1492-1550 (1993).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B.: “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, McGraw-Hill International Editions, (1989).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, H. J., Gaffuri, P., Pitz, W. J., and Westbrook, C. K.: A Comprehensive Modeling Study of n-Heptane Oxidation, Combustion and Flame, Vol. 114, p. 149-177, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, H. J., Gaffuri, P., Pitz, W. J., and Westbrook, C. K.: A Comprehensive Modeling Study of n-Heptane Oxidation, Combustion and Flame, Vol. 129, p. 253-280, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, H. J., P., Pitz, W. J., Westbrook, C. K., Callahan, C. V., and Dryer, F. L.: Oxidation of Automotive Primary Reference Fuels at Elevated Pressures, Proc. Combust. Inst., Vol. 27, p. 379-387, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
