<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Wiley</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26604811</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Original Articles</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Is UK Vice Chancellor Pay Justified by University Performance?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bachan</surname>
                  <given-names>Ray</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reilly</surname>
                  <given-names>Barry</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">36</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26604808</issue-id>
         <fpage>51</fpage>
         <lpage>73</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26604811"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The pay of university managers (vice chancellors, VCs) in the UK has risen sharply in recent years. This paper considers the extent to which VC pay awards are related to university performance measures based around institution mission and financial probity using an individual fixed effects strategy based on data covering academic years 1998–99 to 2008–09. In contrast to earlier studies on this theme, we find evidence that VCs are rewarded for observable mission-based performance measures. Specifically, our results suggest that success in widening participation for students from comprehensive schools and those from areas with low university participation exerts a positive effect on VCs’ pay. Securing income flows from university funding council grants also impacts positively on their remuneration. However, even after controlling for a rich array of observable and unobservable factors, there have been sizeable increases in real pay in recent years that cannot be readily explained.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Acharya, V. and Volpin, P. (2010), ‘Corporate governance externalities’, Review of Finance, vol. 14, pp. 1–33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Audas, R., Barmby, T. and Treble, J. (2004), ‘Luck, effort, and reward in an organisational hierarchy’, Journal of Labor Economics, vol. 22, pp. 375–95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Baimbridge, M. and Simpson, C. (1996), ‘Rewards to academia: the remuneration of vice chancellors and principals’, Applied Economics, vol. 28, pp. 631–9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bargh, C., Bocock, J., Scott, P. and Smith, D. (2000), University Leadership: The Role of the Chief Executive, Maidenhead: Society for Research into Higher Education (SRHE) and Open University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bebchuk, L. and Fried, J. (2003), ‘Executive compensation as an agency problem’, Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 17, no. 3, pp. 71–92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Bebchuk, L. and Fried, J.(2006), ‘Pay without performance: overview of the issues’, Academy of Management Perspectives, vol. 20, pp. 5–24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Becker, G. S. (1993), Human Capital: A Theoretical and Empirical Analysis, with Special Reference to Education, third edition, Chicago, IL: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Bell, B. and Van Reenen, J. (2011), ‘Firm performance and wages: evidence from across the corporate hierarchy’, London School of Economics, Centre for Economic Performance (CEP), Discussion Paper no. 1088.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Bertrand, M. and Mullainathan, S. (2001), ‘Are CEOs rewarded for luck? The ones without principals are’, Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 116, pp. 901–32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Blanchard, O., Lopez-de-Silanes, F. and Shleifer, A. (1994), ‘What do firms do with cash windfalls?’, Journal of Finance and Economics, vol. 36, pp. 337–60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Bognanno, M. (2001), ‘Corporate tournaments’, Journal of Labor Economics, vol. 19, pp. 290–315.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Chen, J., Ezzamel, M. and Cai, Z. (2011), ‘Managerial power theory, tournament theory, and executive pay in China’, Journal of Corporate Finance, vol. 17, pp. 1179–99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Clark, A., Kristensen, N. and Westergard-Nielsen, N. (2009), ‘Job satisfaction and co-worker wages: status or signal’, Economic Journal, vol. 119, pp. 430–47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Committee of University Chairs. (2009), Guide for Members of Higher Education Governing Bodies in the UK: Governance Code of Practice and General Principles, Bristol: Higher Education Funding Council for England (HEFCE).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Conyon, M. (1997), ‘Corporate governance and executive compensation’, International Journal of Industrial Organization, vol. 15, pp. 493–510.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Conyon, M. (2006), ‘Executive compensation and incentives’, Academy of Management Perspectives, vol. 20, pp. 25–44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Conyon, M., Gregg, P. and Machin, S. (1995), ‘Taking care of business: executive compensation in the United Kingdom’, Economic Journal, vol. 105, pp. 704–14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Conyon, M. and Murphy, K. (2000), ‘The prince and the pauper? CEO pay in the United States and the United Kingdom’, Economic Journal, vol. 110, pp. F640–71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Conyon, M., Peck, S., Read, L. and Sadler, G. (2000), ‘The structure of executive compensation contracts: UK evidence’, Long Range Planning, vol. 33, pp. 478–503.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Cornell, B. (2004), ‘Compensation and recruiting: private universities versus private corporations’, Journal of Corporate Finance, vol. 10, pp. 37–52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Data.Gov.UK, ‘Senior officials “high earners” salaries 2011’, HM Government (http://data.gov.uk/dataset/uk-civil-service-high-earners).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Department for Education &amp; Skills (2003), The Future of Higher Education, Cm. 5735, Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">DeVaro, J. (2006), ‘Strategic promotion tournaments and worker performance’, Strategic Management Journal, vol. 27, pp. 721–40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Dixit, A. (2002), ‘Incentives and organizations in the public sector’, Journal of Human Resources, vol. 37, pp. 696–727.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Dolton, P. and Ma, A. (2003), ‘CEO pay in the public sector: the case of vice chancellors in UK universities’, Newcastle University, Discussion Paper in Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Dolton, P. and Makepeace, G. (1982), ‘University typology: a contemporary analysis’, Higher Education Review, vol. 13, pp. 33–47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Ehrenberg, R., Cheslock, J. and Epifantseva, J. (2001), ‘Paying our presidents: what do trustees value?’, Review of Higher Education, vol. 25, pp. 15–37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Fabbri, F. and Marin, D. (2012), ‘What explains CEO pay in Germany? A panel data analysis for 1977–2009’, Institute for the Study of Labor (IZA), Discussion Paper no. 6420.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Farnham, D. and Jones, J. (1998), ‘Who are the vice chancellors and principals in the UK? An analysis of their professional and social backgrounds 1990–1997’, Higher Education Review, vol. 30, pp. 42–58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Frydman, C. and Jenter, D. (2010), ‘CEO compensation’, Annual Review of Financial Economics, vol. 2, pp. 75–102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Gabaix, X. and Landier, A. (2008), ‘Why has CEO pay increased so much?’, Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 123, pp. 49–100.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Girma, S., Thompson, S. and Wright, P. (2007), ‘Corporate governance reforms and executive compensation determination: evidence from the UK’, The Manchester School, vol. 75, pp. 65–81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Gregg, P., Jewell, S. and Tonks, T. (2010), ‘Executive pay and performance in the UK’, London School of Economics, Financial Markets Group (FMG), Discussion Paper no. 657.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Gregg, P., Machin, S. and Szymanski, S. (1993), ‘The disappearing relationship between directors’ pay and corporate performance’, British Journal of Industrial Relations, vol. 31, pp. 1–10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Holmstrom, B. (1979), ‘Moral hazard and observability’, Bell Journal of Economics, vol. 10, pp. 74–91.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Hutton, W. (2011), Hutton Review of Fair Pay in the Public Sector: Final Report, London: HM Treasury.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Jensen, M. and Murphy, K. (1990), ‘Performance pay and top-management incentives’, Journal of Political Economy, vol. 98, pp. 225–64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Jensen, M., Murphy, K. and Wruck, E. (2004), ‘Remuneration: where we’ve been, how we got to here, what are the problems, and how to fix them’, Harvard, NOM (Negotiations, Organizations and Markets) Working Paper no. 04-28 and European Corporate Governance Institute (ECGI), Finance Working Paper no. 44/2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Jensen, M. and Zimmerman, J. (1985), ‘Management compensation and the managerial labor market’, Journal of Accounting and Economics, vol. 7, pp. 3–9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Knoeber, R. and Thurman W. (1994), ‘Testing the theory of tournaments: an empirical analysis of broiler production’, Journal of Labor Economics, vol. 12, pp. 155–79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Lazear, E. and Rosen, S. (1981), ‘Rank-order tournaments as optimal labor contracts’, Journal of Political Economy, vol. 89, pp. 841–64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Main, B. and Johnston, J. (1993), ‘Remuneration committees and corporate governance’, Accounting and Business Research, vol. 23, pp. 351–62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Main, B., O’Reilly, C. and Wade, J. (1993), ‘Top executive pay: tournament or teamwork?’, Journal of Labor Economics, vol. 11, pp. 606–28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Main, B., O’Reilly, C. and Wade, J. (1995), ‘The CEO, the Board of Directors, and executive compensation: economic and psychological perspectives’, Industrial and Corporate Change, vol. 11, pp. 606–28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Marsden, D. (2010), ‘The paradox of performance related pay systems: why do we keep adopting them in the face of evidence that they fail to motivate?’, in H. Margetts, P. 6 and C. Hood (eds), Paradoxes of Modernization: Unintended Consequences of Public Policy Reform, Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Mincer, J. (1974), Schooling, Experience and Earnings, New York: National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Mirrlees, J. (1976), ‘The optimal structure of incentives and authority within an organisation’, Bell Journal of Economics, vol. 7, pp. 105–31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Morse, A., Nanda, V. and Seru, A. (2011), ‘Are incentive contracts rigged by powerful CEOs?’, Journal of Finance, vol. 66, pp. 1779–821.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Murphy, K. (1985), ‘Corporate performance and managerial remuneration: an empirical analysis’, Journal of Accounting and Economics, vol. 7, pp. 11–42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Murphy, K. (1986), ‘Incentives, learning, and compensation: a theoretical and empirical investigation of managerial labor contracts’, Rand Journal of Economics, vol. 17, pp. 69–76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Murphy, K. (1999), ‘Executive compensation’, in O. Ashenfelter and D. Card (eds), Handbook of Labor Economics, Volume 3, Amsterdam: North Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Newman, H. and Mozes, H. (1999), ‘Does the composition of the compensation committee influence CEO compensation practices?’, Financial Management, vol. 28, pp. 41–53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">O’Reilly, C., Main, B. and Crystal, G. (1988), ‘CEO compensation as tournament and social comparison: a tale of two theories’, Administrative Science Quarterly, vol. 33, pp. 273–4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Parry, G. (2006), ‘Policy-participation trajectories in English higher education’, Higher Education Quarterly, vol. 60, pp. 392–412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Prendergast, C. (1999), ‘The provision of incentives in firms’, Journal of Economic Literature, vol. 37, pp. 7–63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Rosen, S. (1986), ‘Prizes and incentives in elimination tournaments’, American Economic Review, vol. 76, pp. 701–15.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Shattock, M. (1999), ‘Governance and management incentives: the way we live now’, Journal of Education Policy, vol. 14, pp. 271–82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Smith, D., Bargh, C., Bocock, J. and Scott, P. (1999), ‘New leaders at the top? The educational and career paths of UK university vice-chancellors (1960–1996)’, Higher Education Management, vol. 11, pp. 113–35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Tarbert, H., Tee, K. and Watson, R. (2008), ‘The legitimacy of pay and performance comparisons: an analysis of UK university chancellors pay awards’, British Journal of Industrial Relations, vol. 46, pp. 771–805.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Tirole, J. (1994), ‘The internal organisation of government’, Oxford Economic Papers, vol. 46, pp. 1–29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Whitchurch, C. (2006), ‘Who do they think they are? The changing identities of professional administrators and managers in UK higher education’, Journal of Higher Education Policy and Management, vol. 28, pp. 159–71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Average annual real pay at 1998 prices: all VCs, CEOs/directors, senior executives and university lecturers</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>VCs’ average annual real pay by institution type at 1998 prices</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Summary statistics at vice-chancellor level</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Vice-chancellor pay and performance: VC fixed effects estimator</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
