<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277826</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>In-Cycle Real-Time Prediction Technology of NOx Emission of Diesel Engines Based on Cylinder Pressure</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
                  <given-names>Jingyi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yang</surname>
                  <given-names>Fuyuan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>State Key Lab. of Auto Safety and Energy</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277784</issue-id>
         <fpage>1084</fpage>
         <lpage>1092</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277826"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper was targeted on achieving in-cycle real-time prediction of NOx emission of diesel engines in both steady-state and transient processes based on cylinder pressure. Specifically, input parameters of the NOx emission model were determined, an offline empirical model of NOx emission was built based on steady-state test data, and in-cycle real-time prediction of NOx emission was achieved in the in-cylinder combustion analysis tool.</p>
            <p>Based on the mechanism of NOx formation, combustion state parameters in strong correlation with NOx emission were extracted from cylinder pressure, rate of cylinder pressure, rate of heat release, accumulated heat release and burned zone temperature. Quantitative correlations between combustion state parameters and NOx emission were calculated based on steady-state test data and the inputs of the empirical model of NOx emission were determined. The quadratic polynomial model from combustion state parameters to NOx emission was built based on steady-state test data. The combustion state parameters and quadratic polynomial model functions were added in the in-cylinder combustion analysis tool, which was developed based on MPC5644A MCU. NOx emission measured from test data and predicted from in-cylinder combustion analysis tool were compared under both steady-state and transient processes, and the accuracy of in-cycle real-time prediction of NOx emission was verified. Under steady-state operating conditions: except for one bad condition, relative errors of the other 15 conditions were all less than 10% ; average relative error of the 16 conditions was 6.8%. Under transient operating conditions, the prediction accuracy of NOx emission was slightly worse.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arrègle, J., López, J., Guardiola, C., and Monin, C., “Sensitivity Study of a NOx Estimation Model for On-Board Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0640, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01- 0640.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Winkler-Ebner, B., Hirsch, M., Del Re, L., Klinger, H. et al., “Comparison of Virtual and Physical NOx-Sensors for Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Application,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):1124-1139, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1296.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Y., He, Y., and Rajagopalan, S., “Design of Engine- Out Virtual NOx Sensor Using Neural Networks and Dynamic System Identification,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):837-849, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0694.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gao Guojing, Yang Fuyuan, Ouyang Minggao, Fang Cheng, “SOC Detection of Diesel Engines Based on Online Estimation of Motored Pressure,” ICEF2013-19030,2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yuping Yang, “Cylinder pressure-based closed-loop combustion control technology research in diesel engines [Master thesis],” Beijing: Tsinghua University, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wilhelmsson, C., Tunestål, P., Widd, B., and Johansson, R., “A Physical Two-Zone NOx Model Intended for Embedded Implementation,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1509, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1509.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng Liu, Jianxin Wang, “Automobile engine theory tutorial,” Beijing: Tsinghua University Press, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Çebi, E., Rottenkolber, G., and Uyar, E., “In-Cylinder Pressure Based Real-Time Estimation of Engine-Out Particulate Matter Emissions of a Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01- 1440, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1440.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
