<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437369</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Lone Mothers, Family Credit and Paid Work</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>ANDREW</given-names>
                  <surname>DILNOT</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>ALAN</given-names>
                  <surname>DUNCAN</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>1992</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">13</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437365</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>21</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 1992</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437369"/>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d15e239a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e246" publication-type="other">
Simulation Program for the Analysis of Incentives (see Blundell, Meghir, Symons and Walker (1988) and Duncan
(1991)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e256a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e263" publication-type="other">
More formally, virtually all single parents in our sample were found to satisfy the Slutsky concavity condition.
In other words, single parents were modelled to behave in a manner almost universally consistent with economic
theory.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e276a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e283" publication-type="other">
See Dilnot, Kay and Morris ( 1984) Chapter 1 for a discussion of the development of the UK social security system,
HMSO (1985) and Dilnot and Webb (1988) for a discussion of the 1988 reforms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e293a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e300" publication-type="other">
Subject to deduction such as mortgage interest and private pension contributions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e308a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e315" publication-type="other">
See Bingley, Symons and Walker (1991), Ermisch and Wright (1989) and Haskey (1989).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e322a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e329" publication-type="other">
A 'probit' analysis is favoured here. The probit technique looks at the statistical relationship between an
unohservable dependent variable (in this case, the probability of participation) and a series of observable variables
(independent variables) assumed to have some bearing on the participation probability. The precise specification
of the probit equation is unavoidably a matter of subjective choice, but variables are included with some prior
economic interpretation. Table A1 of the Data Appendix reports econometric estimates of our participation probit.
A 't-statistic' of around 2 or over indicates that the associated variable has a statistically significant impact on
participation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e355a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e362" publication-type="other">
In the participation probit, the presence of the single parent's mother in the household was included in order to
capture the availability of informal childcare. Formal childcare provision was proxied by the regional density of
full day-care places (see Table Al, Data Appendix). The parameters of both variables are strong and positive.
Moreover, even with the inclusion of variables to capture both regional differences and time variation, the formal
childcare parameter returns a near-significant value.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e381a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e388" publication-type="other">
Calculations are based on the participation probit equation presented in the Data Appendix.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e395a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e402" publication-type="other">
There is a question of causality here. Some single mothers choose to work because their parents are able to look
after the children. However, some single parents may choose to move in with (or stay with) their parents precisely
because they work. Which is cause and which is effect is not clear.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e415a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e422" publication-type="other">
The model used is a variant of the 'semi-log supply' function, and takes the form h = a+ ß In w + y (t/vv where h
represents hours of work, w is the marginal wage and p denotes the unearned income of the household. Parameters
a, ß and yean be varied to reflect demographic heterogeneity. The model is an attractive one for simulation since
the indirect utility function can be explicitly derived. Thus it is relatively simple to carry out utility comparisons
across different segments of a household budget constraint in order to estimate the most preferred choice of hours.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e442a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e449" publication-type="other">
This is not an uncommon feature in estimates of the labour supply behaviour of single parents. Some lone mothers
place a high valuation on their non-work time, given the range of commitments away from the workplace. They
seek to attain a certain standard of living with the minimum amount of time at work. Given an increase in the
marginal wage rate, it may suit such households to reduce labour supply (maintaining earned income at current
levels) rather than to increase their labour supply to take advantage of the wage rise. In other words, some single
parents value an extra hour of non-work time more highly than an extra hour's wages. This is an important point
for policy-makers to recognise, and shows that work incentive effects from changing the tax-benefit system can
be positive or negative.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e478a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e485" publication-type="other">
As with most simulation procedures, we compare preferred hours (rather than actual hours) under the base tax
system with preferred hours under the reform. Given the random preference structure of our model, actual and
preferred hours can diverge quite markedly during simulation. This divergence is due mainly to the measurement
and optimisation errors associated with hours and wages in our sample. We may not observe people to work exactly
the number of hours they want for a number of reasons (misreporting, institutional constraints). However, with the
random preference interpretation, all individuals are assumed to work their preferred number of hours. Clearly, this
is an issue which must be addressed in future work.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d15e520a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e524" publication-type="other">
Bingley, P., Symons, E. and Walker, I. (1991), 'The labour supply of UK lone mothers: the effects of
maintenance and the welfare system', mimeo, Keele University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e534a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e538" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R. W., Duncan, A. S. and Meghir, C. (1990), 'Endogeneity, selectivity and taxes in female
labour supply models', mimeo, Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e548a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e552" publication-type="other">
—, — and — (1991), 'Taxation in empirical labour supply models: lone mothers in the UK', Economic
Journal, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e562a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e566" publication-type="other">
—, Fry, V. C. and Walker, I. (1988), 'Modelling the take-up of means-tested benefits: the case of
housing benefits in the UK', Economic Journal, vol. 98, pp. 58-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e577a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e581" publication-type="other">
—, Meghir, C., Symons, E. and Walker, I. (1988), 'Labour supply specification and the empirical
evaluation of tax reform', Journal of Public Economics, July.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e591a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e595" publication-type="other">
Davis, E. H. and Dilnot, A. W. (1985), 'Restructuring of National Insurance contributions in the 1985
Budget', Fiscal Studies, vol. 6, no. 2, pp. 51-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e605a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e609" publication-type="other">
Dilnot, A. W„ Kay, J. A. and Morris, C. N. (1984), The Reform of Social Security, Oxford: Oxford
University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e619a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e623" publication-type="other">
— and Webb, S. J. (1988), 'The 1988 social security reforms', Fiscal Studies, vol. 9, no. 3, pp. 26-53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e630a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e634" publication-type="other">
—and—(1989), 'Reforming National Insurance contributions: a progress report', Fiscal Studies, vol.
10, no. 2, pp. 38-47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e644a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e648" publication-type="other">
Duncan, A. S. (1990), 'Labour supply decisions and non-convex budget sets', Institute for Fiscal
Studies Working Paper no. W90/7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e659a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e663" publication-type="other">
— (1991), 'A microsimulation model of labour supply for UK tax reform', University of Konstanz
Discussion Paper Series II no. 153.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e673a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e677" publication-type="other">
Ermisch, J. F. and Wright, R. E. (1989), 'Lone parenthood in Great Britain: male-female differences',
Birkbeck College Department of Economics Discussion Paper no. 89/9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e687a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e691" publication-type="other">
Fry, V. C. and Stark, G. K. (1987), 'Take-up of supplementary benefit: gaps in the "safety net"?',
Fiscal Studies, vol. 8, no. 4, pp. 1-14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e701a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e705" publication-type="other">
— and — (1991), 'New rich or old poor: poverty, take-up and indexation of the state pension', Fiscal
Studies, vol. 12, no. 1, pp. 67-77.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e715a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e719" publication-type="other">
Haskey, J. (1989), 'One parent families and their children in Great Britain: numbers and
characteristics', Population Trends, vol. 55, pp. 27-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e729a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e733" publication-type="other">
HMSO (1985), Reform of Social Security: Programme for Action, Cmnd 9691, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e741a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e745" publication-type="other">
Johnson, P. G., Stark, G. K. and Webb, S. J. (1990), "TAXBEN2: the new IFS tax-benefit model',
Institute for Fiscal Studies Working Paper no. W90/5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e755a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e759" publication-type="other">
Walker, I. (1990), 'The effects of income support measures on the labour market behaviour of lone
mothers', Fiscal Studies, vol. 11, no. 2, pp. 55-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
