<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">mathcomp</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100273</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Mathematics of Computation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>American Mathematical Society</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00255718</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">10886842</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">83</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">285</issue>
         <issue-id>i24488196</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24488205</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>AN A POSTERIORI ERROR ESTIMATE FOR VERTEX-CENTERED FINITE VOLUME DISCRETIZATIONS OF IMMISCIBLE INCOMPRESSIBLE TWO-PHASE FLOW</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>CLÉMENT</given-names>
                  <surname>CANCÈS</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>IULIU SORIN</given-names>
                  <surname>POP</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>MARTIN</given-names>
                  <surname>VOHRALÍK</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>153</fpage>
         <lpage>188</lpage>
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2014 American Mathematical Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24488205"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>In this paper we derive an a posteriori error estimate for the numerical approximation of the solution of a system modeling the flow of two incompressible and immiscible fluids in a porous medium. We take into account the capillary pressure, which leads to a coupled system of two equations: parabolic and elliptic. The parabolic equation may become degenerate, i.e., the nonlinear diffusion coefficient may vanish over regions that are not known a priori. We first show that, under appropriate assumptions, the energy-type norm differences between the exact and the approximate nonwetting phase saturations, the global pressures, and the Kirchhoff transforms of the nonwetting phase saturations can be bounded by the dual norm of the residuals. We then bound the dual norm of the residuals by fully computable a posteriori estimators. Our analysis covers a large class of conforming, vertex-centered finite volume-type discretizations with fully implicit time stepping. As an example, we focus here on two approaches: a "mathematical" scheme derived from the weak formulation, and a phase-by-phase upstream weighting "engineering" scheme. Finally, we show how the different error components, namely the space discretization error, the time discretization error, the linearization error, the algebraic solver error, and the quadrature error can be distinguished and used for making the calculations efficient.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1770594e156a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e163" publication-type="other">
M. Ainsworth and J. T. ODEN, A posteriori error estimation in finite element analysis,
Pure and Applied Mathematics (New York), Wiley-Interscience [John Wiley &amp; Sons], New
York, 2000. MR1885308 (2003b:65001)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e176a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e183" publication-type="other">
G. Akrivis, C. Makridakis, and R. H. Nochetto, A posteriori error estimates for the
Crank-Nicolson method for parabolic equations, Math. Comp., 75 (2006), pp. 511—531.
MR2196979 (2007a:65114)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e196a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e203" publication-type="other">
H. W. Alt and S. Luckhaus, Quasilinear elliptic-parabolic differential equations, Math. Z.,
183 (1983), pp. 311-341. MR706391 (85c:35059)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e213a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e220" publication-type="other">
L. Angermann, P. Knabner, AND K. Thiele, An error estimator for a finite volume
discretization of density driven flow in porous media, Appl. Numer. Math., 26 (1998),
pp. 179-191. Proceedings of the International Centre for Mathematical Sciences Conference
on Grid Adaptation in Computational PDEs: Theory and Applications (Edinburgh, 1996).
MR1602860 (98m:76116)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e240a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e247" publication-type="other">
S. N. Antontsev, A. V. Kazhikhov, and V. N. Monakhov, Boundary value problems in
mechanics of nonhomogeneous fluids, North-Holland, Amsterdam, 1990. Studies in Mathe-
matics and Its Applications, Vol. 22. MR1035212 (91d:76018)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e260a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e267" publication-type="other">
T. ARBOGAST, The existence of weak solutions to single porosity and simple dual-porosity
models of two-phase incompressible flow, Nonlinear Anal., 19 (1992), pp. 1009-1031.
MR1194142 (93k:76107)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e280a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e287" publication-type="other">
J. Bear, Dynamics of Fluids in Porous Media, American Elsevier, New York, 1972.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e294a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e301" publication-type="other">
J. Bear and Y. Bachmat, Introduction to Modeling of Transport Phenomena in Porous
Media, vol. 4 of Theory and Applications of Transport in Porous Media, Kluwer Academic
Publishers, Dordrecht, Holland, 1990.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e314a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e321" publication-type="other">
F. Brezzi and M. Fortin, Mixed and hybrid finite element methods, vol. 15 of Springer Series
in Computational Mathematics, Springer-Verlag, New York, 1991. MR1115205 (92d:65187)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e331a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e338" publication-type="other">
C. Cances and T. Gallouet, On the time continuity of entropy solutions, J. Evol. Equ., 11
(2011). MR2780572 (2012b:35140)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e349a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e356" publication-type="other">
J. Carrillo, Entropy solutions for nonlinear degenerate problems, Arch. Ration. Mech. Anal.,
147 (1999), pp. 269-361. MR1709116 (2000m:35132)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e366a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e373" publication-type="other">
G. Chavent and J. Jaffre, Mathematical models and finite elements for reservoir simula-
tion, North-Holland, Amsterdam, 1986. Studies in Mathematics and Its Applications, Vol. 17.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e383a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e390" publication-type="other">
Y. Chen AND W. LlU, A posteriori error estimates of mixed methods for miscible displace-
ment problems, Internat. J. Numer. Methods Engrg., 73 (2008), pp. 331—343. MR2382047
(2009b:76157)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e403a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e410" publication-type="other">
Z. Chen, Degenerate two-phase incompressible flow. I. Existence, uniqueness and regularity of
a weak solution, J. Differential Equations, 171 (2001), pp. 203-232. MR1818648 (2002a:76158)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e420a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e427" publication-type="other">
—, Degenerate two-phase incompressible flow. II. Regularity, stability and stabilization,
J. Differential Equations, 186 (2002), pp. 345-376. MR1942213</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e437a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e444" publication-type="other">
Z. CHEN AND R. E. Ewing, Degenerate two-phase incompressible flow. III. Sharp error esti-
mates, Numer. Math., 90 (2001), pp. 215-240. MR1872726 (2002j:76128)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e455a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e462" publication-type="other">
—, Degenerate two-phase incompressible flow. IV. Local refinement and domain decom-
position, J. Sci. Comput., 18 (2003), pp. 329-360. MR1967254</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e472a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e479" publication-type="other">
Z. Chen and G. Ji, Sharp L1 a posteriori error analysis for nonlinear convection-diffusion
problems, Math. Comp., 75 (2006), pp. 43-71. MR2176389 (2006h:65134)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e489a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e496" publication-type="other">
J. DE FrutOS, B. Garcia-Archilla, and J. Novo, A posteriori error estimates for fully
discrete nonlinear parabolic problems, Comput. Methods Appl. Mech. Engrg., 196 (2007),
pp. 3462-3474. MR2335276 (2008f:65161)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e509a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e516" publication-type="other">
D. A. Di PlETRO, M. Vohralik, and C. WlDMER, An a posteriori error estimator for a
finite volume discretization of the two-phase flow, in Finite Volumes for Complex Applications
VI, J. Fort, J. Fiirst, J. Halama, R. Herbin, and F. Hubert, eds., Berlin, Heidelberg, 2011,
Springer-Verlag, pp. 341-349. MR2882311</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e532a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e539" publication-type="other">
D. A. Di PlETRO, M. Vohralik, and S. Yousef, Adaptive regularization, linearization, and
discretization and a posteriori error control for the two-phase Stefan problem. HAL Preprint
00690862, submitted for publication, 2012.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e552a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e559" publication-type="other">
V. DOLEJSI, A. Ern, AND M. VOHRALIK, A framework for robust a posteriori error control
in unsteady nonlinear advection-diffusion problems. SIAM J. Numer. Anal. 51 (2013), no. 2,
773-793. DOI 10.1137/110859282. MR3033032</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e573a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e580" publication-type="other">
L. El Alaoui, A. Ern, AND M. VOHRALIK, Guaranteed and robust a posteriori error esti-
mates and balancing discretization and linearization errors for monotone nonlinear problems,
Comput. Methods Appl. Mech. Engrg., 200 (2011), pp. 597-613. MR2811915 (2012e:65267)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e593a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e600" publication-type="other">
K. Eriksson and C. Johnson, Adaptive finite element methods for parabolic problems.
IV. Nonlinear problems, SIAM J. Numer. Anal., 32 (1995), pp. 1729-1749. MR1360457
(96i:65081)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e613a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e620" publication-type="other">
A. Ern AND M. VOHRALIK, A posteriori error estimation based on potential and flux recon-
struction for the heat equation, SIAM J. Numer. Anal., 48 (2010), pp. 198-223. MR2608366
(2011d:65281)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e633a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e640" publication-type="other">
A. Ern AND M. Vohrali'k, Adaptive inexact Newton methods with a posteriori stopping
criteria for nonlinear diffusion PDEs, SIAM J. Sci. Comput., Accepted for publication, 2013.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e650a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e657" publication-type="other">
R. Eymard and T. Gallouet, Convergence d'un schema de type elements finis-volumes
finis pour un systeme forme d'une equation elliptique et d'une equation hyperbolique, RAIRO
Model. Math. Anal. Numer., 27 (1993), pp. 843-861. MR1249455 (95b:65118)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e670a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e677" publication-type="other">
R. Eymard, T. Gallouet, and R. Herbin, Finite volume methods, in Handbook of Nu-
merical Analysis, Vol. VII, North-Holland, Amsterdam, 2000, pp. 713—1020. MR1804748
(2002e:65138)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e691a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e698" publication-type="other">
R. Eymard, R. Herbin, and A. Michel, Mathematical study of a petroleum-engineering
scheme, M2AN Math. Model. Numer. Anal., 37 (2003), pp. 937-972. MR2026403
(2004j:76147)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e711a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e718" publication-type="other">
L. GALLIMARD, P. LADEVEZE, and J. P. Pelle, Error estimation and time-space parameters
optimization for FEM non-linear computation, Computers &amp;; Structures, 64 (1997), pp. 145—
156.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e731a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e738" publication-type="other">
R. Huber and R. Helmig, Node-centered finite volume discretizations for the numerical
simulation of multiphase flow in heterogeneous porous media, Comput. Geosci., 4 (2000),
pp. 141-164. MR1800561 (2001j:76073)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e751a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e758" publication-type="other">
W. Jager and J. Kacur, Solution of doubly nonlinear and degenerate parabolic problems by
relaxation schemes, RAIRO Model. Math. Anal. Numer., 29 (1995), pp. 605-627. MR1352864
(96g:65087)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e771a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e778" publication-type="other">
P. Jiranek, Z. Strakos, and M. Vohrali'k, A posteriori error estimates including algebraic
error and stopping criteria for iterative solvers, SIAM J. Sci. Comput., 32 (2010), pp. 1567-
1590. MR2652091 (2011e:65233)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e791a1310">
            <label>34</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e798" publication-type="other">
D. Kroner and S. LuckhauS, Flow of oil and water in a porous medium, J. Differential
Equations, 55 (1984), pp. 276-288. MR764127 (85k:35211)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e809a1310">
            <label>35</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e816" publication-type="other">
S. N. KRUZKOV, First order quasilinear equations with several independent variables., Mat.
Sb. (N.S.), 81 (123) (1970), pp. 228-255. MR0267257 (42:2159)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e826a1310">
            <label>36</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e833" publication-type="other">
A. MICHEL, A finite volume scheme for two-phase immiscible flow in porous media, SIAM J.
Numer. Anal., 41 (2003), pp. 1301-1317. MR2034882 (2005a:65087)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e843a1310">
            <label>37</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e850" publication-type="other">
P. Neittaanmaki and S. Repin, Reliable methods for computer simulation, vol. 33 of Studies
in Mathematics and its Applications, Elsevier Science B.V., Amsterdam, 2004. Error control
and a posteriori estimates. MR2095603 (2005k:65005)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e863a1310">
            <label>38</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e870" publication-type="other">
R. H. NOCHETTO, G. Savare, AND C. Verdi, A posteriori error estimates for variable time-
step discretizations of nonlinear evolution equations, Comm. Pure Appl. Math., 53 (2000),
pp. 525-589. MR1737503 (2000k:65142)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e883a1310">
            <label>39</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e890" publication-type="other">
R. H. Nochetto AND C. Verdi, Approximation of degenerate parabolic problems using nu-
merical integration, SIAM J. Numer. Anal., 25 (1988), pp. 784-814. MR954786 (89m:65102)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e900a1310">
            <label>40</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e907" publication-type="other">
M. Ohlberger, A posteriori error estimate for finite volume approximations to singularly
perturbed nonlinear convection-diffusion equations, Numer. Math., 87 (2001), pp. 737—761.
MR1815733 (2001m:65120)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e921a1310">
            <label>41</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e928" publication-type="other">
—, A posteriori error estimates for vertex centered finite volume approximations of
convection-diffusion-reaction equations, M2AN Math. Model. Numer. Anal., 35 (2001),
pp. 355-387. MR1825703 (2002a:65142)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e941a1310">
            <label>42</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e948" publication-type="other">
F. Otto, L1-contraction and uniqueness for quasilinear elliptic-parabolic equations, J. Dif-
ferential Equations, 131 (1996), pp. 20-38. MR1415045 (97i:35125)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e958a1310">
            <label>43</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e965" publication-type="other">
I. S. Pop, Error estimates for a time discretization method for the Richards' equation, Com-
put. Geosci., 6 (2002), pp. 141-160. MR1926564 (2003h:65136)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e975a1310">
            <label>44</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e982" publication-type="other">
I. S. Pop, F. Radu, and P. Knabner, Mixed finite elements for the Richards' equation:
linearization procedure, J. Comput. Appl. Math., 168 (2004), pp. 365-373. MR2079503</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e992a1310">
            <label>45</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e999" publication-type="other">
W. Prager and J. L. Synge, Approximations in elasticity based on the concept of function
space, Quart. Appl. Math., 5 (1947), pp. 241-269. MR0025902 (10:81b)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e1009a1310">
            <label>46</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e1016" publication-type="other">
A. Quarteroni AND A. Valli, Numerical approximation of partial differential equations,
vol. 23 of Springer Series in Computational Mathematics, Springer-Verlag, Berlin, 1994.
MR1299729 (95i:65005)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e1030a1310">
            <label>47</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e1037" publication-type="other">
F. A. Radu, I. S. Pop, and P. Knabner, Newton-type methods for the mixed finite ele-
ment discretization of some degenerate parabolic equations, in Numerical mathematics and
advanced applications, Springer, Berlin, 2006, pp. 1192—1200. MR2303752</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e1050a1310">
            <label>48</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e1057" publication-type="other">
—Error estimates for a mixed finite element discretization of some degenerate parabolic
equations, Numer. Math., 109 (2008), pp. 285-311. MR2385655</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e1067a1310">
            <label>49</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e1074" publication-type="other">
S. I. Repin, A posteriori estimates for partial differential equations, vol. 4 of Radon Series
on Computational and Applied Mathematics, Walter de Gruyter GmbH k. Co. KG, Berlin,
2008. MR2458008 (2010b:35004)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e1087a1310">
            <label>50</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e1094" publication-type="other">
J. E. Roberts and J.-M. Thomas, Mixed and hybrid methods, in Handbook of Numerical
Analysis, Vol. II, North-Holland, Amsterdam, 1991, pp. 523-639. MR1115239</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e1104a1310">
            <label>51</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e1111" publication-type="other">
R. Verfurth, A review of a posteriori error estimation and adaptive mesh-refinement tech-
niques, Teubner-Wiley, Stuttgart, 1996.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e1121a1310">
            <label>52</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e1128" publication-type="other">
—A posteriori error estimates for nonlinear problems: Lr{0,T',W1,p (CI))-error esti-
mates for finite element discretizations of parabolic equations, Numer. Methods Partial Dif-
ferential Equations, 14 (1998), pp. 487-518. MR1627578 (99g:65099)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e1142a1310">
            <label>53</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e1149" publication-type="other">
—Robust a posteriori error estimates for stationary convection-diffusion equations,
SIAM J. Numer. Anal., 43 (2005), pp. 1766-1782. MR2182149 (2007d:65116)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e1159a1310">
            <label>54</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e1166" publication-type="other">
M. VOHRALIK, Guaranteed and fully robust a posteriori error estimates for conforming dis-
cretizations of diffusion problems with discontinuous coefficients, J. Sci. Comput., 46 (2011),
pp. 397-438. MR2765501 (2012a:65297)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1770594e1179a1310">
            <label>55</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1770594e1186" publication-type="other">
M. Vohrali'k and M. F. Wheeler, A posteriori error estimates, stopping criteria, and
adaptivity for two-phase flows, HAL Preprint 00633594v2, submitted for publication, 2013.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


