<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169306</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Influence of the Upper Body of Pedestrians on Lower Limb Injuries and Effectiveness of the Upper Body Compensation Method of the FlexPLI</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Isshiki</surname>
                  <given-names>Takahiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Japan Automobile Research Institute</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Konosu</surname>
                  <given-names>Atsuhiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Japan Automobile Research Institute</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Takahashi</surname>
                  <given-names>Yukou</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Japan Automobile Manufacturers Association, Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>July 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169300</issue-id>
         <fpage>153</fpage>
         <lpage>163</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169306"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Current legform impact test methods using the FlexPLI have been developed to protect pedestrians from lower limb injuries in collisions with low-bumper vehicles. For this type of vehicles, the influence of the upper body on the bending load generated in the lower limb is compensated by setting the impact height of the FlexPLI 50 mm above that of pedestrians. However, neither the effectiveness of the compensation method of the FlexPLI nor the influence of the upper body on the bending load generated in the lower limb of a pedestrian has been clarified with high-bumper vehicles.</p>
            <p>In this study, therefore, two computer simulation analyses were conducted in order to analyze: (1) The influence of the upper body on the bending load generated in the lower limb of a pedestrian when impacted by high-bumper vehicles and (2) The effectiveness of the compensation method for the lack of the upper body by increasing impact height of the FlexPLI for high-bumper vehicles.</p>
            <p>The results show that the upper body significantly influenced the bending load generated in the lower limb of a pedestrian. This influence was found to be bumper height dependent. In addition, method of compensation for the lack of the upper body by increasing impact height of the FlexPLI was found not to work for high-bumper vehicles effectively. These results suggest the need to develop a new test method that appropriately incorporates upper body representation regardless of bumper height.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">UN/ECE/TRANS/WP.29/GRSP/2013/26, Proposal of 01 series of amendments to Regulation No. 127 (Pedestrian safety), http://www.unece.org/trans/main/wp29/wp29wgs/wp29grsp/grsp2013.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konosu A, Issiki T, Tanahashi M, Suzuki H. Development of a Biofidelic Flexible Pedestrian Legform Impactor Type GT (Flex-GT), Proceedings of 20th International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles, 2007, paper no. 07-0178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konosu A, Issiki T, Tanahashi M, Suzuki H, Development of a Flexible Pedestrian Legform Impactor Type GT (Flex-GT), Proceedings of 20th ESV Conference, 2007, Lyon, France, Paper Number 07 - 0178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konosu A, Issiki T, Takahashi Y, Evaluation of the Validity of the Tibia Fracture Assessment using the Upper Tibia Acceleration Employed in the TRL Legform Impactor, Proceedings of IRCOBI Conference, 2009, York,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takahashi Y, Ikeda M, Imaizumi I, Kikuchi Y, Takeishi S, Validation of Pedestrian Lower Limb Injury Assessment using Subsystem Impactors, Proceedings of IRCOBI Conference, 2012, Dublin, Ireland, pages 304 - 315. UK, pages 251 - 267.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mizuno Y, Chairman, on behalf of IHRA/P.S. WG. Summary of IHRA Pedestrian Safety WG Activities (2005). Proposed Test Methods to Evaluate Pedestrian Protection Afforded by Passenger Cars, 19th International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles, 2005, paper no. 05-0138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taguchi G, Chowdhury S, Wu Y, Taguchi's Quality Engineering Handbook, Wiley-Interscience, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takahashi Y, Kikuchi Y, Mori F, Konosu A. Advanced FE lower limb model for pedestrians, Proceedings of 18th International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles, 2003, paper no. 03-0218.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kikuchi, Y., Takahashi, Y., and Mori, F., “Development of a Finite Element Model for a Pedestrian Pelvis and Lower Limb,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0683, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0683.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kikuchi, Y., Takahashi, Y., and Mori, F., “Full-Scale Validation of a Human FE Model for the Pelvis and Lower Limb of a Pedestrian,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1243, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1243.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takahashi Y, Suzuki S, Ikeda M, Gunji Y. Investigation on pedestrian pelvis loading mechanisms using finite element simulations, Proceedings of IRCOBI Conference, 2010, Hanover, Germany.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Teresinski, G, Madro, R, Knee joint injuries as a reconstructive factor in car-to-pedestrian accidents, Forensic Science International, 124, 2001, pp. 74-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">UN/ECE/WP29/GRSP/INF-GR-PS/Flex-TEG 2009. Development of a FE Flex-GTR-prototype model and Analysis of the Correlation between the Flex- GTR-prototype and Human Lower Limb Outputs, TEG-096, http://www.unece.org/fileadmin/DAM/trans/doc/2009/wp29grsp/teg- 096e.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Issiki T, Konosu A, Masaaki Tanahashi, Development of an FE biofidelic flexible pedestrian leg-form impactor (Flex-GT-prototype) model, 20th International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles (ESV), Paper Number 07-0179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">UN/ECE/TRANS/180/Add.9, Global Technical Regulation No.9 (Pedestrian safety), http://www.unece.org/trans/main/wp29/wp29wgs/wp29gen/wp29glob_registry.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E/ECE/324/Rev.2/Add.126-E/ECE/TRANS/505/Rev.2/Add.126, Regulation No. 127, Uniform provisions concerning the approval of motor vehicles with regard to their pedestrian safety performance, http://www.unece.org/trans/main/wp29/wp29regs121-140.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
