<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26167721</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Closed Loop Control Algorithm of Fuel Cell Output Power for a City Bus</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Xu</surname>
                  <given-names>Liangfei</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tsinghua Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ouyang</surname>
                  <given-names>Minggao</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tsinghua Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Jianqiu</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tsinghua Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Huang</surname>
                  <given-names>Haiyan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tsinghua Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yang</surname>
                  <given-names>Fuyuan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tsinghua Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gan</surname>
                  <given-names>Quanquan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sunrise Power Co,. Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26167713</issue-id>
         <fpage>74</fpage>
         <lpage>81</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26167721"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper studies a control algorithm for fuel cell/battery city buses. The output power of the fuel cell is controlled by a D.C. converter, and the output ports of the converter and the battery are connected in parallel to supply power for the electric motor. One way to prolong service life is to have the fuel cell system to deliver a steady-state power. However, because of fluctuations in the bus voltage and uncertainness in the D.C. converter, the output power of the fuel cell system changes drastically. A closed-loop control algorithm is necessary to eliminate the errors between the output and target power of the fuel cell system. The algorithm is composed of two parts, the feed forward one and the feedback one. Influences of the bus voltage and D.C. efficiency are compensated automatically in the feedback algorithm by using a PI algorithm. The stability and robustness of the algorithm is analyzed. Formulas for choosing suitable parameters are given considering both the transient process and the system stability. Experimental results show that, the stable relative error between the target power and the actual output power of the fuel cell system converges to zero. Because of signal noises introduced in the measurements of the current and the voltage, there are some noises in the actual output power. The average relative error (absolute value) during the measuring processes with the closed loop algorithm reduced to1/3 of the level with the open loop algorithm, 1.5% and 4.5%, respectively. Based on the closed loop control algorithm proposed in this paper, a multi-objective optimal energy management strategy considering both of the fuel economy and system durability can be studied in the future.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Larminie, J., Dicks, A., “Fuel Cell Systems Explained,” Wiley, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gao, M., “Analysis on Research and Development Progress of Fuel Cell Buses,” Bus and coach technology and research (Chinese), 2,1-4,16,2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yi, B.L., Hou, M., “Solutions for the Durability of Fuel Cells in Vehicle Applications,” Journal of Automotive Safety and Energy (Chinese), 2(2),91-100,2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cheng, SJ, Lo, YK, Chiu, HJ, Kuo, SW, “High-Efficiency Digital- Controlled Interleaved Power Converter for High-Power PEM Fuel-Cell Applications,” IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics, 60(2), 773-80, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chao, CH, Shieh, JJ, “A new control strategy for hybrid fuel cell-battery power systems with improved efficiency,” International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 37(17),13141-6, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Erdinc, O., Uzunoglu, M., “Recent trends in PEM fuel cell-powered hybrid systems: Investigation of application areas, design architectures and energy management approaches,” Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 14, 2874-2884, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kelouwani, S, Agbossou, K, Dube, Y, Boulon, L, “Fuel cell Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicle anticipatory and real-time blended-mode energy management for battery life preservation,” Journal of Power Sources, 221,406-18, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdi, S, Afshar, K, Bigdeli, N, Ahmadi, S, “A Novel Approach for Robust Maximum Power Point Tracking of PEM Fuel Cell Generator Using Sliding Mode Control Approach,” International Journal of Electrochemical Science, 7(5),4192-209, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meidanshahi, V, Karimi, G, “Dynamic modeling, optimization and control of power density in a PEM fuel cell,” Applied Energy, 93, 98-105, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thounthong, P., Rael, S., Davat, B., “Energy management of fuel cell/battery/supercapacitor hybrid power source for vehicle applications,” Journal of Power Sources, 193,376-385,2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, X., Mi, C.C., Masrur, A., Daniszewski, D., “Wavelet-transformbased power management of hybrid vehicles with multiple on board energy sources including fuel cell, battery and ultracapacitor,” Journal of Power Sources, 185(2),1533-43, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wai, RJ, Jhung, SJ, Liaw, JJ, Chang, YR, “Intelligent Optimal Energy Management System for Hybrid Power Sources Including Fuel Cell and Battery,” IEEE Transactions on Power Electronics, 28(7), 3231-44, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Segura, F, Andujar, JM, “Power management based on sliding control applied to fuel cell systems: A further step towards the hybrid control concept,” Applied Energy, 99,213-25, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inthamoussou, FA, Mantz, RJ, De Battista, H, “Flexible power control of fuel cells using sliding mode techniques,” Journal of Power Source, 205, 281-9, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, L., Hua, J., Bao, L., Li, J., et al., “Development of a Vehicle Control System for a Fuel Cell Hybrid Bus,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1574, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1574.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ji, GJ, Hanke-Rauschenbach, R, Bornhoft, A, Zhou, S, Sundmacher, K, “Fuel Cell Power Control Based on a Master-Slave Structure: A Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell Case Study,” Journal of Fuel Cell Science and Technology, 9(4), 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, L., Li, J., Ouyang, M., Hua, J.F., “Integration of PEM fuel cell/battery powertrain: EMI noises and power split strategy,” International Conference on Electronic &amp; Mechanical Engineering and Information Technology, 787-792, August 12-14, Harbin, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, L, Yang F, Li J, Ouyang M, Hua J, “Real time optimal energy management strategy targeting at minimizing daily operation cost for a plug-in fuel cell city bus,” International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 37(20),15380-92, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu L, Ouyang M, LI J, Yang F, “Dynamic Programming Algorithm for minimizing operating cost of a PEM fuel cell vehicle,” ISIE 2012, 1490-5, 28-31 May, Hangzhou, China.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu L, Li J, Hua J, Li X, Ouyang M, “Adaptive supervisory control strategy of a fuel cell/battery-powered city bus,” Journal of Power Sources, 194(1), 360-8, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu L, Li J, Hua J, Li X, Ouyang M, “Optimal vehicle control strategy of a fuel cell/battery hybrid city bus,” International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 34(17),7323-33, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li X, Xu L, Hua J, Lin X, Li J, Ouyang M, “Power management strategy for vehicular-applied hybrid fuel cell/battery power system,” Journal of Power Sources, 191(2),542-9, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ouyang M, Xu L, Li J, Lu L, Gao D, Xie Q, “Performance comparison of two fuel cell hybrid buses with different powertrain and energy management strategies,” Journal of Power Sources, 163(1),467-79, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
