<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">accohistjour</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000849</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Accounting Historians Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The Academy of Accounting Historians</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01484184</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">40697490</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>S. PAUL GARNER: ACCOUNTANCY'S AMBASSADOR TO THE WORLD</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Gary John</given-names>
                  <surname>Previts</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>William D.</given-names>
                  <surname>Samson</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>1997</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">24</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i40030740</issue-id>
         <fpage>153</fpage>
         <lpage>169</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement/>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40697490"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Samuel Paul Garner spent nearly seven decades, as a student, professor, administrator, leader and visionary, enhancing the understanding and development of our academic community. Born in 1910, he studied at Duke University, then briefly as a non degree student at Columbia before teaching and then entering the Ph. D. program at the University of Texas at Austin. At Texas, under the direction of George Hillis Newlove, he focused upon accounting. His interest in history had been kindled by a noted economic historian Earl J. Hamilton, under whom Garner had studied at Duke. His first post doctoral appointment would be his lifelong assignment, as a member of the faculty of what is now the Culverhouse School of Accountancy at the University of Alabama. Starting in 1939 he served as a faculty member, next as department chair, and then for seventeen years, from 1954 to 1971, as dean of the College of Business. His career achievements are many and include being the only person to serve as President of both the American Accounting Association [1951] and the American Assembly of Collegiate Schools of Business [1964-65]. His post-retirement activities identified with the quarter century from 1971 through 1996 permitted members of subsequent generations to benefit from his knowledge and counsel. Garner's work as a scholar, a historian, an institutional developer and a visionary— especially in the area of international relations, are told in this paper. A special appendix, which contains the last known curriculum vita prepared by Garner, is also provided.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list>
         <title>BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
         <ref id="d71e127a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d71e131" publication-type="other">
Bohting, A.A.H., "Book Review: Studies in Accounting History -Tradition
and Innovation for the Twenty-First Century, edited by Atsuo Tsuji and
Paul Garner," The CPA Journal. July 1996. p. 10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e144a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d71e148" publication-type="other">
Culverhouse School of Accountancy 1996 Annual Report, The University of
Alabama, College of Commerce and Business Administration. 1996. pp.
3-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e161a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d71e165" publication-type="other">
Garner, R.M., S. Paul Garner: A Study of Selected Contributions to the
Accounting Profession. University of Arkansas Ph.D. dissertation. 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e175a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d71e179" publication-type="other">
Garner, S. P., Evolution of Cost Accounting to 1925. University of Texas
Ph.D. dissertation. 1940. Tuscaloosa AL: University of Alabama Press.
1954. Reprinted by Garland Publishing Company, 1977. Japanese
edition, 1956. Chinese edition, 1989. The foil text of this work, Evolution
of Cost Accounting to 1925 can be found on the Internet at:
weatherhead.cwu.edu/accounting/pub/garner.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e203a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d71e207" publication-type="other">
Graves, O.F., ed. The Cost Heritage: Studies in Honor ofS. Paul Garner.
Harrisonburg VA: The Academy of Accounting Historians. 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e217a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d71e221" publication-type="other">
Littleton, A.C., Accounting Evolution to 1900. New York: American Institute
Publishing Company. 1933.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e231a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d71e235" publication-type="other">
Mayer, M. and Melancon, R. The College of Commerce and Business
Administration -The First 75 Years. Tuscaloosa, AL: University of
Alabama. 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e248a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d71e252" publication-type="other">
Newlove, G.H. and Garner, S. P., Elementary Cost Accounting, New York:
D.C. Heath and Company, 1941. revised edition 1949. Spanish editions
Constabilidad de Costos. 1952, 1953.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e265a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d71e269" publication-type="other">
Newlove, G.H. and Garner, S. P., Advanced Accounting Volume 1. 1951. and
Advanced Accounting Volume 2. 1950. Boston: D.C. Heath and
Company.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e282a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d71e286" publication-type="other">
Newlove, G.H. and Garner, S. P. Advanced Problems Book 1 and Book 2 to
accompany Advanced Accounting, Vol. 1 and Vol. 2. Boston: D.C. Heath
&amp; Company. 1951 and 1950 respectively.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e300a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d71e304" publication-type="other">
Previts, G.J. and Flesher, D.L., "Conversation with Paul darner," videotape.
Oxford MS: Academy of Accounting Historians. September 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e314a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d71e318" publication-type="other">
Tsuji, A. and Garner, S.P. (eds.). Studies in Accounting History -Tradition
and Innovation for the Twenty-First Century. Oxford MS: Greenwood
Publishing Co. 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
