<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">15</volume>
         <issue-id>i40198344</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44717918</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE ESSENTIALS OF HIGH-GRADE STEEL MANUFACTURE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>W R</given-names>
                  <surname>Shimer</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1920</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>922</fpage>
         <lpage>941</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright, 1921, Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44717918"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The manufacture of high-grade automobile steels begins with the selection of proper raw materials. The larger manufacturer of today owns and controls his ore, coal and limestone properties and can obtain a uniform quality of raw materials, enabling him to produce finished steel products of uniform quality. The major portion of steel made for the automobile industry today is manufactured by the basic open-hearth process. Crucible and electric-furnace steel is used to a certain extent, when the tonnage is relatively small and special properties are desired. The physical and chemical charges in the openhearth process are specified, with comments on the resultant product. The making and testing of steel are described, illustrations of test-specimens being presented. The pouring of ingots is stated as being a most important factor in the manufacture of steel. Steel should be poured into the ingot mold as slowly as possible so that the metal can solidify from the bottom upward, the top remaining molten until the "last. Further details of pouring are given and comments are made regarding pipe in bottom-poured ingots, refining high-grade steels, molds, inspection of the steel blooms and samples for analysis taken from the blooms. The heat-treatment of alloy steels actually commences with the ingot after casting. After some discussion of this subject, inspection methods are reviewed in considerable detail and practical examples and comments are included. The causes of failure in service are treated at some length. Three specific statements are made relative to the factors determining the sources of steel supply, which the prospective purchaser of large tonnages of high-grade steels should consider.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


