<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000451</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40008413</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Toward a Lexicalized Grammar for Interlinguas</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Clare</given-names>
                  <surname>Voss</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Bonnie J.</given-names>
                  <surname>Dorr</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1995</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>143</fpage>
         <lpage>184</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1995 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40008413"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>In this paper we present one aspect of our research on machine translation (MT): capturing the grammatical and computational relation between (i) the interlingua (IL) as defined declaratively in the lexicon and (ii) the IL as defined procedurally by way of algorithms that compose and decompose pivot IL forms. We begin by examining the interlinguas in the lexicons of a variety of current IL-based approaches to MT. This brief survey makes it clear that no consensus exists among MT researchers on the level of representation for defining the IL. In the section that follows, we explore the consequences of this missing formal framework for MT system builders who develop their own lexical- IL entries. The lack of software tools to support rapid IL respecification and testing greatly hampers their ability to modify representations to handle new data and new domains. Our view is that IL-based MT research needs both (a) the formal framework to specify possible IL grammars and (b) the software support tools to implement and test these grammars. With respect to (a), we propose adopting a lexicalized grammar approach, tapping research results from the study of "tree grammars" for natural language syntax. With respect to (b), we sketch the design and functional specifications for parts of ILustrate, the set of software tools that we need to implement and test the various IL formalisms that meet the requirements of a lexicalized grammar. In this way, we begin to address a basic issue in MT research, how to define and test an interlingua as a computational language - without building a full MT system for each possible IL formalism that might be proposed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>interlingua</kwd>
            <kwd>machine translation</kwd>
            <kwd>lexicon</kwd>
            <kwd>lexicalized grammar</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d908426e333a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e337" publication-type="other">
Abeillé, A., Y. Schabes, and A. Joshi. 1990. Using Lexicalized Tree Adjoining
Grammars for Machine Translation. In Proceedings of the 13th International
Conference on Computational Linguistics, Helsinki, Finland.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e350a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e354" publication-type="other">
Anderson, J. 1971. The Grammar of Case: Towards a Localist Theory. Cambridge
University Press, Cambridge, England.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e364a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e368" publication-type="other">
DiMarco, C, G. Hirst, and M. Stede. 1993. The Semantic and Stylistic Differenti-
ation of Synonyms and Near-Synonyms. In Working Notes for the AAAI Spring
Symposium on Building Lexicons for Machine Translation, Technical Report SS-
93-02, pages 114-121, Stanford University, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e384a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e388" publication-type="other">
Dorr, B. 1990. Solving Thematic Divergences in Machine Translation. In Pro-
ceedings of the 28th Annual Conference of the Association for Computational
Linguistics, pages 127-134, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e402a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e406" publication-type="other">
Dorr, B. 1993. Machine Translation: A View from the Lexicon. MIT Press,
Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e416a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e420" publication-type="other">
Dorr, B. and M. Palmer. 1995. Building a LCS-Based Lexicon in TAGs. In
Working Notes for the AAAI Spring Symposium on Representation and Aquisition
of lexical Knowledge: Polysemy, Ambiguity, and Generativity, Technical Report
SS-95, Stanford University, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e436a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e440" publication-type="other">
Dorr, B. and C. Voss. 1993. Machine Translation of Spatial Expressions: Defining
the Relation between an Interlingua and a Knowledge Representation System. In
Proceedings of the AAAI, pages 374-379, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e453a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e457" publication-type="other">
Dorr, B. and C. Voss. 1994. The Case for a MT Developers' Tool with a Two-
Component View of the Interlingua. In Proceedings of the First Conference of
the Association for Machine Translation in the Americas, pages 40-47, Columbia,
MD.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e473a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e477" publication-type="other">
Dorr, B., C. Voss, E. Peterson, and M. Kiker. 1994. Concept Based Lexical Selec-
tion. In AAAI 1994 Fall Symposium on Knowledge Representation for Natural
Language Processing in Implemented Systems, New Orleans, LA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e490a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e494" publication-type="other">
Frederking, R., S. Nirenburg, S. Helmrich D. Farwell, E. Hovy, K. Knight, S. Beale,
C. Domashnev, D. Attardo, D. Grannes, and R. Brown. 1994. Integrating Trans-
lations from Multiple Sources within the Pangloss Mark III Machine Translation
System. In Proceedings of the First Conference of the Association for Machine
Translation in the Americas, pages 73-80, Columbia, MD.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e514a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e518" publication-type="other">
Grimshaw, J. 1993. Semantic Structure and Semantic Content in Lexical Repres-
ntation. Manuscript, Rutgers University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e528a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e532" publication-type="other">
Hale, K. and J. Keyser. 1993. On Argument Structure and the Lexical Expression
of Syntactic Relations. In K. Hale and J. Keyser, editors, The View From Building
20: Essays in Linguistics in Honor of Sylvain Bromberger. MIT Press, Cambridge,
MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e548a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e552" publication-type="other">
Herskovits, A. 1986. Language and Spatial Cognition. Cambridge University Press,
Cambridge, England.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e562a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e566" publication-type="other">
Hirst, G. 1995. Near-synonymy and the Structure of Lexical Knowledge. In Work-
ing Notes for the AAAI Spring Symposium on Representation and Aquisition
of lexical Knowledge: Polysemy, Ambiguity, and Generativity, Technical Report
SS-95, Stanford University, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e582a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e586" publication-type="other">
Hirst, G. and M. Ryan. 1992. Mixed-Depth Representations for Natural Language
Text. In P. Jacobs, editor, Text- Based Intelligent Systems. Lawrence Erlbaum,
Hillsdale, NJ, pages 59-82.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e599a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e603" publication-type="other">
Hutchins, W.J. and H. Somers. 1992. An Introduction to Machine Translation.
Academic Press Inc., San Diego, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e614a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e618" publication-type="other">
Jackendoff, R. 1983. Language and Cognition. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e625a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e629" publication-type="other">
Jackendoff, R. 1990. Semantic Structures. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e636a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e640" publication-type="other">
Jensen, K. 1987. Binary Rules and Non-Binary Trees: Breaking Down the Concept
of Phrase Structure. In A. Manaster-Ramer, editor, Mathematics of Language.
John Benjamins Publishing Company, Philadelphia, PA, pages 65-86.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e653a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e657" publication-type="other">
Kay, M., J.M. Gawron, and P. Norvig. 1994. Verbmobil: A Translation System for
Face-to-Face Dialog, volume 33. CSLI Lecture Notes, Stanford, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e667a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e671" publication-type="other">
Langacker, R. 1987. Foundations of Cognitive Grammar, Vol. 1: Theoretical Pre-
requisites. Stanford University Press, Stanford, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e681a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e685" publication-type="other">
Levin, B. and M. Rappaport-Hovav. 1991. Wiping the Slate Clean: A Lexical
Semantic Exploration. In B. Levin p; S. Pinker, editors, Lexical &amp; Conceptual
Semantics. Blackwell Publishers, Cambridge, MA, pages 123-151. (Reprinted
from Cognition (1991) 41).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e702a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e706" publication-type="other">
Levin, B. and M. Rappaport-Hovav. 1995. Unaccusativity: At the Syntax-
Semantics Interface. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e716a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e720" publication-type="other">
Levin, L. and S. Nirenburg. 1994. The Correct Place Of Lexical Semantics in
Interlingual MT. In Proceedings of Fifteenth International Conference on Com-
putational Linguistics, Kyoto, Japan.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e733a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e737" publication-type="other">
Lindner, S. 1981. A Lexico-Semantic Analysis of English Verb Particle Construc-
tions with OUT and UP. Ph.D. thesis, University of California, San Diego.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e747a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e751" publication-type="other">
Mani, I. 1995. An Integrative, Layered Approach to Lexical Semantics and Its
Application to Machine Translation. In Working Notes for the AAAI Spring
Symposium on Representation and Aquisition of lexical Knowledge: Polysemy,
Ambiguity, and Generativity, Technical Report SS-95, Stanford University, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e767a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e771" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, S., J. Carbonell, M. Tomita, and K. Goodman. 1992. Machine Trans-
lation: A Knowledge-Based Approach. Morgan Kaufmann, San Mateo, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e781a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e785" publication-type="other">
Nomura, N., D. Jones, and R.C. Berwick. 1994. An Architecture for a Universal
Lexicon: A Case Study on Shared Syntactic Information in Japanese, Hindi,
Bengali, Greek, and English. In Proceedings of Fifteenth International Conference
on Computational Linguistics, Kyoto, Japan.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e802a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e806" publication-type="other">
Onyshkevich, B. and S. Nirenburg. 1995. A Lexicon for Knowledge-Based MT.
Machine Translation, 10(1-2).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e816a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e820" publication-type="other">
Pinker, S. 1989. Learnability and Cognition: The Acquisition of Argument Struc-
ture. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e830a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e834" publication-type="other">
Rappaport, M. and B. Levin. 1988. What To Do With Theta-Roles. In W. Wilkins,
editor, Thematic Relations. Academic Press, New York, NY, pages 7-36.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e844a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e848" publication-type="other">
Rosenfeld, A. 1990. Array, Tree and Graph Grammars. In H. Bunke and A. San-
feliu, editors, Syntactic and Structural Pattern Recognition: Theory and Applica-
tions. World Scientific, Teaneck, NJ, pages 85-115.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e861a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e865" publication-type="other">
Rosetta, M.T. 1994. Rosetta: Compositional Translation. Kluwer Academic Pub-
lishers, Dordrecht, The Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e875a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e879" publication-type="other">
Schabes, Y. 1990. Mathematical and Computational Aspects of Lexicalized Gram-
mars. Ph.D. thesis, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e890a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e894" publication-type="other">
Schabes, Y., A. Abeillé, and A. Joshi. 1988. Parsing Strategies with 'Lexicalized'
Grammars: Applications to Tree Adjoining Grammars. In Proceedings of 12th
International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Budapest, Hungary.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e907a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e911" publication-type="other">
Schimpf, K. 1982. A Parsing Method for Context-Free Tree Languages. Ph.D.
thesis, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e921a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e925" publication-type="other">
Schimpf, K. and J. Gallier. 1985. Tree Pushdown Automata. Journal of Computer
and System Sciences, 30:25-40.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e935a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e939" publication-type="other">
Sparck-Jones, K. 1983. Shifting Meaning Representations. In Proceedings of the
8th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, Karlsruhe, Germany.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e949a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e953" publication-type="other">
Stede, M. 1993. Lexical Options in Multilingual Generation From a Knowledge
Base. Manuscript, University of Toronto.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e963a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e967" publication-type="other">
Talmy, L. 1985. Lexicalization Patterns: Semantic Structure in Lexical Forms. In
T. Shopen, editor, Language Typology and Syntactic Description 3: Grammatical
Categories and the Lexicon. University Press, Cambridge, England, pages 57-149.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e981a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e985" publication-type="other">
Thatcher, J.W. 1967. Characterizing Derivation Trees of Context-Free Grammars
through a Generalization of Finite Automata Theory. Journal of Computer and
System Sciences, 1:317-322.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e998a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1002" publication-type="other">
Verrière, G. 1994. Manuel d'utilisation de la structure lexicale conceptuelle (LCS)
pour représenter des phrases en français. Research note, IRIT, Université Paul
Sabatier, Toulouse, France, June.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1015a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1019" publication-type="other">
Vijay-Shankar, K. and A. Joshi. 1985. Some Computational Properties of Tree Ad-
joining Grammars. In Proceedings of the 23rd Annual Meeting of the Association
for Computational Linguistics, Chicago, IL.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1032a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1036" publication-type="other">
Vijay-Shankar, K., D. Weir, and A. Joshi. 1987a. Characterizing Structural De-
scriptions Produced by Various Grammatical Formalisms. In Proceedings of the
25rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Stanford,
CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1052a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1056" publication-type="other">
Vijay-Shankar, K., D. Weir, and A. Joshi. 1987b. On the Progression from Context-
Free to Tree Adjoining Languages. In A. Manaster-Ramer, editor, Mathematics
of Language. John Benjamins Publishing Company, Philadelphia, PA, pages 389-
401.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1072a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1076" publication-type="other">
Voss, C, B. Dorr, and M. Ülkü Şencan. 1995. Lexical Allocation in Interlingua-
Based Machine Translation of Spatial Expressions. In Working Notes for IJCAI-
95 Workshop on the Representation and Processing of Spatial Expressions, Mon-
treal, Canada.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1093a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1097" publication-type="other">
Zwarts, J. and H. Verkuyl. 1994. An Algebra of Conceptual Structure: An In-
vestigation Into Jackendoff 's Conceptual Semantics. Linguistics and Philosophy,
17:1-24.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>Notes</title>
            <ref id="d908426e1119a1310">
               <label>4</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1126" publication-type="other">
Zwarts and Verkuyl (1994)</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1132" publication-type="other">
Mani (1995),</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1139a1310">
               <label>5</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1146" publication-type="other">
Kay, Gawron, and Norvig (1994),</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1152" publication-type="other">
Swiss German, validate the ticket. Pinker (1989)</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1159a1310">
               <label>6</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1166" publication-type="other">
(Hirst
and Ryan, 1992),</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1175" publication-type="other">
(Sparck- Jones, 1983).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1182a1310">
               <label>7</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1189" publication-type="other">
(Dorr and Voss, 1993),</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1195" publication-type="other">
Grimshaw (1993),</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1201" publication-type="other">
Levin and Rappaport-Hovav (1995),</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1208" publication-type="other">
Pinker (1989).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1216a1310">
               <label>8</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1223" publication-type="other">
Rosenfeld
(1990);</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1232" publication-type="other">
Schimpf and Gallier (1985)).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1239a1310">
               <label>10</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1246" publication-type="other">
Talmy
(1985)).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1256a1310">
               <label>11</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1263" publication-type="other">
Levin and
Rappaport-Hovav (1995)</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1272" publication-type="other">
Pinker (1989)</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1279a1310">
               <label>13</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1286" publication-type="other">
Pinker (1989,
pp. 236-238),</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1295" publication-type="other">
Rappaport and Levin (1988)</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1301" publication-type="other">
Levin and Rappaport-
Hovav (1991).</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1311" publication-type="other">
(Rappaport and Levin, 1988).</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1317" publication-type="other">
(Levin and Rappaport- Hovav, 1991).</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1323" publication-type="other">
(Pinker, 1989)</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1329" publication-type="other">
(Levin and Rappaport- Hovav, 1991),</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1336a1310">
               <label>20</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1343" publication-type="other">
Jackendoff (1983),</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1349" publication-type="other">
Jackendoff (1990))</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1355" publication-type="other">
(Levin and Rappaport-Hovav, 1995).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1362a1310">
               <label>21</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1369" publication-type="other">
Levin and
Rappaport-Hovav (1995)</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1378" publication-type="other">
Pinker
(1989)</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1389a1310">
               <label>22</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1396" publication-type="other">
Rosetta (Rosetta, 1994)</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1402" publication-type="other">
Vijay-Shankar, Weir, and Joshi (1987a).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1409a1310">
               <label>23</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1416" publication-type="other">
Jensen (1987)</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1423a1310">
               <label>24</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1430" publication-type="other">
(Schimpf, 1982).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1437a1310">
               <label>26</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1444" publication-type="other">
(Thatcher, 1967)</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1451a1310">
               <label>27</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1458" publication-type="other">
Dorr and Palmer (1995)</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1465a1310">
               <label>29</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1472" publication-type="other">
(Schimpf and Gallier, 1985)</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908426e1480a1310">
               <label>32</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908426e1487" publication-type="other">
(Voss, Dorr, and Şencan, 1995),</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
