<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437590</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Child Support Reform: Some Analysis of the 1999 White Paper</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>GILLIAN</given-names>
                  <surname>PAULL</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>IAN</given-names>
                  <surname>WALKER</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>YU</given-names>
                  <surname>ZHU</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2000</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">21</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437584</issue-id>
         <fpage>105</fpage>
         <lpage>140</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2000</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437590"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper uses a sample of lone mothers (and former lone mothers who are now repartnered) drawn from the 1997 Family Resources Survey to analyse the potential effects of reforming the UK system of child support. The main deficiency of the data is that non-resident fathers cannot be matched to the mothers in the data, and this is overcome by exploiting information from another dataset which gives the joint distribution of the characteristics of separated parents. The effects of reforming the child support system are simulated for the amount of maintenance liabilities, the amount paid and the net incomes of households containing mothers-with-care and of households containing non-resident fathers. The likely effects of the reform are simulated at various levels of compliance. The analysis highlights the need for further research into the incentive effects of child support on individual behaviour.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d43e275a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e282" publication-type="other">
See also Hu (1999) for an analysis of the effects of child support on work incentives in the US. Corden (1999)
provides an outline comparison of child support systems across European countries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e292a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e299" publication-type="other">
These issues will be addressed in future work that is being funded directly by the Nuffield Foundation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e306a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e313" publication-type="other">
The White Paper contains some predictions that have been obtained from applying the reforms to
administrative Child Support Agency (CSA) data. While these administrative data provide information on the
non-resident father that is not available in the Family Resources Survey (FRS) data used here, the cases dealt
with by the CSA are not a random sample of all lone parents. For example, the CSA deals with all those cases
where the parent-with-care is on income support (or housing benefit or family credit) and those not on income
support who ask for the CSA's assistance. Thus it seems likely that the typical CSA client will have a
substantially lower level of child support entitlement than the average individual eligible for child support.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e339a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e346" publication-type="other">
The number of lone fathers in the data who have custody of children is too small to facilitate reliable statistical
analysis.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e357a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e364" publication-type="other">
It also includes the income of own children (qualifying or new).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e371a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e378" publication-type="other">
Qualifying children are the natural children of the separated parents. New children are defined as children of
one of the parents and a new partner. Stepchildren are defined as natural children only of the new partner of
one of the parents.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e391a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e398" publication-type="other">
Exemptions include those non-resident parents with any dependent children in their new family, those
receiving certain disability benefits, those under the age of 16, those under the age of 19 and in full-time
education, and those with net income below the minimum.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e411a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e418" publication-type="other">
In addition, the higher the parent-with-care income, the lower the maximum liability level incorporated in J.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e425a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e432" publication-type="other">
These are the marginal rates within the second step bounds, but the average liability rate gradually rises from 5
per cent at £100 to the respective 15 per cent, 20 per cent or 25 per cent at £200 of net earnings.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e442a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e449" publication-type="other">
This is not to say that the non-resident parent may not contribute more or less than the designated percentage
to the support of the new child.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e460a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e467" publication-type="other">
Thus there is a 'double dividend' for stepchildren in the proposed reforms. Not only do the reforms benefit
second families with stepchildren by allowing this new reduction in liability, but also the increased compliance
and the removal of the parent-with-care income from the liability calculation should raise the child support
received for them by the family.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e483a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e490" publication-type="other">
Chapter 2, paragraph 24.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e497a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e504" publication-type="other">
The White Paper proposes that tables will be made widely available showing the liability for any given band
of non-resident-parent income, dependent upon the number of qualifying children and the number of children
in the non-resident parent's second family.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e517a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e524" publication-type="other">
Indeed, the only apparent grounds for a reassessment are if either the number of children changes or there is a
variation in the non-resident parent's earnings of more than 5 per cent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e534a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e541" publication-type="other">
The Australian child support system is similar in structure to the existing UK system in that it is of the
income-shares type, and it achieves a compliance rate of more than 80 per cent. See
http ://w w w. csa. go v,au/scheme/FF4. DOC.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e554a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e561" publication-type="other">
However, the enhanced disregards may increase formal child support payments at the cost of reducing
informal payments and payments-in-kind.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e572a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e579" publication-type="other">
Lin interprets his evidence as implying that fairness would promote compliance. However, perceptions of
fairness are likely to be based on characteristics, such as altruistic attitudes, that themselves are correlated with
compliance. Thus it is unclear that a causal connection can be inferred from this paper.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e592a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e599" publication-type="other">
Quantitative results are available in Garfinkel and Robins (1994), Meyer (1993), Beron (1990, 1988a and
1988b), Garfinkel et al. (1999), Garfinkel, Robins, Wong and Mayer (1999), Garfinkel and Oellierich (1989),
Lin ( 1997) and Freeman and Waldfogel ( 1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e612a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e619" publication-type="other">
To the best of our knowledge, none of the major population surveys provides direct information on parents-
with-care and matched non-resident parents or permits an accurate identification of non-resident parents even
independently of the corresponding parent-with-care. Although the British Household Panel Survey (BHPS)
collects information on fertility histories for men and women, Rendall et al. (1999) investigate the extent to
which BHPS fathers deny their paternity post-separation and find it to be high.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e638a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e645" publication-type="other">
Similar estimation has been done by Beron (1990) in the US using similar methods.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e652a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e659" publication-type="other">
The compliance estimation requires a liability level to be calculated for the FRS data. The liability lev
is that calculated for the baseline scenario for the current child support system described in Section VII.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e669a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e676" publication-type="other">
Alternative ways of defining compliance will be pursued in future work.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e684a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e691" publication-type="other">
It is not clear what the 80 per cent target means precisely. It could mean the 'binary' type of compliance used
here, or it could mean that everyone pays a straight 80 per cent of their liability. This second, 'proportional',
interpretation was also analysed and the outcomes found to lie somewhere between the effects at current
compliance and the effects from the 80 per cent binary compliance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e707a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e714" publication-type="other">
As a reasonable approximation to the observed take-up rates, we assumed full take-up for IS and housing
benefit and 65 per cent take-up (from the FRS family credit information) for WFTC.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e724a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e731" publication-type="other">
It is also true that changes in the total amount available might affect the incidence of poverty for the 'no child
support' starting-point.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e741a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e748" publication-type="other">
Since male labour supply is generally held to be inelastically supplied (see Blundell and MaCurdy (1999)),
ignoring the effect of child support on the non-resident fathers' labour supplies seems reasonable.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e758a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e765" publication-type="other">
Future work will be based on new estimates from the FRS datasets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e772a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e779" publication-type="other">
See also work by Keane and Moffitt (1998) for US data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e787a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e794" publication-type="other">
See Jenkins and Millar (1989).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e801a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e808" publication-type="other">
It turns out that there is some 'negative selectivity' in our results — that is, the predicted wages of non-
workers are higher than of those observed to work. This finding is not uncommon in the UK literature, but it is
something deserving of further research.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d43e830a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e834" publication-type="other">
Bartfeld, J. (1998), 'Child support and the post-divorce economic well-being of mothers, fathers
and children', University of Wisconsin-Madison Institute for Research on Poverty, Discussion
Paper no. 1182-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e847a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e851" publication-type="other">
Beron, K. (1988a), 'Applying the economic model of crime to child support enforcement', Review
of Economics and Statistics, vol. 70, pp. 382-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e861a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e865" publication-type="other">
— (1988b), 'Child support payment behaviour: an econometric decomposition', Southern
Economic Journal, vol. 20, pp. 650-63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e875a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e879" publication-type="other">
— (1990), 'Policy issues and child support payment behaviour: empirical findings', Contemporary
Policy Issues, vol. 8, pp. 124—34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e890a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e894" publication-type="other">
Bianchi, S. M., Subaiya, L. and Khan, J. (1997), 'Women's economic independence within
marriage and their relative well-being after separation', mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e904a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e908" publication-type="other">
Bingley, P., Lanot, G., Symons, E. and Walker, I. (1995), 'Child support reform and the labour
supply of lone mothers in the UK', Journal of Human Resources, vol. 30, pp. 256-79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e918a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e922" publication-type="other">
—, Symons, E. and Walker, I. (1995), 'Child support, income support and lone mothers', Fiscal
Studies, vol. 15, no. 1, pp. 81-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e932a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e936" publication-type="other">
— and Walker, I. (1997), 'The labour supply, unemployment and participation of lone mothers in
in-work transfer programmes', Economic Journal, vol. 107, pp. 1375-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e946a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e950" publication-type="other">
— and — (1998), 'Labour supply and in-work and in-kind transfers', Keele University, Working
Paper no. 97/04.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e960a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e964" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R. W. and MaCurdy, T. (1999), 'Labor supply: a review of alternative approaches', in O.
Ashenfelter and D. Card (eds), Handbook of Labor Economics, Elsevier North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e975a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e979" publication-type="other">
Child Poverty Action Group (1999), Child Support Handbook: 7th Edition, 1999/2000, London:
CP AG.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e989a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e993" publication-type="other">
Corden, A. (1999), 'European approaches to child maintenance payments', JRF Finding, York:
Joseph Rowntree Foundation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1003a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1007" publication-type="other">
Department of Social Security (1999), A New Contract for Welfare: Children's Rights and
Parents' Responsibilities, Cm. 4349, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1017a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1021" publication-type="other">
Freeman, R. and Waldfogel, J. (1998), 'Dunning delinquent dads: the effects of child support
enforcement on receipt by never married mothers', National Bureau of Economic Research,
Working Paper no. 6664.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1034a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1038" publication-type="other">
Garfinkel, I. and Oellierich, D. T. (1989), 'Noncustodial fathers' ability to pay child support',
Demography, vol. 26, pp. 219-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1048a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1052" publication-type="other">
— and Robins, P. K. (1994), 'The relationship between child support enforcement tools and child
support outcomes', in I. Garfinkel, S. S. McLanahan and P. K. Robins (eds), Child Support and
Child Well-Being, Washington, DC: Urban Institute Press; distributed by University Press of
America, Lanham, Md.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1069a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1073" publication-type="other">
—, —, Wong, P. and Meyer, D. R. (1999), 'The Wisconsin child support system: estimated effects
on poverty, labour supply, caseloads and costs', Journal of Human Resources, vol. 25, pp. 1-
31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1086a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1090" publication-type="other">
— et al. (1999), Fathers under Fire: The Revolution in Child Support Enforcement, New York:
Russell Sage Foundation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1100a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1104" publication-type="other">
Hu, W-Y. (1999), 'Child support, welfare dependency and women's labor supply', Journal of
Human Resources, vol. 34, pp. 71-103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1114a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1118" publication-type="other">
Jenkins, S. J. and Millar, J. (1989), 'Income risk and income maintenance: implications for
incentives to work', in A. Dilnot and I. Walker (eds), The Economics of Social Security,
Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1131a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1135" publication-type="other">
Keane, M. and Moffitt, R. (1998), 'A structural model of multiple welfare program participation
and labor supply', International Economic Review, vol. 39, pp. 553-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1145a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1149" publication-type="other">
Lin, W. (1997), 'Perceived fairness and compliance with child support obligations', University of
Wisconsin-Madison Institute for Research on Poverty, Discussion Paper no. 1150.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1160a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1164" publication-type="other">
Meyer, D. R. (1993), 'Child support and welfare dynamics: evidence from Wisconsin',
Demography, vol. 30, pp. 45-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1174a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1178" publication-type="other">
— (1995), 'The effect of child support reforms on the economic status on nonresident fathers',
mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1188a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1192" publication-type="other">
— and Hu, M-C. (1997), 'A note on the effectiveness of child support among mother only
families', University of Wisconsin-Madison, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1202a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1206" publication-type="other">
Moffitt, R. (1984), 'The estimation of a joint wage-hours labor supply model', Journal of Labor
Economics, vol. 2, pp. 550-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1216a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1220" publication-type="other">
Preston, I. P. and Walker, I. (1999), 'Welfare measurement in labour supply models with nonlinear
budget constraints', Journal of Population Economics, vol. 12, pp. 343-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1230a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1234" publication-type="other">
Rendall, M. S., Clarke C., Peters, H. E., Ranjit, N. and Verropoulou, G. (1999), 'Incomplete
reporting of men's fertility in the United States and Britain: a research note', Demography, vol.
36, pp. 135-44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1248a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1252" publication-type="other">
US Census Bureau (1991), Child Support and Alimony, Current Population Survey Report P-60,
173, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
