<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">reviespafinacont</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50009991</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Revista Española de Financiación y Contabilidad</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administarción de Empresas</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">02102412</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">35</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">130</issue>
         <issue-id>i40105592</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">42782485</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>El papel de la información medioambiental en el cambio organizativo: el caso del sector turístico balear / The role of environmental reporting in organizational change: the case of the balearic tourist sector</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Carlos Larrinaga</given-names>
                  <surname>González</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Antoni Llull</given-names>
                  <surname>Gilet</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Miguel Perelló</given-names>
                  <surname>Julià</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2006</year>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2006</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>501</fpage>
         <lpage>522</lpage>
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2001 Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administración de Empresas</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/42782485"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Se ha entendido que la contabilidad medioambiental podía ser una forma de proporcionar visibilidad y poder a los partícipes preocupados por la incidencia medioambiental de la empresa y que esto traería consigo el cambio de las organizaciones. La crítica de esta teoría, ha conducido a Gray et al. [1995] a estudiar el papel de la contabilidad en el proceso de cambio de las organizaciones. Tomando este segundo enfoque teórico como punto de partida, el presente trabajo estudia la incidencia que sobre el cambio organizativo tiene la obligación de informar de todas las empresas turísticas que se han certificado por EMAS. El estudio empírico del sector turístico balear, basado en la realización de entrevistas semiestructuradas, permite concluir que la información medioambiental se utiliza para mejorar la imagen de organizaciones que no están cambiando profundamente, aunque sí llevan a cabo iniciativas limitadas. La falta de presión por parte del público hace que, contrariamente a la evidencia aportada por otros estudios, estas empresas no utilicen la información medioambiental como una forma de controlar y limitar la cuestión medioambiental. Environmental accounting has been seen as a way of increasing visibility and empowering stakeholders, concerned by the environmental effects of companies. This would lead to an organizational change. Earlier critique to this view led Gray et al. [1995] to study the role of accounting in the process of organizational change. Taking this theoretical framework as a starting point, this paper studies how the obligation to report for all the companies that in the tourist sector are certified by EMAS impact on organizational change. The empirical study in the Balearic tourist sector, based on semi-structured interviews, leads to conclude that environmental reporting is being used to improve the image of organizations that are not experimenting dramatic changes, but only undertaking limited initiatives. Conversely to the evidence found in other studies, the lack of public pressure leads these companies not to use environmental reporting as a way of controlling and limiting the environmental issue.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>spa</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d638e168a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d638e175" publication-type="other">
Gray et al. [1987, p. IX]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d638e182a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d638e189" publication-type="other">
Decreto 81/1997</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d638e195" publication-type="other">
EMAS [1993]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d638e201" publication-type="other">
EMAS [2001]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>BIBLIOGRAFÍA</title>
        <ref id="d638e217a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e221" publication-type="other">
Adams, C. A. [2004]: «The ethical, social and environmental reporting-performance gap», Accounting,
Auditing and Accountability Journal, 17 (5), pp. 731-757.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e231a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e235" publication-type="other">
Archel, P. [2003]: «La divulgación de la información social y medioambiental de la gran empresa es-
pañola en el periodo 1994-1998: situación actual y perspectivas», Revista Española de Financiación y
Contabilidad, XXXII (117), pp. 571-601.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e248a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e252" publication-type="other">
Arksey, H., y Knight, P. [1999]: Interviewing of Social Scientists, Sage Publications.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e259a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e263" publication-type="other">
Bebbington, J., y Gray, R. [2001]: «An Account of Sustainability: Failure, Success and a Reconceptuali-
zation», Critical Perspectives on Accounting, 12 (5), pp. 557-588.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e274a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e278" publication-type="other">
Bebbington, J.; Gray, R., y Owen, D. [1999]: «Seeing the wood for the trees. Taking the pulse of social and
environmental accounting», Accounting, Auditing and Accountability Journal 12 (1), pp. 47-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e288a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e292" publication-type="other">
Berger, P., y Luckmann, T. [1966]: The Social Construction of Reality, traducción española: La Construc-
ción Social de la Realidad, Amorrortu Editores, Buenos Aires.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e302a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e306" publication-type="other">
Birkin, F. [1996]: «The ecological accountant: from the cogito to thinking like a mountain», Critical Pers-
pectives on Accounting, 7 (3), pp. 231-257.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e316a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e320" publication-type="other">
Bonache, J. [1999]: «El estudio de casos como estrategia de construcción teórica: características, críti-
cas y defensas», Cuadernos de Economía y Dirección de la Empresa (3), pp. 123-140.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e330a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e334" publication-type="other">
Buhr, N. [1998]: «Environmental performance, legislation and annual report disclosure: the case of
acid rain and Falconbridge», Accounting, Auditing and Accountability Journal, 11 (2), pp. 163-190.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e344a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e348" publication-type="other">
Burchell, S.; Clubb, C.; Hopwood, A. G.; Hughes, J., y Nahapiet, J. [1980]: «The roles of accounting in or-
ganizations and society», Accounting, Organizations and Society, 5 (1), pp. 5-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e359a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e363" publication-type="other">
Cooper, C. [1992]: «The non and nom of accounting for (m)other nature», Accounting, Auditing and Ac-
countability Journal, 5 (1), pp. 16-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e373a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e377" publication-type="other">
Cooper, D., y Sherer, M. [1984]: «The value of corporate accounting reports: arguments for a politic eco-
nomy of accounting», Accounting, Organizations and Society, 9 (3/4), pp. 207-232.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e387a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e391" publication-type="other">
Correa, C. [2001]: El reporting medioambiental como práctica institucional: su proceso de difusión en
una empresa eléctrica, Tesis doctoral, Universidad Pablo de Olavide de Sevilla.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e401a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e405" publication-type="other">
Deegan, C., y Rankin, M. [1996]: «Do Australian companies report environmental news objectively? An
analysis of environmental disclosures by firms prosecuted successfully by the environmental protec-
tion authority», Accounting, Auditing and Accountability Journal, 9 (2), pp. 50-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e418a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e422" publication-type="other">
DiMaggio, P., y Powell, W. [1983]: «The iron cage revisited: institutional isomorphism and collective ra-
tionality in organizational fields», American Sociological Review, (48), pp. 147-160.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e432a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e436" publication-type="other">
EMAS [1993]: Reglamento (CE) 1836/1993, de 29 de junio, por el que se permite que las organizacio-
nes se adhieran con carácter voluntario a un sistema comunitario de gestión y auditoría medioam-
bientales L 168/1, 10-7-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e450a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e454" publication-type="other">
--- [2001]: Reglamento (CE) 761/2001, de 19 de marzo, por el que se permite que las organizaciones
se adhieran con carácter voluntario a un sistema comunitario de gestión y auditoría medioambienta-
les (EMAS) L 114/1, 24-4-2001.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e467a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e471" publication-type="other">
García-Ayuso, M., y Larrínaga, C. [2003]: «Environmental disclosure in Spain: Corporate characteristics
and media exposure», Revista Española de Financiación y Contabilidad, 115, pp. 184-214.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e481a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e485" publication-type="other">
Gómez, M., y Palmer, A. M. [2000]: «Creado del "Distintili Ecoturístic" per a establiments turístics al mu-
nicipi d'Alcúdia», en Evolució turística de la darrera década i disseny de futur, Actes de las II Jorna-
des de Turisme i Medi Ambient, Palma.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e498a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e502" publication-type="other">
Gray, H. [1992]: «Accounting and environmentalism: an exploration of the challenge of gently accoun-
ting for accountability, transparency and sustainability», Accounting, Organizations and Society, 17
(5), pp. 399-425.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e515a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e519" publication-type="other">
--- [1997]: «The practice of silent accounting», en Zadek, S. (ed.), Building Corporate Accountability,
Earthscan, London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e529a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e533" publication-type="other">
--- [2002]: «The social accounting project and Accounting Organizations and Society Privileging enga-
gement, imaginings, new accountings and pragmatism over critique?», Accounting, Organizations and
Society 27, pp. 687-708.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e547a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e551" publication-type="other">
Gray, R.; Owen, D., y Maunders, K. [1987]: Corporate social reporting, Prentice Hall, Hemel Hempstead.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e558a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e562" publication-type="other">
Gray, R.; Walters, D.; Bebbington, J., y Thompson, I. [1995]: «The greening of enterprise: an exploration
of the (non) role of environmental accounting and environmental accountants in organizational chan-
ge», Critical Perspectives on Accounting, 6 (3), pp. 211-239.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e575a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e579" publication-type="other">
Greenwood, R., y Hinings, C. [1988]: «Organizational design types, tracks and the dynamics of strategic
change», Organization Studies, 9 (3), pp. 293-316.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e589a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e593" publication-type="other">
--- [1993]: «Understanding strategic change: the contribution of archetypes», Academy of Manage-
ment Journal, 36 (5), pp. 1.052-1.081.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e603a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e607" publication-type="other">
--- [1996]: «Understanding radical organizational change: bringing together the old and the new ins-
titutionalism», Academy of Management Review, 21 (4), pp. 1.022-1.054.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e617a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e621" publication-type="other">
Hines, R. [1988]: «Financial accounting: in communicating, we construct reality», Accounting, Organi-
zations and Society, 13 (3), pp. 251-261.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e632a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e636" publication-type="other">
Ingram, R. W, y Frazier, K. B. [1980]: «Environmental performance and corporate disclosures», Jour-
nal of Accounting Research, 18 (2), pp. 614-622.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e646a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e650" publication-type="other">
Larrinaga, C. [1999]: «¿Es la contabilidad medioambiental un paso hacia la sostenibilidad o un escudo
contra el cambio? El caso del sector eléctrico español», Revista Española de Financiación y Contabili-
dad, 101, pp. 645-674.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e663a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e667" publication-type="other">
Larrinaga, C., y Bebbington, J. [2001]: «Accounting change or institutional appropriation? A case study
of the implementation of environmental accounting», Critical Perspectives on Accounting, 12 (3),
pp. 269-292.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e680a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e684" publication-type="other">
Larrinaga, C.; Carrasco, F.; Caro, F. J.; Correa, C., y Páez, J. M. [2001]: «The role of environmental ac-
counting in organizational change: An exploration of Spanish companies», Accounting, Auditing and
Accountability Journal, 14 (2), pp. 213-239.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e697a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e701" publication-type="other">
Laughlin, R. [1991]: «Environmental disturbances and organizational transitions and transformations:
some alternative models», Organizational Studies, 12 (2), pp. 209-232.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e711a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e715" publication-type="other">
Lukka, K., y Kasanen, E. [1995]: «The problem of generalizability: anecdotes and evidence in accounting
research», Accounting, Auditing and Accountability Journal, 8 (5), pp. 71-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e726a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e730" publication-type="other">
Martorell, 0. [2001]: Las cadenas hoteleras. Un modelo de crecimiento empresarial, Tesis Doctoral,
Universität de les Bles Balears.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e740a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e744" publication-type="other">
Meyer, J. W., y Rowan, B. [1977]: «Institutionalized organizations: formal structure as myth and cere-
mony», American Journal of Sociology, 83 (2), pp. 340-363.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e754a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e758" publication-type="other">
Moneva, J. M., y Llena, F. [2000]: «Environmental disclosures in the annual report of large companies
in Spain», European Accounting Review, 9 (1), pp. 7-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e768a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e772" publication-type="other">
Moneva, J. M.; Fuertes, Y., y Pascual, E. [2001]: «Información de base social en el sector eléctrico espa-
ñol: análisis de contenido y factores explicativos», Cuadernos de Economía y Dirección de la Empresa,
(9), pp. 227-248.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e785a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e789" publication-type="other">
Neu, D.; Warsame, H., and Pedwell, K. [1998]: «Managing public impressions: environmental disclosu-
res in annual reports», Accounting, Organizations and Society, 23 (3), pp. 265-282.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e799a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e803" publication-type="other">
O'Dwyer, B. [2002]: «Managerial Perceptions of corporate social disclosure. An Irish Story», Accoun-
ting, Auditing and Accountability Journal, 15 (3), pp. 406-436.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e814a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e818" publication-type="other">
Oliver, C. [1992]: «The antecedents of desinstitutionalization», Organization Studies, 13 (4), pp. 563-588.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e825a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e829" publication-type="other">
Owen, D.; Gray, R., y Bebbemgton, J. [1997]: «Green accounting: cosmetic irrelevance of radical agenda
for change», Asia-Pacific Journal of Accounting, 4 (2), pp. 175-198.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e839a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e843" publication-type="other">
Páez Sandubete, J. M. [2001]: «Una exploración empírica de los factores que condicionan la actitud fren-
te a la contabilidad ambiental», Revista de Contabilidad, 4 (7), pp. 177-206.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e853a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e857" publication-type="other">
Patten, D. [1992]: «Intra-industry environmental disclosure in response to the Alaskan oil spill: a note
on Legitimacy Theory», Accounting, Organizations and Society, 17 (5), pp. 471-475.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e867a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e871" publication-type="other">
Patton, M. Q. [1990]: Qualitative evaluation and research methods, Sage Publications, Newbury Park,
California.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e881a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e885" publication-type="other">
Power, M. [1991]: «Auditing and environmental expertise: between protest and professionalisation»,
Accounting, Auditing and Accountability Journal, 4 (1), pp. 30-42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e896a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e900" publication-type="other">
Puxty, A. G. [1986]: «Social accounting as immanent legitimation. A critique of a technicist ideology»,
Advances in Public Interest Accounting, Vol. 1, pp. 95-111.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e910a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e914" publication-type="other">
Rockness, J. W. [1985]: «An assessment of the relationship between US corporate environmental per-
formance and disclosure», Journal of Business Finance &amp; Accounting, 12 (3), pp. 339-353.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e924a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e928" publication-type="other">
Rovira, R. [2002]: El proceso de elaboración del informe medioambiental, Tesis doctoral, Universidad
de Barcelona.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e938a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e942" publication-type="other">
Sa Nostra [2000]: Informe economic i social de les liles Balears, 1999, Ed. Sa Nostra, Palma.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e949a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e953" publication-type="other">
Scott, W. R. [1995]: Institutions and Organizations, Sage Publications.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e960a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e964" publication-type="other">
Tilt, C. A. [2001]: «The content and disclosure of Australian corporate environmental policies», Ac-
counting, Auditing and Accountability Journal, 14 (2), pp. 190-212.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e975a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e979" publication-type="other">
Tinker, T.; Lehman, Ch., y Neimark, M. [1991]: «Falling down the hole in the middle of the road: political quie-
tism in corporate social reporting», Accounting, Auditing and Accountability Journal, 4 (2), pp. 28-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e989a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e993" publication-type="other">
Unión Europea, Comisión [2001] VI Programa [2001-2010]: «Sexto programa de acción de la Comunidad
Europea en materia de medio ambiente. Medio ambiente 2010: el futuro está en nuestras manos»,
COM (2001) 31 final 2001/0029 COD.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e1006a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e1010" publication-type="other">
Wengraf, T. [2001]: Qualitative Research Interviewing, Sage Publications.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e1017a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e1021" publication-type="other">
Wiseman, J. [1982]: «An Evaluation of Environmental Disclosure Made in Corporate Annual Reports»,
Accounting, Organizations and Society, 7 (1), pp. 53-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d638e1031a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d638e1035" publication-type="other">
Yin, R. [1994]: Case Study Research. Design and Methods, Sage Publications.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


