<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">mathcomp</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100273</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Mathematics of Computation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>American Mathematical Society</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00255718</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">10886842</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">76</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">258</issue>
         <issue-id>i40008726</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40234402</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Tractability of Quasilinear Problems II: Second-Order Elliptic Problems</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>A. G.</given-names>
                  <surname>Werschulz</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>H.</given-names>
                  <surname>Woźniakowski</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2007</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>745</fpage>
         <lpage>776</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2007 American Mathematical Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40234402"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>In a previous paper, we developed a general framework for establishing tractability and strong tractability for quasilinear multivariate problems in the worst case setting. One important example of such a problem is the solution of the Helmholtz equation -Δu + qu = f in the d-dimensional unit cube, in which u depends linearly on f, but nonlinearly on q. Here, both f and q are d-variate functions from a reproducing kernel Hilbert space with finite-order weights of order ω. This means that, although d can be arbitrarily large, f and q can be decomposed as sums of functions of at most ω variables, with ω independent of d. In this paper, we apply our previous general results to the Helmholtz equation, subject to either Dirichlet or Neumann homogeneous boundary conditions. We study both the absolute and normalized error criteria. For all four possible combinations of boundary conditions and error criteria, we show that the problem is tractable. That is, the number of evaluations of f and q needed to obtain an ϵ-approximation is polynomial in ϵ⁻¹ and d, with the degree of the polynomial depending linearly on ω. In addition, we want to know when the problem is strongly tractable, meaning that the dependence is polynomial only in ω⁻¹, independently of d. We show that if the sum of the weights defining the weighted reproducing kernel Hilbert space is uniformly bounded in d and the integral of the univariate kernel is positive, then the Helmholtz equation is strongly tractable for three of the four possible combinations of boundary conditions and error criteria, the only exception being the Dirichlet boundary condition under the normalized error criterion.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>Primary 65N15</kwd>
            <kwd>Secondary 41A65</kwd>
            <kwd>Complexity</kwd>
            <kwd>tractability</kwd>
            <kwd>high-dimensional problems</kwd>
            <kwd>elliptic partial differential equations</kwd>
            <kwd>reproducing kernel hilbert spaces</kwd>
            <kwd>quasi-linear problems</kwd>
            <kwd>finite-order weights</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d3021887e157a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e164" publication-type="other">
R. A. Adams and J. J. F. Fournier, Sobolev spaces, second ed., Pure and Applied Mathematics,
vol. 140, Academic Press, Boston, 2003.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e174a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e181" publication-type="other">
N. Aronszajn, Theory of reproducing kernels, Trans. Amer. Math. Soc. 68 (1950), 337-404.
MR0051437 (14:479c)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e191a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e198" publication-type="other">
P. G. Ciarlet, Basic error estimates for elliptic problems, Handbook of Numerical Analysis,
Vol. II, North-Holland, Amsterdam, 1991, pp. 17-351. MR1115237</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e208a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e215" publication-type="other">
J. Dick, I. H. Sloan, X. Wang, and H. Woźniakowski, Good lattice rules in weighted Korobov
spaces with general weights, To appear in Numerische Mathematik.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e226a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e233" publication-type="other">
D. Gilbarg and N. S. Trudinger, Elliptic partial differential equations of second order, second
ed., Grundlehren der mathematischen Wissenschaften, vol. 224, Springer-Verlag, Berlin, 1983.
MR0737190 (86c:35035)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e246a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e253" publication-type="other">
A. Messiah, Quantum mechanics, Dover, Mineola, NY, 1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e260a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e267" publication-type="other">
E. Novak and H. Woźniakowski, When are integration and discrepancy tractable?, Foundations
of Computational Mathematics, Proceedings of Oxford 1999 (R. A. DeVore, A. Iserles, and
E. Süli, eds.), Cambridge University Press, 2001, pp. 211-266. MR1836619 (2002h:68083)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e280a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e287" publication-type="other">
J. T. Oden and J. N. Reddy, An introduction to the mathematical theory of finite elements,
Wiley-Interscience, New York, 1976. MR0461950 (57:1932)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e297a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e304" publication-type="other">
I. H. Sloan and H. Woźniakowski, When are quasi-Monte Carlo algorithms efficient for high-
dimensional integrals?, J. Complexity 14 (1998), no. 1, 1-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e314a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e321" publication-type="other">
J. F. Traub, G. W. Wasilkowski, and H. Wozniakowski, Information-based complexity, Aca-
demic Press, Boston, 1988. MR0958691 (90f:68085)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e332a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e339" publication-type="other">
J. F. Traub and A. G. Werschulz, Complexity and information, Cambridge University Press,
Cambridge, 1998. MR1692462 (2000m:65170)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e349a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e356" publication-type="other">
G. W. Wasilkowski and H. Woźniakowski, Finite-order weights imply tractability of linear
multivariate problems, J. Approx. 130 (2004), 57-77. MR2086810 (2005d:41048)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e366a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e373" publication-type="other">
A. G. Werschulz, The computational complexity of differential and integral equations:
An information-based approach, Oxford University Press, New York, 1991. MR1 144521
(93a:68061)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e386a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e393" publication-type="other">
A. G. Werschulz and H. Woźniakowski, Tractability of quasilinear problems. I: General results,
Tech. Report CUCS-025-05, Columbia University, Department of Computer Science, New
York, 2005, Submitted to J. Approx. Theory for publication. Available at http://mice.cs.
Columbia . edu/getTechreport . php?techreportID=248&amp;format=pdf&amp;.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3021887e409a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3021887e416" publication-type="other">
William P. Ziemer, Weakly differentiate functions: Sobolev spaces and functions of bounded
variation, Graduate Texts in Mathematics, vol. 120, Springer-Verlag, New York, 1989.
MR1014685 (91e:46046)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


