<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440019</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Elasticity of Marginal Utility of Consumption: Estimates for 20 OECD Countries</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>David J.</given-names>
                  <surname>Evans</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2005</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">26</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440014</issue-id>
         <fpage>197</fpage>
         <lpage>224</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2005</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440019"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>In social project appraisal, the policy profile of both distributional welfare weights and the social discount rate has risen considerably in recent years. This fact has important implications for the allocation of funds to social projects and policies in countries, and in unions of countries such as the EU. A key component in the formulae for both welfare weights and the social discount rate is the elasticity of marginal utility of consumption, e. A critical review of existing evidence on e suggests that the UK Treasury's preferred value of unity is too low. New evidence presented in this paper, based on the structure of personal income tax rates, suggests that, on average, for developed countries e is close to 1.4. This particular approach to the estimation of e has previously been under-utilised by researchers.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d22e169a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e176" publication-type="other">
The author would like to thank the anonymous referees for their helpful comments and suggestions
for revising the original draft.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e186a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e193" publication-type="other">
The Frisch formula can be expressed as follows:
(1 -wy)y
where y is the income elasticity of demand, p is the absolute value of the compensated price elasticity of
demand and w is the budget share of the preference-independent product group.
The Amundsen modification is as follows:
P
where: b is the marginal propensity to spend on consumer goods other than the product group in
question, so b = (l-b')&gt; where b' is the marginal propensity to spend on the selected preference-
independent product group; y is the income elasticity of demand; and p is the absolute value of the
compensated price elasticity of demand.
It can easily be shown that b = 1 -wy, meaning that the two approaches are equivalent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e231a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e238" publication-type="other">
This evidence from the National Food Survey concerning the constancy of the income elasticity of
demand for food is based on very large samples of household data. These cross-section data have been
taken over three-year periods on a rolling basis from 1979 to 2000 (1979-81, 1980-82, 1981-83, etc. up
to 1998-2000). See MAFF (2000, pages 97-98). In 2001, the National Food Survey was combined with
the Family Expenditure Survey and renamed the Expenditure and Food Survey.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e257a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e264" publication-type="other">
Annual data were used to estimate the different demand models. While the use of quarterly data
would increase the number of sample observations fourfold, it would not increase the effective sample
size to anything like the same extent. This is especially the case in low-inflation periods, when successive
quarters may yield very little variation in price data. Furthermore, a more complex dynamic model would
become relevant in the context of quarterly data, with additional regressors including lagged variables.
This increase in the number of variables may well introduce multicollinearity problems. Finally, the
seasonal variation in the quarterly data is unlikely to exhibit regularity over a suitably lengthy data period
and there is therefore a danger that the estimated regression model would not properly capture the
seasonal effects. For all of these reasons, an annual model is preferred, even though its use necessitates
only modest-sized data samples.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e300a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e307" publication-type="other">
Tax aversion in the case of individual taxpayers may lead to tax evasion problems. Underpayment of
income tax is quite a serious problem in some of the OECD countries included in the data sample - for
example, Italy, Spain and Turkey. This creates a divergence between a government's desired degree of
progressiveness in the income tax structure, as expressed in the tax schedule, and the degree of
progressiveness reflected in the actual tax payments. Clearly, more effective policing of the tax system is
the answer, although this may prove costly. If serious tax evasion is a consequence of a lack of political
will to remedy the situation, then there is a problem since the government is accepting the fact of a less
progressive tax system than the one it has designed. In short, use of the official tax schedules would then
produce an upward-biased measure of e. There is scope here for research into the extent of tax evasion in
different countries and its persistence over time.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e342a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e349" publication-type="other">
Differences in e values are, by appeal to the central limit theorem, likely to be normally distributed.
So, if the sample had consisted of randomly selected observations then the matched samples t-test would
have been appropriate. Although the data for 20 OECD countries do not constitute a random sample, the
power of the test is still appealing. In any case, other tests are also applied to the data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d22e374a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e378" publication-type="other">
Amiel, Y., Creedy, J. and Hum, D. (1999), 'Measuring attitudes towards inequality',
Scandinavian Journal of Economics, vol. 101, pp. 83-96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e388a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e392" publication-type="other">
Amundsen, A. (1964), 'Private consumption in Norway 1930-1978', in J. Sandee (ed.),
Europe's Future Consumption, Amsterdam: North Holland Publishing Company.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e402a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e406" publication-type="other">
Attanasio, O. P. and Browning, M. (1995), 'Consumption over the life cycle and over the
business cycle', American Economic Review, vol. 85, pp. 1118-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e416a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e420" publication-type="other">
Barsky, R. B„ Kimball, M. S., Juster, F. T. and Shapiro, M. D. (1995), 'Preference parameters
and behavioural heterogeneity: an experimental approach in the Health and Retirement
Survey', National Bureau for Economic Research, Working Paper no. 5213.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e434a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e438" publication-type="other">
Besley, T. and Meghir, C. (1998), Tax Based Savings INcentives, TEchnical Report, London:
London School of Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e448a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e452" publication-type="other">
Blue, E. N. and Tweeten, C. (1997), 'The estimation of marginal utility of income for
application to agricultural policy analysis', Agricultural Economics, vol. 16, pp. 155-69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e462a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e466" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R., Browning, M. and Meghir, C. (1994), 'Consumer demand and the life-cycle
allocation of household expenditures', Review of Economic Studies, vol. 61, pp. 57-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e476a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e480" publication-type="other">
Cowell, F. A. and Gardiner, K. (1999), 'Welfare weights', London School of Economics,
STICERD, Economics Research Paper no. 20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e490a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e494" publication-type="other">
Deaton, A. and Muellbauer, J. (1980), Economics and Consumer Behaviour, Cambridge:
Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e504a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e508" publication-type="other">
Evans, D. (2004a), 'The elevated status of the elasticity of marginal utility of consumption',
Applied Economics Letters, vol. 11, pp. 443-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e519a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e523" publication-type="other">
— (2004b), 'A social discount rate for France', Applied Economics Letters, vol. 11, pp. 803-
8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e533a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e537" publication-type="other">
—, Kula, E. and Sezer, H. (2005), 'Regional welfare weights for the UK: England, Scotland,
Wales and Northern Ireland', Regional Studies, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e547a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e551" publication-type="other">
— and Sezer, H. (2002), 'A time preference measure of the social discount rate for the UK',
Applied Economics, vol. 34, pp. 1925-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e561a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e565" publication-type="other">
— and — (2004), 'Social discount rates for six major countries', Applied Economics Letters,
vol. 11, pp. 557-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e575a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e579" publication-type="other">
Fellner, W. (1967), 'Operational utility: the theoretical background and a measurement', in
W. Fellner (ed.), Ten Economic Studies in the Tradition of Irving Fisher, New York: John
Wiley and Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e592a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e596" publication-type="other">
Fisher, I. (1927), 'A statistical method for measuring marginal utility', in Economic Essays
Contributed in Honour of J. Bates, London: Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e607a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e611" publication-type="other">
Frisch, R. (1932), New Methods of Measuring Marginal Utility, Tubingen: J. C. B. Möhr.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e618a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e622" publication-type="other">
— (1959), 'A complete system for computing all direct and cross demand elasticities in a
model with many sectors', Econometrica, vol. 27, pp. 177-96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e632a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e636" publication-type="other">
HM Treasury (1997), Appraisal and Evaluation in Central Government, The Green Book,
London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e646a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e650" publication-type="other">
— (2003), Appraisal and Evaluation in Central Government, The Green Book, London:
HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e660a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e664" publication-type="other">
Hotelling, H. (1931), 'Economics of exhaustible resources', Journal of Political Economy,
vol. 39, pp. 137-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e674a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e678" publication-type="other">
Kula, E. (1987), 'Social interest rate for public sector appraisal in the United Kingdom,
United States and Canada', Project Appraisal, vol. 2, pp. 169-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e689a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e693" publication-type="other">
— (2002), 'Regional welfare weights in investment appraisal: the case of India', Journal of
Regional Analysis and Policy, vol. 32, pp. 99-114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e703a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e707" publication-type="other">
— (2004), 'Estimation of a social rate of interest for India', Journal of Agricultural
Economics, vol. 55, pp. 91-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e717a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e721" publication-type="other">
MAFF (2000), The National Food Survey, London: Office for National Statistics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e728a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e732" publication-type="other">
OECD (2001), Assessing the Benefits of Transport, European Conference of Ministers of
Transport.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e742a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e746" publication-type="other">
— (2003), Taxing Wages 2002, Paris: Organisation for Economic Cooperation and
Development.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e756a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e760" publication-type="other">
— (2004), Extracts from the National Accounts of OECD Countries Database, Paris:
Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e771a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e775" publication-type="other">
OXERA (2002), A Social Time Preference Rate for Use in Long-Term Discounting: A Report
for ODPM, DfT and DEFRA, Oxford.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e785a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e789" publication-type="other">
Pearce, D. and Ulph, D. (1995), 'A social discount rate for the UK', University of East
Anglia, School of Environmental Studies, CSERGE, Working Paper no. 95-01.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e799a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e803" publication-type="other">
— and — (1999), 'A social discount rate for the UK', in D. W. Pearce (ed.), Environmental
Economics: Essays in Ecological Economics and Sustainable Development, Cheltenham:
Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e816a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e820" publication-type="other">
Ramsey, F. P. (1928), 'A mathematical theory of saving', Economic Journal, vol. 38, pp.
543-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e830a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e834" publication-type="other">
Scott, M. F. G. (1989), A New View of Economie Growth, Oxford: Clarendon Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e841a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e845" publication-type="other">
Selvanathan, S. (1988), 'A system-wide analysis of international consumption patterns:
advanced econometric series', Ph.D. thesis. University of Western Australia.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e856a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e860" publication-type="other">
— and Selvanathan, E. A. (1993), 'A cross-country analysis of consumption patterns',
Applied Economics, vol. 25, pp. 1245-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e870a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e874" publication-type="other">
Slade, M. E. (1982), 'Trends in natural-resource commodity prices: an analysis of time
domain', Journal of Environmental Economics and Management, vol. 9, pp. 122-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e884a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e888" publication-type="other">
Stern, H. N. (1977), 'Welfare weights and the elasticity of marginal utility of income', in M.
Artis and R. Norbay (eds), Proceedings of the Annual Conference of the Association of
University Teachers of Economics, Oxford: Blackwell.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
