<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169142</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investigation of Combustion Optimization Control Strategy for Stable Operation of Linear Internal Combustion Engine-Linear Generator Integrated System</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zang</surname>
                  <given-names>Pengfei</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wang</surname>
                  <given-names>Zhe</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sun</surname>
                  <given-names>Chenle</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Tongji University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>July 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169125</issue-id>
         <fpage>382</fpage>
         <lpage>390</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169142"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The linear internal combustion engine-linear generator integrated system (LICELGIS) is an innovative structure as a range-extender for the hybrid vehicles, which contains two opposed free piston engines and one linear generator between them. The LICELGIS is a promising power package due to its high power density and multi-fuel flexibility.</p>
            <p>In the combustion process of linear engines, the top dead center (TDC) position is not stable in different cycles, which significantly affects system operations. Otherwise, pistons move away from the TDC with high-speed because of the tremendous explosive force, which incurs the short residence time of pistons around the TDC and rapid decrease of in-cylinder temperature, pressure and the combustion efficiency. In order to address this problem, a scientific simulation model which includes dynamic and thermodynamic models, is established and a combustion optimization control strategy is proposed. The control strategy is based on the variable electromagnetic resistance force of the system. The electromagnetic resistance force is predictive and adjustable based on the velocity of midpoint and piston displacement.</p>
            <p>The simulation results indicate that under this control strategy, the TDC position is stable in different cycles and the power of the linear engine in one working cycle increased 5.6% than that without this control strategy. The control strategy based on combustion law and compression ratio of different fuels should be useful to control the piston trajectory around the TDC or even the whole cycle to realize high-efficiency combustion of different fuels.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, J. and Yan, Y., “A Wavelet-based Approach to Abrupt Fault Detection and Diagnosis of Sensor,” IEEE Transactions on Instrumentation and Measurement. 2001, 50(5): 1389-1396.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jia, B., Zuo, Z., Feng, H., Tian, G. et al., "Development Approach of a Spark-Ignited Free-Piston Engine Generator," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-2894, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2894.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deng, J., Ye, X., Yin, Z and Wang, Z., “Simulation on Starting Performance of a Linear Engine/Generator,” Journal of Tongji University, 2013, 41:596-599,613.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goto, S., Moriya, K., Kosaka, H., Akita, T. et al., "Development of Free Piston Engine Linear Generator System Part 2 -Investigation of Control System for Generator," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1193, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kosaka, H., Akita, T., Moriya, K., Goto, S. et al., "Development of Free Piston Engine Linear Generator System Part 1 -Investigation of Fundamental Characteristics," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1203, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1203.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mikalsen, R., Roskilly, A., “The Control of a Free-Piston Engine Generator. Part 1: Fundamental Analysis,” Applied Energy 87(4): 1273-1280, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mikalsen, R., Jones, E. and Roskilly, A., “Predictive Piston Motion Control in a Free-Piston Internal Combustion Engine,” Applied Energy 87(4): 1722-1728, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atkinson, C., Petreanu, S., Clark, N., Atkinson, R. et al., "Numerical Simulation of a Two-Stroke Linear Engine-Alternator Combination," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0921, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0921.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Subhash Nandkumar. Two-stroke linear engine. Dissertation, West Virginia University,1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">David Houdyschell. A diesel two-stroke linear engine. Dissertation, West Virginia University, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Blarigan, P., Paradiso, N., and Goldsborough, S., "Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition with a Free Piston: A New Approach to Ideal Otto Cycle Performance," SAE Technical Paper 982484, 1998, doi:10.4271/982484.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mikalsen, R., Roskilly, A., “The Control of a Free-Piston Engine Generator. Part 2: Engine Dynamics and Piston Motion Control,” Applied Energy 87(4): 1281-1287, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mao, J., Zuo, Z., and Feng, H., “Multi-dimensional Scavenging Analysis of a Free-Piston Linear Alternator,” Applied Energy 88(4): 1140-1152, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jia, B., Zuo, Z., Tian, G., Feng, H. et al., “Development and Validation of a Free-Piston Engine Generator Numerical Model,” Applied Energy 91(2): 333-341, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, D., Zuo, Z., Feng, H., and Tian, G., “Stable Compression Ratio Control for Free-Piston Engine Generator,” Journal of Xi`an Jiaotong University 48(5): 56-60, 88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun, C., Wang, Z., Deng, J., Yin, Z. et al., “Structural Design and Optimization of Linear ISG for Linear Range Extender,” Chinese Automotive Engineering 36(9): 1132-1139, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun, C., Wang, Z., Yin, Z., and Zhang, T., "Investigation of Control Method for Starting of Linear Internal Combustion Engine-Linear Generator Integrated System," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1729, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1729.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shoukry, E., “Numerical Simulation for Parametric Study of a Two Stroke Compression Ignition Direct Injection Linear Engine,” Morgantown, WV: West Virginia University, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Z., Ye, X., and Deng, J., “A Simulation Analysis on Free-Piston Engine Based on Matlab/Simulink,” Chinese Internal Combustion Engine Engineering 30(1): 69-73, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yin, Z., Wang, Z., Deng, J., Luan, L. et al., “Air-Fuel Ratio and Combustion Characteristics for Linear Engine at Low Speed,” Transactions of the Chinese Society of Agricultural Engineering, 28(18): 57-63, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
