<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">natitaxjour</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50005631</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>National Tax Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00280283</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19447477</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26349714</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>INCOME EFFECTS ON MATERNAL LABOR SUPPLY: EVIDENCE FROM CHILD-RELATED TAX BENEFITS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Philippe</given-names>
                  <surname>Wingender</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Sara</given-names>
                  <surname>LaLumia</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2017</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">70</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i26349711</issue-id>
         <fpage>11</fpage>
         <lpage>52</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2017 National Tax Association-Tax Institute of America</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26349714"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>A mother giving birth in December can claim child-related tax benefits when she files her tax return a few months later. Mothers of January-born children must wait more than a year before receiving child-related tax benefits. Thus, families with December births have higher after-tax income in the first year of a child's life than otherwise similar families with January births. This paper estimates the corresponding income effect on maternal labor supply. December mothers have a lower probability of working, particularly in the third month after a child's birth, and we find some evidence that child-related tax benefits reduce maternal earnings.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d936e265a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e272" publication-type="other">
Estimates of the income effect on labor supply that rely on a very different source of exogenous variation
in income, lottery winnings, find an income elasticity of -0.11, with no significant difference between men
and women (Imbens, Rubin, and Sacerdote, 2001).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e285a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e292" publication-type="other">
We do not include the Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit (CDCTC), which reimburses parents for
some portion of out-of-pocket child care expenses paid in order to allow a parent to work. The reason
for excluding this from our calculation is that we do not observe child care expenses in any of our data-
sets. The total tax savings delivered to families through the CDCTC is only about one-tenth of the tax
savings associated with the dependent exemption, and about one-twentieth of the tax savings associated
with the EITC, so our inability to calculate this benefit likely has little effect on our results (Isaacs et al.,
2011).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e318a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e325" publication-type="other">
More specifically, we restrict the sample to those mothers who worked in some capacity other than unpaid
family worker at some point in the previous five years. Had we not used this restriction, the sample would
have been approximately 13 percent larger.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e338a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e345" publication-type="other">
We are grateful to Dan Feenberg for providing a version of TAXSIM for use in the Federal Statistical
Research Data Center.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e356a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e363" publication-type="other">
This assumption is likely correct for the majority of our sample, as the percentage of all returns taking the
standard deduction ranged between 62.6 and 67.5 percent over the time period of our analysis (Statistics
of Income, 2015). To the extent that this assumption is incorrect, though, it will cause us to overstate the
value of child-related tax benefits. Presumably those who choose to itemize do so because it lowers their
tax liability, which in turn will reduce the value of nonrefundable tax credits, including the Child Tax
Credit.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e386a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e393" publication-type="other">
There is evidence that December and January EITC-eligible parents report different amounts of self-
employment income on tax returns. LaLumia, Sallee, and Turner (2015) consider filers with incomes in
the EITC-eligible range and with self-employment income. Comparing those whose December newborns
qualify them for a more generous EITC schedule to those with January newborns and less generous EITC
treatment, the parents of December newborns report self-employment income that bunches around the
EITC-maximizing level. If this is strictly a tax reporting response, and does not reflect real changes in
labor supply, then the bunching pattern will not necessarily appear in income data drawn from surveys
instead of from tax returns.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e422a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e429" publication-type="other">
If a mother is living with either a husband or male partner, we control for his income in the regression
analysis. However, following the provisions of the tax code, his income is used in calculating child-related
tax benefits only in cases where the couple is married.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e442a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e449" publication-type="other">
This procedure will produce valid estimates as long as the differing tax treatment of December and January
mothers has no dynamic effect on maternal labor supply persisting into the second year of a child's life.
We provide evidence supporting this assumption in Table 6.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e462a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e469" publication-type="other">
Seasonal patterns are also strong in the construction industry, which employs few women, and in state and
local government, where activity declines in the summer months when many schools are not in session.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e479a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e486" publication-type="other">
This is the full set of years that both overlaps with the ACS and SIPP data used in this paper and for which
publicly-available counts by exact date of birth are available. The NCVS has not published birth counts
by exact date of birth for years after 2003. In the set of six December-January pairs included in the figure,
there is no Saturday observation for December 3, 10, 17, 24, and 31 or January 7, 14, 21, and 28. There is
no Sunday observation for December 4,11, 18, and 25 or January 1,8,15,22, and 29. Daily birth counts
are consistently lower on weekends than on weekdays. As a result, we observe higher birth counts on dates
that are missing either a Saturday or Sunday over the period plotted in the figure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e513a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e520" publication-type="other">
The survey does not ask about all previous children born to a mother. We characterize a child as first-bom
if a mother has no other own children living in her household at the time of the ACS interview.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e530a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e537" publication-type="other">
We cannot report similar analysis for our ACS sample, as the number of mothers giving birth on a particular
calendar date, and observed t months after birth, is so small as to generate disclosure risk.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e547a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e554" publication-type="other">
Fitted values are computed using a cubic in the running variable, the day of birth centered around the
turn of the year. Results are robust to using alternative procedures developed by Calonico, Cattaneo, and
Titiunik (2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e567a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e574" publication-type="other">
In results not shown, we have also checked the robustness of the SIPP results by using inverse probability
weights to address selection of women with different observable characteristics into the group of December
mothers. The pattern of results is very similar to what we find without adjustment. Full results are available
upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e590a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e597" publication-type="other">
It would be interesting to study additional graphical evidence related to the probability that a mother is
working three months after giving birth. In particular, we would like to produce a regression discontinuity
figure plotting the share of mothers at work three months after birth, by exact date of birth. The need to
protect the confidentiality of survey respondents prevents us from producing such a figure. When cells
are defined by a combination of exact date of birth and time elapsed between giving birth and the ACS
interview, the number of cell-specific observations is often below the Census Bureau threshold for report-
ing means.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e623a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e630" publication-type="other">
Recall that in the SIPP we observe only month of birth, not exact date of birth, and thus we are comparing
mothers who give birth at any point in December to mothers who give birth at any point in January. This
difference in the set of births included in the SIPP and ACS analysis could complicate comparisons across
datasets. To probe this issue, we have estimated ACS results as if only month of birth was observable.
That is, we expand the ACS sample to include mothers giving birth at any point in December or January.
We again find that December mothers are significantly less likely to be currently employed and at work
in the third month after birth and in the eight month after birth. The coefficients on these two interaction
terms are -0.028 (standard error = 0.016) and -0.051 (standard error = 0.018).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e660a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e667" publication-type="other">
The full set of results is available upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e674a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e681" publication-type="other">
These mothers may be on either paid or unpaid leave. The employment status variables in the SIPP do
not allow identification of a corresponding group. In the SIPP, anyone who is receiving pay from a job
is categorized as being employed. It is impossible to identify those who are currently being paid while
temporarily absent from work.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e697a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e704" publication-type="other">
A 2008 survey of state education administrators, conducted by the Council of Chief State School Officers,
found that 40 states have ranges of acceptable school starting dates that include August, and of these 24
states had ranges beginning in August and ending in September (Stillman and Blank, 2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e717a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e724" publication-type="other">
Even though we have argued above that tax refunds are likely to have the greatest impact on short-term
labor supply decisions at the moment that they are received, taxpayers do not immediately spend the
entirety of any refunds received. For example, Souleles (1999) finds that recipients spend between 35 and
60 percent of tax refund payments within one quarter of receipt. The slower the rate at which refunds are
spent down, the more plausible it is that the differing tax treatment of December and January mothers will
affect labor supply several months after refunds are disbursed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e747a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e754" publication-type="other">
Tax treatment does differ again when children age out of eligibility for child-related benefits. For most
tax provisions, this occurs when the child turns age 18 or when a child who is a full-time student turns
age 24. Several authors have used variation in the time at which a child becomes ineligible for benefits to
estimate labor supply and other effects (Looney and Singhal, 2006; Dokko, 2008; Feldman, Kawano, and
KatuSiék, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e773a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e780" publication-type="other">
It is worth noting that this falsification test will be invalid if the differing tax treatment of December and
January mothers during the first year of a child's life has dynamic or persistent effects on labor supply in
subsequent years. For example, it could be the case that if December mothers take more time away from
work in the first year of a child's life, their lower levels of recent work experience make them less attrac-
tive job candidates in subsequent years.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e800a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e807" publication-type="other">
Better-educated workers tend to sort into larger firms (Evans and Leighton, 1989), and only firms with 50
or more employees are mandated by the FMLAto provide job-protected leave (Ruhm, 1997), It is worth
noting that this leave can begin before the birth of a child. Thus, greater scheduling flexibility may affect
the length of antenatal leave, which we cannot measure in ACS data, rather than the timing of the return
to work after giving birth.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e826a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e833" publication-type="other">
In principle, we could use β measure of hours worked to consider the intensive margin of labor supply.
In practice, ACS respondents report the usual number of hours worked per week, averaging over the 12
months prior to the ACS interview. This makes the ACS hours worked variable a poor candidate for ana-
lyzing short-run changes in work intensity.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e849a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e856" publication-type="other">
For mothers in our SIPP sample, the mean monthly labor income, averaging over all available months of
data, is $1,367. Scaling this up by 12 yields an average annual earned income of $16,404. This method
allows us to approximate annual earnings even for those who are in the SIPP for fewer than 12 months.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d936e869a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d936e876" publication-type="other">
In this figure, the fitted value is computed using a cubic in day of birth relative to January 1. Results are
similar when the fitted value is instead calculated using the techniques of Calonico, Cattaneo, and Titiunik
(2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d936e898a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e902" publication-type="other">
Baker, Michael, and Kevin Milligan, 2008. "How Does Job-Protected Maternity Leave Affect
Mothers' Employment?" Journal of Labor Economics 26 (4), 655-691.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e912a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e916" publication-type="other">
Baker, Michael, and Kevin Milligan, 2010. "Evidence from Maternity Leave Expansions of the
Impact of Maternal Care on Early Child Development." Journal of Human Resources 45 ( 1), 1-
32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e929a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e933" publication-type="other">
Baker, Michael, and Kevin Milligan, 2015. "Maternity Leave and Children's Cognitive and
Behavioral Development." Journal of Population Economics 28 (2), 373-391.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e943a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e947" publication-type="other">
Barsky, Robert B., and Jeffrey A. Miron, 1989. "The Seasonal Cycle and the Business Cycle."
Journal of Political Economy 97 (3), 503-534.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e958a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e962" publication-type="other">
Baum, Charles L., 2003. "The Effects of Maternity Leave Legislation on Mothers' Labor Supply
after Childbirth." Southern Economic Journal 69 (4), 772-799.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e972a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e976" publication-type="other">
Baum, Charles L., and Christopher J. Ruhm, 2016. "The Effects of Paid Family Leave in Califor-
nia on Labor Market Outcomes. "Journal of Policy Analysis and Management 35 (2), 333-356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e986a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e990" publication-type="other">
Berger, Lawrence M., Jennifer Hill, and Jane Waldfogel, 2005. "Maternity Leave, Early Mater-
nal Employment and Child Health and Development in the US " Economic Journal 115 (501),
F29-F47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1003a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1007" publication-type="other">
Berger, Lawrence M., and Jane Waldfogel, 2004. "Maternity Leave and the Employment of New
Mothers in the United States." Journal of Population Economics 17 (2), 331-349.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1017a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1021" publication-type="other">
Blau, Francine D., and Lawrence M. Kahn, 2007. "Changes in the Labor Supply Behavior of
Married Women: 1980-2000." Journal of Labor Economics 25 (3), 393-438.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1031a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1035" publication-type="other">
Blundell, Richard, and Thomas MaCurdy, 1999. "Labor Supply: A Review of Alternative
Approaches." In Ashenfelter, Orley, and David Card (eds.), Handbook of Labor Economics,
1560-1695. North-Holland Publishing Company, Amsterdam, Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1049a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1053" publication-type="other">
Borra, Cristina, Libertad Gonzalez, and Almudena Sevilla-Sanz, 2015. "The Impact of Schedul-
ing Birth Early on Infant Health." Barcelona Graduate School of Economics Working Paper No.
707. Barcelona Graduate School of Economics, Barcelona, Spain.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1066a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1070" publication-type="other">
Buckles, Kasey S., and Daniel M. Hungerman, 2013. "Season of Birth and Later Outcomes: Old
Questions, New Answers" Review of Economics and Statistics 95 (3), 711-724.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1080a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1084" publication-type="other">
Calonico, Sebastian, Matias Cattaneo, and Rocio Titiunik, 2014. "Robust Data-Driven Inference
in the Regression-Discontinuity Design." Stata Journal 14 (4), 909-946.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1094a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1098" publication-type="other">
Chatterji, Pinka, and Sara Markowitz, 2005. "Does the Length of Maternity Leave Affect Maternal
Health?" Southern Economic Journal 72 (1), 16-41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1108a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1112" publication-type="other">
Chetty, Raj, 2008. "Moral Hazard versus Liquidity and Optimal Unemployment Insurance."
Journal of Political Economy 116 (2), 173-234.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1122a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1126" publication-type="other">
Dickert-Conlin, Stacy, and Amitabh Chandra, 1999. "Taxes and the Timing of Births." Journal
of Political Economy 107 (1), 161-177.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1137a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1141" publication-type="other">
Dokko, Jane, 2008. "The Effect of Taxation on Lifecycle Labor Supply: Results from a Quasi-
Experiment." Finance and Economics Discussion Series No. 2008-24. Board of Governors of
the Federal Reserve System, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1154a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1158" publication-type="other">
Evans, David S., and Linda S. Leighton, 1989. "Why Do Smaller Firms Pay Less?" Journal of
Human Resources 24 (2), 299-318.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1168a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1172" publication-type="other">
Feldman, Naomi E., Laura Kawano, and Peter Katuscâk, 2016. "Taxpayer Confusion: Evidence
from the Child Tax Credit." American Economic Review 106 (3), 807-835.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1182a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1186" publication-type="other">
Gonzalez, Libertad, 2013. "The Effect of a Universal Child Benefit on Conceptions, Abortions,
and Early Maternal Labor Supply." American Economic Journal: Economic Policy 5 (3), 160-188.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1196a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1200" publication-type="other">
Guendelman, Sylvia, Michelle Pearl, Steve Graham, Alan Hubbard, Nap Hosang, and Martin
Kharrazi, 2009. "Maternity Leave in the Ninth Month of Pregnancy and Birth Outcomes Among
Working Women." Women's Health Issues 19 (1), 30-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1213a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1217" publication-type="other">
Han, Wen-Jui, Christopher Ruhm, and Jane Waldfogel, 2009. "Parental Leave Policies and Parents'
Employment and Leave-Taking." Journal of Policy Analysis and Management 28 (1), 29-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1228a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1232" publication-type="other">
Han, Wen-Jui, and Jane Waldfogel, 2003. "Parental Leave: The Impact of Recent Legislation on
Parents' Leave Taking." Demography 40 (1), 191-200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1242a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1246" publication-type="other">
Heim, Bradley T., 2007. "The Incredible Shrinking Elasticities: Married Female Labor Supply,
1979-2003." Journal of Human Resources 42 (4), 881-918.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1256a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1260" publication-type="other">
Holland, Burt S., and Margaret D. Copenhaver, 1987. "An Improved Sequentially Rejective
Bonferroni Test Procedure." Biometrics 43 (2), 417-424.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1270a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1274" publication-type="other">
Imbens, Guido W., Donald B. Rubin, and Bruce I. Sacerdote, 2001. "Estimating the Effect of
Unearned Income on Labor Earnings, Savings, and Consumption: Evidence from a Survey of
Lottery Players." American Economic Review 91 (4), 778-794.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1287a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1291" publication-type="other">
Isaacs, Julia, Heather Hahn, Stephanie Rennane, C. Eugene Steuerle, and Tracy Vericker, 2011.
"Kids' Share 2011 : Report on Federal Expenditures on Children Through 2010." Urban Institute,
Washington, DC, https://www.brookings.edu/wp-contentyuploads/2016/06/072 l_kids_share_
isaacs.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1307a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1311" publication-type="other">
Klerman, Jacob Α., and Arleen Leibowitz, 1994. "The Work-Employment Distinction among
New Mothers." Journal of Human Resources 29 (2), 277-303.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1322a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1326" publication-type="other">
Krane, Spencer, and William Wascher, 1999. "The Cyclical Sensitivity of Seasonality in U.S.
Employment." Journal of Monetary Economics 44 (3), 523-553.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1336a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1340" publication-type="other">
Kumar, Anil, and Che-Yuan Liang, 2016. "Declining Female Labor Supply Elasticities in the
United States and Implications for Tax Policy: Evidence from Panel Data "National Tax Journal
69 (3), 481-516.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1353a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1357" publication-type="other">
LaLumia, Sara, 2013. "The EITC, Tax Refunds, and Unemployment Spells." American Economic
Journal: Economic Policy 5 (2), 188-221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1367a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1371" publication-type="other">
LaLumia, Sara, James M. Sallee, and Nicholas Turner, 2015. "New Evidence on Taxes and the
Timing of Birth." American Economic Journal: Economic Policy 7 (2), 258-293.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1381a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1385" publication-type="other">
Laughlin, Lynda, 2011. "Maternity Leave and Employment Patterns: 2006-2008." Current
Population Report, 70-128.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1395a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1399" publication-type="other">
Looney, Adam, and Monica Singhal, 2006. "The Effect of Anticipated Tax Changes on Inter-
temporal Labor Supply and the Realization of Taxable Income." NBER Working Paper 12417.
National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1413a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1417" publication-type="other">
Maag, Elaine, 2013. "Child-Related Benefits in the Federal Income Tax." Urban Institute Brief
27. Urban Institute, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1427a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1431" publication-type="other">
Orszag, Peter R., and Matthew G. Hall, 2003. "Nonfilers and Filers with Modest Tax Liabilities.''
Tax Notes (August 4), 723.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1441a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1445" publication-type="other">
Plueger, Dean, 2009. "Earned Income Tax Credit Participation Rate for Tax Year 2005." Internal
Revenue Service, Washington, DC, http://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-soi/09resconeitcpart.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1455a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1459" publication-type="other">
Romano, Joseph P., and Michael Wolf, 2005. "Exact and Approximate Stepdown Methods for
Multiple Hypothesis Testing." Journal of the American Statistical Association 100 (469), 94-
108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1472a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1476" publication-type="other">
Rossin, Maya, 2011. "The Effects of Maternity Leave on Children's Birth and Infant Health
Outcomes in the United States." Journal of Health Economics 30 (2), 221-239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1486a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1490" publication-type="other">
Rossin-Slater, Maya, Christopher J. Ruhm, and Jane Waldfogel, 2013. "The Effects of California's
Paid Family Leave Program on Mothers' Leave-Taking and Subsequent Labor Market Outcomes."
Journal of Policy Analysis and Management 32 (2), 224-245.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1504a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1508" publication-type="other">
Ruhm, Christopher J., 1997. "Policy Watch: The Family and Medical Leave Act." Journal of
Economic Perspectives 11 (3), 175-186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1518a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1522" publication-type="other">
Schirle, Tammy, 2015. "The Effect of Universal Child Benefits on Labour Supply." Canadian
Journal of Economics 48 (2), 437-463.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1532a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1536" publication-type="other">
Schulkind, Lisa, and Teny M. Shapiro, 2014. "What a Difference a Day Makes: Quantifying the
Effects of Birth Timing Manipulation on Infant Health." Journal of Health Economics 33,139-158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1546a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1550" publication-type="other">
Souleles, Nicholas, 1999. "The Response of Household Consumption to Income Tax Refunds."
American Economic Review 89 (4), 947-958.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1560a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1564" publication-type="other">
Statistics of Income, 2015. "SOI Bulletin Historical Table 7." Statistics of Income, Internal
Revenue Service, Washington, DC, http://www.irs.gov/uac/SOI-Tax-Stats-Historical-Table-7.
Stillman, Lauren, and Rolf K. Blank, 2009. "Key State Education Policies on PK-12 Education:
2008." Technical Report. Council of Chief State School Officers, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1580a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1584" publication-type="other">
Tax Policy Center, 2011. "EITC Distribution by Number of Qualifying Children, 1999-2011."
Tax Policy Center, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1595a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1599" publication-type="other">
Waldfogel, Jane, 2001. "International Policies Toward Parental Leave and Child Care." Future
of Children 11 (1), 98-111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d936e1609a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d936e1613" publication-type="other">
Wingender, Philippe, 2010. "Birth Timing, Taxes, and Maternal Labor Supply: Evidence from
a Large Administrative Dataset." Manuscript. University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley, CA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
