<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422612</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Reduced Convective Combustion Chamber Wall Heat Transfer Losses of Hydrogen-Fueled Engines by Vortex-Stratified Combustion - Part 2</article-title>
            <subtitle>Numerical Analyses</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Oh</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Brouillette</surname>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Plante</surname>
                  <given-names>Jean-Sebastien</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Université de Sherbrooke</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>December 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>5</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422609</issue-id>
         <fpage>2259</fpage>
         <lpage>2274</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422612"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>In this second of two parts, the fundamentals of convective wall heat transfer losses are elucidated in the context of the desired objective toward its reduction in a direct-injected, hydrogen-fueled internal combustion engine. A comparative, transient 2D CFD analysis evaluated at 4500 RPM between a combustion chamber design representing current practice and the here-introduced “vortex-stratified combustion” process finds an approximately 50% reduction in the peak convective flux with the latter. The simulation results show that reduced heat flux of the vortex approach is driven by the combination of two effects: The first is finite-time diffusive mixing getting outpaced by the replenishment of pure air being introduced preferentially along the circumference of the combustion chamber due to the Coandă effect; this results in a distinct radial charge stratification during mixture preparation in the compression stroke, with a fuel-concentrated center and essentially pure air at the periphery. The second effect is the forced-segregation of different density reactants during the course of the combustion process caused by large body forces that result from the gravitational acceleration of the rapidly rotating charge, thereby constraining the combustible mixture and the flame to some distance from the walls. Evidence for this is observed by hot, low-density hydrogen being forced to remain near the center and cooler, heavier oxygen being inhibited from migrating from the outer periphery to react with the aforementioned hydrogen, and the distinct curvature of the radial gas temperature profile at a substantially greater distance from the wall than the thermal boundary layer thickness.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oh D., Brouillette, M., Plante J., “Reduced Convective Combustion Chamber Wall Heat Transfer Losses of Hydrogen-Fueled Engines by Vortex-Stratified Combustion - Part 1: Background and Optical Engine Observations,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2017-01-9286, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-9286.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Demuynck, J., Raes, N., Zuliani, M., De Paepe, M., Sierens, R., Verhelst, S., “Local heat flux measurements in a hydrogen and methane spark ignition engine with a thermopile sensor,” Int J Hydrogen Energy 34(24):9857-9868, December 2009, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2009.10.035.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamo, R., Bryzik, W., and Glance, P., "Adiabatic Engine Trends-Worldwide," SAE Technical Paper 870018, 1987, https://doi.org/10.4271/870018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Watts, P. and Heywood, J., "Simulation Studies of the Effects of Turbocharging and Reduced Heat Transfer on Spark-Ignition Engine Operation," SAE Technical Paper 800289, 1980, https://doi.org/10.4271/800289.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oppenheim, A., Kuhl, A., Packard, A., Hedrick, J. et al., "Model and Control of Heat Release in Engines," SAE Technical Paper 960601, 1996, https://doi.org/10.4271/960601.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borman, G., Nishiwaki, K., “Internal combustion engine heat transfer,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 13(1):1-46, 1987, doi:10.1016/0360-1285(87)90005-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals,” 1988, New York, McGraw-Hill.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pischinger, R., “The Importance of Heat Transfer to IC Engine Design and Operation,” ICHMT Digital Library, 1988, pp. 445-466, doi: 10.1615/ICHMT.1988.20thAHT.400.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caton, J. A., “The thermodynamic characteristics of high efficiency, internal-combustion engines,” Energy Conversion and Management 58:84-93, June 2012, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2012.01.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fridriksson, H. S., Hajireza, S., Tunér, M., Sunén, B., “A CFD Investigation of Heat Transfer in a Diesel Fueled PPC Engine Applying Design of Experiments,” Proc. ASME 2012 Internal Combustion Engine Division Fall Technical Conference, Vancouver, BC, Canada, September 23-26, 2012, ICEF2012-92059, pp. 747-756, doi:10.1115/ICEF2012-92059.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hendricks, T. L., Splitter, D. A., Ghandhi, J. B., “Experimental investigation of piston heat transfer under conventional diesel and reactivity-controlled compression ignition combustion regimes,” International Journal of Engine Research, 15(6):684-705, September 2014, doi: 10.1177/1468087413512310.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LeFeuvre, T., Myers, P., Uyehara, O., “Experimental Instantaneous Heat Fluxes in a Diesel Engine and Their Correlation,” SAE Technical Paper 690464, 1969, doi:10.4271/690464.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alkidas A.C., Myers J.P., “Transient Heat-Flux Measurements in the Combustion Chamber of a Spark-Ignition Engine,” ASME. J. Heat Transfer 104(1):62-67, 1982, doi:10.1115/1.3245069.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">White, C.M.; Steeper, R.R.; Lutz, A.E., “The Hydrogen-Fueled Internal Combustion Engine: A Technical Review,” Int J Hydrogen Energy 31(10):1292-1305, August 2006, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2005.12.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Verhelst, S., Wallner, T., “Hydrogen-Fueled Internal Combustion Engines,” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci., 35(6):490-527, December 2009, doi:10.1016/j.pecs.2009.08.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Drell I.L., Belles F.E., “Survey of hydrogen combustion properties,” Technical Report 1383, National Advisory Committee on Aeronautics, 1958.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Das, L.M., “Hydrogen-oxygen reaction mechanism and its implication to hydrogen engine combustion,” Int. J. Hydrogen Energy, 21(8):703-715, August 1996, doi:10.1016/0360-3199(95)00138-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wimmer, A., Wallner, T., Ringler, J., and Gerbig, F., "H2-Direct Injection - A Highly Promising Combustion Concept," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0108, 2005, https://doi.org/10.4271/2005-01-0108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Demuynck, J., De Paepe, M., Verhaert I., Verhelst, S., “Heat loss comparison between hydrogen, methane, gasoline and methanol in a spark-ignition internal combustion engine,” Energy Procedia 29:138-146, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.egypro.2012.09.018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blanc, M. V., Guest, P. G., von Elbe, G., Lewis, B., “Ignition of Explosive Gas Mixtures by Electric Sparks. I. Minimum Ignition Energies and Quenching Distances of Mixtures of Methane, Oxygen, and Inert Gases,” The Journal of Chemical Physics 15(798), 1947, doi: 10.1063/1.1746337.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harris, M. E., Grumer, J., von Elbe, G., Lewis, B., “Burning velocities, quenching, and stability data on nonturbulent flames of methane and propane with oxygen and nitrogen: Application of theory of ignition, quenching, and stabilization to flames of propane and air,” Third Symposium on Combustion and Flame and Explosion Phenomena, 3(1):80-89, 1948, doi:10.1016/S1062-2896(49)80010-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Friedman, R., Johnston, W. C., “The Wall-Quenching of Laminar Propane Flames as a Function of Pressure, Temperature, and Air-Fuel Ratio,” J. Appl. Phys. 21:791-795, 1950, doi:10.1063/1.1699760.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Friedman, R., Johnston, W. C., “Pressure Dependence of Quenching Distance of Normal Heptane, Iso-Octane, Benzene, and Ethyl Ether Flames,” J. Chem. Phys. 20:919, 1952, doi:10.1063/1.1700600.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shudo, T., Nabetani, S., Nakajima, Y., “Analysis of the degree of constant volume and cooling loss in a spark ignition engine fuelled with hydrogen,” International Journal of Engine Research, 2(1):81-92, February 2001, doi:10.1243/1468087011545361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shudo T., Oba S., “Mixture distribution measurements using laser induced breakdown spectroscopy in hydrogen direct injection stratified charge,” Int J Hydrogen Energy 34(5):2488-2493, March 2009, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2009.01.012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oppenheim, A., "Prospects for Combustion in Piston Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0999, 2002, https://doi.org/10.4271/2002-01-0999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lapsa, A. P., Dahm, W. J. A., “Hyperacceleration effects on turbulent combustion,” Proc. of the Combustion Institute 32(2):1731-1738, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2008.05.038.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heindl, R., Eichlseder, H., Spuller, C., Gerbig, F. et al., "New and Innovative Combustion Systems for the H2-ICE: Compression Ignition and Combined Processes," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1231-1250, 2009, https://doi.org/10.4271/2009-01-1421.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scarcelli, R., Wallner, T., Matthias, N., Salazar, V. et al., "Numerical and Optical Evolution of Gaseous Jets in Direct Injection Hydrogen Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0675, 2011, https://doi.org/10.4271/2011-01-0675.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scarcelli, R., Wallner, T., Matthias, N., Salazar, V. et al., "Mixture Formation in Direct Injection Hydrogen Engines: CFD and Optical Analysis of Single- and Multi-Hole Nozzles," SAE Int. J. Engines 4(2):2361-2375, 2011, https://doi.org/10.4271/2011-24-0096.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ANSYS® Academic Research, Release 16.2, Help System, Fluent Theory Guide, Chapter 4.14 - Near-Wall Treatments for Wall-Bounded Turbulent Flows, ANSYS, Inc.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, W., “Large-Eddy Simulation of Premixed Turbulent Combustion Using Flame Surface Density Approach,” PhD dissertation, University of Toronto, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sukumaran, S., Kong, S. C., “Numerical study on mixture formation characteristics in a direct-injection hydrogen engine,” Int J Hydrogen Energy 35(15):7991-8007, 2010, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2010.05.090.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Le Moine J., Senecal P. K., Kaiser S.A., et al., “A Computational Study of the Mixture Preparation in a Direct-Injection Hydrogen Engine,” ASME. J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power 137(11):111508-111508-5, 2015, doi:10.1115/1.4030397.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Propagation of the Flame Front,” accessed March 29, 2016, https://www.sharcnet.ca/Software/Ansys/16.0/en-us/help/flu_th/flu_th_sec_zimont_flame.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peters, N., “Turbulent Combustion,” Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, England. 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
