<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816600</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>U.S. Fiscal Policy Past, Present, and Future (Macro and Fiscal Policy)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>FEDERAL BUDGET POLICY WITH AN AGING POPULATION AND PERSISTENTLY LOW INTEREST RATES</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Elmendorf</surname>
                  <given-names>Douglas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sheiner</surname>
                  <given-names>Louise</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>57</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816600"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Relative to the size of the economy, U.S. federal debt is larger now than at any time since the end of World War II. Under current policies, the debt is expected to climb from around 75% of the Gross Domestic Product today to over 140% by 2046 and keep growing after that. Debt is rising in part because of a major demographic shift as the baby boom generation retires. It is projected to occur even though interest rates on Treasury borrowing likely will be persistently lower than historic norms.</p>
            <p>We analyze how these and other developments should affect the optimal debt path going forward and conclude that tax increases or spending cuts will be essential eventually because federal debt relative to GDP cannot increase indefinitely. We argue that restraining the debt is necessary to give the government room to maneuver if a crisis of any sort occurs. In addition, we observe that the aging of the U.S. population, which lowers the fraction of the population that is working, means that the country should save more now than otherwise, which can be achieved by reducing federal debt.</p>
            <p>How much and how quickly should the federal government tighten its belt? We note that, while debt should eventually decrease relative to GDP, the fact that U.S. government borrowing rates are at historical lows and likely to stay low for some time implies spending cuts and tax increases should be delayed and smaller in size than widely believed. Low long-term interest rates mean that the U.S. should borrow to make additional public investments. They also reduce the payoff from near-term debt reduction.</p>
            <p>After considering other factors—including the role that fiscal policy can play during economic downturns when short-term interest rates are already so low that the Federal Reserve has little room to cut them—we argue for measured, gradual debt reduction with a higher debt-to-GDP ratio than has historically been the case.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Abel, Andrew B., N. Gregory Mankiw, Lawrence H. Summers, and Richard Zeckhauser. 1989. “Assessing Dynamic Efficiency: Theory and Evidence.” The Review of Economic Studies. 56 (1), 1-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Ball, Laurence M. 2009. “Hysteresis in Unemployment: Old and New Evidence.” National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper No. 14818. March.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Ball, Laurence M., Douglas W. Elmendorf, and N. Gregory Mankiw. 1998. “The Deficit Gamble.” Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking. 30 (4), 699-720.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Banerjee, Ryan, Jonathan Kearns, and Marco Lombardi. 2015. “(Why) Is Investment Weak?” BIS Quarterly Review, March.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Becker, Bo and Victoria Ivashina. 2015. “Reaching for Yield in the Bond Market.” The Journal of Finance. Volume 70, Issue 5. October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Bernanke, Ben. 2005. “The Global Saving Glut and the U.S. Current Account Deficit.” Federal Reserve Board.March 10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Bernanke, Ben. 2015a. “Why Are Interest Rates So Low.” March.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Bernanke, Ben. 2015b. “Why Are Interest Rates So Low, Part 2: Secular Stagnation.” March.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Bernanke, Ben. 2015c. “Why Are Interest Rates So Low, Part 3: The Global Savings Glut.” April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Bernanke, Ben. 2015d. “Why Are Interest Rates So Low, Part 4: Term Premiums.” April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Blanchard, Olivier, Eugenio Cerutti, and Lawrence Summers. 2015. “Inflation and Activity—Two Explorations and their Monetary Policy Implications.” National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper No. 21726. November.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Caballero, Ricardo J., Emmanuel Farhi, and Pierre-Olivier Gourinchas. 2008. “An Equilibrium Model of ‘Global Imbalances’ and Low Interest Rates.” American Economic Review, 98(1): 358-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Caballero, Ricardo J., Emmanuel Farhi, and Pierre-Olivier Gourinchas. 2015. “Global Imbalances and Currency Wars at the ZLB.” National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper No. 21670. October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Centre for Economic Policy Research. 2015. Conference on “Removing the Zero Lower Bound on Interest Rates,”May 18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Congressional Budget Office. 2010. Federal Debt and Interest Costs. December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Congressional Budget Office. 2013. The Budget and Economic Outlook: Fiscal Years 2013 to 2023, February.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Congressional Budget Office. 2014a. The 2014 Long-Term Budget Outlook. July.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Congressional Budget Office. 2014b. How CBO Analyzes the Effect of Changes in Federal Fiscal Policies on the Economy. November.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Congressional Budget Office. 2015a. The 2015 Long-Term Budget Outlook. June.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Congressional Budget Office. 2015b. “CBO’s Assessment of the Long-Term Outlook for Interest Rates.” October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Congressional Budget Office. 2016a. The Budget and Economic Outlook, 2016 to 2026. January 25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Congressional Budget Office. 2016b. The 2015 Long-Term Budget Outlook. July.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Congressional Budget Office. 2016c. An Update to the Budget and Economic Outlook: 2016 to 2026. August.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Council of Economic Advisers. 2015. “Long-Term Interest Rates: A Survey.” July.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Cummins, Jason, Kevin A. Hassett, and N. Glenn Hubbard, 1994. “A reconsideration of investment behavior using tax reforms as natural experiments.” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Cutler, David M., James M. Poterba, Louise M. Sheiner, and Lawrence H. Summers. 1990. “An Aging Society: Opportunity or Challenge?” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity. 1-73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Davis, Morris A. and Jonathan Heathcote, 2007, “The Price and Quantity of Residential Land in the United States,”Journal of Monetary Economics, vol. 54 (8), p. 2595-2620; data located at Land and Property Values in the U.S., Lincoln Institute of Land Policy http://www.lincolninst.edu/resources/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">DeLong, J. Bradford and Lawrence H. Summers. 2012. “Fiscal Policy in a Depressed Economy.” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity. 233-297.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Draghi, Mario. 2015. “Interview with Il Sole 24 Ore.” October 31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Dudley, William C. 2012. “The Recovery and Monetary Policy,” October 16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Dynan, Karen, Jonathan Skinner, and Stephen Zeldes. 2004. “Do the Rich Save More?” Journal of Political Economy. 112 (2): 397-444.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Elmendorf, Douglas W. and Louise M. Sheiner. 2000. “Should America Save for its Old Age? Fiscal Policy, Population Aging, and National Saving.” Journal of Economic Perspectives. 14 (3): 57-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Fatas, Antonio and Lawrence H. Summers. 2015. “The Permanent Effects of Fiscal Consolidations.” Centre for Economic Policy Research Discussion Paper No. 10902. October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Federal Reserve Board. 2015a. “Minutes of the Federal Open Market Committee, October 27-28.”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Federal Reserve Board. 2016. “Economic Projections of Fed Board Members and Federal Reserve Bank Presidents.” September.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Federal Reserve Board. “Flow of Funds Accounts.” Z.1 Statistical Release. http://www.federalreserve.gov/releases/z1/current/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Feldstein, Martin. 2015. “The Future of Fiscal Policy.” Presentation at IMF Conference. April 15.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Furman, Jason. 2015. “Smart Social Programs.” New York Times Op-Ed. May. http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/11/opinion/smart-social-programs.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Furman, Jason. 2015. “Business Investment in the United States: Facts, Explanations, Puzzles, and Policies.”September.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Furman, Jason and Peter Orszag. 2015. “A Firm-Level Perspective on the Role of Rents in the Rise in Inequality.”October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Gilchrist, Simon, and Egon Zakrajsek. 2007. “Investment and the Cost of Capital: New Evidence from the Corporate Bond Market,” NBER Working Paper No. 13174, June.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Hamilton, James D., Ethan S. Harris, Jan Hatzius, and Kenneth D. West. 2015. “The Equilibrium Real Funds Rate: Past, Present, and Future.” Hutchins Center on Fiscal &amp; Monetary Policy at Brookings. October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Heller, Peter. 2005. “Fiscal Space—What It Is and How to Get It.” Finance and Development. June.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">International Monetary Fund. 2014. “Perspectives on Global Interest Rates.” In World Economic Outlook, April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Jagannathan, Ravi, David A. Matsa, Iwan Meier, and Vefa Tarhan, 2015. “Why Do Firms Use High Discount Rates?” http://ssrn.com/abstract=2412250</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Kothari, S.P., Jonathan Lewellen, and Jerold B. Warner. 2014. “The Behavior of Aggregate Corporate Investment,”Bradley Policy Research Center Financial Research and Policy Working Paper no FR 14-19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Krugman, Paul. 2015. “Liquidity Traps: Local and Global.” April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Krugman, Paul, 2014. “Currency Regimes, Capital Flows, and Crises.” IMF Economic Review, 62 (4). International Monetary Fund.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Laubach, Thomas and John C. Williams. 2003. “Measuring the Natural Rate of Interest.” Review of Economics and Statistics 85 (4): 1063-1070.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Laubach, Thomas and John C. Williams. 2015. “Measuring the Natural Rate of Interest Redux.” Hutchins Center on Fiscal &amp; Monetary Policy at Brookings. October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Lee, Ronald, and Andrew Mason, lead authors and editors. 2011. Population Aging and the Generational Economy: A Global Perspective. Cheltenham, UK and Northampton, MA: Edward Elgar. National Transfer Accounts, www.ntaccounts.org</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Mericle, David and Daan Struyven. 2016. “Capital-Light Technologies and the Long-Term Capex Outlook.”Goldman Sachs US Daily Report.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Office of Management and Budget. 2015. Analytical Perspectives, Budget of the United Sates Government, Fiscal Year 2016. February.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Ostry, Jonathan D., Atish R. Ghosh, and Raphael Espinosa. 2015. “When Should Public Debt Be Reduced?”IMF Staff Discussion Note. June.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">National Research Council. (2012). Aging and the Macroeconomy: Long-Term Implications of an Older Population.Washington, DC: The National Academies Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Pinto, Eugenio and Tevlin, Stacey. 2014. “Perspectives on the Recent Weakness in Investment.” Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. Feds Notes. May 21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Posen, Adam S. 2015. “Discussion of ‘Abenomics: An Update’.” forthcoming Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, September.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Rachel, Lukasz and Thomas D. Smith. 2015. “Secular Drivers of the Global Real Interest Rate.” Bank of England Staff Working Paper No. 571. December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Sharpe, Steve A. and Gustavo A. Suarez. 2014. “The insensitivity of investment to interest rates: Evidence from a survey of CBOs, Federal Reserve Board of Governors, FEDS Working Paper 2014-02.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Sheiner, Louise. 2014. “The Determinants of the Macroeconomic Implications of Aging.” American Economic Review. 104(5): 218-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Stein, Jeremy C. 2013. “Overheating in Credit Markets: Origins, Measurement, and Policy Responses,” Speech.February 7. http://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/speech/stein20130207a.htm</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <mixed-citation id="c62">Summers, Lawrence H. 2013. “The battle over the US budget is the wrong fight.” October 13. http://larrysummers.com/the-battle-over-the-us-budget-is-the-wrong-fight/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Summers, Lawrence H. 2013. “Remarks at International Monetary Fund Economic Forum: Policy Responses to Crises.” November.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Summers, Lawrence H. 2014. “U.S. Economic Prospects: Secular Stagnation, Hysteresis, and the Zero Lower Bound.” Business Economics. 49 (2): 65-73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r65">
            <mixed-citation id="c65">Summers, Lawrence H. 2015a. “On Secular Stagnation: Larry Summers Responds to Ben Bernanke.” April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r66">
            <mixed-citation id="c66">Summers, Lawrence H. 2015b. “Rethinking Secular Stagnation After Seventeen Months.” April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r67">
            <mixed-citation id="c67">Summers, Lawrence H. 2016. “A postscript to Delong and Krugman.” January 2. http://larrysummers.com/2016/01/02/a-postscript-to-delong-and-krugman/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r68">
            <mixed-citation id="c68">Teulings, Coen and Richard Baldwin, editors. 2014. Secular Stagnation: Facts, Causes and Cures. CEPR Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r69">
            <mixed-citation id="c69">Tevlin, Stacey, and Karl Whelan. 2003. “Explaining the investment boom of the 1990s. Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking, 35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r70">
            <mixed-citation id="c70">Thwaites, Gregory. 2015. “Why Are Real Interest Rates So Low? Secular Stagnation and the Relative Price of Investment Goods.” Bank of England Staff Working Paper No. 564. November.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r71">
            <mixed-citation id="c71">U.S. Bureau of Economic Analysis. 2016. “National Income and Product Accounts.” http://www.bea.gov/national/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r72">
            <mixed-citation id="c72">World Bank. 2015. “Health, Nutrition and Population Statistics.” September. http://datatopics.worldbank.org/hnp/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r73">
            <mixed-citation id="c73">Yellen, Janet. 2015. “Inflation Dynamics and Monetary Policy.” Federal Reserve Board. September 24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Federal Debt Held by the Public (Extended Baseline)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Federal Nondefense Investment</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Sustainable Consumption Frontiers</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Sustainable Consumption Frontiers</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>2015 Optimal Consumption Path</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Optimal Consumption Paths for 2000 and 2015</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Closed-Economy Sustainable Consumption Paths</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>US and Non-US Support Ratios</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>US and Non-US Labor Force Growth Rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>World Support Ratios</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 11:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>US Optimal Consumption Paths</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 12:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Aging-Only Projection of Primary Deficits</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 13:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Required Change in GDP Share of Taxes/Spending</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 14:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Debt to GDP</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 15:</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Primary Deficits</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 16:</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Why Aging-Only Deficit is Larger than CBO Baseline</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Difference Between Aging-Only Projection and CBO’s Extended Baseline</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 17:</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Reductions in Primary Deficit Needed in Addition to Those Assumed by CBO</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 18:</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Yield on 3-Month Treasury Bills</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 19:</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Yield on 10-Year Treasury Notes</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 20:</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Real Interest Rate and Growth Rate Differentials</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 21:</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Business Investment as Share of GDP</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 22:</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Gross Capital Income Share of GDP</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 23:</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Average Return to Capital</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 24:</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>BAA to AA and AA to 10-year spreads (5-year MA)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 25:</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Inelastic Investment, Elastic Savings</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 26:</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>AA Corporate Bond Yields</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 27:</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>U.S. Consumption with Aging and Low Foreign Time</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 28:</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>U.S. Consumption with Aging and Low MFP Growth</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 29:</label>
         <caption id="ca-30">
            <p>Inelastic Investment, Elastic Savings</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-31">
            <p>Implications for Fed. Budget Policy of Persistently Lower Treasury Int. Rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
