<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308356</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A 1d Model for the Prediction of Flash Atomization in Gdi Multi-Hole Injectors</article-title>
            <subtitle>Preliminary Results</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bianchi</surname>
                  <given-names>G. M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Forte</surname>
                  <given-names>C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Negro</surname>
                  <given-names>S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pelloni</surname>
                  <given-names>P.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>1278</fpage>
         <lpage>1293</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308356"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A flash evaporation model is being developed to capture the effects of bubble nucleation and growth inside multi-hole injector nozzles to investigate the flash evaporation in fuel injector sprays in Gasoline Direct Injection (GDI). The 1D flash evaporation model is a key tool for providing the 3D Eulerian-Eulerian or Lagrangian spray simulation model with the right droplet size in order to properly predict the effect of degree of superheating on mixture formation. Super heating conditions are likely to be found under partial load conditions in GDI applications or they might be deliberately induced to enhance fuel atomization and vaporization. A quasi-1D nozzle flow model has been developed to help quantifying the effects of main physical and geometrical parameters in promoting fuel flash evaporation. This model is based on an weakly compressible homogenous two-phase mixture assumption. A non-equilibrium model is used to predict the vapour formation rate along the nozzle. A fully explicit method based on a two-step Lax-Wendroff method is used together with a TVD scheme. An atomization model has been proposed to correlate the void fraction at nozzle exit to the most probable radius of the droplet generated from flashing atomization. An accurate two phase speed of sound is adopted allowing to predict the choked flow conditions once saturation has been reached. Metastable states are not considered in this first approach. A preliminary validation has been carried out based on an experimental nozzle flow configuration at two different values of superheating degree. A preliminary assessment of the model capability in capturing the effect of fuel conditions on droplet most probable diameter is presented.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gopalakrishnan S. and Schmidt, D.P. ”A omputational Study of Flashing Flow in Fuel Injector ozzles” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):160-170, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Rossmeissl, K. E. Wirth, Critical Mass-Flow in rifice-nozzles at the Disintegration of Superheated iquids – SPRAY ’06 Workshop Workshop über prays, Erfassung von Sprühvor- gängen und echniken der Fluidzerstäubungy, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. Downar-Zapolski, Z. Bilicki. The Non-Equilibrium elaxation Model for One-Dimensional Flashing Liquid low, Int. J. Multiphase Flow, vol. 3, 22, pp. 473-483 , 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A.E. Catania, A. Ferrari, M. Manno, E. Spessa. “Comprehensive Thermodynamic Approach to coustic Cavitation Simulation in High-Pressure njection Systems by a Conservative Homogeneous wo-Phase Barotropic Flow Model” - ASME Journal of. ngineering for Gas Turbines and Power, Vol 128, N. 2, pp. 434-445, April 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. Wallis. “One Dimensional Two-Phase Flow” - cGraw Hill, 1975</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. Reynier, P. Wesseling, L. Marraffa, D. Giordano. “Numerical Investigation on Liquid Hydrazine ehaviour During Venting Into Space” - European ongress on Computational Methods in Applied ciences and Engineering, ECCOMAS 2000, pp. 1-20 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C. von Kuensberg Sarre, S.C. Kong, R.D. Reitz. “Modeling the Effects of Injector Nozzle Geometry on iesel Sprays” - SAE paper 1999-01-0912, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Annual Report 2005 CERC – Chalmers University 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D.E. Winterbone, R.J. Pearson. “Design echniques for Engine Manifolds: Wave Action ethods for IC Engine”, Wiley, 1999</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. Kawano, H Ishii, H. Suzuki, Y. Goto, M. Odaka, . Senda. “Numerical Study on Flash-Boiling Spray of ulticomponent Fuel”, Wiley Periodicals (2006)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Senda, Y. Hojyo and H. Fujimoto, “Modelling of tomization Process in Flash Boiling Spray”, SAE aper 941925, 1994</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Adachi, V. G. McDonell, D. Tanaka, J. Senda nd H. Fujimoto, “Characterization of Fuel Vapor oncentration Inside a Flash Boiling Spray”, SAE aper 970871 (1997)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Kato, H. Kayano, and Y. Kageyama, “A onsideration of Thermal Effects on Cavitation Bubble rowth”, Cavitation multiphase flow, vol. 194 of FED, SME (1994)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leipertz, et al. “. “Flash-Boiling Effects on the evelopment of Gasoline Direct-Injection Engine prays, SAE paper 2002-01-2661, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>[15]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oza, R. D., and Sinnamon, J. F., “An Experimental nd Analytical study of Flash boiling Fuel Injection”, AE Paper 830590, 1983</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>[16]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aquino, C., Plensdorf, W.. Lavoie, G., and Curtis, ., “The Occurrence of Flash Boiling in a Port Injected asoline Engine," SAE Paper 982522, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>[17]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, Y. K., Twai, N.. Suto, H.. and Tsuruga, T.. "Improvement of Alcohol Engine Performance by lashing Injection." JSAE Review, pp. 81-86., 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>[18]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vanderwege, E., and Hochgreb, S., “The Effect of uel Volatility on Sprays from High-pressure Swirl njectors", 26th Symposium (International) on ombustion, pp. 1865-1871., 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>[19]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Simoes-Moreira, J. R., and Shepherd, J.E., “Evaporation waves in superheated dodecane”, J. luid Mech. , vol. 382, pp. 63-86. 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>[20]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vieira, M. M., and Simoes-Moreira, J. R., “Lowpressure lashing mechanisms in iso-octane liquid ets”, J. Fluid Mech. vol. 572, pp. 121–144. 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>[21]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yildiz, D., et al. “A study on the dynamic of a lashing jet”, Final Contract Research Report AR0030/2002 – von Karman Institute for Fluid ynamics, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>[22]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang D., and Lee, C., “Preliminary omputational Studies of Flash Boiling for Fuel njectors in Gasoline Direct Injection Automotive ngines”, IECEC 2002 Paper No. 20164, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>[23]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zuo. B., Gomes, A. M., and Rutland, C. J.. "Modeling Superheated Fuel Sprays and aporization," Int. J. of Engine Research, Vol. 1, No. 4, p. 321-336, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>[24]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Le Metayer, O., Massoni, J. Saurel, R.”Modelling vaporation fronts with reactive Riemann solvers,” ournal of Computational Physics 205 567–610, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>[25]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bianchi, G.M., Minelli, F., Zaleski, S., Scardovelli, ., ” 3D Large Scale Simulation of the High Speed iquid Jet Atomization”, SAE TRANSACTIONS - ournal of Passenger Cars-Mechanical Systems. 116-2007, ISBN978-0-7680-1987-2, aprile 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>[26]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Villiers, E. D., Gosman, D. A., and Weller, H. G., 2004. “Large Eddy Simulation of Primary Diesel Spray tomization”. SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0100 , 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>[27]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeng, Y. E., and Lee, C. F, “An atomization model or flash boiling sprays”, Combust. Sci. andTech.. 169:45-67,2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>[28]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barret, M., Fucher, E., and Herard, J-M-, “Schemes to Compute Unsteady Flashing Flows”, IAA JOURNAL Vol. 40, No. 5, May 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>[29]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huh, K.Y. and Gosman, A.D.,”A henomenological Model of Diesel Spray tomization”, Proceedings of The International onference on Multiuphase Flows, September 24-27, sukuba, Japan, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>[30]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. F. Davis, “A Simplified TVD Finite Difference cheme via Artificial Viscosity”, SIAM J. Sci. Stat. omput., 8, 1-18, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>[31]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Brown and J. L. York, “Spray Formed by lashing Liquids Jets”, A. I. Ch. E. J., Vol.8, n. 2, p.149-153, 1962.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>[32]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lienhard, J.H., &amp; Day, J.B., “The Breakup of uperheated Liquid jets”, Trans. ASME, J. of Basic ng., Vol.92, N.3, pp. 515-522, 1970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>[33]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H., and Ge, W.,”A theoretical bubble reakup model for slurry beds or three-phase fluidised eds under high pressure”, Chemical Engineering cience 62 pp. 109 – 115, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>[34]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kolmogorov, A.N., 1949. On the breakage of rops in a turbulent flow. Doklady Akademii Nauk SSR 66, 825–828</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>[35]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sallam, K. A., and Faeth, G. M., “Surface roperties During Primary Breakup of TurbulentLiquid ets in Still Air”. AIAA Journal, 41 (8) August , pp. 1514–1524, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
