<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278089</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development and Validation of a New Zero-Dimensional Semi-Physical NOx Emission Model for a D.I. Diesel Engine Using Simulated Combustion Process</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Karaky</surname>
                  <given-names>Hassan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Renault</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mauviot</surname>
                  <given-names>Gilles</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Renault</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tauzia</surname>
                  <given-names>Xavier</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ecole Centrale De Nantes</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Maiboom</surname>
                  <given-names>Alain</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ecole Centrale De Nantes</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>September 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278043</issue-id>
         <fpage>1924</fpage>
         <lpage>1937</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278089"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Reducing NOₓ tailpipe emissions is one of the major challenges when developing automotive Diesel engines which must simultaneously face stricter emission norms and reduce their fuel consumption/CO2 emission. In fact, the engine control system has to manage at the same time the multiple advanced combustion technologies such as high EGR rates, new injection strategies, complex after-treatment devices and sophisticated turbocharging systems implemented in recent diesel engines. In order to limit both the cost and duration of engine control system development, a virtual engine simulator has been developed in the last few years. The platform of this simulator is based on a 0D/1D approach, chosen for its low computational time. The existing simulation tools lead to satisfactory results concerning the combustion phase as well as the air supply system. In this context, the current paper describes the development of a new<italic>NOₓ</italic>emission model which is coupled with the combustion model.</p>
            <p>The proposed zero-dimensional, semi-physical, NOₓ prediction model is based mainly on a high frequency combustion model (Barba's approach) coupled with a thermodynamic calculation of the temperature (adiabatic flame temperature) in the burned gas products from a stoichiometric mixture. Furthermore, a new empirical correlation is created to relate the corresponding physical components such as the highest local temperature and the available oxygen concentration, describing a uniform progression of NOₓ emissions. The model was built and validated over a large range of operating points on a 1.6 liter Euro 5 diesel engine. The simulation results show that the model can predict the multiple effects of exhaust gas recirculation and of the various injection parameters for both single and multiinjection cases.</p>
            <p>The model provides the required trade-off between predictability (pure physical models) and simplicity (empirical models) which are mostly incompatible. A major advantage of the final NOₓ model is that it does not require any calibration process once the combustion model is identified.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals,” McGraw- Hill Book Company, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fenimore, C. P., “Formation of Nitric Oxide in Premixed Hydrocarbon Flames,” chez in Thirteen Symposium (International) on Combustion, 1971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lavoie, G. A., Heywood, J. B., and Keck, J. C., “Experimental and Theoretical Study of Nitric Oxide Formation in Internal Combustion Engines,” Combustion Science and Technology, vol. 1, pp. 313-326, 1970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, R., Davis, G., Lavoie, G., Newman, C. et al., “A Super-Extended Zel'dovich Mechanism for Nox Modeling and Engine Calibration,” SAE Technical Paper 980781, 1998, doi:10.4271/980781.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Valério, M., Raggi, K., and Sodré, J., “Improvement of a Model for Calculation of Oxides of Nitrogen Emissions from Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-3001, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004- 01-3001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, J., Lee, S., Park, W., Min, K. et al., “The Development of Real-time NOx Estimation Model and its Application,” SAE Technical Paper 2013- 01-0243, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0243.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kouremenos, D., Rakopoulos, C., and Hountalas, D., “Multi-Zone Combustion Modelling for the Prediction of Pollutants Emissions and Performance of DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 970635, 1997, doi:10.4271/970635.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakoupoulos, C. D., Rakoupoulous, D. C., Giakoumis, E. G., and Kyristis, D. C., “Validation and sensitivity of a two zone Diesel engine model for combustion and emissions prediction,” Energy Conversion and management, vol. 45, pp. 1471-1495, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scappin, F., Stefansson, S. H., Haglind, F., Andreasen, A., et al., “Validation of a zero-dimensional model for prediction of NOx and engine performance for electronically controlled marine two-stroke diesel engines,” Applied Thermal Engineering, vol. 37, pp. 344-352, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pariotis, E., Hountalas, D., and Rakopoulos, C., “Sensitivity Analysis of Multi-Zone Modeling for Combustion and Emissions Formation in Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1383, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1383.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Müller, E. and Zillmer, M., “Modeling of Nitric Oxide and Soot Formation in Diesel Engine Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 982457, 1998, doi:10.4271/982457.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lafossas, F., Marbaix, M., and Menegazzi, P., “Development and Application of a 0D D.I. Diesel combustion model for Emissions Prediction,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1841, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1841.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bordet, N., and Talon, V., “Estimation par modèle 0D de la concentration des polluants Euro V: NOx, CO, HC, Particules,” Renault SAS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arrègle, J., López, J., Martín, J., and Mocholí, E., “Development of a Mixing and Combustion Zero-Dimensional Model for Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1382, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1382.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lebas, R., Fremovici, M., Font, G., and Le Berr, F., “A Phenomenological Combustion Model Including In-Cylinder Pollutants To Support Engine Control Optimisation Under Transient Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1837, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1837.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walke, N., Marathe, N., and Nandgaonkar, M., “Simplified Combustion Pressure and NOx Prediction Model for DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-26-0131, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-26-0131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gong, J. and Rutland, C., “A Quasi-Dimensional NOx Emission Model for Spark Ignition Direct Injection (SIDI) Gasoline Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1311, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1311.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ericson, C., Westerberg, B., Andersson, M., and Egnell, R., “Modelling Diesel Engine Combustion and NOx Formation for Model Based Control and Simulation of Engine and Exhaust Aftertreatment Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0687, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0687.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersson, M., Johansson, B., Hultqvist, A., and Nöhre, C., “A Real Time NOx Model for Conventional and Partially Premixed Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0195, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0195.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hegarty, K., Favrot, R., Rollett, D., and Rindone, G., “Semi-Empiric Model Based Approach for Dynamic Prediction of NOx Engine Out Emissions on Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0155, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oppenauer, K. and Re, L., “Hybrid 2-Zone Diesel Combustion Model for NO Formation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):584-596, 2010, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Querel, C., “Modélisation des émissions de NOx pour le contrôle des moteurs diesel,” Rouen: Université de Rouen, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Quérel, C., Grondin, O., and Letellier, C., “A Semi-Physical NOx Model for Diesel Engine Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0356, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heider, G., Rechenmodel zur Vorausberechnung der {NO}- Emission von Dieselmotoren, TU München, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Finesso, R., and Spessa, E., “A real time zero-dimensional diagnostic model for the calculation of in-cylinder temperatures, HRR and nitrogen oxides in diesel engines,” Energy Conversion and Management, vol. 79, pp. 498-510, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Savva, N. and Hountalas, D., “Detailed Evaluation of a New Semi- Empirical Multi-Zone NOx Model by Application on Various Diesel Engine Configurations,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1156, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1156.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guardiola, C., Lopez, J. J., and Garcia-Sarmiento, D., “Semi empirical in-cylinder pressure based model for NOx prediction oriented to control applications,” Applied Thermal Engineering, vol. 31, pp. 3275-3286, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Y., He, Y., and Rajagopalan, S., “Design of Engine- Out Virtual NOx Sensor Using Neural Networks and Dynamic System Identification,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):837-849, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0694.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saravanan, S., Nagarajan, G., Anand, S., and Sampath, S., “Correlation for thermal NOx formation in compression ignition (CI) engine fuelled with diesel and biodiesel,” Energy, vol. 42, pp. 401-410, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, N., Nagabushan-Venkatesh, P., Nigro, E., and Lack, A., “Development of the NOx Emission Model for the Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Application Using Combustion Characteristic Parameters,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0532, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0532.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jaine, T., “Simulation zéro dimensionnelle de la combustion dans un moteur Diesel à injection directe,” Université d'Orléans, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barba, C., Burkhardt, C., Boulouchos, K., and Bargende, M., “A Phenomenological Combustion Model for Heat Release Rate Prediction in High-Speed DI Diesel Engines with Common Rail Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2933, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-2933.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chmela, F. and Orthaber, G., “Rate of Heat Release Prediction for Direct Injection Diesel Engines Based on Purely Mixing Controlled Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0186, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Asay, R., Svensson, K., and Tree, D., “An Empirical, Mixing-Limited, Zero-Dimensional Model for Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0924, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0924.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mauviot, G., Albrecht, A., and Poinsot, T., “A New 0D Approach for Diesel Combustion Modeling Coupling Probability Density Function with Complex Chemistry,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3332, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3332.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caillol, C., Porterie, B., and Delorme, T., “Modélisation phénoménologique de la combustion dans un moteur à gaz fonctionnant en mélange pauvre: application à la prédiction des émissions polluantes,” chez 12 èmes journées Internationales de Thermique, 2005. Laurent, A., “Modeling of NOx engine out emissions,” Renault SAS, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laurent, A., “Modeling of NOx engine out emissions,” Renault SAS, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bordet, N., Caillol, C., Higelin, P., and Talon, V., “A Physical 0D Combustion Model Using Tabulated Chemistry with Presumed Probability Density Function Approach for Multi-Injection Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1493, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010- 01-1493.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lebas, R., Mauviot, G., Le Berr, F., and Albrecht, A., “A Phenomenological Approach to Model Diesel Engine Combustion and In-Cylinder Pollutant Emissions Adapted to Control Strategy,” chez E-COSM IFAC Congress, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lebas, R., Fremovici, M., Font, G., and Le Berr, F., “A Phenomenological Combustion Model Including In-Cylinder Pollutants To Support Engine Control Optimisation Under Transient Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1837, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1837.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Finesso, R. and Spessa, E., “Real-Time Predictive Modeling of Combustion and NOx Formation in Diesel Engines Under Transient Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0899, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merker, G., Hohlbaum, B., and Rauscher, M., “Two-Zone Model for Calculation of Nitrogen-Oxide Formation in Direct-Injection Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 932454, 1993, doi:10.4271/932454.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, W., Lee, J., Min, K., Yu, J. et al., “Prediction of real-time NO based on the in-cylinder pressure in Diesel engines,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, vol. 34, pp. 3075-3082, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
