<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939390</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Debt, Equity, and International Taxation</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Allowance for Corporate Equity in Europe: Latvia, Italy and Portugal</article-title>
            <subtitle>First draft</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kock</surname>
                  <given-names>Jan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gérard</surname>
                  <given-names>Marcel</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>40</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939390"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Classical corporate taxation typically favours debt finance over equity. The resulting bias leads firms to be over-leveraged. The Allowance for Corporate Equity (ACE) tries to stop such bias by granting a deduction on the cost of equity. The implementation of that principle however differs between countries. In this paper we investigate three recent ACE reforms which occurred in Latvia, Italy and Portugal respectively. Using a broad range of evaluation methods and a large dataset at firm level, we analyse the possible debt-reducing effect of an ACE. From a methodological point of view we innovate by relating the difference-in-differences (DID) method, which captures the effect of the treatment, i.e. the sole existence of an ACE, and the Effective Marginal Tax Rate (EMTR), which measures the impact of the intensity of that treatment. When we do not make a difference between, say, firm sizes, we find a decrease of the financial leverage by 1-2% for both Italy and Portugal, while the leverage increases in Latvia. Also of interest is that, though Italy and Latvia show a larger leverage cut among large firms, small firms are relatively more affected than medium-sized firms in Portugal</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Acemoglu, Daron, David Autor, and David Lyle. 2004. “Women, War, and Wages: The Effect of Female Labor Supply on the Wage Structure at Midcentury.” Journal of Political Economy 112 (3): 497–551.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Almeida, Heitor, and Murillo Campello. 2007. “Financial Constraints, Asset Tangibility, and Corporate Investment.” Review of Financial Studies 20 (5): 1429–1460.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Aus dem Moore, Nils. 2014. Corporate Taxation and Investment: Evidence from the Belgian ACEReform. Ruhr Economic Papers 534. RWI - Leibniz-Institut für Wirtschaftsforschung, RuhrUniversity Bochum, TU Dortmund University, University of Duisburg-Essen.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Blouin, Jennifer, Harry Huizinga, Luc Laeven, and Gaëtan Nicodème. 2014. Thin Capitalization Rules and Multinational Firm Capital Structure. Taxation Papers 42. Directorate General Taxation and Customs Union, European Commission, January.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Boadway, Robin, and Neil Bruce. 1984. “A general proposition on the design of a neutral business tax.” Journal of Public Economics 24 (2): 231–239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Bond, Stephen R., and Michael Devereux. 2003. “Generalised R-based and S-based taxes under uncertainty.” Journal of Public Economics 87 (5-6): 1291–1311.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Bontempi, Maria Elena, Silvia Giannini, and Roberto Golinelli. 2004. “Corporate taxation and its reform: the effects on corporate financing decisions in Italy.” March.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Bordignon, Massimo, Silvia Giannini, and Paolo Panteghini. 1999. “Corporate Tax in Italy: An Analysis of the 1998 Reform.” FinanzArchiv: Public Finance Analysis 56 (3/4).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Buettner, Thiess, Michael Overesch, Ulrich Schreiber, and Georg Wamser. 2012. “The impact of thin-capitalization rules on the capital structure of multinational firms.” Fiscal Federalism, Journal of Public Economics 96 (11): 930–938. issn: 0047-2727.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">de Mooij, Ruud A. 2012. “Tax Biases to Debt Finance: Assessing the Problem, Finding Solutions*.”Fiscal Studies 33 (4): 489–512. issn: 1475-5890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">de Mooij, Ruud, and Shafik Hebous. 2017. Curbing Corporate Debt Bias: Do Limitations to Interest Deductibility Work? CESifo Working Paper Series 6312. CESifo Group Munich.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Devereux, Michael, and Aart Gerritsen. 2010. “The tax treatment of debt and equity.” In Towards a European Profits Tax, edited by D. Albregtse and P. Kavelaars. Kluwer.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Devereux, Michael, and Rachel Griffith. 1998. The taxation of discrete investment choices. IFSWorking Papers 98/16. Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Devereux, Michael, and Rachel Griffith 2003. “Evaluating Tax Policy for Location Decisions.” International Tax and Public Finance 10, no. 2 (March): 107–126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Devereux, Michael, and Peter Sørensen. 2006. The Corporate Income Tax: international trends and options for fundamental reform. European Economy - Economic Papers 2008 - 2015 264.Directorate General Economic and Financial Affairs (DG ECFIN), European Commission, December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Economic and Development Review Committee (EDRC). 2017. Economic Survey of Portugal.Technical report. OECD.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Fatica, Serena, Thomas Hemmelgarn, and Gaëtan Nicodème. 2012. The Debt-Equity Bias: consequences and solutions. Taxation Papers 33. Directorate General Taxation and Customs Union, European Commission.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Frühwirth, Manfred, and Marek Kobialka. 2011. Do equity tax shields reduce leverage? The Austrian Case. Technical report. July.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Gérard, Marcel, and Bastien Mahoux. 2017. On the effectivity of tax incentives: Patent Box Regimes and Allowance for Corporate Equity. Technical report. Working Paper, Université Catholique de Louvain.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Gordon, Roger, and Young Lee. 2001. “Do taxes affect corporate debt policy? Evidence from U.S. corporate tax return data.” Journal of Public Economics 82 (2): 195–224.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Graham, John R. 2000. “How Big Are the Tax Benefits of Debt?” The Journal of Finance 55 (5): 1901–1941. issn: 1540-6261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Harris, Milton, and Artur Raviv. 1991. “The Theory of Capital Structure.” The Journal of Finance 46 (1): 297–355. issn: 1540-6261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Hebous, Shafik, and Martin Ruf. 2015. Evaluating the Effects of ACE Systems on Multinational Debt Financing and Investment. CESifo Working Paper Series 5360. CESifo Group Munich.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">International Monetary Fund. 2009. IMF Country Report No. 09/3. Technical report. January.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Kalemli-Özcan, Sebnem, Bent Sorensen, Carolina Villegas-Sanchez, Vadym Volosovych, and Sevcan Yesiltas. 2015. How to Construct Nationally Representative Firm Level data from the ORBIS Global Database. NBER Working Papers 21558. National Bureau of Economic Research, Inc, September.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Keen, Michael, and John King. 2003. “The Croatian Profit Tax: An ACE in Practice.” In Integriertes Steuer- und Sozialsystem, edited by Manfred Rose, 323–342. Heidelberg: Physica-Verlag HD. isbn: 978-3-642-57376-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Kestens, Katrien, Philippe Van Cauwenberge, and Johan Christiaens. 2012. “An Investigation of the Effect of the Notional Interest Deduction on the Capital Structure of Belgian SMEs.”Working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">King, Mervin A. 1974. “Taxation and the Cost of Capital.” Review of Economic Studies 41 (1): 21–35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">King, Mervin A.. 1977. Public policy and the corporation. Cambridge studies in applied econometrics. Chapman/Hall.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">King, Mervyn A., and Don Fullerton. 1984. The Taxation of Income from Capital. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Klemm, Alexander. 2007. “Allowances for Corporate Equity in Practice.” CESifo Economic Studies 53, no. 2 (June): 229–262.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Konings, J., C. Lecocq, B. Merlevede, and R. Vandendriessche. 2016. The Role of an Allowance for Corporate Equity for the Capital Structure and Employment in Multinational Enterprises - An evaluation of the Notional Interest Deduction in Belgium. Technical report. Vives Policy Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Langedijk, Sven, Gaëtan Nicodème, Andrea Pagano, and Alessandro Rossi. 2014. Debt Bias in Corporate Taxation and the Costs of Banking Crises in the EU. Taxation Papers 50. Directorate General Taxation and Customs Union, European Commission, October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Laureano, Luis, and Márcio Telles Portal. 2016. “Does Brazilian allowance for corporate equity reduce the debt bias? Evidences of rebound effect and ownership-induced ACE clientele.”Research in International Business and Finance.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Leary, Mark T., and Michael R. Roberts. 2005. “Do Firms Rebalance Their Capital Structures?”The Journal of Finance 60 (6): 2575–2619. issn: 1540-6261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Massimi, Francesco, and Carlo Petroni. 2012. “Real-World ACE reforms and the Italian Experience.Towards a General Trend?” Intertax 11:632–642.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Modigliani, Franco, and Merton H. Miller. 1958. “The Cost of Capital, Corporation Finance and the Theory of Investment.” The American Economic Review 48 (3): 261–297. issn: 00028282.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Myers, Stewart C., and Nicholas S. Majluf. 1984. “Corporate financing and investment decisions when firms have information that investors do not have.” Journal of Financial Economics 1(2): 187–221. issn: 0304-405X.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Oestreicher, A., R. Koch, D. Vorndamme, and S. Hohls. 2014. ASSERT - Assessing the effects of reforms in taxation - a micro-simulation approach. S. FAT Working Paper, no. 14-001.Göttingen University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Panier, Frédéric, Francisco Pérez-González, and Pablo Villanueva. 2013. Capital Structure and Taxes: What Happens When You (Also) Subsidize Equity?</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Panteghini, P. M., M. L. Parisi, and F. Pighetti. 2012. Italy’s ACE tax and its effect on a firm’s leverage. Technical report. CESifo WP Series 3869.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Princen, Savina. 2012. Taxes do Affect Corporate Financing Decisions: The Case of Belgian ACE.CESifo Working Paper Series. CESifo Group Munich.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Rubin, Donald. 1979. “Using Multivariate Matched Sampling and regression Adjustment to Control Bias in Observational Studies.” Journal of the American Statistical Association 75 (366): 318–329.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Santoro, Alessandro. 2005. “The Italian Partial ACE: An Ex-post Evaluation.” University of Milano-Biocca.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Sørensen, Peter Birch. 2014. Taxation and the optimal constraint on corporate debt finance. Working Papers 1427. Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Sørensen, Peter Birch. 2015. Taxation and the optimal constraint on corporate debt finance. Working Papers 1427.CES-ifo Area Conference on Public Sector Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Spengel, Christoph, Dieter Endres, Katharina Finke, and Jost Heckemeyer. 2014. Effective tax levels using the DEVEREUX/GRIFFITH methodology: Project for the EU Commission TAXUD/2013/CC/120.ZEW - Zentrum für Europäische Wirtschaftsforschung/Center for European Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Spengel, Christoph, Frank Schmidt, Jost H. Heckemeyer, Katharina Nicolay, Alexandra Bartholmeß, Rainer Bräutigam, Julia Braun, et al. 2016. Effective tax levels using the Devereux/Griffith methodology. Project for the EU Commission TAXUD/2013/CC/120: Final report. ZEW -Zentrum für Europäische Wirtschaftsforschung/Center for European Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Staderini, Alessandra. 2001. Tax reform to influence Corporate Financial Policy: the Case of the Italian Business Tax Reform of 1997-97. Technical report 423:1-30. Banca d’Italia Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Stiglitz, Joseph. 1973. “Taxation, corporate financial policy, and the cost of capital.” Journal of Public Economics 2 (1): 1–34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Strebulaev, Ilya A. 2007. “Do Tests of Capital Structure Theory Mean What They Say?” The Journal of Finance 62 (4): 1747–1787. issn: 1540-6261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">van Campenhout, Geert, and Tom van Caneghem. 2013. “How did the notional interest deduction affect Belgian SMEs’ capital structure?” Small Business Economics 40 (2): 351–373.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Vandenberghe, Vincent. 2017. Treatment-effect identification without parallel paths: An illustration in the case of Objective 1-Hainaut/Belgium, 1994-2006. Economics Discussion Papers 2017-23.Kiel Institute for the World Economy (IfW).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Zangari, Ernesto. 2014. Addressing the Debt Bias: A Comparison between the Belgian and the Italian ACE Systems. Taxation Papers 44. Directorate General Taxation and Customs Union, European Commission.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Effect of different ACE versions on firm leverage</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Examinations of ACE schemes</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Trend in Book Leverage for Latvia, Lithuania and Estonia</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Trend in Book Leverage for Italy and France</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Trend in Book Leverage for Portugal and Spain</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - DID - Latvia</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Heterogeneous Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - DID - Latvia</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - DID Intensity - Latvia</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Heterogeneous Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - DID and Intensity - Latvia</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - Intensity - Latvia</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Heterogeneous Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - Intensity - Latvia</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - DID - Italy</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Heterogeneous Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - DID - Italy</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - DID and Intensity - Italy</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 11:</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Heterogeneous Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - DID and Intensity - Italy</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 12:</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - Intensity - Italy</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 13:</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Heterogeneous Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - Intensity - Italy</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 14:</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - DID - Portugal</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 15:</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Heterogeneous Impact of Taxation on Firm Leverage - DID - Portugal</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
