<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26167753</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Alternative Approaches to Occupant Response Evaluation in Frontal Impact Crash Testing</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Keon</surname>
                  <given-names>Timothy</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>NHTSA</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26167738</issue-id>
         <fpage>202</fpage>
         <lpage>217</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26167753"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration has performed research investigating the Test Device for Human Occupant Restraint 50<sup>th</sup>male (THOR-50M) response in Oblique crash tests. This research is being expanded to investigate THOR-50M in the driver position in a 56 km/h frontal impact crash. Hybrid III 5<sup>th</sup>percentile adult female (AF05) anthropomorphic test devices (ATDs) were used in this testing to evaluate the RibEye Deflection Measurement System. The AF05 ATDs were positioned in the right front passenger and right rear passenger seating positions. For the right front passenger, the New Car Assessment Procedure (NCAP) seating procedure was used, except the seat fore-aft position was set to mid-track. For the right rear passenger, the seating followed the FMVSS No. 214 Side Impact Compliance Test Procedure. The NCAP frontal impact test procedure was followed with additional vehicle instrumentation and pre/post-test measurements. Results from this test series were compared with previous NCAP crash tests. The THOR-50M showed similar kinematics to the Hybrid III 50<sup>th</sup>but predicted a higher risk of chest and femur injury. The mid-track seat position of the right front passenger AF05 led to lower levels of femur compression loading due to additional distance to the dash. BrIC for the driver and front passenger showed higher injury risk than HIC<sub>15</sub>. In all vehicles, the rear seat AF05 predicted a substantially higher risk of head, neck and chest injury than the right front passenger. The AF05 RibEye output showed a higher peak deflection (x-axis) than the chest potentiometer.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parent, D., Craig, M., Ridella, S., McFadden, J., “Thoracic Biofidelity Assessment of the THOR Mod Kit ATD,” 23rd Enhanced Safety of Vehicles Conference, Paper No. 13-0327, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuppa, S., Saunders, J., Fessahaie, O., “Rear Seat Occupant Protection in Frontal Crashes,” The 19th Enhanced Safety of Vehicles Conference, Paper No. 05-0212, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boxboro Systems. Accessed December 31, 2015. http://www.boxborosystems.com/ribeye.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AAAM: The Abbreviated Injury Scale - 1990, Update 1998. Des Plaines, Il. 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AAAM: The Abbreviated Injury Scale - 2005, Update 2008. Des Plaines, Il. 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saunders, J., Parent, D., Ames, Eva. “NHTSA Oblique Crash Test Results: Vehicle Performance and Occupant Injury Risk Assessment in Vehicles with Small Overlap Countermeasures,” 24th ESV conference, Paper No. 15-0108, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Docket No. NHTSA-2006-26555, Consumer Information: New Car Assessment Program, Federal Register Volume 73, Issue 134 (July 11, 2008), pg. 40042.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takhounts, E.G., Hasija, V., Moorhouse, K., McFadden, J., Craig, M., “Development of Brain Injury Criteria (BrIC),” Proceedings of the 57th Stapp Car Crash Conference, Orlando, FL, November 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">THOR Driver Seating Procedure - Draft 7-22-2015. Accessed December 31, 2015. http://www.nhtsa.gov/DOT/NHTSA/NVS/Crashworthiness/Small%20Overlap%20and%20Oblique%20Research/THOR%20Driver%20Seating%20Procedure%20Draft_July%2022%202015.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamasaki, T., Uesaka, K., “Rear Occupant Protection JNCAP Test - Test Results and Findings,“ 22nd ESV conference, Paper No. 11-0445, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CORA. Accessed December 31, 2015. http://www.pdb-org.com/en/information/18-cora-download.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eggers, A., Adolph, T., “Evaluation of the Thoracic Deflection Measurement System ‘RibEye’ in the Hybrid III 50th in Frontal Sled Tests,” 22nd ESV conference, Paper No. 11-0190, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
