<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277539</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Estimation of Surface Heat Flux in IC Engines Using Temperature Measurements</article-title>
            <subtitle>Processing Code Effects</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hendricks</surname>
                  <given-names>Terry</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ghandhi</surname>
                  <given-names>Jaal</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Wisconsin - Madison</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>1268</fpage>
         <lpage>1285</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277539"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Heat transfer in internal combustion engines is taking on greater importance as manufacturers strive to increase efficiency while keeping pollutant emissions low and maintaining adequate performance. Wall heat transfer is experimentally evaluated using temperature measurements both on and below the surface using a physical model of conduction in the wall. Three classes of model inversion are used to recover heat flux from surface temperature measurements: analytical methods, numerical methods and inverse heat conduction methods; the latter method has not been previously applied to engine data. This paper details the inherent assumptions behind, required steps for implementation of, and merits and weaknesses of these heat flux calculation methods. The analytical methods, which have been most commonly employed for engine data, are shown to suffer from sensitivity to measurement noise that requires<italic>a priori</italic>signal filtering. The numerical methods are computationally demanding and do not offer any advantage over the analytical methods unless the wall is a composite structure. The inverse methods are found to be relatively insensitive to noise because of the use of future-time information, the inclusion of a regularization term that relaxes the exact-matching constraint, and the fact that finite derivatives are not required to estimate the heat flux.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bendersky, D. A., A Special Thermocouple for Measuring Transient Temperatures, Mechanical Engineering, vol. 75, No. 2, 117-121, 1953.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MEDTHERM CORP, Coaxial Surface Thermocouple Probes, Bulletin 500, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eichelberg, G., Some New Investigations on Old Combustion-Engine Problems, Engineering, Vol. 148 (1939), 463-466, 547-550.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hohenberg, G., “Advanced Approaches for Heat Transfer Calculations,” SAE Technical Paper 790825, 1979, doi: 10.4271/790825.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Annand, W. J. D. Heat Transfer in the Cylinders of Reciprocating Internal Combustion Engines, Proc. Instn Mech Engrs, vol. 177, no. 36, pp. 973-990, 1963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G., “A Universally Applicable Equation for the Instantaneous Heat Transfer Coefficient in the Internal Combustion Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 670931, 1967, doi: 10.4271/670931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LeFeuvre, T., Myers, P., and Uyehara, O., “Experimental Instantaneous Heat Fluxes in a Diesel Engine and Their Correlation,” SAE Technical Paper 690464, 1969, doi: 10.4271/690464.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Overbye, V., Bennethum, J., Uyehara, O., and Myers, P., “Unsteady Heat Transfer in Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 610041, 1961, doi: 10.4271/610041.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alkidas, A. C. Heat Transfer Characteristics of a Spark-Ignition Engine, Trans. ASME, J. Heat Transfer, 102, pp. 189-193, 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, X., Stone, R., Stevens, R., Arita, Y. et al., “Finite Element Analysis of Eroding Type Surface Thermocouple with Application to Engine Heat Flux Measurement,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1045, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1045.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hendricks, T., Brossman, J.R., and Ghandhi, J.B., Instantaneous Local Heat Flux Measurements in a Small Utility Engine, ASME Paper ICES2009-76035.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Güralp, O., Hoffman, M., Assanis, D., Filipi, Z. et al., “Characterizing the Effect of Combustion Chamber Deposits on a Gasoline HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3277, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-3277.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carslaw, H. S., and Jaeger, J. C., Conduction of Heat in Solids, 2nd Edition, Oxford University Press, USA, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hager, J.M., et al. Experimental Performance of a Heat Flux Microsensor, presented at the 35th International Gas Turbine and Aeroengine Congress, Brussels, ASME 90-GT-256, 1990</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Suslov, D., et al, Development and Application of a Novel Technique for Direct Heat Flux Measurements in Turbomachinery Flows, Flow, Turbulence and Combustion, 69: 249-270, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoag, K., “Measurement and Analysis of the Effect of Wall Temperature on Instantaneous Heat Flux,” SAE Technical Paper 860312, 1986, doi: 10.4271/860312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Incropera, F.P., and DeWitt, D.P., Fundamentals of Heat and Mass Transfer, 3rd Edition, John Wiley and Sons, New York, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diller, T.E., Methods of Determining Heat Flux From Temperature Measurements, Instrumentation in the Aerospace Industry : Proceedings of the International Symposium, p 251-262, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schultz, D.L., and Jones, T.V., Heat Transfer Measurements in Short Duration Hypersonic Facilities, AGARDograph, TR 165, Feb. 1973.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cook, W.J., and Felderman, E.J., Reduction of Data/From Thin-Film Heat-Transfer Gages: A Concise Numerical Technique, AIAA J. 4, 561-562 (1966).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kendall, D.N., and Dixon, W.P., Heat Transfer Measurements in a Hot Shot Wind Tunnel, Trans. on Aerospace and Electronic Systems, Vol. AES-3, No. 4, pp. 596-603, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gatowski, J. A., et al. An Experimental Investigation of Surface Thermometry and Heat Flux, Expl. Thermal Fluid Sci., 1989, 2, 280-292.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wimmer, A., Pivec, R., and Sams, T., “Heat Transfer to the Combustion Chamber and Port Walls of IC Engines - Measurement and Prediction,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0568, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0568.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hollis, B.R., User's Manual for the One-Dimensional Hypersonic Experimental Aero-Thermodynamic (1DHEAT) Data Reduction Code, NASA CR 4691, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walker, D.G., and Scott, E.P., Evaluation of Estimation Methods for High Unsteady Heat Fluxes from Surface Measurements, J. Thermo. Heat Trans., Vol. 12, No. 4, pp. 543-550, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Myers, G. E. Analytical Methods in Conduction Heat Transfer, 2nd Edition, AMCHT Publications, Madison, WI 53705, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nijeweme, Oude, et al, Unsteady In-Cylinder Heat Transfer in a Spark- Ignition Engine: Experiments and Modeling, Proc. Instn Mech Eng., Part D, J. Automob. Eng., 215, 747-760.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lawton, B. Effect of compression and expansion on instantaneous heat transfer in reciprocating internal combustion engines. Proc. Instn Mech. Engrs, Part A, Journal of Power and Energy, 1987, 201(A3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Press, W.H., et al, Numerical Recipes in C: The Art of Scientific Computing, 2nd Edition, Cambridge University Press, Oakleigh, Victoria, Australia (1992).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hadamard, J., Sur les problèmes aux dérivées partielles et leur signification physique. Princeton University Bulletin, pages 49-52, 1902.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stolz, G. Jr., Numerical Solution to an Inverse Problem of Heat Conduction for Simple Shapes, Trans. ASME Journal of Heat Transfer, vol. 82, Series C, 1960, pp. 20-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burgraff, O.R., An Exact Solution of the Inverse Problem in Heat Conduction and Applications, ASME J. Heat Transfer 86C, 373-382 (1964).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taler, J., Theory of Transient Experimental Techniques for Surface Heat Transfer, Int. J. Heat Mass Transfer, vol. 39, No. 17, pp. 3733-3748, 1996</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beck, J.V., Calculation of Surface Heat Flux from an Internal Temperature History, ASME Paper No. 62-Ht-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beck, J.V., Wolf, H., The Nonlinear Inverse Heat Conduction Problem, ASME Paper No. 65-HT-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beck, J. V., Blackwell, B., and St. Clair, C. R., Inverse Heat Conduction: Ill-Posed Problems, Wiley-Interscience, USA, Oct. 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blackwell, B.F., Douglas, R.W., and Wolf, H., A User's Manual For the Sandia One-Dimensional Direct and Inverse Thermal (SODDIT) Code, DOE Report, SAND85-2478, UC-32., 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tikhonov, A.N., and Aresenin, V.Y., Solutions of Ill-Posed Problems, V.H. Winston and Sons, Washington, D.C., 1977.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walker, D.G., and Scott, E.P., Evaluation of Estimation Methods for High Unsteady Heat Fluxes from Surface Measurements, J. Thermo. Heat Trans., Vol. 12, No. 4, pp. 543-550, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kidd, C.T., Recent Developments in High Heat-Flux Measurements Techniques At The AEDC, Instrum. Aero. Ind., Proc. ISA Aerospace Instrum. Symp., Vol. 36, 472-492, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buttsworth, D. R., et al, Eroding Ribbon Thermocouples: Impulse Response and Transient Heat Flux Analysis, Meas. Sci. Technol, 16 (2005), 1487-1494.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carslaw, H. S.. Introduction to the Theory of Fourier's Series and Integrals (Third Edition). New York: Dover Publications Inc., 1930.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
