<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26840429</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Using Ducted Fuel Injection to Attenuate Soot Formation in a Mixing-Controlled Compression Ignition Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nilsen</surname>
                  <given-names>Christopher W.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Biles</surname>
                  <given-names>Drummond E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mueller</surname>
                  <given-names>Charles J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2019</year>
            <string-date>2019</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26840424</issue-id>
         <fpage>309</fpage>
         <lpage>322</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26840429"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Ducted fuel injection (DFI) has been proposed as a strategy to enhance the fuel/charge gas mixing within the combustion chamber of a direct-injection mixing-controlled compression ignition engine. The concept involves injecting each fuel spray through a small tube within the combustion chamber to facilitate the creation of a leaner mixture in the autoignition zone, relative to a conventional free-spray configuration (i.e., a fuel spray that is not surrounded by a duct). While previous experiments demonstrated that DFI lowers both soot incandescence and soot mass in a constant-volume combustion vessel with a single-component normal-alkane fuel (n-dodecane), this study provides the first evidence that the technology provides similar benefits in an engine application using a commercial diesel fuel containing ~30 wt% aromatics. The present study investigates the effects on engine-out emissions and efficiency with a two-orifice injector tip for charge gas mixtures containing 16 and 21 mol% oxygen. The result is that DFI is confirmed to be effective at curtailing engine-out soot emissions. It also breaks the tradeoff between emissions of soot and nitrogen oxides (NOₓ) by simultaneously attenuating soot and NOₓ with increasing dilution.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Ramanathan, V. and Carmichael, G., “Global and Regional Climate Changes Due to Black Carbon,” Nature Geoscience 1(4):221-227, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Global EV Outlook 2018, 2018. Online source, https://www.iea.org/gevo2018/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Wissink, M. and Reitz, R.D., “Direct Dual Fuel Stratification, a Path to Combine the Benefits of RCCI and PPC,” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(2):878-889, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0856.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Reitz, R.D. and Duraisamy, G., “Review of High Efficiency and Clean Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Combustion in Internal Combustion Engines,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 46:12-71, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Dec, J.E., Yang, Y., Dernotte, J., and Ji, C., “Effects of Gasoline Reactivity and Ethanol Content on Boosted, Premixed and Partially Stratified Low-Temperature Gasoline Combustion (LTGC),” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(3):935-955, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0813.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Dempsey, A.B., Walker, N.R., Gingrich, E., and Reitz, R.D., “Comparison of Low Temperature Combustion Strategies for Advanced Compression Ignition Engines with a Focus on Controllability,” Combustion Science and Technology 186(2):210-241, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Saxena, S. and Bedoya, I.D., “Fundamental Phenomena Affecting Low Temperature Combustion and HCCI Engines, High Load Limits and Strategies for Extending These Limits,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 39(5):457-488, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Musculus, M.P.B., Miles, P.C., and Pickett, L.M., “Conceptual Models for Partially Premixed Low- Temperature Diesel Combustion,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 39(2-3):246-283, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Splitter, D., Wissink, M., DelVescovo, D., and Reitz, R.D., “RCCI Engine Operation Towards 60% Thermal Efficiency,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0279, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0279.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Johnson, T. and Joshi, A., “Review of Vehicle Engine Efficiency and Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-0907, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Johnson, T., “Vehicular Emissions in Review,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(2):1258-1275, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0919.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Bergmann, M., Kirchner, U., Vogt, R., and Benter, T., “On- Road and Laboratory Investigation of Low-Level PM Emissions of a Modern Diesel Particulate Filter Equipped Diesel Passenger Car,” Atmospheric Environment 43:1908-1916, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Twigg, M.V., “Progress and Future Challenges in Controlling Automotive Exhaust Gas Emissions,” Applied Catalysis B: Environmental Journal 70(1-4):2-15, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Pickett, L. and Siebers, D., “Non-Sooting, Low Flame Temperature Mixing-Controlled DI Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1399, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Polonowski, C.J., Mueller, C.J., Gehrke, C.R., Bazyn, T. et al., “An Experimental Investigation of Low-Soot and Soot-Free Combustion Strategies in a Heavy-Duty, Single-cylinder, Direct-Injection, Optical Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):51-77, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Manin, J., Skeen, S., Pickett, L., Kurtz, E. et al., “Effects of Oxygenated Fuels on Combustion and Soot Formation/ Oxidation Processes,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 7(3):704-717, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2657.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Higgins, B. and Siebers, D.L., “Measurement of the Flame Lift-Off Location on D.I. Diesel Sprays Using OH Chemiluminescence,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0918, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0918.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Pickett, L.M. and Siebers, D.L., “Soot Formation in Diesel Fuel Jets near the Lift-Off Length,” International Journal of Engine Research 7(2):103-130, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Gehmlich, R.K., Dumitrescu, C.E., Wang, Y., and Mueller, C.J., “Leaner Lifted-Flame Combustion Enabled by the Use of an Oxygenated Fuel in an Optical CI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0730, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0730.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Bunsen, R. and Roscoe, H.E., “XVII. Photo-Chemical Researches.-Part I. Measurement of the Chemical Action of Light,” Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society London 147:355-380, 1857.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Gehmlich, R.K., Mueller, C.J., Ruth, D.J., Nilsen, C.W. et al., “Using Ducted Fuel Injection to Attenuate or Prevent Soot Formation in Mixing Controlled Combustion Strategies for Engine Applications,” Applied Energy 226:1169-1186, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Mueller, C.J., Nilsen, C.W., Ruth, D.J., Gehmlich, R.K. et al., “Ducted Fuel Injection: A New Approach for Lowering Soot Emissions from Direct-Injection Engines,” Applied Energy 204:206-220, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Fitzgerald, R.P., Svensson, K., Martin, G., Qi, Y. et al., “Early Investigation of Ducted Fuel Injection for Reducing Soot in Mixing-Controlled Diesel Flames,” SAE Technical Paper 2018-01-0238, 2018, doi:10.4271/2018-01-0238.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Mueller, C.J. and Martin, G.C., “Effects of Oxygenated Compounds on Combustion and Soot Evolution in a DI Diesel Engine: Broadband Natural Luminosity Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1631, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1631.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Mueller, C.J., Cannella, W.J., Bays, J.T., Bruno, T.J. et al., “Diesel Surrogate Fuels for Engine Testing and Chemical- Kinetic Modeling: Compositions and Properties,” Energy Fuel 30(2):1445-1461, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Mueller, C.J., Cannella, W.J., Bruno, T.J., Bunting, B. et al., “Methodology for Formulating Diesel Surrogate Fuels with Accurate Compositional, Ignition-Quality, and Volatility Characteristics,” Energy Fuel 26(6):3284-3303, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Musculus, M., “Effects of the In-Cylinder Environment on Diffusion Flame Lift-Off in a DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0074, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0074.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Valentino, G., Iannuzzi, S., and Corcione, F.E., “Experimental Investigation on the Combustion and Emissions of a Light Duty Diesel Engine Fuelled with Butanol-Diesel Blend,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0915, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0915.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Light-Duty Noise Guidelines for Advanced Combustion Research, 2015. Online source, http://www.uscar.org/ commands/files_download.php?files_id=399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Schematic of DFI concept on a single spray. © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Optical engine schematic. Top and bottom cameras are used for chemiluminescence and natural luminosity imaging, respectively. Only the natural luminosity (lower) camera was used for this study. © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Experimental conditions. © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Schematic of important DFI parameters. The duct in this image has the δ geometry. © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Three-dimensional computer-generated rendering of two-duct assembly in the optical engine. The ducts are D2L12G3δ. © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Spatially integrated natural luminosity (SINL), apparent heat release rate (AHRR), engine-out filter smoke number (FSN), and engine-out indicated specific soot (ISSoot) emissions as functions of duct presence/configuration and intake oxygen mole fraction (X<sub>O2</sub>). © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>NL images acquired at CA50. The same exposure, f-stop, and lens were used for all images. © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>ISNOₓ, ISHC, and ISCO results. IS emissions are a quantification of the mass of the given species measured per unit energy delivered by the engine. © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>In-cylinder pressure and temperature. The results shown are the averaged data for all the runs at the given condition. The D2L12G1.6δ results are not shown as they overlap with the D2L12G3δ results. © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Load, combustion efficiency, and fuel conversion efficiency. © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Percentage of heat release from SOI to EOPMB (Q1), quasi-steady combustion from EOPMB to EOI (Q2), and EOI to EOC (Q3), ignition delay, CA50, and combustion noise for DFI vs. CDC. © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>DFI breaks the soot/NOₓ tradeoff by simultaneously attenuating soot and NOₓ formation. Plot shows measured ISSoot and NOₓ data for CDC and for DFI with the D2L12G3δ configuration at 21% O₂ and 16% O₂. © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>DFI dramatically lowers soot at constant dilution and combustion phasing. Plot shows the change in IS emissions of soot, NOₓ, HC, CO, and η<sub>f</sub> with DFI (D2L12G3δ) at 16 mol% O₂, relative to CDC at 16 mol% O₂. For a given parameter X, the bar plot shows (X<sub>DFI</sub> - X<sub>CDC</sub>)/min(X<sub>DFI</sub>,X<sub>CDC</sub>). Inset shows heat release rates for the two cases. © 2019 National Technology &amp; Engineering Solutions of Sandia, LLC.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
