<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278318</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Key Role of the Closed-loop Combustion Control for Exploiting the Potential of Biodiesel in a Modern Diesel Engine for Passenger Car Applications</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ciaravino</surname>
                  <given-names>Claudio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors LLC</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Guido</surname>
                  <given-names>Chiara</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori CNR</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Vassallo</surname>
                  <given-names>Alberto</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors LLC</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Beatrice</surname>
                  <given-names>Carlo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori CNR</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278288</issue-id>
         <fpage>2576</fpage>
         <lpage>2589</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278318"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The present paper describes the results of a cooperative research project between GM Powertrain Europe and Istituto Motori - CNR aimed at studying the capability of GM Combustion Closed-Loop Control (CLCC) in enabling seamless operation with high biodiesel blending levels in a modern diesel engine for passenger car applications. As a matter of fact, fuelling modern electronically-controlled diesel engines with high blends of biodiesel leads to a performance reduction of about 12-15% at rated power and up to 30% in the low-end torque, while increasing significantly the engine-out NOx emissions. These effects are both due to the interaction of the biodiesel properties with the control logic of the electronic control unit, which is calibrated for diesel operation. However, as the authors previously demonstrated, if engine calibration is re-tuned for biodiesel fuelling, the above mentioned drawbacks can be compensated and the biodiesel environmental inner qualities can be fully deployed.</p>
            <p>In order to enable such calibration re-tuning, it is fundamental to achieve a reliable biodiesel blending detection, and to use it for real-time combustion optimization, chiefly by optimizing the injection train. Therefore, the authors investigated the capability of CLCC to detect biodiesel blending ratio on the recently released 2.0L Euro5 GM diesel engine equipped with embedded pressure sensors in the glow plugs.</p>
            <p>Various blends of biodiesel were tested, notably 20% by volume (B20), 50% (B50) and pure biodiesel (B100). Tests on the multi-cylinder engine were carried out in a wide range of engine operating points for the complete characterization of the biodiesel performance in the NEDC cycle.</p>
            <p>The results demonstrated the successful capability of the CLCC control to detect biodiesel blending with reasonable accuracy and to implement the corrective actions to avoid emission drift and performance losses.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sheehan, J., Camobreco, V., Duffield, J., Graboski, M., and Shapouri, H., “An Overview of Biodiesel and Petroleum Diesel Life Cycles”, National Renewable Energy Lab, May 1998. Available online at: http://devafdc.nrel.gov/pdfs/3812.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Report of the Commission of the European Communities, “Biofuels Progress Report”, Bruxelles, 2007. Available online at: http://www2.epia.org/documents/NL_0711_037.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lapuerta, M., Armas, O., and Rodríguez-Fernández, J., “Effect of biodiesel fuels on diesel engine emissions”, Progress in Energy Combustion Science, Vol. 34:198-223, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawano, D., Ishii, H., Goto, Y., Noda, A. et al., “Application of Biodiesel Fuel to Modern Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0233, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0233.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beatrice, C., Di Iorio, S., Guido, C., Mancaruso, E. et al., “Alternative Diesel Fuels Effects on Combustion and Emissions of an Euro4 Automotive Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):542-561, 2010, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0088.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DIRECTIVE 2009/28/EC OF THE EUROPEAN PARLIAMENT AND OF THE COUNCIL, Bruxelles, 2009. Available online at: www.energy.eu/directives/pro-re.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Soltic, P., Edenhauser, D., Thurnheer, T., Schreiber, D., and Sankowski, A., “Experimental investigation of mineral diesel fuel, GTL fuel, RME and neat soybean and rapeseed oil combustion in a heavy duty on-road engine with exhaust gas aftertreatment”, Fuel, Vol. 88: 1-8, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beatrice, C., Guido, C., and Di Iorio, S., “Experimental analysis of alternative fuel impact on a new ‘torquecontrolled’ light-duty diesel engine for passenger cars”, Fuel, Vol. 89: 3278-3286, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, F., Bianco, A., Vezza, D., Vlachos, T., Ciaravino, C., and Vassallo, A., “Biodiesel fuelling impact on performance and dilution of Euro5 small displacement passenger car diesel engine”, conference proceedings of SEET 2010, Jun 29th-Jul 2th, Bari, Italy, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mueller, C., Ras Robotti, B., Wesslau, M., Drangel, H., Agricola, U., Catanese, A., and Manta, E., “Opel's new 2.0L BiTurbo Diesel engine with highly innovative CleanTech combustion concept”, MTZ Worldwide, Vol. 12, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">British Patent Application GB 0918272.6, 2009, Inventors: Ciaravino, C., Guglielmone, F., and Vassallo, A.,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos, C. D., Antonopoulos, K.A., Rakopoulos, D.C., Hountalas, D.T., and Giakoumis, E.G., “Comparative performance and emissions study of a direct injection Diesel engine using blends of Diesel fuel with vegetable oils or biodiesels of various origins”, Energy Conversion and Management, Vol. 47: 3272-3287, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AVL documents, “Smoke value measurement with filter paper method”, https://www.avl.com/c/document_library/get_file?uuid=2b39210c-6937-43e4-b223- b5c2cllf91ac&amp;groupId=10138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
