<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="other"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">3663852</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/341641</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB750407</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Books Received</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2002</year>
            <string-date>October 2002</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>75</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2002.75.issue-4</issue-id>
         <fpage>733</fpage>
         <lpage>734</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/341641"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <title>Business Economics and Economics</title>
         <p>Baumol, William J. The Free‐Market Innovation Machine: Analyzing the Growth Miracle of Capitalism. Princeton, N.J.: Princeton University Press, 2002. Pp. 300. $35.00/£24.95.</p>
         <p>Caves, Richard E. Creative Industries: Contracts between Art and Commerce. Cambridge, Mass.: Harvard University Press. Pp. 454. $19.95.</p>
         <p>Litan, Robert E., and Rivlin, Alice M. Beyond the Dot.coms: The Economic Promise of the Internet. Washington, D.C.: Brookings Institution Press, 2001. Pp. 132. $19.95.</p>
         <p>Pryor, Frederic L. The Future of U.S. Capitalism. New York: Cambridge University Press, 2002. Pp. xiii+447. $35.00.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <title>Business Ethics</title>
         <p>Marrella, Len. In Search of Ethics: Conversations with Men and Women of Character. Sanford, Fla.: DC Press, 2001. Pp. xx+255. $19.95 (U.S.); $30.95 (Canada).</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <title>Management Organization Theory and Practice</title>
         <p>Dawson, Tony. Principles and Practices of Modern Management. 3d ed. Liverpool: Liverpool Academic Press, 2000. Pp. 407. $29.95.</p>
         <p>Goldsmith, Marshall, and Belasco, James, eds. Leading Authorities on Business: Winning Strategies from the Greatest Minds in Business Today. Washington, D.C.: Leading Authorities Press, 2002. Pp. xviii+222. $29.95.</p>
         <p>Neely, Andy. Business Performance Measurement: Theory and Practice. New York: Cambridge University Press, 2002. Pp. xiii+366. $60.00.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <title>Marketing</title>
         <p>Beck‐Burridge, Martin, and Walton, Jeremy. Sports Sponsorship and Brand Development: The Subaru and Jaguar Stories. New York: Palgrave, 2002. Pp. vi+178.</p>
         <p>Bedbury, Scott, with Fenichell, Stephen. A New Brand World: Eight Principles for Achieving Brand Leadership in the 21st Century. New York: Penguin Putnam, 2002. Pp. 288. $24.95.</p>
         <p>Franses, Philip Hans, and Paap, Richard. Quantitative Models in Marketing Research. New York: Cambridge University Press, 2002. Pp. xiii+206. $45.00.</p>
         <p>Power, Ken, and Winn, Craig. In the Company of Good and Evil: From Zero to $3 Billion and Back Again. Charlottesville, Va.: CricketSong Books, 2001. Pp. xiii+594. $29.95.</p>
         <p>Vandermerwe, Sandra. Customer Capitalism: Increasing Returns in New Market Spaces. Philadelphia: Whurr Publishers, 1999. Pp. xvi+296. $27.95.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc5">
         <title>Mathematical Models and Computer Research</title>
         <p>Garrity, Thomas A. All the Mathematics You Missed [But Need to Know for Graduate School]. New York: Cambridge University Press, 2002. Pp. xxvii+347. $55.00 (cloth); $25.00 (paper).</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc6">
         <title>Personnel, Industrial Relations, Labor, and Manpower</title>
         <p>Balsam, Steven. An Introduction to Executive Compensation. San Diego: Academic Press, 2002. Pp. xvii+387.</p>
         <p>Chester, Eric. Employing a Generation Why? Understanding, Managing, and Motivating Your New Workforce. Lakewood, Colo.: Tucker House Books, 2002. Pp. xi+212. $24.95.</p>
         <p>Logue, John, and Yates, Jacquelyn. The Real World of Employee Ownership. Ithaca, N.Y.: Cornell University Press, 2001. Pp. xvi+247. $45.00 (cloth); $17.95 (paper).</p>
         <p>McKenna, Patrick J., and Maister, David H. First among Equals: How to Manage a Group of Professionals. New York: Free Press, 2002. Pp. 288. $26.00.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc7">
         <title>Social Issues and Public Policy</title>
         <p>Carnoy, Martin. Sustaining the New Economy: Work, Family, and Community in the Information Age. Cambridge, Mass.: Harvard University Press, 2002. Pp. 238. $19.95.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc8">
         <title>Miscellaneous</title>
         <p>Hart, John Mason. Empire and Revolution: The Americans in Mexico since the Civil War. Berkeley: University of California Press, 2002. Pp. 688. $39.95/£27.95.</p>
         <p>Hubbard, L. Ron. Clean Body, Clear Mind. Los Angeles: Bridge Publications, 1990, 2001. Pp. xiii+246. $14.95 (U.S.); $22.95 (Canada).</p>
         <p>Laermer, Richard. Trend Spotting: Think Forward, Get Ahead, and Cash In on the Future. New York: Berkeley Publishing Group, 2002. Pp. xv+239. $14.95.</p>
         <p>Rustmann, F. W., Jr. CIA, Inc.: Espionage and the Craft of Business Intelligence. Dulles, Va.: Brassey's, Inc., 2002. Pp. xiii+217. $27.50.</p>
         <p>Whyte, David. Crossing the Unknown Sea: Work as a Pilgrimage of Identity. New York: Riverhead Books, 2002. Pp. xiv+257. $14.00.</p>
      </sec>
   </body>
</article>
