<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">16</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830312</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830318</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>WOMEN's ACCESS TO CREDIT FACILITIES FROM COMMERCIAL BANKS IN NIGERIA: CHALLENGES FOR THE 1990s / L'ACCES DES FEMMES AU CREDIT DES BANQUES COMMERCIALES AU NIGERIA: UN DEFI POUR LES ANNEES '90</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>John C.</given-names>
                  <surname>Anyanwu</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1992</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>421</fpage>
         <lpage>440</lpage>
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830318"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This study was meant to determine the extent of women's limited access to credit facilities from commercial banks in Nigeria, factors inhibiting them (particularly gender-related ones), and to make policy recommendations. The results of the findings can be summarized as: (a) Nigerian women do not have limited access to commercial bank credit, rather there are fewer women credit applicants due to ignorance and general illiteracy. There is rather widespread participation in borrowing in the informal credit market. (b) Nigerian commercial banks do not discriminate against women on the basis of gender in approving credit applications. Nigerian women are not also constrained generally by tradition and/or religion, age, educational level, occupational group, physical/biological conditions, cost of credit, distance, language, etc. (c) However, the size of women's business and income, lack of collaterals, and perceived risk costs act as limitations to their access to commercial bank credit in Nigeria. Based on these findings, policy options were proffered. Cette étude a été conçue pour déterminer l'étendue de l'accés aux facilités de crédit aux femmes par les banques de commerce au Nigéria, les facteurs qui leur interdissent (surtout la discrimination de sexe) et pour faire des recommandations politiques. Les résultats des recherches peuvent être ainsi résumés: a) Les Nigériannes n'ont pas accés limité au crédit des banques de commerce, mais plutôt il y a moins de candidates qui profitent de cette facilité à cause d'ignorance et d'analphabétisme générale. Au contraire, il y a une grande participation aux prêts dans le marché de crédit non-officiel. b) Les banques de commerce nigeriens ne font pas de discrimination contre les femmes en approuvant la demande du crédit. Les Nigériannes ne sont pas forcées des traditions, ou de la religion, de l'age, du niveau d'éducation, du groupe professionnel, des conditions physiques ou biologiques, du coût du crédit, de la distance ou du langage, etc. c) Cependant, l'étendue ou la grandeur d'affaire féminin et le revenu, la manque de garanties et le risque anticipé, agissent en limitations à leur accés aux prêts des banques de commerce au Nigéria. Sur la base de ces résultats, des options politiques ont été présentées.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1e126a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e130" publication-type="other">
Anyanwu, J.C, An Appraisal of the Agricultural Credit Performance of Nigerian Merchant Banks, 1975-1984,
Unpublished M. Sc. (Economics) Project, University of Ibadan, Ibadan (1986).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e140a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e144" publication-type="other">
—, The Impact and Policy Implications of the Financial Deregulation Revolution: An International Perspective,
Award-Winning Essay, 1990 Amex Bank Review Awards, 1990.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e154a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e158" publication-type="other">
Donnelly, J. "Human Rights at the United Nations, 1955-85: The Question of Bias", International Studies Quarterly,
Vol. 32, No. 2, September 1988, 275-304.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e168a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e172" publication-type="other">
Eide, A. "The World of Human Rights as seen from a small, Industrialized Country", International Studies Quarter-
ly, Vol. 23, No. 2, June 1979, 249, 246-272.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e183a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e187" publication-type="other">
Herz, B., "Bringing Women into the Economic Mainstream", Finance and Development, Vol. 26, No. 4, December,
1989, 22-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e197a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e201" publication-type="other">
Miller, CJ. and Ladman, J.R. "Factors Impeding Credit Use in Small-Farm Households in Bolivia", The Journal
of Development Studies, Vol. 19, No. 4, July 1983, 522-538.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e211a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e215" publication-type="other">
Mitchell, I.S. and Still, R.R., "Correlates of Consumer Banking Behaviour in the Socialist Cooperative Republic
of Guyana", Social and Economic Studies, Vol. 28, No. 2, June 1979, 397-430.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e225a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e229" publication-type="other">
Osarenren, F. and Daodu, K., "Do Women Need their Own Bank?", National Concord, November 27, 1990
P. 5.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e239a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e243" publication-type="other">
Palmer, I. Women's Roles and Gender Differences in Development: The Nemow Case, Kumarian Press, West
Hartford, 1985, 30-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e253a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e257" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz, J.E. "Peer Monitoring and Credit Markets", The World Bank Economic Review, Vol. 4, No. 3, September
1990, 351-366.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e268a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e272" publication-type="other">
—, and Weiss, A. "Incentive Effects of Termination: Applications to the Credit and Labour Markets", American
Economic Review, Vol. 72, December, 1983, 912-927.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e282a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e286" publication-type="other">
Udry, C "Credit Markets in Northern Nigeria: Credit as Insurance in a Rural Economy", The World Bank Economic
Review, Vol. 4, No. 3, September 1990, 251-270.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e296a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e300" publication-type="other">
UNCTAD, The Least Developed Countries, 1989 Report, Un, New York, 1990.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


