<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26649122</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Potential of Negative Valve Overlap for Part-Load Efficiency Improvement in Gasoline Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rodriguez</surname>
                  <given-names>J. Felipe</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cheng</surname>
                  <given-names>Wai K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">11</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26649117</issue-id>
         <fpage>657</fpage>
         <lpage>668</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26649122"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This article reports on the potential of negative valve overlap (NVO) for improving the net indicated thermal efficiency (η <sub>NIMEP</sub>) of gasoline engines during part load. Three fixed fuel flow rates, resulting in indicated mean effective pressures of up to 6 bar, were investigated. At low load, NVO significantly reduces the pumping loses during the gas exchange loop, achieving up to 7% improvement in indicated efficiency compared to the baseline. Similar efficiency improvements are achieved by positive valve overlap (PVO), with the disadvantage of worse combustion stability from a higher residual gas fraction (x<sub>r</sub>). As the load increases, achieving the wide-open throttle limit, the benefits of NVO for reducing the pumping losses diminish, while the blowdown losses from early exhaust valve opening (EVO) increase. However, a symmetric NVO strategy combined with a shorter exhaust duration has a higher potential for reduction in part-load fuel consumption, as the EVO timing can be optimized to minimize the blowdown losses.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Jo, Y.S., “More Effective Use of Fuel Octane in a Turbocharged Gasoline Engine: Combustion, Knock, Vehicle Impacts,” Ph.D. thesis, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Fitzgerald, R., Steeper, R., Snyder, J., Hanson, R. et al., “Determination of Cycle Temperatures and Residual Gas Fraction for HCCI Negative Valve Overlap Operation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):124-141, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010- 01-0343.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Guohong, T., Zhi, W., Jianxin, W., Shijin, S. et al., “HCCI Combustion Control by Injection Strategy with Negative Valve Overlap in a GDI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006- 01-0415, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0415.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Koopmans, L., Ogink, R., and Denbratt, I., “Direct Gasoline Injection in the Negative Valve Overlap of a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1854, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1854.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Olesky, L.M., Martz, J.B., Lavoie, G.A., Vavra, J. et al., “The Effects of Spark Timing, Unburned Gas Temperature, and Negative Valve Overlap on the Rates of Stoichiometric Spark Assisted Compression Ignition Combustion,” Appl. Energy 105:407-417, May 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Persson, H., Agrell, M., Olsson, J., Johansson, B. et al., “The Effect of Intake Temperature on HCCI Operation Using Negative Valve Overlap,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01- 0944, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0944.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Urushihara, T., Hiraya, K., Kakuhou, A., and Itoh, T., “Expansion of HCCI Operating Region by the Combination of Direct Fuel Injection, Negative Valve Overlap and Internal Fuel Reformation,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0749, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Pischinger, M., Salber, W., van der Staay, F., Baumgarten, H. et al., “Benefits of the Electromechanical Valve Train in Vehicle Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1223, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Bonatesta, F. and Shayler, P.J., “Factors Influencing the Burn Rate Characteristics of a Spark Ignition Engine with Variable Valve Timing,” Proc. Inst. Mech. Eng. Part J. Automob. Eng. 222(11):2147-2158, Nov. 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Chang, Y., Wooldridge, M., and Bohac, S., “Extending the Dilution Limit of Spark Ignition Combustion via Fuel Injection during Negative Valve Overlap,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0671, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0671.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Rodriguez, J. and Cheng, W., “Reduction of Cold-Start Emissions through Valve Timing in a GDI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(2):1220-1229, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0827.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Rodriguez, J. and Cheng, W., “Analysis of NOx Emissions during Crank-Start and Cold Fast-Idle in a GDI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 10(2):646-655, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0796.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Kuratle, R.H. and Marki, B., “Influencing Parameters and Error Sources During Indication on Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 920233, 1992, doi:10.4271/920233.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Davis, R. and Patterson, G., “Cylinder Pressure Data Quality Checks and Procedures to Maximize Data Accuracy,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1346, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1346.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Operating points on the engine map (midsize sedan vehicle, 2.5-L NA engine with a compression ratio of 11.5:1) determined using Autonomie over the UDDS cycle. Spark timings at maximum brake torque (MBT) timing. Adapted from Jo, 2016 [1]. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Pressure-volume diagram for a part-load operation in SI engines (logarithmic scales) at 3.75-bar NIMEP. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Valve timing diagram for the engine used. The intake and exhaust valve openings have a duration of 220°CA. The position shown on the left is the stock valve timing with de-energized variable valve timing (VVT) solenoids. The black arrows represent the direction of phasing for NVO. The position shown on the right is the most aggressive NVO pursued, with de-energized VVT solenoids. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Specifications of the base engine, stock parked valve timing. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Diagram of the experimental setup and measurement points. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Valve timing experiment matrix. The two black stars represent the parked valve timing settings (i.e., no VVT actuation) used to cover the valve timing map. The orange and blue squares represent the range covered by the VVT system from the corresponding parked valve timings. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Positive and negative valve overlap regions as a function of valve timing. The bigger green points highlight the individual valve timings that will be discussed in detail. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Engine operating points investigated. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Change in net indicated thermal efficiency (η<sub>NIMEP</sub>) as a function of valve overlap. Different valve timing settings can result in the same valve overlap. The results shown correspond to the greatest positive change in efficiency observed for a given valve overlap. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Valve timings for which the pressure traces are analyzed in detail. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>η<sub>NIMEP</sub> as a function of valve timing for a constant fuel injection of 14.7 mg per cylinder per cycle. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Relative change in η<sub>NIMEP</sub> with respect to the baseline valve (fuel mass = 14.7 mg/cyl./cycle). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Combustion stability, CoV (top) and LNV (bottom), as a function of valve timing for a constant fuel injection of 14.7 mg per cylinder per cycle. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Comparison of the pumping loops (logarithmic scales) of the baseline and symmetric PVO valve timings (fuel mass = 14.7 mg/cyl./cycle). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>x<sub>r</sub> as a function of valve timing for a constant fuel injection of 14.7 mg per cylinder per cycle. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>log(P)-log(V) diagrams for baseline and late IVO valve timings for a constant fuel injection of 14.7 mg per cylinder per cycle. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Comparison of the pumping loops (linear scales) of the baseline and late IVO valve timings (fuel mass = 14.7 mg/cyl./cycle). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>log(P)-log(V) diagrams for baseline and early EVC valve timings for a constant fuel injection of 14.7 mg per cylinder per cycle. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Comparison of the high-pressure loops (linear scales) of the baseline and early EVC valve timings (fuel mass = 14.7 mg/cyl./cycle). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Comparison of the pumping loops (linear scales) of the baseline and early EVC valve timings (fuel mass = 14.7 mg/cyl./cycle). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 18</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>log(P)-log(V) diagrams for baseline and symmetric NVO valve timings for a constant fuel injection of 14.7 mg per cylinder per cycle. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 19</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Comparison of the pumping loops (linear scales) of the baseline and symmetric NVO valve timings (fuel mass = 14.7 mg/cyl./cycle). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>CoV of NIMEP for the three fueling cases and different valve timings. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 20</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Change in GIMEP and PMEP with respect to the baseline for the symmetric NVO, early EVC, late IVO, and symmetric PVO. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 21</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>Simulated pressure-volume traces and exhaust valve lift profile for different exhaust opening durations using the symmetric NVO strategy. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 22</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Effect of exhaust opening duration on net indicated efficiency and the mean effective pressures for the symmetric NVO strategy. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
