<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26529478</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>LAST WORD</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Trusting what is inside the bright and shiny new box of technology</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Harris</surname>
                  <given-names>Sinclair</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Sinclair Harris serves as LMI’s vice president of business development for the defense sector. He retired as a rear admiral after a 34-year career in the US Navy. His service culminated as the vice director for operations to the chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff. During his distinguished career, he led joint, combined, multinational, and interagency organizations both at sea and ashore across all aspects of defense, including full spectrum operations, program management, strategic planning, and execution. He was also commander of the US Fourth Fleet, leading US Naval forces assigned to US Southern Command. Mr. Harris has been published in numerous journals on the topics of surface warfare, combat logistics, irregular warfare, and leadership. He earned a BS in economics from James Madison University, an MS in operations research from the Naval Postgraduate School, and an MS in defense and strategic studies from the University of Madras, India. Mr. Harris voluntarily serves as chairman of the Maritime Policy Committee of the Navy League of the United States, chairman of the National Defense Industrial Association Expeditionary Warfare Division, senior advisor to the National Naval Officers Association, member of the board of directors for the Surface Navy Association, and member of the Northern Virginia Armed Forces Communications and Electronics Association.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>March 2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>51</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e26529458</issue-id>
         <fpage>62</fpage>
         <lpage>64</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2018, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26529478"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DeZyre. 2015. Data Science Compared with Different Analytics Disciplines. Blog (October 20). https://www.dezyre.com/article/data-science-compared-withdifferent-analytics-disciplines/175.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gupta, S. 2017. Machine Learning, Data Science, And Operations Research—What’s the Difference. Blog. Revenue Analytics (September 14). https://revenueanalytics.com/machinelearning-data-science-andoperations-research-whats-thedifference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mitchell-Guthrie, P. 2015. OR vs. Data Science vs. Analytics: What’s in a Name? LinkedIn Pulse (December 15). https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/vs-datascience-analytics-whats-namepolly-mitchell-guthrie.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
