<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">24</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186402</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44434396</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Operation and Maintenance</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Long-Distance Passenger Services</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>R. E.</given-names>
                  <surname>Plimpton</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1929</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>631</fpage>
         <lpage>643</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44434396"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>EXTENSION of motorcoach services over routes of 100 miles or more in length in all parts of the Country is shown by a map, and figures are given of the number of routes, the miles of highway over which the services are operated, running time, rates of fare charged and like data. Facilities and operating methods differentiating long-distance from suburban services are mentioned and the similarity to railroad practice pointed out. A characteristic of routes ranging from several hundred to nearly 1500 miles is that service is afforded continuously for 24 hr. per day seven days per week and many passengers ride day and night. Such, long runs are broken into stages so that a driver does not work more than 8 to 10 hr. as a rule and vehicles are changed at the end of a run of a certain distance, which may vary from about 200 to nearly 750 miles. Tickets bearing coupons for the successive stages or divisions are issued, garage facilities are provided at division points, and intermediate stations for passenger comfort and meals are provided, often by others than the operating company. Factors affecting speed are discussed and the painstaking care with which running schedules are developed is explained. Types of vehicle used vary with volume of traffic and road conditions. Standardization of equipment is greatly preferred by passengers and should be practicable ordinarily on lines of a single company. Sleeper motorcoaches are now being tried between Buffalo and Cleveland and a similar service was started in June between Los Angeles and San Francisco. Some tendency to find additional sources of revenue than passenger traffic is observed, and at least one long-distance line is engaged in furniture moving. Local and suburban passenger service is operated in conjunction with long-distance services by a number of lines, and a tendency exists to absorb independent connecting lines. Union terminals are maintained in various large cities. In concluding, the author praises the high type of driver now handling the vehicles and the motorcoach engineers and manufacturers for the great reliability of the vehicles under the severe duty imposed by the service.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


