<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">34</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i24440349</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24440393</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Going beyond GDP: An OECD Perspective</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Romina</given-names>
                  <surname>Boarini</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Marco Mira</given-names>
                  <surname>d'Ercole</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2013</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>289</fpage>
         <lpage>314</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2013 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440393"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper presents some of the main features of recent OECD work on people's well-being and societies' progress. After discussing the main limitations of GDP as a measure of 'welfare', the paper presents the multidimensional framework and rationale underpinning the OECD Better Life Initiative, and describes how this framework aims to overcome the limitations of GDP. The paper also presents some of the evidence from the OECD 'Better Life Index', an interactive tool that allows citizens to compare countries according to their own views and preferences on the relative importance of the different aspects of human well-being.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d2541880e217a1310">
            <label>*</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e224" publication-type="other">
Submitted June 2012.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e231a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e238" publication-type="other">
Nordhaus and Tobin, 1973; Sen, 1985 and 1998; OECD, 2008c; Fleurbaey, 2009; Stiglitz, Sen and
Fitoussi, 2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e248a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e255" publication-type="other">
Kuznets, 1934.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e262a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e269" publication-type="other">
Christian, 1974; OECD, 1982 and 1986.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e277a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e284" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz, 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e291a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e298" publication-type="other">
The notion of 'framework', in this context, should not be understood as referring to the type of
'accounting framework' used for economic statistics, with a sequence of accounts linked to each other in
a logical sequence and with entries all expressed through a common metric (money). It is used here rather
as a graphical representation of the dimensions and items that should be taken into account for any
comprehensive assessment of individual and societal well-being.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e317a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e324" publication-type="other">
The OECD Better Life Initiative approaches sustainability through the capital approach and in
particular defines sustainability in terms of the non-negative change of some key assets that generate
well-being over time. These assets comprise types of capital that are traditionally well measured by
official statistical systems - for example, physical and natural capital - but also types of capital that
remain challenging to measure across countries, notably human and social capital. Given these gaps, the
dashboard of OECD well-being indicators includes at the moment only a few indicators of economic and
environmental sustainability (for example, intensity of use of forest resources, nitrogen surplus intensities
and freshwater abstraction) that are not discussed in this paper. The OECD is currently carrying out
various research projects to build additional indicators of sustainability.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e356a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e363" publication-type="other">
Sen, 1985; Anand et al., 2009; Anand, Durand and Heckman, 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e370a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e377" publication-type="other">
Fleurbaey (2006) highlights that functionings are 'selected achievements' that matter from a
normative point of view - for instance, achievements that go beyond subjective well-being and
encompass objective achievements. Functionings matter beyond resources, as people may have different
attributes and needs, and can achieve different levels of well-being with the same amount of resources.
Capabilities need to be considered alongside achievements to take into account the importance of freedom
for human life (i.e. the possibility of choosing one's own functionings).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e400a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e407" publication-type="other">
Crocker, 1992.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e415a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e422" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Stiglitz, Sen and Fitoussi (2009) for a review, Sen (1998) and Nussbaum (2011).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e429a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e436" publication-type="other">
Face validity is the capacity to capture what is intended to be measured. By summary outcomes, we
refer to relatively broad achievements (for example, good health status) that can be easily understood and
that display no ambiguity in interpretation, showing either good/bad performance or progress/regress
when looking at changes over time.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e452a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e459" publication-type="other">
http://www.ifs.org.uk/docs/fssepl 3 boarini&amp;dercole appendix.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e466a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e473" publication-type="other">
For example, the indicator of household wealth currently included in the OECD set measures 'net
financial wealth', i.e. the sum of financial assets and liabilities owned by households. Thus the indicator
is only a limited proxy of people's consumption possibilities, as it excludes those non-financial assets
(such as dwellings and land) that represent the bulk of household wealth in most countries because
information on these currently does not exist on a comparable basis across OECD countries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e492a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e499" publication-type="other">
The SNA defines the general production boundary as referring to 'activity carried out under the
control and responsibility of an institutional unit that uses inputs of labour, capital, and goods and
services to produce outputs of goods and services' (SNA 2008, 6.24). The more restricted production
boundary used in the SNA, however, excludes all household production of services for own final use,
except services from owner-occupied dwellings and services produced by employing paid domestic staff
(SNA 2008, 6.26).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e522a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e529" publication-type="other">
Boarini, Johansson and Mira d'Ercole, 2006; Stiglitz, Sen and Fitoussi, 2009; Eurostat, 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e537a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e544" publication-type="other">
In principle, monetary evaluation of these non-market services could either rely on quality-adjusted
market price equivalents of these non-market services (Holloway, Short and Tamplin, 2002) or,
alternatively, be based on an estimation of the labour costs involved in producing these non-market
services. In practice, the former method requires a large range of assumptions and various data that are
not easily available, especially for cross-country comparisons. Therefore, most approaches in this field (as
reflected in estimates of household satellite accounts) make use of the labour cost method.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e567a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e574" publication-type="other">
Di Telia and MacCulloch, 2004; Helliwell, 2003; Fleche, Smith and Sorsa, 2011; Boarini et al., 2012.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e581a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e588" publication-type="other">
For subjective well-being, see van Praag, Frijters and Ferrer-i-Carbonell (2003), Gardner and Oswald
(2007), Clark, Frijters and Shields (2008) for a review, Sacks, Stevenson and Wolfers (2010), Kahneman
and Deaton (2010) and Boarini et al. (2012). For health, see Furnée, Groot and Pfann (2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e601a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e608" publication-type="other">
Dolan, Peasgood and White, 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e615a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e622" publication-type="other">
Boarini, Johansson and Mira d'Ercole, 2006; Jones and KJenow, 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e629a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e636" publication-type="other">
OECD, 2011b.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e644a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e651" publication-type="other">
OECD, 2008a and 2011a.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e658a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e665" publication-type="other">
OECD, 2011a.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e672a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e679" publication-type="other">
A similar analysis is performed in OECD (201 la) and in Boarini et al. (2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e686a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e693" publication-type="other">
The analysis summarised in Table 1 covers 34 OECD countries and six emerging economies (Brazil,
China, India, Indonesia, Russian Federation and South Africa). The sample size in the Gallup World Poll
is about 1,000 observations per country, with larger samples (around 4,000 observations) in some of the
larger countries (such as China and India). The number of observations included in each regression is
given in the table. These regressions are weighted with post-stratification weights provided by Gallup.
Post-stratification weights correct for non-random response patterns to the survey. More information on
these weights and the survey is available at https://worldview.gallup.com/content/methodology.asDx.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e719a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e726" publication-type="other">
However, people with higher education do not report higher satisfaction with the quality of the local
environment where they live. This can be explained by the higher environmental awareness and concerns
of high-educated people (OECD, 201 la).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e739a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e746" publication-type="other">
Black and Devereux, 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e754a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e761" publication-type="other">
Alkire and Foster, 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e768a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e775" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz, Sen and Fitoussi, 2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e782a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e789" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz, Sen and Fitoussi, 2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e796a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e803" publication-type="other">
OECD, 2008b.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e810a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e817" publication-type="other">
For a review, see Decancq and Lugo (2012), Sharpe (2011); Ravallion (2011), OECD (2008b).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e824a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e831" publication-type="other">
Sharpe and Andrews, 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e839a1310">
            <label>34</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e846" publication-type="other">
In the OECD application, users are prompted to rate dimensions on a scale from 0 ('the item is not
important at all') to 6 ('the item is extremely important'). These rates are then converted into relative
weights by dividing them by the total sum of rates attributed by users to all dimensions. For the sake of
simplicity and user-friendliness, users are asked to rate the 11 dimensions that make up well-being as if
they were independent dimensions of well-being, i.e. at no point are users prompted to take into account
interrelationships between the dimensions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e869a1310">
            <label>35</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e876" publication-type="other">
OECD, 2011a.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e883a1310">
            <label>36</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e890" publication-type="other">
http://www.ifs.org.uk/docs/fssepl3 boarini&amp;dercole appendix.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e897a1310">
            <label>37</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e904" publication-type="other">
Weights applied to elementary indicators to obtain normalised scores by dimensions are set, for the
sake of simplicity, in a normative way. Ideally, one would like to ask users to rate indicators directly. This
would, however, be very difficult to visualise with a user-friendly tool. It should also be noted that, since
the OECD well-being indicators are not available at the level of the individual (as emphasised in Section
II), the BLI cannot be built as a true synthetic index, where well-being scores would be aggregated across
dimensions and individuals. The BLI is obtained simply as a weighted average of a country's scores in
the 11 dimensions, with weights assigned by users. Since 2012, the BLI has also been broken down for
women and men (i.e. it corresponds to the weighted women/men country-average well-being scores of the
11 dimensions).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e936a1310">
            <label>38</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e943" publication-type="other">
Boarini et al., 2013.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e950a1310">
            <label>39</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e957" publication-type="other">
OECD, 2008c.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e965a1310">
            <label>40</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e972" publication-type="other">
OECD, 2011a.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e979a1310">
            <label>41</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e986" publication-type="other">
See Ruiz (2011).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2541880e993a1310">
            <label>42</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1000" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz, Sen and Fitoussi, 2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d2541880e1016a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1020" publication-type="other">
Alkire, S. and Foster, J. E. (2010), 'Designing the inequality-adjusted Human Development
Index', Oxford Poverty &amp; Human Development Initiative (OPHI), Working Paper no. 37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1030a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1034" publication-type="other">
Anand, P., Durand, M. and Heckman, J. (2011), 'The measurement of progress: some
achievements and challenges', Journal of the Royal Statistical Society: Series A, vol. 174,
pp. 851-5.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1047a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1051" publication-type="other">
—, Hunter, G., Carter, I., Dowding, K., Guala, F. and van Hees, M. (2009), 'The development
of capability indicators', Journal of Human Development Capabilities, vol. 10, pp. 125—
52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1064a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1068" publication-type="other">
Black, S. E. and Devereux, P. J. (2011), 'Recent developments in intergenerational mobility',
in D. Card and O. Ashenfelter (eds), Handbook of Labor Economics, Volume 4, Part B,
Amsterdam: Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1082a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1086" publication-type="other">
Boarini, R., Cohen, G., Denis, V. and Ruiz, N. (2013), 'Designing the "Your Better Life
Index": methodology and results', OECD Statistics Department, Working Paper,
forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1099a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1103" publication-type="other">
—, Comola, M., Smith, C., Manchin, R. and De Keulenaer, F. (2012), 'What makes for a
better life? The determinants of subjective well-being in OECD countries: evidence from
the Gallup World Poll', OECD Statistics Directorate, Working Paper no. 2012/3.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1116a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1120" publication-type="other">
—, Johansson, A. and Mira d'Ercole, M. (2006), 'Alternative measures of well-being', OECD
Economics Department, Working Paper no. 476.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1130a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1134" publication-type="other">
Christian, D. E. (1974), 'International social indicators: the OECD experience', Social
Indicators Research, vol. l,pp. 169-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1144a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1148" publication-type="other">
Clark, A., Frijters, P. and Shields, M. A. (2008), 'A survey of the income happiness gradient',
Journal of Economic Literature, vol. 46, pp. 95-144.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1158a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1162" publication-type="other">
Crocker, D. A. (1992), 'Functioning and capability: the foundations of Sen's and Nussbaum's
development ethic', Political Theory, vol. 20, pp. 584-612.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1173a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1177" publication-type="other">
Decancq, K. and Lugo, M. A. (2012), 'Weights in multidimensional indices of wellbeing: an
overview', Econometric Reviews, vol. 32, pp. 7-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1187a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1191" publication-type="other">
Di Telia, R. and MacCulloch, R. (2004), 'Happiness adaption to income beyond "basic
needs'", in E. Diener, J. Helliwell and D. Kahneman (eds), International Differences in
Weil-Being, New York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1204a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1208" publication-type="other">
Dolan, P., Peasgood, T. and White, M. (2008), 'Do we really know what makes us happy? A
review of the economic literature on the factors associated with subjective well-being',
Journal of Economic Psychology, vol. 29, pp. 94-122.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1221a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1225" publication-type="other">
Easterlin, R. and Angelescu, L. (2009), 'Happiness and growth the world over: time series
evidence on the happiness-income paradox', Institute for the Study of Labor (IZA),
Discussion Paper no. 4060.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1238a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1242" publication-type="other">
Eurostat (2011), Report of the Sponsorship Group on Measuring Progress, Weil-Being and
Sustainable Development, http://eDp.eurostat.ec.europa.eu/portal/page/portal/pgp ess/
0 DOCS/estat/SpG progress wellbeing report after ESSC adoption 22Novl.pdf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1255a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1259" publication-type="other">
Fleche, S., Smith, C. and Sorsa, P. (2011), 'Exploring determinants of subjective wellbeing in
OECD countries: evidence from the World Value Survey', OECD Economics
Department, Working Paper no. 921.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1273a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1277" publication-type="other">
Fleurbaey, M. (2006), 'Capabilities, functionings and refined functionings', Journal of
Human Development, vol. 7, pp. 299-310.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1287a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1291" publication-type="other">
— (2009), 'Beyond GDP: the quest for a measure of social welfare', Journal of Economic
Literature, vol. 47, pp. 1029-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1301a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1305" publication-type="other">
— and Gauliier, G. (2009), 'International comparisons of living standards by income
equivalent', Scandinavian Journal of Economics, vol. 111, pp. 597-624.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1319" publication-type="other">
Furnée, C. A., Groot, W. and Pfann, G. A. (2010), 'Health and income: a meta-analysis to
explore cross-country, gender and age differences', European Journal of Public Health,
vol. 21, pp. 775-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1332a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1336" publication-type="other">
Gardner, J. and Oswald, A. J. (2007), 'Money and mental well-being: a longitudinal study of
medium-sized lottery wins', Journal of Health Economics, vol. 26, pp. 49-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1346a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1350" publication-type="other">
Hagerty, M. R. and Land, K. C. (2007), 'Constructing summary indices of quality of life: a
model for the effect of heterogeneous importance weights', Sociological Methods and
Research, vol. 35, pp. 455-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1364a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1368" publication-type="other">
Helliwell, J. (2003), 'How's life? Combining individual and national variables to explain
subjective well-being', Economic Modelling, vol. 20, pp. 331-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1378a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1382" publication-type="other">
Holloway, S., Short, S. and Tamplin, S. (2002), Household Satellite Account (Experimental)
Methodology, London: Office for National Statistics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1392a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1396" publication-type="other">
Jones, C. I. and Klenow, P. J. (2010), 'Beyond GDP? Welfare across countries and time',
National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER), Working Paper no. 16352.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1406a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1410" publication-type="other">
Kahneman, D. and Deaton, A. (2010), 'High income improves evaluation of life but not
emotional well-being', Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United
States of America, vol. 107, pp. 16489-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1423a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1427" publication-type="other">
Kuznets, S. (1934), National Income 1929-32, New York: National Bureau of Economic
Research.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1437a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1441" publication-type="other">
Nordhaus, W. D. and Tobin, J. (1973), 'Is growth obsolete?', in M. Moss (ed.), The
Measurement of Economic and Social Performance, Studies in Income and Wealth, vol.
38, Cambridge, MA: National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1455a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1459" publication-type="other">
Nussbaum, M. (2011), Creating Capabilities: The Human Development Approach,
Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1469a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1473" publication-type="other">
OECD (1982), The OECD List of Social Indicators, Paris: OECD Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1480a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1484" publication-type="other">
— (1986), Living Conditions in OECD Countries: Compendium of Social Indicators, Paris:
OECD Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1494a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1498" publication-type="other">
— (2008a), Growing Unequal? Income Distribution and Poverty in OECD Countries, Paris:
OECD Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1508a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1512" publication-type="other">
— (2008b), Handbook on Constructing Composite Indicators, Paris: OECD Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1519a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1523" publication-type="other">
— (2008c), Statistics, Knowledge and Policy 2007: Measuring and Fostering the Progress of
Societies, Paris: OECD Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1534a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1538" publication-type="other">
— (2010), PISA 2009 Results: Overcoming Social Background - Equity in Learning
Opportunities and Outcomes, Paris: OECD Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1548a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1552" publication-type="other">
— (201 la), How's Life? Measuring Weil-Being, Paris: OECD Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1559a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1563" publication-type="other">
— (201 lb), Divided We Stand: Why Inequality Keeps Rising, Paris: OECD Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1570a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1574" publication-type="other">
Ravallion, M. (2011), 'On multidimensional indices of poverty', Journal of Economic
Inequality, vol. 9, pp. 235^18.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1584a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1588" publication-type="other">
Ruiz, N. (2011), 'Measuring the joint distribution of household's income, consumption and
wealth using nested Atkinson measures', OECD Statistics Directorate, Working Paper no.
2011/5.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1601a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1605" publication-type="other">
Sacks, D. W., Stevenson, B. and Wolfers, J. (2010), 'Subjective well-being, income,
economic development and growth', National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER),
Working Paper no. 16441.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1619a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1623" publication-type="other">
Sen, A. (1985), Commodities and Capabilities, Amsterdam: North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1630a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1634" publication-type="other">
— (1998), Development as Freedom, Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1641a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1645" publication-type="other">
Sharpe, A. (2011), 'The weighting issues in composite indicators: the experience of the Index
of Economic Well-Being', paper prepared for the 2011 World Statistics Congress.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1655a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1659" publication-type="other">
— and Andrews, B. (2011), 'The weighting issues in composite indicators: an assessment of
the Index of Economic Well-Being', paper presented to the International Statistical
Institute Conference, 21-26 August, Dublin.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1672a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1676" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz, J. (2010), Freefall: America, Free Markets, and the Sinking of the World Economy,
London: W. W. Norton.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1686a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1690" publication-type="other">
—, Sen, A. and Fitoussi, J-P. (2009), Mismeasuring Our Lives: Why GDP Doesn't Add Up,
Report by the Commission on the Measurement of Economic Performance and Social
Progress, New York: The New Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2541880e1704a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2541880e1708" publication-type="other">
Van Praag, B. M. S., Frijters, P. and Ferrer-i-Carbonell, A. (2003), 'The anatomy of
subjective well-being', Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization, vol. 51, pp. 29-
49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


