<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277801</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effect of Ignition Improvers on the Combustion Performance of Regular-Grade E10 Gasoline in an HCCI Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ji</surname>
                  <given-names>Chunsheng</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Labs.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dec</surname>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Labs.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dernotte</surname>
                  <given-names>Jeremie</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Labs.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cannella</surname>
                  <given-names>William</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chevron USA Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277784</issue-id>
         <fpage>790</fpage>
         <lpage>806</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277801"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This study explores the use of two conventional ignition improvers, 2-ethylhexyl nitrate (EHN) and di-tert-butyl peroxide (DTBP), to enhance the autoignition of the regular gasoline in an homogeneous charge compression ignition (HCCI) engine at naturally aspirated and moderately boosted conditions (up to 180 kPa absolute) with a constant engine speed of 1200 rpm. The results showed that both EHN and DTBP are very effective for reducing the intake temperature (T<sub>in</sub>) required for autoignition and for enhancing stability to allow a higher charge-mass fuel/air equivalence ratio (<italic>ϕ</italic>
               <sub>m</sub>). On the other hand, the addition of these additives can also make the gasoline too reactive at some conditions, so significant exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) is required at these conditions to maintain the desired combustion phasing. Thus, there is a trade-off between improving stability and reducing the oxygen available for combustion when using ignition improvers to extend the high-load limit. Because previous works have shown that partial fuel stratification (PFS) can be applied with more reactive fuels to reduce the heat release rate to allow higher loads or more advanced combustion timing without knock, the potential of the ignition improvers to allow effective PFS was also explored over the same range of intake pressures. The effect of the additives on NOx emissions was also studied. The results showed that NOx emissions increase with increased EHN concentration but are not affected by DTBP. This work indicates that conventional ignition improvers can effectively enhance the HCCI autoignition reactivity of conventional gasoline at naturally aspirated and modestly boosted operations, offering significant benefits for HCCI engines.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>KEYWORDS:</label>
            <kwd>HCCI</kwd>
            <kwd>Autoignition Reactivity</kwd>
            <kwd>Ignition Improvers</kwd>
            <kwd>ITHR</kwd>
            <kwd>PFS</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., Yang, Y., and Dronniou, N., “Boosted HCCI - Controlling Pressure-Rise Rate for Performance Improvements using Partial Fuel Stratification with Conventional Gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1169-1189, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0897.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., Yang, Y., and Dronniou, N., “Improving Efficiency and Using E10 for Higher Loads in Boosted HCCI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1009-1032, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J., Dronniou, N., and Cannella, W., “Boosted HCCI Combustion Using Low-Octane Gasoline with Fully Premixed and Partially Stratified Charges,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1075-1088, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., and Yang, Y., “Boosted HCCI for high power without engine knock and with ultra-low NOx emissions - using conventional gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1): 750-767, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjoberg, M. and Dec, J., “Combined Effects of Fuel-Type and Engine Speed on Intake Temperature Requirements and Completeness of Bulk-Gas Reactions for HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3173, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3173.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Sjoberg, M., “Isolating the Effects of Fuel Chemistry on Combustion Phasing in an HCCI Engine and the Potential of Fuel Stratification for Ignition Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01- 0557, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0557.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Johansson, B., Amneus, P., and Mauss, F., “Supercharged Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 980787, 1998, doi:10.4271/980787.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M. and Johansson, B., “Supercharged Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) with Exhaust Gas Recirculation and Pilot Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1835, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1835.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bessonette, P., Schleyer, C., Duffy, K., Hardy, W. et al., “Effects of Fuel Property Changes on Heavy-Duty HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0191, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0191.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krisman, A., Hawkes, E.R., Kook, S., Sjoberg, M., Dec, J.E., “On the potential of ethanol fuel stratification to extend the high load limit in stratified-charge compression-ignition engines,” Fuel 99: 45-54, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2012.04.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, X., Zheng, M., Wang, J., “Fuel suitability for low temperature combustion in compression ignition engines,” Fuel 109: 336-349, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2013.01.049.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yu, C., Wang, J., Wang, Z., Shuai, S., “Comparative study on Gasoline Homogeneous Charge Induced Ignition (HCII) by diesel and Gasoline/Diesel Blend Fuels (GDBF) combustion,” Fuel 106: 470-477, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2012.10.068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Starck, L., Lecointe, B., Forti, L., Jeuland, N., “Impact of fuel characteristics on HCCI combustion: Performances and emissions,” Fuel 89 (10): 3069-3077, 2010, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2010.05.028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., “Advanced compression-ignition engines-understanding the in-cylinder processes,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 32(2): 2727-2742, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2008.08.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Machrafi, H., Cavadias, S., Gilbert, P., “An experimental and numerical analysis of the HCCI auto-ignition process of primary reference fuels, toluene reference fuels and diesel fuel in an engine, varying the engine parameters,” Fuel Processing Technology 89(11): 1007-1016, 2008, doi:10.1016/j.fuproc.2008.03.007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu, X., Shen, Y., Zhang, Y., Zhou, X., Ji, L., Yang, Z., Huang, Z., “Controlled three-stage heat release of stratified charge compression ignition (SCCI) combustion with a two-stage primary reference fuel supply,” Fuel 90(5): 2026-2038, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2011.01.026.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guidance on Quantifying NOx Benefits for Cetane Improvement Programs for Use in SIPs and Transportation Conformity EPA420-B-04-005, June 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Fuel Effects on Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Combustion at Low Load,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):394-411, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaddatz, J., Andrie, M., Reitz, R., and Kokjohn, S., “Light-Duty Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition Combustion Using a Cetane Improver,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1110, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hosseini, V., Neill, W.S., Guo, H., Chippior, W.L., Fairbridge, C., Mitchell, K., “Effects of different cetane number enhancement strategies on HCCI combustion and emissions,” Int. J. Engine Res. 12: 89-108, 2011, doi:10.1177/1468087410395873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J., Leppard, W., and Sloane, T., “The Effect of Di-Tertiary Butyl Peroxide (DTBP) Addition to Gasoline on HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3170, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01- 3170.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mack, J., Dibble, R., Buchholz, B., and Flowers, D., “The Effect of the Di-Tertiary Butyl Peroxide (DTBP) additive on HCCI Combustion of Fuel Blends of Ethanol and Diethyl Ether,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2135, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gong, X., Johnson, R., Miller, D., and Cernansky, N., “Effects of DTBP on the HCCI Combustion Characteristics of SI Primary Reference Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3740, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3740.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gupta, A., Miller, D., and Cernansky, N., “A Detailed Kinetic Study on the Effect of DTBP on PRF Combustion in HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-2002, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thompson, A., Lambert, S., and Mulqueen, S., “Prediction and Precision of Cetane Number Improver Response Equations,” SAE Technical Paper 972901, 1997, doi:10.4271/972901.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ickes, A.M., Bohac, S.V., Assanis, D.N., “Effect of 2- Ethylhexyl Nitrate cetane improver on NOx emissions from premixed lowtemperature diesel combustion,” Energy and Fuels 23 (10): 4943- 4948, 2009, doi:10.1021/ef900408e.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bunting, B.G., Wildman, C.B., Szybist, J.P., Lewis, S., Storey, J., “Fuel chemistry and cetane effects on diesel homogeneous charge compression ignition performance, combustion, and emissions,” Journal of Engine Research 8 (1): 15-27, 2007, doi:10.1243/14680 874JER01306.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Reitz, R., and Hanson, R., “High Efficiency, Low Emissions RCCI Combustion by Use of a Fuel Additive,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(2):742-756, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2167.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J., Dronniou, N., Sjoberg, M., “Tailoring HCCI heat release rates with partial fuel stratification: Comparison of twostage and single-stage ignition fuels,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 33 (2): 3047-3055, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2010.06.114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J., Dronniou, N., Sjoberg, M. et al., “Partial Fuel Stratification to Control HCCI Heat Release Rates: Fuel Composition and Other Factors Affecting Pre-Ignition Reactions of Two-Stage Ignition Fuels,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1903-1920, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1359.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Sjoberg, M., “A Parametric Study of HCCI Combustion - the Sources of Emissions at Low Loads and the Effects of GDI Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0752, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0752.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals. New York: McGraw-Hill; 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J., “Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjoberg, M. and Dec, J., “Ethanol Autoignition Characteristics and HCCI Performance for Wide Ranges of Engine Speed, Load and Boost,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):84-106, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010- 01-0338.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjoberg, M. and Dec, J., “Smoothing HCCI Heat-Release Rates Using Partial Fuel Stratification with Two-Stage Ignition Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0629, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01- 0629.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjoberg, M., Dec, J., Babajimopoulos, A., and Assanis, D., “Comparing Enhanced Natural Thermal Stratification Against Retarded Combustion Phasing for Smoothing of HCCI Heat- Release Rates,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2994, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjoberg, M., Dec, J., “Comparing late-cycle autoignition stability for single- and two-stage ignition fuels in HCCI engines,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 31: 2895-2902, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2006.08.010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
