<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="other"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">3663757</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/380824</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB770108</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Books Received</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>01</month>
            <year>2004</year>
            <string-date>January 2004</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>77</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2004.77.issue-1</issue-id>
         <fpage>201</fpage>
         <lpage>202</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/380824"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <title>Business Economics and Economics</title>
         <p>Collis, Jill, and Roger Hussey. Business Research: A Practical Guide for Undergraduate and Postgraduate Students. 2d ed. New York: Palgrave Macmillan, 2003. Pp. viii+374. $39.95.</p>
         <p>Davenport, Thomas H., and Laurence Prusak, with H. James Wilson. What's the Big Idea? Creating and Capitalizing on the Best Management Thinking. Boston: Harvard Business School Press, 2003. Pp. xi+242. $27.50.</p>
         <p>Gleaser, Edward L. The Governance of Not‐for‐Profit Organizations. Chicago: University of Chicago Press for National Bureau of Economic Research, 2003. Pp. 336. $55.00.</p>
         <p>Kelly, Anthony. Decision Making Using Game Theory: An Introduction for Managers. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2003. Pp. x+204. $40.00.</p>
         <p>Sander, Jennifer Basye, and Peter Sander. Niche and Grow Rich: Practical Ways to Turn Your Ideas into a Business. New York: Entrepreneur Press, 2003. Pp. xii+244. $16.95.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <title>Information Systems</title>
         <p>Cushman, Donald P., and Sarah Sanderson King. Communication Best Practices at Dell, General Electric, Microsoft, and Monsanto. Albany, NY: SUNY Press, 2003. Pp. x+153.</p>
         <p>White, Gary W., ed. The Core Business Web: A Guide to Key Information Resources. New York: Haworth Press, 2003. Pp. 325. $29.95 (paper); $49.95 (cloth).</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <title>International Trade and Finance</title>
         <p>Baldwin, John R., and Petr Hanel. Innovation and Knowledge Creation in an Open Economy: Canadian Industry and International Implications. New York: Cambridge University Press, 2003. Pp. xxvii+512. $100.00.</p>
         <p>Bordo, Michael D., Alan M. Taylor, and Jeffrey G. Williamson, eds. Globalization in Historical Perspective. Chicago: University of Chicago Press for National Bureau of Economic Research, 2003. Pp. ix+588. $95.00; £66.50.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <title>Mathematical Models and Computer Research</title>
         <p>Herzog, Thomas N., and Graham Lord. Applications of Monte Carlo Methods to Finance and Insurance. Winsted, CT: ACTEX Publications, 2002. Pp. xiv+264. With solutions manual.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc5">
         <title>Miscellaneous</title>
         <p>Alexander, James A., and Mark W. Hordes. S‐Business: Reinventing the Services Organization. New York: SelectBooks, 2003. Pp. vii+251. $24.95.</p>
         <p>Aronson, Eric J. Dash. Austin, TX: Turnkey Press, 2003. Pp. 213. $17.95.</p>
         <p>Kingaard, Jan. Start Up: Start Your Own Successful Retail Business. New York: Entrepreneur Press, 2003. Pp. xii+252. $12.95.</p>
         <p>Leeds, Dorothy. Power Speak: Engage, Inspire, and Stimulate Your Audience. Franklin Lakes, NJ: Career Press, 2003. Pp. 286. $15.99.</p>
      </sec>
   </body>
</article>
