<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277526</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investigating the Development of Thermal Stratification from the Near-Wall Regions to the Bulk-Gas in an HCCI Engine with Planar Imaging Thermometry</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dronniou</surname>
                  <given-names>Nicolas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dec</surname>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>1046</fpage>
         <lpage>1074</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277526"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A tracer-based single-line PLIF imaging technique using a unique optical configuration that allows simultaneously viewing the bulk-gas and the boundary layer region has been applied to an investigation of the naturally occurring thermal stratification in a HCCI engine. Thermal stratification is critical for HCCI engines, because it determines the maximum pressure rise rate which is a limiting factor for high-load operation. The investigation is based on the analysis of temperature maps that were derived from PLIF images, using the temperature sensitivity of fluorescence from toluene introduced as tracer in the fuel. Measurements were made in a single-cylinder optically accessible HCCI engine operating under motored conditions with a vertical laser-sheet orientation that allows observation of the development of thermal stratification from the cold boundary layers into the central region of the charge. Sequences of temperature maps acquired at various crank angles were used to analyze the temporal evolution of thermal stratification.</p>
            <p>The temperature maps showed that the thermal stratification in the bulk-gas was not due to a consistent gas flow coming from the cylinder walls or to the transport of isolated cold gas pockets. Rather it is a consequence of cold turbulent structures extending from the firedeck and the piston-top. Furthermore, the cold structures extending from the firedeck appear to be especially important, since they are bigger and penetrate further toward the central region of the charge than those from the piston top. Comparison with previous measurements made in the horizontal mid-plane with the same optical engine showed a good agreement. However, these side-view measurements extend this previous work by highlighting new patterns which were impossible to identify with a bottom-view setup. Beyond the qualitative analysis of temperature fields, quantitative measurements of the thermal stratification are also provided both in terms of magnitude and characteristic dimensions of cold pockets.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J., and Cernansky, N., “Potential of Thermal Stratification and Combustion Retard for Reducing Pressure-Rise Rates in HCCI Engines, Based on Multi-Zone Modeling and Experiments,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0113, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0113.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J. E., Dronniou, N., and Sjöberg, M., “Tailoring HCCI Heat Release Rates with Partial Fuel Stratification: Comparison of Two- Stage and Single-Stage Ignition Fuels,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 33(2):3047-3055, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., Hwang, W., and Sjöberg, M., “An Investigation of Thermal Stratification in HCCI Engines Using Chemiluminescence Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1518, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1518.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Einecke, S., Schulz, C., Sick, V., Dreizler, A. et al., “Two-Dimensional Temperature Measurements in an SI Engine Using Two-Line Tracer LIF,” SAE Technical Paper 982468, 1998, doi: 10.4271/982468.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rothamer, D., Snyder, J., Hanson, R., and Steeper, R., “Two- Wavelength PLIF Diagnostic for Temperature and Composition,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):520-533, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1067.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rothamer, D. A., Snyder, J. A., Hanson, R. K., and Steeper, R. R., “Optimization of a Tracer-based PLIF Diagnostic for Simultaneous Imaging of EGR and Temperature in IC Engines,” Appl Phys B 99:371-384, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Snyder, J., Hanson, R., Fitzgerald, R., and Steeper, R., “Dual- Wavelength PLIF Measurements of Temperature and Composition in an Optical HCCI Engine with Negative Valve Overlap,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):460-474, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0661.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Löffler, M., Beyrau, F., and Leipertz, A., “Acetone Laser-induced Fluorescence Behavior for the Simultaneous Quantification of Temperature and Residual Gas Distribution in Fired Spark-ignition Engines,” Applied Optics 49(1):37-49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Löffler, M., Kröckel, K., Koch, P., Beyrau, F. et al., “Simultaneous Quantitative Measurements of Temperature and Residual Gas Fields Inside a Fired SI-Engine Using Acetone Laser-Induced Fluorescence,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0656, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0656.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fujikawa, T., Fukui, K., Hattori, Y., and Akihama, K., “2-D Temperature Measurements of Unburned Gas Mixture in an Engine by Two-line Excitation LIF Technique,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3336, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3336.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kakuho, A., Nagamine, M., Amenomori, Y., Urushihara, T. et al., “In- Cylinder Temperature Distribution Measurement and Its Application to HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1202, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-1202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Devillers, R., Bruneaux, G., and Schulz, C., “Investigation of Toluene LIF at High Pressure and High Temperature in an Optical Engine,” Appl Phys B 96:735-739, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Luong, M., Zhang, R., Schulz, C., and Sick, V., “Toluene Laser-induced Fluorescence for In-cylinder Temperature Imaging in Internal Combustion Engines,” Appl Phys B 91:669-675, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Hwang, W., “Characterizing the Development of Thermal Stratification in an HCCI Engine Using Planar-Imaging Thermometry,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):421-438, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0650.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Snyder, J., Dronniou, N., Dec, J., and Hanson, R., “PLIF Measurements of Thermal Stratification in an HCCI Engine under Fired Operation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1669-1688, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1291.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Snyder, J. A., Dronniou, N., Dec, J. E., and Hanson, R. K., “Development of Ketone-based PLIF Temperature Diagnostics for Application in HCCI Engines,” Applied Optics (to be submitted), 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Sjöberg, M., “A Parametric Study of HCCI Combustion - the Sources of Emissions at Low Loads and the Effects of GDI Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0752, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-0752.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hwang, W., Dec, J., and Sjöberg, M., “Fuel Stratification for Low-Load HCCI Combustion: Performance &amp; Fuel-PLIF Measurements,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4130, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-4130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koban, W., Koch, J., Hanson, R. K., and Schulz, C., “Absorption and Fluorescence of Toluene Vapor at Elevated Temperatures,” Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 6(11):2940-2945, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strozzi, C., Sotton, J., Mura, A., and Bellenoue, M., “Characterization of a Two-dimensional Temperature Field within a Rapid Compression Machine using a Toluene Planar laser-induced Fluorescence Imaging Technique,” Meas. Sci. Technol. 20:125403, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schulz, C. and Sick, V., “Tracer-LIF Diagnostics: Quantitative Measurement of Fuel Concentration, Temperature and Fuel/air Ratio in Practical Combustion Systems,” Prog. Energy Comb. Sci. 31:75-121, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “An Investigation of the Relationship Between Measured Intake Temperature, BDC Temperature, and Combustion Phasing for Premixed and DI HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1900, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1900.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
