<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</issue>
         <issue-id>i40038998</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40865572</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Credit Line Usage, Checking Account Activity, and Default Risk of Bank Borrowers</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Lars</given-names>
                  <surname>Norden</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
                  <surname>Weber</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2010</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>3665</fpage>
         <lpage>3699</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40865572"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Information on borrower quality is a fundamental issue in debt contracting, corporate and consumer finance, and financial intermediation. We investigate the link between account activity and information production on borrower risk. Based on a unique data set, we find that credit line usage, limit violations, and cash inflows exhibit abnormal patterns approximately 12 months before default events. Measures of account activity substantially improve default predictions and are especially helpful for monitoring small businesses and individuals. Furthermore, early warning indications result in higher loan spreads, and in a higher likelihood of limit reductions and complete write-offs. Our study shows that account activity provides a real-time window into the borrower's cash flows, thus explaining why banks have an advantage in providing certain types of debt financing.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d78e238a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e245" publication-type="other">
(Berlin and Mester 1999;</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e251" publication-type="other">
Kashyap,
Rajan, and Stein 2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d78e270a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e274" publication-type="other">
Agarwal, S., B. Ambrose, and C. Liu. 2006. Credit Lines and Credit Utilization. Journal of Money, Credit, and
Banking 38:1-22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e284a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e288" publication-type="other">
Agarwal, S., and R. Hauswald. 2007. The Choice between Arm's-length and Relationship Debt: Evidence from
eLoans. Working Paper, Federal Reserve Bank Chicago and American University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e298a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e302" publication-type="other">
Apilado, V., D. Warner, and J. Dauten. 1974. Evaluative Techniques in Consumer Finance-Experimental Results
and Policy Implications for Financial Institutions. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis
9:275-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e319" publication-type="other">
Basel Committee on Banking Supervision. 2006. Basel II: International Convergence of Capital Measurement
and Capital Standards: A Revised Framework.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e330a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e334" publication-type="other">
Berger, A., N. Miller, M. Petersen, R. Rajan, and J. Stein. 2005. Does Function Follow Organizational Form?
Evidence from the Lending Practices of Large and Small Banks. Journal of Financial Economics 76:237-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e344a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e348" publication-type="other">
Berger, A., and G. Udell. 1995. Relationship Lending and Lines of Credit in Small Firm Finance. Journal of
Business 68:351-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e358a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e362" publication-type="other">
--- . 2006. A More Complete Conceptual Framework for SME Finance. Journal of Banking and Finance
30:2945-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e372a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e376" publication-type="other">
Berlin, M., and L. Mester. 1999. Deposits and Relationship Lending. Review of Financial Studies 12:579-607.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e383a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e387" publication-type="other">
Bharath, S., S. Dahiya, A. Saunders, and A. Srinivasan. 2007. So What Do I Get? The Bank's View of Lending
Relationships. Journal of Financial Economics 85:368-419.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e397a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e401" publication-type="other">
Black, F. 1975. Bank Funds Management in an Efficient Market. Journal of Financial Economics 2:323-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e409a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e413" publication-type="other">
Blackwell, D., and D. Winters. 1997. Banking Relationships and the Effect of Monitoring in Loan Pricing.
Journal of Financial Research 20:275-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e423a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e427" publication-type="other">
Boot, A. 2000. Relationship Banking: What Do We Know? Journal of Financial Intermediation 9:7-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e434a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e438" publication-type="other">
Boyd, J., and E. Prescott. 1986. Financial Intermediary-Coalitions. Journal of Economic Theory 38:21 1-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e445a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e449" publication-type="other">
Chakravarty, S., and J. Scott. 1999. Relationships and Rationing in Consumer Loans. Journal of Business
72:523-44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e459a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e463" publication-type="other">
Cole, R., L. Goldberg, and L. White. 2004. Cookie-cutter versus Character: The Micro Structure of Small-
business Lending by Large and Small Banks. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 39:227-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e473a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e477" publication-type="other">
Degryse, H., and S. Ongena. 2005. Distance, Lending Relationships, and Competition. Journal of Finance
60:231-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e488a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e492" publication-type="other">
Deutsche Bundesbank. 2008. Statistics on Payment Systems in Germany. January.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e499a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e503" publication-type="other">
Diamond, D. W. 1984. Financial Intermediation and Delegated Monitoring. Review of Economic Studies
51:393-414.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e513a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e517" publication-type="other">
--- . 1991 . Monitoring and Reputation: The Choice Between Bank Loans and Directly Placed Debt. Journal
of Political Economy 99:689-721.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e527a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e531" publication-type="other">
Eisfeld, C. 1935. Kontenanalyse im Dienste der Kreditbeobachtung. Sparkasse 55:333-5.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e538a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e542" publication-type="other">
Elsas, R., and J. Krahnen. 1998. Is Relationship Lending Special? Evidence from Credit-File Data in Germany.
Journal of Banking and Finance 22: 1283-3 16.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e552a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e556" publication-type="other">
Elsas, R. 2005. Empirical Determinants of Relationship Lending. Journal of Financial Intermediation 14:32-57.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e564a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e568" publication-type="other">
Elyasiani, E., and L. Goldberg. 2004. Relationship Lending: A Survey of the Literature. Journal of Economics
and Business 56:3 1 5-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e578a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e582" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. 1985. What's Different about Banks? Journal of Monetary Economics 15:29-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e589a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e593" publication-type="other">
Federal Statistics Office. 2006. Business Register: Enterprises by Employees Liable to Pay Social Insurance
Contributions and Taxable Turnover.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e603a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e607" publication-type="other">
Grunert, J., L. Norden, and M. Weber. 2005. The Role of Non-financial Factors in Internal Credit Ratings.
Journal of Banking and Finance 29:509-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e617a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e621" publication-type="other">
Hackl, P., and A. Schmoll. 1990. Kontodatenanalyse zur Früherkennung von Kreditrisiken. Österreichisches
Bank-Archiv 38:870-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e631a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e635" publication-type="other">
Ho, T, and A. Saunders. 1983. Fixed Rate Loan Commitments, Take-down Risk, and the Dynamcis of Hedging
with Futures. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 1 8:499-516.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e646a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e650" publication-type="other">
Ioannidou, V., and S. Ongena. 2010. Time for a Change: Loan Conditions and Bank Behavior When Firms
Switch. Forthcoming. Journal of Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e660a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e664" publication-type="other">
Jiménez, G., J. Lopez, and J. Saurina. 2009. Empirical Analysis of Corporate Credit Lines. Review of Financial
Studies 22:5069-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e674a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e678" publication-type="other">
Kallberg, J., and G. Udell. 2003. The Value of Private Sector Business Credit Information Sharing: The U.S.
Case. Journal of Banking and Finance 27:449-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e688a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e692" publication-type="other">
Kashyap, A., R. Rajan, and J. Stein. 2002. Banks as Liquidity Providers: An Explanation for the Coexistence of
Lending and Deposit-taking. Journal of Finance 57:33-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e702a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e706" publication-type="other">
Kirschenmann, K., and L. Norden. 2008. The Relation between Borrower Risk and Loan Maturity in Small
Business Lending. Working Paper, University of Mannheim.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e716a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e720" publication-type="other">
Machauer, A., and M. Weber. 1998. Bank Behavior Based on Internal Credit Ratings of Borrowers. Journal of
Banking and Finance 22: 1355-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e731a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e735" publication-type="other">
Melnik, A., and S. Plaut. 1986. Loan Commitment Contracts, Terms of Lending, and Credit Allocation. Journal
of Finance 41:425-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e745a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e749" publication-type="other">
Mester, L., L. Nakamura, and M. Renault. 2007. Transaction Accounts and Loan Monitoring. Review of Finan-
cial Studies 20:529-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e759a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e763" publication-type="other">
Nakamura, L. 1993. Commercial Bank Information: Implications for the Structure of Banking. In Michael
Klausner, and Lawrence J. White (eds.), Structural Change in Banking. Homewood, IL: Business One/Irwin.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e773a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e777" publication-type="other">
Petersen, M. 2004. Information: Hard and Soft. Working Paper, Kellogg Graduate School of Management,
Northwestern University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e787a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e791" publication-type="other">
Petersen, M., and R. Rajan. 1994. The Benefits of Lending Relationships: Evidence from Small Business Data.
Journal of Finance 49:3-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e801a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e805" publication-type="other">
--- . 2002. Does Distance Still Matter? The Information Revolution in Small Business Lending. Journal of
Finance 57:2533-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e816a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e820" publication-type="other">
Rajan, R. 1992. Insiders and Outsiders: The Choice between Informed and Arm's-length Debt. Journal of Fi-
nance 47:1367-406.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e830a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e834" publication-type="other">
Ramakrishnan, R. T., and A. V. Thakor. 1984. Information Reliability and a Theory of Financial Information.
Review of Economic Studies 5 1 :4 15-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e844a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e848" publication-type="other">
Schlüter, B. 2005. Empirische Analyse der Bedeutung interner Informationen von Kreditinstituten für die
Bonitätsprüfung. Aachen: Shaker.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e858a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e862" publication-type="other">
Shockley, R., and A. V. Thakor. 1997. Bank Loan Commitment Contracts: Data, Theory, and Tests. Journal of
Money, Credit, and Banking 29:517-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e872a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e876" publication-type="other">
Sufi, A. 2009. Bank Lines of Credit in Corporate Finance: An Empirical Analysis. Review of Financial Studies
22:1057-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e886a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e890" publication-type="other">
Treacy, W., and M. Carey. 2000. Credit Risk Rating Systems at Large U.S. Banks. Journal of Banking and
Finance 24:167-201.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e901a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e905" publication-type="other">
Vale, B. 1993. The Dual Role of Demand Deposits under Asymmetric Information. Scandinavian Journal of
Economics 95:77-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e915a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e919" publication-type="other">
Von Stein, J. 1983. Früherkennung von Kreditrisiken mit quantitativen Methoden. Betriebswirtschaftliche Blätter
57:367-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


