<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26142250</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>How Risky Is Consumption in the Long-Run? Benchmark Estimates from a Robust Estimator</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Ian</given-names>
                  <surname>Dew-Becker</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>2017</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">30</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i26142242</issue-id>
         <fpage>631</fpage>
         <lpage>666</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/26142250"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The long-run standard deviation (LRSD) of consumption growth is a key moment in determining risk premiums under Epstein-Zin preferences. Standard estimators of the LRSD are biased downward and have poor confidence interval coverage, making them overreject the long-run risk model. This paper studies a new estimator with smaller bias and accurate confidence intervals. Standard long-run risk calibrations are still rejected in the data. The LRSD of consumption growth in the postwar sample is estimated to be 2.5% per year with an upper bound to the 95% confidence interval of 4.9%. These values can be taken as benchmarks for future calibrations.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1139e288a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e295" publication-type="other">
0 is approximately equal to the time discount factor in the agent's utility function. The approximation is obtained
from Restoy and Weil (2011).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e305a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e312" publication-type="other">
Equation ( 1 ) is exact when p = 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e319a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e326" publication-type="other">
I restrict my attention to nonparametric methods both because they are generally robust to heteroscedasticity and
nonnormality in ways that parametric methods often are not and because they take seriously the fact that we do
not know the true dynamic process driving consumption growth.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e339a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e346" publication-type="other">
See, recently, Tallarini (2000), Barro (2006), and Gourio (2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e354a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e361" publication-type="other">
Kaltenbrunner and Lochstoer (2010) study a range of different calibrations, but the one with an LRSD of 8.22
seems to fit the data best.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e371a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e378" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Harvey (1985), Clark (1987), Poterba and Summers (1988), Lo and MacKinlay (1988),
Cochrane (1988, 1994), Cochrane and Sbordone (1988), and Morley (2007).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e388a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e395" publication-type="other">
Suppose ACt = fi+B(L)st, where et is a j x 1 vector, and B(L)=J2k^oBk^k» where is a 1 xy vector. The
calculation of the covariances and LRSD then yield the same result that the LRSD is equal to /(0)1/2.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e405a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e412" publication-type="other">
Andrews (1991) examines kernels with negative weight at certain frequencies, and Politis and Romano (1995)
give an extensive analysis. However, in neither of those cases is a minimum-variance unbiased kernel derived.
Gasser, Muller, and Mammitzsch (1985) also discuss the RQS kernel as a second-order optimal kernel, but not in
the context of spectral density estimation. They do not provide a sampling distribution, and they do not examine
its performance in simulations or empirical analyses.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e431a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e438" publication-type="other">
The theorem in Brillinger ( 1981 ) has a small typo: the denominator should not be squared. Referring to Brillinger's
Appendix, the result is derived using the continuous mapping theorem applied to the result that the periodogram
ordinates are asymptotically independent x\ /2 random variables.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e451a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e458" publication-type="other">
Brillinger (1969) derives the asymptotic distribution of the multivariate periodogram and shows that it follows
a Wishart distribution that is independent across frequencies with scale matrix equal to fxx&amp;) (where fxx
is the multivariate spectral density matrix). Since /xx(0) has rank 1 when output and consumption growth
are cointegrated, the periodogram ordinates local to zero are perfectly correlated. A similar result holds under
Midler's (2007) asymptotics.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e478a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e485" publication-type="other">
VMuellerJ isdeûaedas(oMueuerj=j 1 £jj_, /g, where xj =&lt;Jij)2 (t 1 Yj=i KrVäsinO'jrf/r)) and ut =
T~l/ T?j=l Acj• Here, t formula for xj differs slightly from Midler's (2007) because his paper assumes the
data are not demeaned. When the data are demeaned, the trigonometric transforms must be the eigenfunctions
for a Brownian bridge (Phillips 1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e501a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e508" publication-type="other">
The estimator in Müller (2007) is positive-semidefinite, so it can be expected to inherit the bias that the other
positive-semidefinite estimators have. And, in fact, his reported simulation results show that for persistent time
series, his estimator is biased downward. On the other hand, Müller (2007) shows that the KLT-based estimator
is robust to contaminations in models that the usual Newey-West estimator is not. His estimator is designed
to be robust and optimize a bias/variance trade-off in the presence of those contaminations in the class of
positive-semidefinite estimators.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e531a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e538" publication-type="other">
The ARMA( 1,1) model is chosen because it is sufficiently flexible to fit a wide range of shapes for the spectral
density (as opposed to a low-order AR or MA model). It is also preferred in the empirical analysis below according
to the Bayesian information criterion. The ARCH(4) specification for the residuals is implemented to help control
for heteroscedasticity. To correct for potential bias in the estimator, and to obtain robust confidence intervals, I
construct a bootstrapped sampling distribution of the estimate of the long-run variance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e557a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e564" publication-type="other">
Given values for LRSD, std(Act), and corr (Act, Act_i ), the parameters p, &lt;pe, and o2 are identified. To study
the effects of a change in the LRSD, I hold std (Act) and corr(Ac/, Ac,_i) fixed at their original values from
Bansal and Yaron (2004) and solve for the implied values of p, &lt;pe, and o2 given a value of the LRSD. In Bansal
and Yaron's calibration, std(Act)=0.00S0 and corr [Act, Acf_i) =0.043. The calibration is in monthly terms,
so std (Act ) corresponds to an annualized standard deviation of 2.76%. Note that in the simulations we retain the
original specification for stochastic volatility, and its persistence and volatility (uj and aw) are held fixed at their
original values. The original calibration is p=0.979, &lt;pe~0.044, a2 =0.00782, v\ =0.987, and ow =0.0000232.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e590a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e597" publication-type="other">
I also ran similar simulations using sample sizes corresponding to the longer periods available in annual data.
The results are not reported here, but they yield qualitatively similar conclusions. Quantitatively, with the longer
samples every estimator has better confidence interval coverage and less bias.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e610a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e617" publication-type="other">
It is perhaps surprising that the ARM A( 1,1 )-ARCH(4) model performs so poorly. The specification of that model
is (\-ßL)Act=(l— 6L)et. The long-run variance is then var(et)[jE~fi) • Since the point estimate of ß can
approach one in the simulations, the distribution of the long-run variance is extremely poorly behaved. To help
control its behavior, I force the estimates of ß to have an upper bound of 0.99, but Figures 2 and 3 show that the
bias, variance, and confidence interval coverage are all poor compared with the nonparametric estimators. The
results are somewhat worse when using asymptotic confidence intervals without the bias correction.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e641a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e648" publication-type="other">
Since all the estimators are biased upward in this case, I examine two-sided instead of one-sided confidence
intervals (with one-sided intervals, all estimators have 100% coverage).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1139e658a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1139e665" publication-type="other">
It is not possible to escape having to choose a bandwidth or a fixed model at some point. Newey and West
(1994) suggest, though, that the selection of the bandwidth in the estimation of the normalized curvature is less
consequential for the final estimates of the LRSD than the selection of the bandwidth for estimating the LRSD
itself, so using an arbitrary choice in the first stage may be more justified.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d1139e690a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e694" publication-type="other">
Abel, A. B. 1990. Asset prices under habit formation and catching up with the joneses. American Economic
Re-view, Papers and Proceedings 80:38-42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e704a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e708" publication-type="other">
Andrews, D. W. 1991. Heteroscedasticity and autocorrelation consistent covariance matrix estimation.
Econometrica 59:817-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e718a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e722" publication-type="other">
Bailie, R. T. 1996. Long memory processes and fractional integration in econometrics. Journal of Econometrics
73:5-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e732a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e736" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., D. Kiku, and A. Yaron. 2010. Long-run risks, the macroeconomy, and asset prices. American Economic
Review 100:542-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e747a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e751" publication-type="other">
. 2012. An empirical evaluation of the long-run risks model for asset prices. Critical Finance Review
1:183-221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e761a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e765" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., and A. Yaron. 2004. Risks for the long run: a potential resolution of asset pricing puzzles. Journal of
Finance 59:1481-1509.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e775a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e779" publication-type="other">
Barberis, N., M. Huang, and T. Santos. 2001. Prospect theory and asset prices. Quarterly Journal of Economics
116:1-53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e789a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e793" publication-type="other">
Barro, R. J. 2006. Rare disasters and asset markets in the twentieth century. Quarterly Journal of Economics
121:823-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e803a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e807" publication-type="other">
Barro, R. J., and J. F. Ursua. 2010. Barro-Ursua macroeconomic dataset. http://scholar.harvard.edu/barro/
publications/barro-ursua-macroeconomic-data.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e817a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e821" publication-type="other">
Beeler, J., and J. Y. Campbell. 2012. The long-run risks model and aggregate asset prices: an empirical assessment.
Critical Finance Review 1:141-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e832a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e836" publication-type="other">
Boldrin, M., L. J. Christiano, and J. D. M. Fisher. 2001. Habit persistence, asset returns, and the business cycle.
American Economic Review 91:149-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e846a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e850" publication-type="other">
Brillinger, D. R. 1969. Asymptotic properties of spectral estimates of second order. Biometrika 56:375-390.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e857a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e861" publication-type="other">
-. 1981. Time series: data analysis and theory. New York: McGraw Hill.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e868a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e872" publication-type="other">
Campanale, C., R. Castro, and G. L. Clementi. 2010. Asset pricing in a production economy with chew-dekel
preferences. Review of Economic Dynamics 13:379^-02.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e882a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e886" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., and J. H. Cochrane. 1999. By force of habit: a consumption-based explanation of aggregate
stock market behavior. Journal of Political Economy 107:205-51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e896a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e900" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., and N. G Mankiw. 1989. Consumption, income and interest rates: reinterpreting the time series
evidence. In NBER Macroeconomics Annual. Eds. O. J. Blanchard and S. Fischer. Cambridge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e911a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e915" publication-type="other">
Christiano, L. J., and T. J. Fitzgerald. 2003. The band pass filter. International Economic Review 44:435-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e922a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e926" publication-type="other">
Clark, P. K. 1987. The cyclical component of u. s. economic activity. Quarterly Journal of Economics 102:797-
814.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e936a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e940" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. H. 1988. How big is the random walk in gnp? Journal of Political Economy 96:893-920.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e947a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e951" publication-type="other">
. 1994. Permanent and transitory components of gnp and stock prices. Quarterly Journal of Economics
109:241-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e961a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e965" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. H., and A. Sbordone. 1988. Multivariate estimates of the permanent components of gnp and stock
prices. Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control 12:255-96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e975a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e979" publication-type="other">
Colacito, R., and M. M. Croce. 2011. Risks for the long run and the real exchange rate. Journal of Political
Economy 119:153-81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e990a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e994" publication-type="other">
Croce, M. M. 2014. Long-run productivity risk: a new hope for production-based asset pricing? Journal of
Monetary Economics 66:13-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1004a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1008" publication-type="other">
Croce, M., M. Lettau, and S. C. Ludvigson. 2010. Investor information, long-run risk, and the duration of risky
cash flows. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1018a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1022" publication-type="other">
Dew-Becker, I., and S. Giglio. 2015. Asset pricing in the frequency domain: theory and empirics. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1029a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1033" publication-type="other">
Drechsler, I., and A. Yaron. 2011. What's vol got to do with it? Review of Financial Studies 24:1^-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1040a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1044" publication-type="other">
Epanechnikov, V. A. 1969. Non-parametric estimation of a multivariate probability density. Theory of Probability
&amp; Its Applications 14:153-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1054a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1058" publication-type="other">
Epstein, L. G, arid S. E. Zin. 1991. Substitution, risk aversion, and the temporal behavior of consumption and
asset returns: an empirical analysis. Journal of Political Economy 99:263-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1069a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1073" publication-type="other">
Gasser, T., H. Muller, and V. Mammitzsch. 1985. Kernels for nonparametric curve estimation. Journal of the
Royal Statistical Society. Series B 47:238-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1083a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1087" publication-type="other">
Gourio, F. 2012. Disaster risk and businesscCycles. American Economic Review 102:2734-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1094a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1098" publication-type="other">
Hansen, L. P., and R. Jagannathan. 1991. Implications of security market data for models of dynamic economies.
Journal of Political Economy 99:225-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1108a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1112" publication-type="other">
Harvey, A. C. 1985. Trends and cycles in macroeconomic time series. Journal of Business &amp; Economic Statistics
3:216-27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1122a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1126" publication-type="other">
Kaltenbrunner, G., and L. A. Lochstoer. 2010. Long-run risk through consumption smoothing. Review of Financial
Studies 23:3141-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1136a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1140" publication-type="other">
Kiefer, N. M., and T. J. Vogelsang. 2005. A new asymptotic theory for heteroscedasticity-autocorrelation robust
tests. Econometric Theory 21:1130-64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1151a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1155" publication-type="other">
Lo, A. W., and A. C. MacKinlay. 1988. Stock market prices do not follow random walks: evidence from a simple
specification test. Review of Financial Studies 1:41-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1165a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1169" publication-type="other">
Mehra, R., and E. C. Prescott. 1985. The equity premium: a puzzle. Journal of Monetary Economics 15:145-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1176a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1180" publication-type="other">
Müller, U. K. 2007. A theory of robust long-run variance estimation. Journal of Econometrics 141:1331-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1187a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1191" publication-type="other">
Morley, J. C. 2007. The slow adjustment of aggregate consumption to permanent income. Journal of Money,
Credit, and Banking 39:615-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1201a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1205" publication-type="other">
Newey, W. K., and K. D. West. 1987. A simple, positive semi-definite, heteroscedasticity and autocorrelation
consistent covariance matrix. Econometrica 55:703-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1215a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1219" publication-type="other">
. 1994. Automatic lag selection in covariance matrix estimation. Review of Economic Studies 61:631-53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1227a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1231" publication-type="other">
Phillips, P. C. 1998. New tools for understanding spurious regressions. Econometrica 66:1299-1325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1238a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1242" publication-type="other">
Politis, D. N., and J. P. Romano. 1995. Bias-corrected nonparametric spectral estimation. Journal of Time Series
Analysis 16:67-103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1252a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1256" publication-type="other">
Porterba, J. M., and L. H. Summers. 1988. Mean reversion in stock prices: evidence and implications. Journal
of Financial Economics 22:27-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1266a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1270" publication-type="other">
Priestley, M. B. 1962. Bias considerations in estimation of spectra. Technometrics 4:551-64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1277a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1281" publication-type="other">
. 1981. Spectral Analysis and Time Series London: Elsevier Academic Press</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1288a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1292" publication-type="other">
Restoy, F., and P. Weil. 2011. Approximate equilibrium asset prices. Review of Finance 15:1-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1300a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1304" publication-type="other">
Tallarini, T. D. 2000. Risk-sensitive real business cycles. Journal of Monetary Economics 45:507-32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1311a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1315" publication-type="other">
Wächter, J. 2013. Can time-varying risk of rare disasters explain aggregate stock market volatility? Journal of
Finance 68:987-1035.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1325a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1329" publication-type="other">
Wand, M., and M. Jones. 1994. Kernel smoothing. Boca Raton, FL: CRC Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1139e1336a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1139e1340" publication-type="other">
Working, H. 1960. Note on the correlation of first differences of averages in a random chain. Econometrica
28:916-18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
