<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277519</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Hydrocarbon Fouling of SCR During PCCI Combustion</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Prikhodko</surname>
                  <given-names>Vitaly Y.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pihl</surname>
                  <given-names>Josh A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lewis</surname>
                  <given-names>Sam A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Parks</surname>
                  <given-names>James E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Oak Ridge National Laboratory</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>947</fpage>
         <lpage>957</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277519"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The combination of advanced combustion with advanced selective catalytic reduction (SCR) catalyst formulations was studied in the work presented here to determine the impact of the unique hydrocarbon (HC) emissions from premixed charge compression ignition (PCCI) combustion on SCR performance. Catalyst core samples cut from full size commercial Fe- and Cu-zeolite SCR catalysts were exposed to a slipstream of raw engine exhaust from a 1.9-liter 4-cylinder diesel engine operating in conventional and PCCI combustion modes. The zeolites which form the basis of these catalysts are different with the Cu-based catalyst made on a chabazite zeolite which las smaller pore structures relative to the Fe-based catalyst. Subsequent to exposure, bench flow reactor characterization of performance and hydrocarbon release and oxidation enabled evaluation of overall impacts from the engine exhaust. The Fe-zeolite NO<sub>X</sub>conversion efficiency was significantly degraded, especially at low temperatures (&lt;250°C), after the catalyst was exposed to the raw engine exhaust. The degradation of the Fe-zeolite performance was similar for both combustion modes. The Cu-zeolite showed better tolerance to HC fouling at low temperatures compared to the Fe-zeolite but PCCI exhaust had a more significant impact than the exhaust from conventional combustion on the NO<sub>X</sub>conversion efficiency. Furthermore, chemical analysis of the hydrocarbons trapped on the SCR cores was conducted to better determine chemistry specific effects.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Okude, K., Mori, K., Shiino, S., and Moriya, T., “Premixed Compression Ignition (PCI) Combustion for Simultaneous Reduction of NOx and Soot in Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1907, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, S., Prikhodko, V., Cho, K., Sluder, C. et al., “In-Cylinder Fuel Blending of Gasoline/Diesel for Improved Efficiency and Lowest Possible Emissions on a Multi-Cylinder Light-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2206, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fujdala, K., Truex, T., Nicholas, J., and Woo, J., “Rational Design of Oxidation Catalysts for Diesel Emission Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0070, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0070.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montreuil, C. and Lambert, C., “The Effect of Hydrocarbons on the Selective Catalyzed Reduction of NOx over Low and High Temperature Catalyst Formulations,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):495-504, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-1030.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Girard, J., Snow, R., Cavataio, G., and Lambert, C., “Influence of Hydrocarbon Storage on the Durability of SCR Catalysts,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0767, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0767.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Devarakonda, M., Tonkyn, R., and Herling, D., “Hydrocarbon Effect on a Fe-zeolite Urea-SCR Catalyst: An Experimental and Modeling Study,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1171, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1171.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prikhodko, V., Pihl, J., Lewis, S. and Parks, J., “Effect of Hydrocarbon Emissions from PCCI-type Combustion on the Performance of Selective Catalytic Reduction Catalysts”, ASME Technical Paper Series, ICEF2011-60129 (2011)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grossale, A., Nova, I., and Tronconi, E., “Study of a Fe-zeolite-based system as NH3-SCR catalyst for diesel exhaust aftertreatment”, Catalyst Today, 136, pp. 18-27 (2008)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fedeyko, J., Chen, H., Ballinger, T., Weigert, E. et al., “Development of Thermally Durable Cu/SCR Catalysts,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0899, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CLEERS is an acronym for “Cross-cut Lean Exhaust Emission Reduction Simulation” and is a U.S. Department of Energy sponsored consortium of industry, national laboratory, and university researchers focused on developing computational simulations for lean emission control technologies. For more information, visit www.cleers.org.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kenney, T., Gardner, T., Low, S., Eckstrom, J. et al., “Overall Results: Phase I Ad Hoc Diesel Fuel Test Program,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0151, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sluder, C., Wagner, R., Storey, J., and Lewis, S., “Implications of Particulate and Precursor Compounds Formed During High- Efficiency Clean Combustion in a Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3844, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3844.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sluder, C. and Wagner, R., “An Estimate of Diesel High-Efficiency Clean Combustion Impacts on FTP-75 Aftertreatment Requirements,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3311, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3311.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
