<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26168982</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Optimization of Rule-Based Control Strategy for a Hydraulic-Electric Hybrid Light Urban Vehicle Based on Dynamic Programming</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lin</surname>
                  <given-names>Xianke</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ivanco</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrej</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Filipi</surname>
                  <given-names>Zoran</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Univ of Michigan</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>June 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26168958</issue-id>
         <fpage>249</fpage>
         <lpage>259</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26168982"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper presents a low-cost path for extending the range of small urban pure electric vehicles by hydraulic hybridization. Energy management strategies are investigated to improve the electric range, component efficiencies, as well as battery usable capacity. As a starting point, a rule-based control strategy is derived by analysis of synergistic effects of lead-acid batteries, high efficient operating region of DC motor and the hydraulic pump/motor. Then, Dynamic Programming (DP) is used as a benchmark to find the optimal control trajectories for DC motor and Hydraulic Pump/Motor. Implementable rules are derived by studying the optimal control trajectories from DP. With new improved rules implemented, simulation results show electric range improvement due to increased battery usable capacity and higher average DC motor operating efficiency.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">2001 National Household Travel Survey, Bureau of Transportation Statistics, US Department of Transportation. See also: http://www.bts.gov/programs/national_household_travel_survey/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shafer, A., Victor, DG. The future mobility of the world population. Transportation Research Record A 2000;34(3):171-205.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Filipi, Z., Loucas, L., Daran, B., Lin, C-C., Yildir, U., Wu, B., Kokkolaras, M., Assanis, D., Peng, H., Papalambros, P., Stein, J., Szkubiel, D., Chapp, R., “Combined Optimization of Design and Power Management of the Hydraulic Hybrid Propulsion System for the 6×6 Medium Truck”, International Journal of Heavy Vehicle Systems, Vol. 11, Nos. 3/4, 2004, pp. 371-401</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, Y. and Filipi, Z., “Simulation Study of a Series Hydraulic Hybrid Propulsion System for a Light Truck,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4151, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-4151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woon, M., Lin, X., Ivanco, A., Moskalik, A. et al., “Energy Management Options for an Electric Vehicle with Hydraulic Regeneration System,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0868, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0868.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pourmovahed, A., Beachley, N., Fronczak, F., “Modeling of a Hydraulic Energy Regeneration System- Part I: Analytical Treatment” Journal of Dynamic System, Measurement, and Control, vol. 114, pp. 155-159, March 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Doerffel, D., Sharkh, S-A., “A critical review of using the Peukert equation for determining the remaining capacity of lead-acid and lithium-ion batteries”, Journal of Power Sources, vol. 155, issue 2, pp. 395-400, 21 April 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ceraolo, M., “New Dynamical Models of Lead-Acid Battery”, IEEE Transactions on Power Systems, vol. 15, no. 4, pp. 1184-1190, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caumont, O., Le Moigne, P., Rombaut, C., Muneret, X., Lenain, P., “Energy Gauge for Lead-Acid batteries in Electric Vehicles”, IEEE Transactions on Energy Conversion, vol. 15, no. 3, pp. 354-360, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Drouilhet, S., Johnson, B.L., “A Battery Life Prediction Method for Hybrid Power Applications,” 35th AIAA Aerospace Sciences Meeting and Exhibit, Reno, Nevada January 6-9, 1997</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Culpin, B., Rand, D., “Failure modes of lead/acid batteries,” Journal of Power Sources, vol. 36, pp. 415-438, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.-C., Kang, J.-M., Grizzle, J.W., Peng, H., “Energy Management Strategy for a Parallel Hybrid Electric Truck”, Proceedings of the American Control Conference, v 4, p 2878-2883, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.-C., Peng, H., Grizzle, J.W., “A stochastic control strategy for hybrid electric vehicles”, 2004, Proceedings the 2004 American Control Conference, Boston, v 5, pp. 4710-4715</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundström, O., Guzzella, L., “A generic dynamic programming Matlab function”, 2009, Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Control Applications, pp. 1625-1630</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
