<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939356</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Investment in K-12 Education</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effect of Education Spending on Student Achievement</article-title>
            <subtitle>Evidence from Property Values and School Finance Rules</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Miller</surname>
                  <given-names>Corbin L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>121</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939356"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Opportunities to estimate the causal effect of school spending on student achievement are infrequent and have been based, almost entirely, on variation in spending from large school finance reforms. Property values also affect school spending through both local property tax revenue and the level of state aid provided to each school district. However, little is known about the effect property values have on student achievement through their impact on school revenue. In this paper, I estimate the effect of education spending on district-level student outcomes in 24 states by leveraging changes in revenue driven by property value variation. I interact state-level changes in property values with fixed school finance formulas that measure how state aid and local revenue respond to those changes to create a simulated instrument for school spending. By collecting administrative data on property values for over 7,000 school districts, I am able to measure a leave-one-out mean change in property values for school districts in each state. The instrument is highly predictive of changes in revenue and spending. My estimates suggest that a 10 percent increase in spending improves graduation rates by 2.1 to 4.4 percentage points and student test scores by 0.05 to 0.09 standard deviations. These results suggest that market variation in property values affects student outcomes through existing school finance formulas.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Angrist, Joshua D. and Victor Lavy (1999). "Using Maimonides' Rule To Estimate The E ect Of Class Size On Scholastic Achievement." Quarterly Journal of Economics, 114(2):533–575.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Bartik, Timothy J. (1991). Who Benefits from State and Local Economic Development Policies? W.E. Upjohn Institute for Employment Research, Kalamazoo, Michigan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Bayer, Patrick; Fernando Ferreira; and Robert McMillan (2007). "A Unified Framework for Measuring Preferences for Schools and Neighborhoods." Journal of Political Economy, 115(4):588-638.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Black, Sandra E. (1999). "Do Better Schools Matter? Parental Valuation Of Elementary Education." Quarterly Journal of Economics, 114(2):577-599.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bowles, Samuel and Henry M. Levin (1968). "The Determinants of Scholastic Achievement- An Appraisal of Some Recent Evidence." The Journal of Human Resources, 3(1):3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Cain, Glen G. and Harold W. Watts (1970). "Problems in Making Policy Inferences from the Coleman Report." American Sociological Review, 35(2):228.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Candelaria, Christopher A. and Kenneth A. Shores (2017). "Court-Ordered Finance Reform on Spending and Graduation Rates." Forthcoming, Education Finance and Policy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Card, David and Abigail A. Payne (2002). "School finance reform, the distribution of school spending, and the distribution of student test scores." Journal of Public Economics, 83(1):49-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Cellini, Stephanie Riegg; Fernando Ferreira; and Jesse Rothstein (2010). "The Value of School Facility Investments: Evidence from a Dynamic Regression Discontinuity Design." Quarterly Journal of Economics, 125(1):215-261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Chetty, Raj; John N. Friedman; Nathaniel Hilger; Emmanuel Saez; Diane Whitmore Schanzenbach; and Danny Yagan (2011). "How Does Your Kindergarten Classroom A ect Your Earnings? Evidence from Project Star." Quarterly Journal of Economics, 126(4):1593-1660.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Clark, Melissa A. (2003). "Education reform, redistribution, and student achievement: Evidence from the Kentucky Education Reform Act." Unpublished working paper, Mathe- matica Policy Research, (October).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Coleman, James S.; Ernest Q. Campbell; Carol J. Hobson; Jame McPartland; Alexander M. Mood; Frederic D. Weinfeld; and Robert L. York (1966). Equality of Educational Oppor-tunity. U.S. Government Printing Office, Washington D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Cragg, John G. and Stephen G. Donald (1993). "Testing Identiability and Specification in Instrumental Variable Models." Econometric Theory, 9(2):222-240.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Davis, Matthew and Fernando Ferreira (2017). "Housing Disease and Public School Finances." Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Downes, Thomas A.; Richard F. Dye; and Therese J. McGuire (1998). "Do Limits Matter? Evidence on the E ects of Tax Limitations on Student Performance." Journal of Urban Economics, 43(3):401-417.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Figlio, David N. (1998). "Short-Term E ects of a 1990s-Era Property Tax Limit: Panel Evidence on Oregon's Measure 5." National Tax Journal, 51(1):55-70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Figlio, David N. and Kim S. Rueben (2001). "Tax limits and the qualifications of new teachers." Journal of Public Economics, 80(1):49-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Gordon, Nora and Brian Knight (2009). "A spatial merger estimator with an application to school district consolidation." Journal of Public Economics, 93(5-6):752-765.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Guryan, Jonathan (2001). "Does Money Matter? Regression-Discontinuity Estimates from Education Finance Reform in Massachusetts."</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Hanushek, Eric A. (2003). "The Failure of Input-Based Schooling Policies." The Economic Journal, 113(485):F64-F98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Hong, Kai and Ron Zimmer (2016). "Does Investing in School Capital Infrastructure Improve Student Achievement?" Economics of Education Review, 53:143-158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Hoxby, Caroline M. (2000). "The E ects Of Class Size On Student Achievement: New Evidence From Population Variation." Quarterly Journal of Economics, 115(4):1239–1285.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Hoxby, Caroline M. (2001). "All School Finance Equalizations Are Not Created Equal." Quarterly Journal of Economics, 116(4):1189-1231.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Hyman, Joshua (2017). "Does Money Matter in the Long Run? E ects of School Spending on Educational Attainment." Forthcoming, American Economic Journal: Economic Policy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Jackson, C. Kirabo; Rucker C. Johnson; and Claudia Persico (2016). "The E ects of School Spending on Educational and Economic Outcomes: Evidence from School Finance Reforms." The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 131(1):157-218.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Kleibergen, Frank and Richard Paap (2006). "Generalized reduced rank tests using the singular value decomposition." Journal of Econometrics, 133(1):97-126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Krueger, Alan B. (1999). "Experimental Estimates Of Education Production Functions." Quarterly Journal of Economics, 114(2):497-532.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Krueger, Alan B. (2003). "Economic Considerations and Class Size." The Economic Journal, 113:F34-F63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Krueger, Alan B. and Diane M. Whitmore (2001). "The E ect of Attending a Small Class in the Early Grades on College-Test Taking and Middle School Test Results: Evidence from Project STAR." Economic Journal, 111(468):1-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Lafortune, Julien; Jesse Rothstein; and Diane Whitmore Schanzenbach (2018). "School Finance Reform and the Distribution of Student Achievement." American Economic Jour- nal: Applied Economics, 10(2):1-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Martorell, Paco; Kevin Stange; and Isaac McFarlin (2016). "Investing in schools: capital spending, facility conditions, and student achievement." Journal of Public Economics, 140:13-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Mosteller, Frederick and Daniel P. Moynihan (1972). On Equality of Educational Opportu- nity. Vintage Books, New York, 1st edition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Murray, Sheila E; William N Evans; and Robert M Schwab (1998). "Education-Finance Reform and the Distribution of Education Resources." American Economic Review, 88(4):789-812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Oates, Wallace E. (1969). "The E ects of Property Taxes and Local Public Spending on Property Values: An Empirical Study of Tax Capitalization and the Tiebout Hypothesis." Journal of Political Economy, 77(6):957-971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Papke, Leslie E. (2005). "The e ects of spending on test pass rates: Evidence from Michigan." Journal of Public Economics, 89(5-6):821-839.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Reardon, Sean F. and Demetra Kalogrides (2017). "Linking U. S. School District Test Score Distributions to a Common Scale." CEPA Working Paper No. 16-09, pages 1-50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Ries, John and Tsur Somerville (2010). "School Quality and Residential Property Values: Evidence from Vancouver Rezoning." Review of Economics and Statistics, 92(4):928-944.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Todd, Petra E. and Kenneth I. Wolpin (2003). "On The Specification and Estimation of The Production Function for Cognitive Achievement." Economic Journal, 113(485):F3-F33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">U.S. Bureau of Economic Analysis (2017). "Table 1.1.5. Gross Domestic Product."</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">U.S. Department of Education National Center for Education Statistics (2001). "Public School Finance Programs of the United States and Canada: 1998-99."</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">U.S. Department of Education National Center for Education Statistics (2016a). "Table 235.10. Revenues for public elementary and secondary schools, by source of funds: Selected years, 1919-20 through 2013-14."</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">U.S. Department of Education National Center for Education Statistics (2016b). "Table 236.10. Summary of expenditures for public elementary and secondary education and other related programs, by purpose: Selected years, 1919-20 through 2013-14."</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Verstegen, Deborah A. and Teresa S. Jordan (2009). "A Fifty-State Survey of School Finance Policies And Programs: An Overview." Journal of Education Finance, 34(3):213-230.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Historical Sources of School District Revenue</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Relationship between revenue and wealth/tax rate for general school finance plans</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Distribution of estimated wealth price in 1999</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>First-stage effect of a 10% increase in simulated revenue on total expenditure for graduate rate samples – individual year lags</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>First-stage effect of a 10% increase in simulated revenue on log expenditure for SEDA test score samples – individual year lags</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of log spending on graduation rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of log spending on SEDA test scores</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Change in district characteristics relative to 1999, by base-year wealth and effective tax rate</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Summary statistics for main estimation samples</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Summary statistics for characteristics of districts in and out of the sample</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>First stage estimates of log simulated revenue on log spending – average lags</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of log spending on graduation rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of log spending on test scores</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of log spending on student composition</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of future log spending on graduation rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of spending on source of revenue</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of spending on total expenditure sub-categories – graduation rate sample, 10th grade cohort, one-year lag</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of log spending on total expenditure sub-categories – SEDA sample, five to eight year lag</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 11:</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of log spending on current expenditure sub-categories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 12:</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of log spending on graduation rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Example of District Consolidation - Minnesota</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Example of Overlapping/Nested Districts - New Jersey</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>First-stage effect of simulated revenue ($1,000 per pupil) on total expenditure ($1,000 per pupil) in graduation rate samples – individual year lags</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>First-stage effect of simulated revenue ($1,000 per pupil) on total expenditure ($1,000 per pupil) for SEDA test score samples – individual year lags</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of per-pupil spending on graduation rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of per-pupil spending on SEDA test scores</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>School Finance Formula Type for Each State</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>States with Tax and Expenditure Limits</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>State Summary Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-30">
            <p>First stage estimates of log simulated revenue on log spending for graduation rate samples – individual year lags</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-31">
            <p>First stage estimates of log simulated revenue on log spending for test score samples – individual year lags</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-32">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of log spending on graduation rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-33">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of log spending on SEDA test scores</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-34">
            <p>First stage estimates of simulated revenue ($1,000 per pupil) on total expenditure ($1,000 per pupil) for graduation rate samples – individual year lags</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-35">
            <p>First stage estimates of simulated revenue ($1,000 per pupil) on total expenditure ($1,000 per pupil) for test score samples – individual year lags</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-36">
            <p>First stage estimates of simulated revenue ($1,000 per pupil) on total expenditure ($1,000 per pupil) – average lags</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A11:</label>
         <caption id="ca-37">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of per-pupil spending on graduation rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A12:</label>
         <caption id="ca-38">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of per-pupil spending on graduation rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A13:</label>
         <caption id="ca-39">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of per-pupil spending on test scores</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A14:</label>
         <caption id="ca-40">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of per-pupil spending on test scores</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A15:</label>
         <caption id="ca-41">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of log spending on instructional expenditure sub-categories – Graduation Rate sample, one-year lag</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A16:</label>
         <caption id="ca-42">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of per-pupil spending on support service expenditure sub-categories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A17:</label>
         <caption id="ca-43">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of per-pupil spending on capital expenditure sub-categories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A18:</label>
         <caption id="ca-44">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of per-pupil spending on other current expenditure sub-categories</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A19:</label>
         <caption id="ca-45">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of spending on teacher counts</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A20:</label>
         <caption id="ca-46">
            <p>Two-stage least squares estimates of log spending on graduation rates and test scores – robustness checks</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table C1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-47">
            <p>Florida Pupil Weights</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table C2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-48">
            <p>Georgia Pupil Weights</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table C3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-49">
            <p>Idaho Support Unit Weights</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table C4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-50">
            <p>Kentucky Pupil Weighted Factors</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table C5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-51">
            <p>Per Pupil Weighting Factors</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure C1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-52">
            <p>New Mexico Funding Formula</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table C6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-53">
            <p>Pupil Weights for Calculating TAPU</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table C7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-54">
            <p>Number of Students per Alloted Teacher</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table C8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-55">
            <p>Weights for Calculating Weighted Pupil Units</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table C9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-56">
            <p>Oklahoma Pupil Weights</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table C10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-57">
            <p>Tier I Program Weights</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
