<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169030</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Model to Assess the Benefits of an After-Market Hybridization Kit based on Realistic Driving Habits and Charging Infrastructure</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Marano</surname>
                  <given-names>Vincenzo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Medina</surname>
                  <given-names>Hebert</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sorrentino</surname>
                  <given-names>Marco</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rizzo</surname>
                  <given-names>Gianfranco</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Universita Degli Studi Di Salerno</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>December 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169025</issue-id>
         <fpage>471</fpage>
         <lpage>481</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169030"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Despite the recent commercial success of HEVs, their market share is still insufficient to produce a significant impact on energy consumption on a global basis. Moreover, it is unlikely that, in next few years, the scenario will drastically change, since relevant investments on production plants would be needed and the market does not seem to provide the expected growth for such technologies. Therefore, the possibility of upgrading conventional vehicles to hybrid electric vehicles is gaining interest. Among the diverse options for hybridization, researchers are focusing on electrification of rear wheels in front-driven vehicles, by adopting in-wheel motors and adding a lithium-ion battery. Thus, the vehicle is transformed in a Through-The-Road parallel hybrid electric vehicle.</p>
            <p>This paper presents an energy-based model, developed in Matlab/Simulink environment, of a conventional vehicle hybridized by means of such conversion kit. The model has a modular approach, where different powertrain configurations are considered, specifically with different battery sizes, different in-wheel motors power, with/without plug-in capabilities. An additional level of complexity comes from the opportunity to integrate flexible PV panels into the hybridization kit.</p>
            <p>In order to assess the benefits of the proposed kit with respect to the conventional vehicle, the analysis was performed over a variety of realistic driving cycles to reflect common driving habits. Results show that driver habits (in terms of driving style and distance driven), and the availability of charging infrastructure play an important role in fuel economy of the vehicle, thus making one configuration more convenient than others.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. Department of Energy, Energy Information Administration. “Monthly Energy Review.” March 2012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Associated Press. “GE to develop home fueling for natural gas cars.” 18 July 2012: [Online] Available: http://www.businessweek.com/ap/2012-07-18/ge-todevelop-home-fuelingfornatural- gas-cars.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The International Council on Clean Transportation, Global Comparison of Light-Duty Vehicle Fuel Economy/GHG Emissions Standards, June 2012 Report</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flynn, Peter C. “Commercializing an alternate vehicle fuel: lessons learned from natural gas for vehicles.” Energy Policy 30, 2002: 613-619.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">National Petroleum Council - An Oil and Natural Gas Advisory Committee to the Secretary of Energy. Future Transportation Fuels Study: Advancing Technology for Americas Transportation Future. [Online]. Available: http://www.npc.org/FTF-80112.html, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oak Ridge National Laboratory. TRANSPORTATION ENERGY DATA BOOK: EDITION 31. U.S. DOE Center for Transportation Analysis Energy and Transportation Science Division, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marano V, Rizzoni G, Tulpule P, Gong Q Khayyam H (2012), “Intelligent Energy Management for Plugin Hybrid ElectricVehicles: The Role of ITS Infrastructur e in Vehicle Electrification”. Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology 67: 4. 575-587 July-August</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sioshansi R, Fagiani R, Marano V (2010), “Cost and Emissions Impacts of Plug-In Hybrid Vehicles on the Ohio Power System”, Energy Policy 38: 11. 6703-6712 November</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rizzo, G. (2010). Automotive Applications of Solar Energy. 6th IFAC Symp. “Advances in Automotive Control”, AAC10, July 11-14, 2010, Munich (Germany).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">REN21, Renewables - Global Status Report - 2012 Update, http://new.ren21.net/REN21Activities/GlobalStatusReport.aspx</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rizzo G., Arsie I., Sorrentino M. (2010). Hybrid Solar Vehicles. Solar Collectors and Panels, Theory and Applications. Edited by:Reccab Manyala. SCIYO, http://www.intechopen.com/articles/show/title/hybridsolar-vehicles, ISBN:978-953-307-142-8</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arsie I., D'Agostino M., Naddeo M., Rizzo G., Sorrentino M. (2013). Toward the Development of a Through-The-Road Solar Hybridized Vehicle. Submitted to 7th IFAC Symp. “Advances in Automotive Control”, AAC13, September 4-7, 2013, Tokyo (Japan).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Onori S, Spagnol P, Marano V, Guezennec Y, Rizzoni G (2012), “A new life estimation method for Lithium-ion batteries in Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles applications”, International Journal of Power Electronics 4: 3. 302-319</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">PVWatts Grid Data Calculator, http://www.nrel.gov/rredc/pvwatts/grid.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rousseau A (2008), PHEV Component Requirements Summary, Argonne National Laboratory, November</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sikes K, Hadley S W, McGill R N, Cleary T, Marano V, Ungar E, Gross T (2010), Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicle ValueProposition Study - Final Report, Oak Ridge National Laboratory ORNL/TM-2010/46</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">European Automobile Manufacturers Association (ACEA) - vehicle in use -http://www.acea.be/news/news_detail/vehicles_in_use/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ACI-CENSIS, Annual Report 2012, http://www.aci.it/fileadmin/immagini/Notizie/ACICENSIS_2012_-_Rapporto_integrale_-_def.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Muratori M., Serra E., Marano V., and Moran M.J., “Personal Transportation Energy Consumption.” Ecos 2012 - The 25Th Intl. Conference On Efficiency, Cost, Optimization, Simulation And Environmental Impact Of Energy Systems. Perugia, Italy, June 26-29, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stockar S, Marano V, Canova M, Rizzoni G, Guzzella L (2011), “Energy-Optimal Control of Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles for Real- World Driving Cycles”. IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology 60: 7. 2949-2962 September.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Covenant of Mayors, Technical annex to the SEAP template instructions document: The Emission Factors, http://www.eumayors.eu/IMG/pdf/technical_annex_en.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CO2 Emissions Factors for Transportation Fuels, US Energy Information Administration (EIA), http://www.eia.gov/oiaf/1605/coefficients.html#tbl2</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Europe's Energy Portal, http://www.energy.eu/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
