<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">natitaxjour</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50005631</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>National Tax Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association (NTA)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00280283</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19447477</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26418786</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>ARTICLES</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>HOW TAXES AND REQUIRED RETURNS DROVE COMMERCIAL REAL ESTATE VALUATIONS OVER THE PAST FOUR DECADES</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Duca</surname>
                  <given-names>John V.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Research Department, Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas and Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX, USA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hendershott</surname>
                  <given-names>Patric H.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Professor Emeritus at The Ohio State University and the University of Aberdeen Business School, Scotland, UK</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ling</surname>
                  <given-names>David C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Hough Graduate School of Business, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL, USA</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>September, 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>70</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26418782</issue-id>
         <fpage>549</fpage>
         <lpage>584</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26418786"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We document the evolution of U.S. tax law regarding commercial real estate (CRE) since 1975, noting changes in income and capital gains tax rates and tax depreciation methods. The most prominent changes were in the 1981 and 1986 Tax Acts, but numerous significant changes occurred in the last dozen years. We then compute both the present value of tax depreciation per dollar of acquisition price and an effective tax rate for CRE. We explain the quarterly variation in CRE capitalization rates using an error-correction framework and find that the long-run estimates are statistically significant in the way theory would suggest. Moreover, the required financial asset return and the tax depreciation variables temporally predict (“cause”) capitalization rates in the long run, but not vice versa.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label> 
            <kwd>taxes</kwd> 
            <kwd>commercial real estate valuation</kwd> 
            <kwd>tax depreciation</kwd> 
            <kwd>capitalization rates</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Antoniades, Adonis, 2013. “Commercial Bank Failures during the Great Recession: The Real (Estate) Story.” SSRN Electronic Journal, http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2325261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aron, Janine, John V. Duca, John Muellbauer, Keiko Murata, and Anthony Murphy, 2012. “Credit, Housing Collateral and Consumption in the UK, U.S., and Japan.” Review of Income and Wealth 58, 397–423.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Autin, Gerald, and Charles Clotfelter, 1982. “Permanent vs. Transitory Effects and the Realization of Capital Gains.” Quarterly Journal of Economics 97 (4), 613–632.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bailey, Martin J., 1974. “Progressivity and Investment Yields under U.S. Income Taxation.”Journal of Political Economy 82 (6), 1157–1175.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bernanke, Ben S., and Cara S. Lown, 1991. “The Credit Crunch.” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 1991 (2), 205–247.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blanchard, Olivier J., 1993. “Movements in the Equity Premium.” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 1993 (2), 75–118.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bokhari, Sheharyar, and David Geltner, 2015. “Commercial Buildings Capital Consumption in the United States.” MIT Center for Real Estate Paper. Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brannon, Gerard M., and Emil M. Sunley, Jr., 1976. “The Recapture of Excess Depreciation on the Sale of Real Estate.” National Tax Journal 29 (4), 413–423.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Browne, Lynn E., and Karl E. Case, 1992. “How the Commercial Real Estate Boom Undid the Banks.” In Browne, Lynn E., and Eric S. Rosengren (eds.), Real Estate and the Credit Crunch, Federal Reserve Bank of Boston Conference Series no. 36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brueggeman, William B., Jeffrey D. Fisher, and Jerrold J. Stern, 1981. “Federal Income Taxes, Inflation and Holding Periods for Income-Producing Property.” Journal of the American Real Estate and Urban Economics Association 9 (2) 148–164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burman, Leonard, and William Randolph, 1994. “Measuring Permanent Responses to Capital-Gains Tax Changes in Panel Data.” American Economic Review 84 (4), 794–809.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Campbell, John Y., and Tuomo Vuolteenaho, 2004. “Inflation Illusion and Stock Prices.” American Economic Review 94 (2), 19–23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duca, John V., and David C. Ling, 2015. “The Other (Commercial) Real Estate Boom and Bust: The Effects of Risk Premia and Regulatory Capital Arbitrage.” FRB of Dallas Paper No. 1504. Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas, Dallas, TX.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duca, John V., and John Muellbauer, 2014. “Tobin LIVES: Integrating Evolving Credit Market Architecture into Flow of Funds Based Macro-Models.” In Winkler, Bernhard, Ad van Riet, and Peter Bull (eds.), A Flow-of-Funds Perspective on the Financial Crisis Volume II, 11–39. Palgrave-Macmillan, Basingstoke, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duca, John V., and Tao Wu, 2009. “Regulation and the Neo-Wicksellian Approach to Monetary Policy.” Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking 41 (3), 799–807.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Feldstein, Martin, and Joel Slemrod, 1979. “Inflation and the Excess Taxation of Capital Gains on Corporate Stock.” National Tax Journal 31 (2), 107–188.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferreira, Fernando V., 2010. “You Can Take It with You: Proposition 13 Tax Benefits, Residential Mobility, and Willingness to Pay for Housing Amenities.” Journal of Public Economics 94, 661–673.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fisher, Jeffrey D., and Michael S. Young, 2000. ”Holding Periods for Institutional Real Estate in the NCREIF Database.” Real Estate Finance 17 (3), 27–34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Follain, James R., Patric Hendershott, and David C. Ling, 1987. “Understanding the Real Estate Provisions of Tax Reform: Motivation and Impact.” National Tax Journal 40 (3), 363–372.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Follain, James R., Patric Hendershott, and David C. Ling, 1987. “Effects on Real Estate.” In Pechman, J. (ed.), Evaluating Tax Reform, 71–94. Brookings Institution, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gau, George W., and Ko Wang, 1994. “The Tax-Induced Holding Periods of Real Estate Investors: Theory and Empirical Evidence.” Journal of Real Estate Finance and Economics 8, 71–85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Granger, Clive W. J., and Jin-Lung Lin, 1996. “Causality in the Long Run.” Econometric Theory 11 (3), 530–536.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gravelle, Jane G., 1994. The Economic Effects of Taxing Capital Income, Ch. 6. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA and London, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hendershott, Patric H., and Edward J. Kane, 1992. “The Causes and Consequences of the 1980s Commercial Real Estate Boom.” Journal of Applied Corporate Finance 5 (1), 61–70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hendershott, Patric H., and David C. Ling, 1984. “Trading and the Tax Shelter Value of Depreciable Real Estate.” National Tax Journal 37 (2), 213–223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hulten, Charles R., and Frank C. Wykoff, 1996. “Issues in the Measurement of Economic Depreciation: Introductory Remarks.” Economic Inquiry 34 (1), 10–23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ihlanfeldt, Keith R., 2011. “Do Caps on Increases in Assessed Values Create a Lock-in Effect? Evidence from Florida’s Amendment One.” National Tax Journal 64 (1), 7–26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johansen, Soren, 1995. Likelihood-Based Inference in Cointegrated Vector Autoregressive Models, Oxford University Press, New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manolaksa, Thomas G., and Paul E. Anderson, 1990. Tax Factors in Real Estate Operations 7th ed. Prentice Hall, Upper Saddle River, NJ.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Penick, William P., 1983. “Evolution of the Federal Tax System: 1954–1983.” Federal Tax Policy Memo 7 (2). Tax Foundation, Incorporated, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robinson, Gerald J., 1984. Federal Income Taxation of Real Estate. Warren, Gorham, &amp; Lamont, New York, NY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sinai, Todd, and Joseph Gyourko, 2004. “The Asset Price Incidence of Capital Gains Taxes: Evidence from the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997 and Publicly-traded Real Estate Firms.” Journal of Public Economics 88 (7–8), 1543–1565.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
