<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">21</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830618</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830621</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE FINANCIAL SERVICES INDUSTRY: EMERGING TRENDS IN THE OECS CREDIT UNION SECTOR / L'INDUSTRIE DES SERVICES FINANCIERS - LES TENDANCES EMERGEANTES DANS LE SECTEUR DU SYNDICAT CRÉDITEUR DE L'ORGANISATION DES ÉTATS DE LA CARAÏBE DE L'EST (O.E.C.S.)</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Peter</given-names>
                  <surname>Adrien</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1997</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>275</fpage>
         <lpage>294</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830621"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Credit unions in the O.E.C.S. countries are challenging small banks and thrift institutions for retail banking business, becoming increasingly involved in mortgage lending, and in the last few years, have become a significant financier of micro and small enterprises. They offer long term home improvement loans, chequing accounts through special clearing-house facilities with commercial banks, utility bill-paying services and automated teller machines. This paper discusses the role of credit unions in the financial services industry in the O.E.C.S. countries, analyses the nature of trade in financial services in the credit unions and the way in which trade in financial services takes place, and examines the implications of these developments for the maintenance of financial stability. Les syndicats créditeurs des pays O.E.C.S. provoquent les petites banquent et les institutions économes associés avec les affaires bancaires détaillantes deviennent de plus en plus engagés dans les prêt-logements et dans les derniers trois ou quatre and sont devenics un fanancier significatif des et petites micro-initiatives. On offre les prêts sur l'amélioration des maisons, les comptes courants par l'élimination des facilités spéciales avec les banques commerciales, les services publics pour régler les comptes et les machines au caissier automatique. Ce document discute le rôle des syndicats créditeurs dans l'industrie des services financiers des pays O.E.C.S., analyse la nature du commerce dans les services financiers dans les syndicats créditeurs et comment le commerce dans les services financiers a lieu et examine les implications de ces développements pour le maintien de la stabilité financière.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d36e144a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e148" publication-type="other">
ADRIEN, P. 1991 "The Credit Union Sector in the ECCB Area: A Social, Economic and Financial Impact Study",
Eastern Caribbean Central Bank, Mimeo.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e158a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e162" publication-type="other">
BANKING ACT, An Act to Provide for Regulating Banking Business in the ECCB Territories, No. 23 of 1983.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e169a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e173" publication-type="other">
BANK SUPERVISION DEPARTMENT, 1995. "The Move Towards a Central Supervisory Authority - A Case for
Integrated Supervision of the Financial Institutions," Mimeo, Eastern Caribbean Central Bank, St Kitts.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e183a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e187" publication-type="other">
BOLLENBACHER, G.M. 1995. The New Business of Banking, Illinois: Irwin Professional Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e195a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e199" publication-type="other">
CARMICHAEL, T. 1989. "Development of Financial Services in Barbados, Mimeo., Barbados: Conference on
Financing Development in the Caribbean.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e209a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e213" publication-type="other">
GARDENER, E. P. M. 1989. Towards European Financial Supermarkets?, North Wales: Institute of European
Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e223a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e227" publication-type="other">
GART, A. 1984. The Insider's Guide to the Financial Services Revolution, New York: Mc Graw-Hill Book Company.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e234a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e238" publication-type="other">
GOMEZ, T. 1993. "Human Resource Development in the Financial Sector", Mimeo.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e245a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e249" publication-type="other">
JOHN, L. and Polius, T. 1995. "Changes in the Financial System of the OECS Territories 1980 -1994", Mimeo, U
Wl.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e259a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e263" publication-type="other">
LEPP. A. 1996. "Financial Products for MSEs - The Municipal Savings and Loans Banks of Peru" Small Enterprise
Development, 7(2).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e274a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e278" publication-type="other">
LIBURD, E. E. 1988. "Financial Markets: The ECCB Experience", Eastern Caribbean Central Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e285a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e289" publication-type="other">
MORAN, M. 1991. The Politics of the Financial Services Revolution, London: MacMillan Academic and Professional
Ltd.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e299a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e303" publication-type="other">
MOSSHIRIAN, F. 1994. "Trade in Financial Services", The World Economy, 17 (3) Oxford: Blackwell Publishers.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e310a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e314" publication-type="other">
ODLE, M. 1972. The Significance of Non-Bank Financial Intermediaries in the Caribbean, Jamaica: ISER.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


