<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i24464784</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24464821</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Venture Capitalists on Boards of Mature Public Firms</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ugur</given-names>
                  <surname>Celikyurt</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Merih</given-names>
                  <surname>Sevilir</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Anil</given-names>
                  <surname>Shivdasani</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>56</fpage>
         <lpage>101</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24464821"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Venture capitalists (VCs) often serve on the board of mature public firms long after their initial public offering (IPO), even for companies that were not VC-backed at the IPO. Board appointments of VC directors are followed by increases in research and development intensity, innovation output, and greater deal activity with other VC-backed firms. VC director appointments are associated with positive announcement returns and are followed by an improvement in operating performance. Firms experience higher announcement returns from acquisitions of VC-backed targets following the appointment of a VC director to the board. Hence, in addition to providing finance, monitoring and advice for small private firms, VCs play a significant role in mature public firms and have a broader influence in promoting innovation than has been established in the literature.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d57e266a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e273" publication-type="other">
See, for example, "Glaxo Tries Biotech Model to Spur Drug Innovations," Wall Street Journal, July 1, 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e280a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e287" publication-type="other">
Our sample period starts in 1998 because this is the first year that the IRRC database collects primary employment
data of directors—the main data item we need for our analysis. We end our sample period in 2006 because
the Institutional Shareholder Services (ISS) acquired IRRC in 2005 and changed the methodology to collect
governance data in 2007 to follow ISS specifications. Because this change from year 2007 had a significant
impact on the governance data, the time series of variables provided after 2007 are not necessarily comparable
to the previous data years before 2007.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e310a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e317" publication-type="other">
The keywords that we search for are venture, capital, partner, fund, investor, angel, finance, financial, and
management.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e327a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e334" publication-type="other">
In our data-collection process, we distinguish between VC firms and private equity firms and do not classify
private equity professionals as VC directors in our analysis.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e345a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e352" publication-type="other">
The company founding dates are obtained from Jay Ritter's Web site and are available for 43% of our sample
firms. Data on IPO dates come from Securities Data Company's (SDC) New Issues database from 1970 onward.
For firms that went public before 1970, we use the first trading date in CRSP as the IPO date.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e365a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e372" publication-type="other">
The fifth percentile of the distribution for the number of years a firm has been public is four years in our sample,
indicating that the vast majority of the sample firms have been public for several years. 1.2% of firms in the
sample have been public for less than three years. Excluding these firms from the sample provides qualitatively
similar results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e388a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e395" publication-type="other">
The data on VC backing at the time of the IPO come from SDC's New Issues database and are reported in SDC
starting from year 1970 on. These data are available for 48% of our sample firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e405a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e412" publication-type="other">
The original work by Hall, Jaffe, and Trajtenberg (2001) covers patent data until the end of 1999, which is then
extended by Bronwyn H. Hall until the end of 2006.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e422a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e429" publication-type="other">
Year fixed effects in our estimation control for the possibility that our results might be driven by the idiosyncrasies
of the Internet boom period. In our time-series analysis discussed later, we ensure that our results are not specific
to the Internet boom period by including indicator variables for the Internet boom period from 1999 to 2001.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e442a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e449" publication-type="other">
Because this variable is missing for firms that went public prior to 1970, we also estimate the model without this
variable in untabulated tests and continue to find a positive relation between the presence of VC directors and
R&amp;D intensity that is significant at the 10% level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e463a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e470" publication-type="other">
This variable is relevant in the context of recent work showing that geography impacts corporate finance
outcomes. It affects ownership structure of firms (Coval and Moskowitz 1999), access to financing (Becker
2007), market valuations (Hong, Kubik, and Stein 2008), shareholder composition (Ivkovich and Weisbenner
2005), and dividend policy (Becker, Ivkovich, and Weisbenner 2011). In other related work, Chen et al. (2010)
study the geographical concentration of VC firms and VC-financed firms and find that VC firms that are located
in concentrated areas of VC activity tend to perform better.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e493a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e500" publication-type="other">
In untabulated tests, we considered other attributes of VCs that may contribute to higher R&amp;D efforts. Specifically,
we used the Industry Concentration Index (ICI) to measure the industry concentration of a VC firm's portfolio
following Kacperczyk, Sialm, and Zheng (2005) and Tian (2011). We also considered whether the VC firms
specialized in early- or late-stage investments and whether there was an overlap between the VC firm's investment
portfolio and the industry of the mature firm. We do not find evidence that these VC firm characteristics are
associated with greater R&amp;D expenses.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e523a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e530" publication-type="other">
The Post-VC director appointment indicator variable is defined only for those firms that had no VC directors
at the beginning of the sample period and subsequently appoint a VC director to their board within the sample
period. Hence, this indicator variable is defined only for firms that make the transition from being a firm without
a VC director to a firm with a VC director.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e546a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e553" publication-type="other">
The technology classes defined by USPTO are computers and communications, drugs and medical, electrical
and electronics, chemical, mechanical, and others.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d57e572a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e576" publication-type="other">
Aghion, P., J. Van Reenen, and L. Zingales. Forthcoming. Innovation and institutional ownership. American
Economic Review.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e586a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e590" publication-type="other">
Altonji, J. G, T. E. Elder, and C. R. Taber. 2005. Selection on observed and unobserved variables: Assessing the
effectiveness of Catholic schools. Journal of Political Economy 113:151-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e600a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e604" publication-type="other">
Baker, M. P., and P. A. Gompers. 2003. The determinants of board structure at the initial public offering. Journal
of Law and Economics 46:569-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e614a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e618" publication-type="other">
Barry, C. B., C. J. Muscarella, J. W. Peavy III, and M. R.Vetsuypens. 1990. The role of venture capital in
the creation of public companies: Evidence from the going-public process. Journal of Financial Economics
27:447-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e632a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e636" publication-type="other">
Becker, B. 2007. Geographical segmentation of U.S. capital markets. Journal of Financial Economics 85:151 -78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e643a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e647" publication-type="other">
Becker, B., Z. Ivkovich, and S. Weisbenner. 2011. Local dividend clienteles. Journal of Finance 66:655-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e654a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e658" publication-type="other">
Brav, A., and P. A. Gompers. 1997. Myth or reality? The long-run underperformance of initial public offerings:
Evidence from venture and nonventure capital-backed companies. Journal of Finance 52:1791-821.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e668a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e672" publication-type="other">
Brown, S. J., and J. B. Warner. 1985. Using daily stock returns: The case of event studies. Journal of Financial
Economics 14:3-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e682a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e686" publication-type="other">
Chemmanur, T. J., K. Krishnan, and D. K. Nandy. 2011. How does venture capital financing improve efficiency
in private firms? A look beneath the surface. Review of Financial Studies 24:4037-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e696a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e700" publication-type="other">
Chemmanur, T. J., E. Loutskina, and X. Tian. 2012. Corporate venture capital, value creation, and innovation.
Working Paper, Boston College.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e711a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e715" publication-type="other">
Chen, H., P. Gompers, A. Kovner, and J. Lerner. 2010. Buy local? The geography of venture capital. Journal of
Urban Economics 67:90-102.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e725a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e729" publication-type="other">
Chesbrough, H. 2002. Making sense of corporate venture capital. Harvard Business Review 80:90-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e736a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e740" publication-type="other">
Coval, J. D., and T. J. Moskowitz. 1999. Home bias at home: Local equity preference in domestic portfolios.
Journal of Finance 54:2045-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e750a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e754" publication-type="other">
Dlugosz, J., R. Fahlenbrach, P. Gompers, and A. Metrick. 2006. Large blocks of stock: Prevalence, size, and
measurement. Journal of Corporate Finance 12:594-618.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e764a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e768" publication-type="other">
Dushnitsky, G., and M. J. Lenox. 2005. When do incumbents learn from entrepreneurial ventures? Research
Policy 34:615-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e778a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e782" publication-type="other">
. 2006. When does corporate venture capital investment create firm value? Journal of Business Venturing
21:753-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e793a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e797" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and M. C. Jensen. 1983. Separation of ownership and control. Journal of Law and Economics
26:301-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e807a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e811" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and K. R. French. 1997. Industry costs of equity. Journal of Financial Economics 43:153-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e818a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e822" publication-type="other">
Fich, E. 2005. Are some outside directors better than others? Journal of Business 78:1943-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e829a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e833" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P. A. 1995. Optimal investment, monitoring, and the staging of venture capital. Journal of Finance
50:1461-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e843a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e847" publication-type="other">
Griliches, Z. 1990. Patent statistics as economic indicators: A survey. Journal of Economic Literature 28:1661-
707.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e857a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e861" publication-type="other">
Guner, B., U. Malmendier, and G Tate. 2008. Financial expertise of directors. Journal of Financial Economics
88:323-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e872a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e876" publication-type="other">
Hall, B. H., A. B. Jaffe, and M. Trajtenberg. 2001. The NBER Patent Citations Data File: Lessons, insights, and
methodological tools. Working Paper, NBER.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e886a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e890" publication-type="other">
. 2005. Market Value and Patent Citations. RAND Journal of Economics 36:16-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e897a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e901" publication-type="other">
Hellmann, T., and M. Puri. 2000. The interaction between product market and financing strategy: The role of
venture capital. Review of Financial Studies 13:959-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e911a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e915" publication-type="other">
. 2002. Venture capital and the professionalization of start-up firms: Empirical evidence. Journal of
Finance 57:169-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e925a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e929" publication-type="other">
Hochberg, Y. V. 2012. Venture capital and corporate governance in the newly public firm. Review of Finance
16:429-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e939a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e943" publication-type="other">
Hochberg, Y. V., A. Ljungqvist, and Y. Lu. 2007. Whom you know matters: Venture capital networks and
investment performance. Journal of Finance 62:251-301.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e954a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e958" publication-type="other">
Hong, H., J. Kubik, and J. Stein. 2008. The only game in town: Stock price consequences of local bias. Journal
of Financial Economics 90:20-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e968a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e972" publication-type="other">
Ivkovich, Z., and S. Weisbenner. 2005. Local does as local is: Information content of the geography of individual
investors' common stock investments. Journal of Finance 60:267-306.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e982a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e986" publication-type="other">
Kacperczyk, M., C. Sialm, and L. Zheng. 2005. On the industry concentration of actively managed equity mutual
funds. Journal of Finance 60:1983—2011.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e996a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1000" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S. N., and P. Stromberg. 2003. Financial contracting theory meets the real world: Evidence from venture
capital contracts. Review of Economic Studies 70:281-316.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1010a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1014" publication-type="other">
. 2004. Characteristics, contracts, and actions: Evidence from venture capitalist analyses. Journal of
Finance 59:2173-206.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1024a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1028" publication-type="other">
Kortum, S., and J. Lemer. 2000. Assessing the contribution of venture capital to innovation. RAND Journal of
Economics 31:674-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1039a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1043" publication-type="other">
Lerner, J. 1994. The syndication of venture capital investments. Financial Management 23:16-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1050a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1054" publication-type="other">
. 1995. Venture capitalists and the oversight of private firms. Journal of Finance 50:301-18.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1061a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1065" publication-type="other">
Lindsey, L. 2008. Blurring firm boundaries: The role of venture capital in strategic alliances. Journal of Finance
63:1137-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1075a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1079" publication-type="other">
Masulis, R. W., C. Wang, and F. Xie. 2010. Globalizing the boardroom: The effects of foreign directors on
corporate governance and firm performance. Working Paper, Australian National University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1089a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1093" publication-type="other">
Megginson, W. L., and K. Weiss. 1991. Venture capitalist certification in initial public offerings. Journal of
Finance 46:879-903.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1103a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1107" publication-type="other">
Nahata, R. 2008. Venture capital reputation and investment performance. Journal of Financial Economics 90:127-
51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1118a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1122" publication-type="other">
Ostromogolsky, P. 2011. The strategic value of lending relationships. Working Paper, Yale University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1129a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1133" publication-type="other">
Perry, T., and U. Peyer. 2005. Board seat accumulation by executives: A shareholder's perspective. Journal of
Finance 60:2083-123.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1143a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1147" publication-type="other">
Robinson, D. T. 2008. Strategic alliances and the boundaries of the firm. Review of Financial Studies 21:649-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1154a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1158" publication-type="other">
Rosenstein, S., and J. Wyatt. 1990. Outside directors, board independence and shareholder wealth. Journal of
Financial Economics 26:175-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1168a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1172" publication-type="other">
Shivdasani, A., and D. Yermack. 1999. CEO involvement in the selection of new board members: An empirical
analysis. Journal of Finance 54:1829-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1182a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1186" publication-type="other">
Tian, X. 2011. The causes and consequences of venture capital stage financing. Journal of Financial Economics
101:132-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1197a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1201" publication-type="other">
Trajtenberg, M. 1990. A penny for your quotes: Patent citations and the value of information. RAND Journal of
Economics 21:325—4-2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


