<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26168983</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Energy Management Strategy and Optimal Hybridization Level for a Diesel HEV</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Thibault</surname>
                  <given-names>Laurent</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Grondin</surname>
                  <given-names>Olivier</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Querel</surname>
                  <given-names>Carole</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Corde</surname>
                  <given-names>Gilles</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>IFP Energies Nouvelles</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>June 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26168958</issue-id>
         <fpage>260</fpage>
         <lpage>271</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26168983"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The design and the supervision of hybrid electric vehicles (HEV) are strongly coupled. The mutual influence between the optimal components sizing and the optimal operating points choice makes the problem complex. This was previously exposed in literature for spark ignition (SI) HEV. In this paper, we address the same issue for Diesel HEV. In this case, the energy management strategy must take nitrogen oxides (NOₓ) emissions into account in addition to fuel consumption. This paper presents an optimal supervision strategy and its impact on the electric components sizing. The energy management strategy is based on the equivalent consumption minimization strategy (ECMS) using Pontryagin's minimum principle. It allows an adjustable trade-off between NOₓ and fuel consumption to be minimized. It was validated experimentally with a hardware-in-the-loop test bed. By moving the engine operating points into optimal zones, this strategy allows important NOₓ emissions reduction while keeping interesting fuel consumption. In comparison to a fuel consumption reduction oriented strategy, the integration of NOₓ emissions deeply changes the energy management strategy choices and, as a consequence, the optimal electric components size. Indeed, to limit NOₓ emissions engine high load operating points are avoided and a smaller hybridization level is sufficient. Compared to the SI engine, the Diesel has a better efficiency at part load. As a consequence, high NOₓ reduction is possible without important fuel consumption increase. The interactions between electric components sizing and energy mangement strategy design are studied in this paper. Depending on the chosen value of the adjustable trade-off of the strategy, the optimal hybridization level changes because the engine optimal operation areas move. The driving cycle influence is also studied here to draw global conclusions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ambühl, D., Sciarretta, A., Onder, C., Guzzella, L., Sterzing, S., Mann, K., Kraft, D., and Küsell, M., “A causal operation strategy for hybrid electric vehicles based on optimal control theory,” in Proceedings of the 4th Symposium on Hybrid Vehicles and Energy Management, Stadthalle Branuschweig, Germany, February 2007, pp. 318-331.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chasse, A., Chauvin, J., and Sciarretta, A., “Online optimal control of a parallel hybrid with costate adaptation rule,” in Proceedings of the 6th IFAC Symposium Advances in Automotive Control, 2010, pp. 318-331.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chasse, A., Hafidi, G., Pognant-Gros, P., and Sciarretta, A., “Supervisory control of hybrid powertrains: an experimental benchmark of offline optimization and online energy management,” in Proceedings of ECOSM' 09 - IFAC Workshop on Engine and Powertrain Control, Simulation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chasse, A., Pognant-Gros, P., and Sciarretta, A., “Online Implementation of an Optimal Supervisory Control for a Parallel Hybrid Powertrain,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1630-1638, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1868.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mastro, A., Chasse, A., Pognant-Gros, P., Corde, G. et al., “Advanced Hybrid Vehicle Simulation: from “Virtual” to “HyHiL” test bench,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-24-0068, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grondin, O., Thibault, Laurent, Moulin, Philippe, Chasse, Alexandre &amp; Sciarretta, Antonio - “Energy management strategy for Diesel hybrid vehicle” VPPC, Chicago, September 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, V., Wipke, K., and Rausen, D., “HEV Control Strategy for Real-Time Optimization of Fuel Economy and Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1543, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1543.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.-C., Peng, H., Grizzle, J. W., and Kang, J.-M., “Power management strategy for a parallel hybrid electric truck,” IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, Vol. 11, no. 6, pp. 839-849, November 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musardo, C., Rizzoni, G., and Staccia, B., “A-ECMS: An adaptive algorithm for hybrid electric vehicle energy management,” in Proceedings of the 44th IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musardo, C., Staccia, B., Midlam-Mohler, S., Guezennec, Y., and Rizzoni, G., “Supervisory control for NOx reduction of an HEV with a mixedmode HCCI/CIDI</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neely, G., Sasaki, S., Huang, Y., Leet, J. et al., “New Diesel Emission Control Strategy to Meet US Tier 2 Emissions Regulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1091, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1091.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Predelli, O., Bunar, F., Manns, J., Buchwald, R., and Sommer, A., “Laying out Diesel engine control systems in passenger car hybrid drives,” in Proceedings of the 4th Symposium on Hybrid Vehicles and Energy Management, Stadthalle Branuschweig, Germany, 2007, pp. 131-151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sciarretta, A., Back, M., and Guzzella, L., “Optimal control of parallel hybrid electric vehicles,” IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, Vol. 12, no. 3, May 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sciarretta, A. and Guzzella, L., “Control of hybrid electric vehicles - optimal energy management strategies,” IEEE Control Systems Magazine, pp. 60-70, April 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundström, Olle, Guzella, L. and Soltic, P. “Torque-Assist hybrid electric powertrain sizing : from optimal control towards a sizing law” IEEE Transactions on control systems technology, Vol. 18, no 4, july 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
