<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">107</volume>
         <issue-id>i40199364</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/44735866</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Improving Aircraft Composite Inspections Using Optimized
                            Reference Standards</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Dennis</given-names>
                  <surname>Roach</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Larry</given-names>
                  <surname>Dorrell</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Jeff</given-names>
                  <surname>Kollgaard</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Tom</given-names>
                  <surname>Dreher</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1998</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1339</fpage>
         <lpage>1349</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1999 Society of Automotive Engineers,
                Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44735866"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The rapidly increasing use of composites on commercial airplanes coupled
                            with the potential for economic savings associated with their use in
                            aircraft structures means that the demand for composite materials
                            technology will continue to increase. Inspecting these composite
                            structures is a critical element in assuring their continued
                            airworthiness. The FAA's Airworthiness Assurance NDI Validation Center,
                            in conjunction with the Commercial Aircraft Composite Repair Committee,
                            is developing a set of composite reference standards to be used in NDT
                            equipment calibration for accomplishment of damage assessment and
                            post-repair inspection of all commercial aircraft composites. In this
                            program, a series of NDI tests on a matrix of composite aircraft
                            structures and prototype reference standards were completed in order to
                            minimize the number of standards needed to carry out composite
                            inspections on aircraft. Two tasks, related to composite laminates and
                            non-metallic composite honeycomb configurations, were addressed. A suite of 64 honeycomb panels, representing the bounding conditions of
                            honeycomb construction on aircraft, were inspected using a wide array of
                            NDI techniques. An analysis of the resulting data determined the
                            variables that play a key role in setting up NDT equipment. This has
                            resulted in a prototype set of minimum honeycomb reference standards
                            that include these key variables. A sequence of subsequent tests
                            determined that this minimum honeycomb reference standard set is able to
                            fully support inspections over the full range of honeycomb construction
                            scenarios. Current tasks are aimed at optimizing the methods used to
                            engineer realistic flaws into the specimens. In the solid composite
                            laminate arena, we have identified what appears to be an excellent
                            candidate, G11 Phenolic, as a generic solid laminate reference standard
                            material. Testing to date has determined matches in key velocity and
                            acoustic impedance properties, as well as, low attenuation relative to
                            carbon laminates. Furthermore, comparisons of resonance testing response
                            curves from the G11 Phenolic prototype standard was very similar to the
                            resonance response curves measured on the existing carbon and fiberglass
                            laminates. NDI data shows that this material should work for both
                            pulse-echo (velocity-based) and resonance (acoustic impedance-based)
                            inspections. Additional testing and industry review activities are
                            underway to complete the validation of this material.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d2390414e250a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2390414e257" publication-type="other">
"Composite Repair NDT/NDI Handbook," SAE
Aerospace Recommended Practice ARP5089,
issued Nov. 1996, prepared by the ATA/IATA/SAE
Commercial Aircraft Composite Repair Committee,
Inspection Task Group.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


