<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000476</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40009033</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Glossary-Based MT Engines in a Multilingual Analyst's Workstation Architecture</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Rémi</given-names>
                  <surname>Zajac</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Michelle</given-names>
                  <surname>Vanni</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1997</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>131</fpage>
         <lpage>151</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1997 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40009033"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>Fast access to information in different languages is still a major problem for many organizations. We have built a multilingual analyst's workstation integrated in the Tipster document management toolkit. The analyst workstation offers to an English-speaking analyst a variety of tools to browse sets of documents in Arabic, Japanese, Spanish and Russian, including a Unicode-based multilingual editor, and a simple machine translation functionality. The Temple project has developed an open multilingual architecture and software support for rapid development of extensible machine translation functionalities. The targeted languages are those for which natural language processing and human resources are scarce or difficult to obtain. The goal is to support rapid development of machine translation functionalities in a very short time with limited resources. Glossary-based machine-translation (GBMT) is used to provide an English gloss of a foreign document. A GBMT system uses a bilingual phrasal dictionary (glossary) to produce a phrase-by- phrase translation. Translation (based on phrase pattern-matching) is fast and accurate regarding the content of the document and browsed documents can be translated almost in real-time. A GBMT system for a language pair is also extremely simple, cheap and fast to develop. Moreover, all language resources used by the system are entirely under the control of the user.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>multilingual information processing</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d3301853e187a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e191" publication-type="other">
Callan J.P., Croft W.B., and Harding S.M.: 1992, 'The Inquery Retrieval System', in Proceedings of
the 3rd International Conference on Database and Expert Systems Applications, Valencia, Spain,
pp. 78-83.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e204a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e208" publication-type="other">
Church, K. and Hovy, E.: 1993, 'Good Applications for Crummy Machine Translation', Machine
Translation 8, 239-258.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e218a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e222" publication-type="other">
Cohen, A., Cousseau, P., Frederking, R., Grannes, D., Khanna, S., McNeilly, C, Nirenburg, S., Shell,
P., and Waeltermann, D.: 1993, Translator's Workstation User Document, Center for Machine
Translation, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e235a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e239" publication-type="other">
Davis, M.W., Dunning, T.E., and Ogden, W.C.: 1995, 'Text Alignment in the Real World: Improving
Alignments of Noisy Translations Using Common Lexical Features, String Matching Strategies
and N-Gram Comparisons', Seventh Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for
Computational Linguistics, Dublin, Ireland, pp. 67-74.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e256a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e260" publication-type="other">
Frederking, R., Grannes, D., Cousseau, P., and Nirenburg, S.: 1993, 'An MAT Tool and Its
Effectiveness', Proceedings of the DARPA Human Language Technology Workshop, Princeton,
NJ.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e273a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e277" publication-type="other">
Grishman, R., (ed.): 1995, Tipster Phase II Architecture Design Document Version 1.52. URL-
http://cs.nyu.edu/tipster.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e287a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e291" publication-type="other">
Guthrie, L., Guthrie, J., Wilks, Y., Cowie, J., Farwell, D., Slator, B., and Bruce, R.: 1993a, A
Research Program on Machine-Tractable Dictionaries and their Application to Text Analysis,
CRL Technical Report MCCS-92-249, NMSU, Las Cruces, NM.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e304a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e308" publication-type="other">
Guthrie, L., Rauls, V, Luo, T., and Bruce, R.: 1993b, LEXI-CADICAM, A Tool for Lexicon Builders,
CRL Technical Report MCCS-93-259, NMSU, Las Cruces, NM.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e318a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e322" publication-type="other">
Johnson, R.L. and Whitelock, P.: 1987, 'Machine Translation as an Expert Task', in S. Nirenburg,
(ed.), Theoretical and Methodological Issues in Machine Translation, Cambridge University
Press, Cambridge, pp. 136-144.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e335a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e339" publication-type="other">
Kay, M.: 1980, The Proper Place of Men and Machines in Machine Translation, Xerox PARC
Technical Report CSL-80-11. Reprinted in this issue, pp. 3-23.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e350a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e354" publication-type="other">
Macklovitch, Eliot: 1989, 'An Off-the-Shelf Workstation for Translators', Proceedings of the 30th
American Translators Conference, Washington D.C., pp. 491-498.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e364a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e368" publication-type="other">
Matsumoto, Y., Kurohashi, S., Nyoki, Y., Shinho, H., and Nagao, M.: 1995, User's Guide for the
JUMAN System, a User-Extensible Morphological Analyzer for Japanese. Version 0.5, Kyoto
University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e381a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e385" publication-type="other">
Nagao, M. and Mori, S.: 1994, 'A New Method of n-gram Statistics for Large Number of n and
Automatic Extraction of Words and Phrases from Large Text Data of Japanese', in COLING 94:
The 15th International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Kyoto, Japan, pp. 611-615.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e398a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e402" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, S. (ed): 1995, The Pangloss Mark III Machine Translation System, Joint Technical Report,
CRL, NMSU, Las Cruces, NM, ISI USC, Marina del Rey, CA, and CMU-CMT-95-145, Carnegie
Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e415a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e419" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, S., Shell, P., Cohen, A., Cousseau, P., Grannes, D., and McNeilly, C: 1993, 'Multi-
Purpose Development and Operation Environments for Natural Language Applications', Third
Conference on Applied Natural Language Processing, Trento, Italy, pp. 255-265.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e432a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e436" publication-type="other">
Ogden, W. and Bernick, P.: 1996, 'Oleada: User-Centered Tipster Technology for Language Instruc-
tion', to appear in the Proceedings of the Tipster Phase II 24 Month Workshop, Tysons Corner,
VA, pp. 85-90.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e450a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e454" publication-type="other">
, Penman: 1988, The Penman Primer, User Guide, and Reference Manual, USC/ISI Marina del Rey,
CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e464a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e468" publication-type="other">
Smadja, F.: 1993, 'Retrieving Collocations from Text: Xtract', Computational Linguistics 19, 143-
175.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e478a1310">
               
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e484" publication-type="other">
Stein, G.C., Lin, F., Bruce, R., Weng, F., and Guthrie, L.: 1993, The Development of an Application
Independent Lexicon: LexBase, CRL Technical Report MCCS-92-247, NMSU, Las Cruces, NM.
Tipster: 1994, Proceedings of the Tipster Text Program (Phase I), Morgan Kaufman, San Francisco,
CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301853e500a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301853e504" publication-type="other">
Unicode Consortium: 1991, The Unicode Standard, Worldwide Character Encoding, Addison-
Wesley, Reading, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
