<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939365</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Optimal Tax 2</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Optimal Income Taxation with Spillovers from Employer Learning</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Craig</surname>
                  <given-names>Ashley C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>82</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939365"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>I study optimal income taxation when human capital investment is imperfectly observable by employers. In my model, Bayesian employer inference about worker productivity drives a wedge between the private and social returns to human capital investment by compressing the wage distribution. The resulting positive externality from worker investment implies lower optimal marginal tax rates, all else being equal. To quantify the significance of this externality for optimal taxation, I calibrate the model to match empirical moments from the United States, including new evidence on how the speed of employer learning about new labor market entrants varies over the worker productivity distribution. Taking into account the spillover from human capital investment introduced by employer inference reduces optimal marginal tax rates by 13 percentage points at around 100,000 dollars of income, with little change in the tails of the income distribution. The welfare gain from this adjustment is equivalent to raising every worker’s consumption by one percent.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Aakvik, Arild, Kjell G. Salvanes, and Kjell Vaage, “Measuring Heterogeneity in the Returns to Education using an Education Reform,” European Economic Review, 2010, 54 (4), 483–500.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Abramitzky, Ran and Victor Lavy, “How Responsive is Investment in Schooling to Changes in Returns? Evidence from an Unusual Pay Reform in Israel’s Kibbutzim,” Econometrica, 2010, 82 (4), 1241–1272.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Acemoglu, Daron and Jorn-Steffen Pischke, “Why Do Firms Train? Theory and Evidence,” The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1998, 113 (1), 79–119.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Agan, Amanda and Sonja Starr, “Ban the Box, Criminal Records, and Racial Discrimination: A Field Experiment,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2018, 133 (1), 191–235.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Aigner, Dennis J. and Glen G. Cain, “Statistical Theories of Discrimination in Labor Markets,” Industrial and Labor Relations Review, 1977, 30 (2), 175–187.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Akerlof, George A., “The Economics of “Tagging” as Applied to the Optimal Income Tax, Welfare Programs, and Manpower Planning,” American Economic Review, 1978, 68 (1), 8–19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Albanesi, Stefania and Christopher Sleet, “Dynamic Optimal Taxation with Private Information,” Review of Economic Studies, 2006, 733 (1), 1–30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Altonji, Joseph G. and C. Pierret, “Employer Learning and Statistical Discrimination,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2001, 116 (1), 313–50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Andersson, Fredrik, “Income Taxation and Job-market Signaling,” Journal of Public Economics, 1996, 59 (2), 277–298.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Arcidiacono, Peter, Patrick Bayer, and Aurel Hizmo, “Beyond Signaling and Human Capital: Education and the Revelation of Ability,” American Economic Journal: Applied Economics, 2010, 2 (4), 76–104.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Arrow, Kenneth, “The Theory of Discrimination,” in Orley Ashenfelter and Albert Rees, eds., Discrimination in Labor Markets, New Jersey: Princeton University Press, 1973, pp. 3–33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Baker, George P., Michael Gibbs, and Bengt Holmstrom, “The Internal Economics of the Firm-Evidence From Personnel Data,” The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1994, 109 (4), 881–919.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Bedard, Kelly, “Human Capital versus Signaling Models: University Access and High School Dropouts,” Journal of Political Economy, 2001, 109 (4), 749–775.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Bertrand, Marianne and Sendhil Mullainathan, “Are Emily and Greg More Employable Than Lakisha and Jamal? A Field Experiment on Labor Market Discrimination,” American Economic Review, 2004, 94 (4), 991–1013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Best, Michael Carlos and Henrik Jacobsen Kleven, “Optimal Income Taxation with Career Effects of Work,” Working Paper, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Blair, Peter Q and BobbyWChung, “Job Market Signaling Through Occupational Licensing,” NBER Working Paper No. 24791, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Blomquist, Sören and Håkan Selin, “Hourly Wage Rate and Taxable Labor Income Responsiveness to Changes in Marginal Tax Rates,” Journal of Public Economics, 2010, 94 (11-12), 878–889.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Boháček, Radim and Marek Kapička, “Optimal Human Capital Policies,” Journal of Monetary Economics, 2008, 55 (1), 1–16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Bovenberg, A. Lans and Bas Jacobs, “Redistribution and Education Subsidies are Siamese Twins,” Journal of Public Economics, 2005, 89 (11-12), 2005–2035.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Champernowne, D. G., “The Graduation of Income Distributions,” Econometrica, 1952, 20 (4), 591–615.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Chetty, Raj, “Bounds on Elasticities With Optimization Frictions: A Synthesis of Micro and Macro Evidence on Labor Supply,” Econometrica, 2012, 80 (3), 969–1018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Coate, Stephen and Glenn C. Loury, “Antidiscrimination Enforcement and the Problem of Patronization,” American Economic Review, 1993, 83 (2), 92–98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Craig, Ashley C. and Roland G. Fryer, “Complementary Bias: A Model of Two-Sided Statistical Discrimination,” NBER Working Paper No. 23811, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">da Costa, Carlos E. and Lucas J. Maestri, “The Risk Properties of Human Capital and the Design of Government Policies,” European Economic Review, 2007, 51 (3), 695-713.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Diamond, Peter A., “Optimal Income Taxation: An Example with a U-Shaped Pattern of Optimal Marginal Tax Rates,” American Economic Review, 1998, 88 (1), 83–95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Doleac, Jennifer L. and Benjamin Hansen, “The Unintended Consequences of ’Ban the Box’: Statistical Discrimination and Employment Outcomes When Criminal Histories Are Hidden,” SSRN Working Paper, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Fang, Hanming and Andrea Moro, “Theories of Statistical Discrimination and Affirmative Action: A Survey,” in Jess Benhabib, Matthew O. Jackson, and Alberto Bisin, eds., Handbook of Social Economics, Elsevier, 2011, chapter 5, pp. 133–200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Farber, Henry S and Robert Gibbons, “Learning and Wage Dynamics,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1996, 111 (4), 1007–1047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Farhi, Emmanuel and Iván Werning, “Insurance and Taxation over the Life Cycle,” Review of Economic Studies, 2013, 80 (2), 596–635.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Feldstein, Martin, “Tax Avoidance and the Deadweight Loss of the Income Tax,” Review of Economics and Statistics, 1999, 81 (4), 674–680.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Findeisen, Sebastian and Dominik Sachs, “Education and Optimal Dynamic Taxation: The Role of Income-Contingent Student Loans,” Journal of Public Economics, 2016, 138, 1–21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Fryer, Roland G., “Belief Flipping in a Dynamic Model of Statistical Discrimination,” Journal of Public Economics, 2007, 91 (5-6), 1151–1166.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Fryer, Roland G. and Glenn C. Loury, “Valuing Diversity,” Journal of Political Economy, 2013, 121 (4), 747–774.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Golosov, Mikhail, Maxim Troshkin, and Aleh Tsyvinski, “Redistribution and Social Insurance,” American Economic Review, 2016, 106 (2), 359–386.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Gomes, Renato, Jean Marie Lozachmeur, and Alessandro Pavan, “Differential Taxation and Occupational Choice,” Review of Economic Studies, 2018, 85 (1), 511–557.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Hansen, Karsten T., James J. Heckman, and Kathleen J. Mullen, “The Effect of Schooling and Ability on Achievement Test Scores,” Journal of Econometrics, 2004, 121 (1-2), 39–98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Heckman, James J., Jora Stixrud, and Sergio Urzua, “The Effects of Cognitive and Noncognitive Abilities on Labor Market Outcomes and Social Behavior,” Journal of Labor Economics, 2006, 24 (3), 411–482.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Heckman, James J. , Lance J. Lochner, and Petra E. Todd, “Earnings Functions, Rates of Return and Treatment Effects: The Mincer Equation and Beyond,” in Eric A. Hanushek and Finis Welch, eds., Handbook of the Economics of Education, Elsevier, 2006, chapter 7, pp. 307–458.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Hedlund, Aaron, “Estate Taxation and Human Capital with Information Externalities,” Macroeconomic Dynamics, 2018, pp. 1–33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Hendren, Nathaniel, “The Policy Elasticity,” NBER Working Paper No. 19177, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Jacobs, Bas, “Optimal Income Taxation with Endogenous Human Capital,” Journal of Public Economic Theory, 2005, 7 (2), 295–315.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Jacobs, Bas, “Optimal Tax and Education Policies and Investments in Human Capital,” in Joop Hartog and Henriëtte Maassen van den Brink, eds., Human Capital: Moving the Frontier, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2007, pp. 212–232.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Jensen, Robert T., “The (Perceived) Returns to Education and the Demand for Schooling,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2010, 125 (2), 515–548.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Kahn, Lisa B. and Fabian Lange, “Employer Learning, Productivity, and the Earnings Distribution: Evidence from Performance Measures,” Review of Economic Studies, 2014, 81 (4), 1575–1613.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Kapička, Marek, “Optimal Mirrleesean Taxation in a Ben-Porath Economy,” American Economic Journal: Macroeconomics, 2015, 7 (2), 219–248.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Kaplow, Louis, “Optimal Income Transfers,” International Tax and Public Finance, 2007, 14 (3), 295–325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Kline, Patrick and Enrico Moretti, “Local Economic Development, Agglomeration Economies, and the Big Push: 100 Years of Evidence from the Tennessee Valley Authority,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2014, 129 (1), 275–331.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Krueger, Dirk and Alexander Ludwig, “On the Optimal Provision of Social Insurance: Progressive Taxation versus Education Subsidies in General Equilibrium,” Journal of Monetary Economics, 2016, 77, 72–98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Kuka, Elira, Na’ama Shenhav, and Kevin Shih, “Do Human Capital Decisions Respond to the Returns to Education? Evidence from DACA,” NBERWorking Paper No. 24315, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Lang, Kevin and David Kropp, “Human Capital Versus Sorting: The Effects of Compulsory Attendance Laws,” The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1986, 101 (3), 609–624.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Lang, Kevin and Michael Manove, “Education and Labor-market Discrimination,” American Economic Review, 2006, 101 (4), 1467–1496.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Lange, Fabian, “The Speed of Employer Learning,” Journal of Labor Economics, 2007, 25 (1), 1–35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Lange, Fabian and Robert Topel, “The Social Value of Education and Human Capital,” in Eric A. Hanushek and Finis Welch, eds., Handbook of the Economics of Education, Vol. 1, Elsevier, 2006, chapter 8, pp. 459–509.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Lazear, Edward P. and Sherwin Rosen, “Rank-Order Tournaments as Optimum Labor Contracts,” Journal of Political Economy, 1981, 89 (5), 841–864.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Lehmann, Etienne, Laurent Simula, and Alain Trannoy, “Tax Me if You Can! Optimal Nonlinear Income Tax Between Competing Governments,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2014, 129 (4), 1995–2030.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Lindqvist, Erik and Roine Westman, “The Labor Market Returns to Cognitive and Noncognitive Ability: Evidence from the Swedish Enlistment,” American Economic Journal: Applied Economics, 2011, 3 (January), 101–128.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Lockwood, Benjamin B., Charles G. Nathanson, and E. Glen Weyl, “Taxation and the Allocation of Talent,” Journal of Political Economy, 2017, 125 (5), 1–49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Lundberg, Shelly J. and Richard Startz, “Private Discrimination and Social Intervention in Competitive Labor Market,” American Economic Review, 1983, 73 (3), 340–347.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">MacLeod, W. Bentley, Evan Riehl, Juan E. Saavedra, and Miguel Urquiola, “The Big Sort: College Reputation and Labor Market Outcomes,” American Economic Journal: Applied Economics, 2017, 9 (3), 223–261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Mailath, George J. and Ernst Ludwig von Thadden, “Incentive Compatibility and Differentiability: New Results and Classic Applications,” Journal of Economic Theory, 2013, 148 (5), 1841–1861.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Makris, Miltiadis and Alessandro Pavan, “Taxation under Learning-by-Doing,” Working Paper, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <mixed-citation id="c62">Maldonado, Darío, “Education Policies and Optimal Taxation,” International Tax and Public Finance, 2008, 15 (2), 131–143.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Mankiw, N. Gregory and Matthew Weinzierl, “The Optimal Taxation of Height: A Case Study of Utilitarian Income Redistribution,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 2010, 2 (1), 155–176.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Mankiw, N. Gregory, Matthew Weinzierl and Danny Yagan, “Optimal Taxation in Theory and Practice,” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 2009, 23 (4), 147–174.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r65">
            <mixed-citation id="c65">Meghir, Costas and Marten Palme, “Educational Reform, Ability, and Family Background,” American Economic Review, 2005, 95 (1), 414–424.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r66">
            <mixed-citation id="c66">Mertens, Karel and José L. M. Montiel-Olea, “Marginal Tax Rates and Income: New Time Series Evidence,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2018, 4 (1), 1803–1884.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r67">
            <mixed-citation id="c67">Milgrom, Paul and Sharon Oster, “Job Discrimination, Market Forces, and the Invisibility Hypothesis,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1987, 102 (3), 453–476.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r68">
            <mixed-citation id="c68">Mirrlees, James A., “An Exploration in the Theory of Optimum Income Taxation,” Review of Economic Studies, 1971, 38 (2), 175–208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r69">
            <mixed-citation id="c69">Moretti, Enrico, “Estimating the Social Return to Higher Education: Evidence from Longitudinal and Repeated Cross-sectional Data,” Journal of Econometrics, 2004, 121 (1-2), 175–212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r70">
            <mixed-citation id="c70">Moro, Andrea and Peter Norman, “A General Equilibrium Model of Statistical Discrimination,” Journal of Economic Theory, 2004, 114 (1), 1–30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r71">
            <mixed-citation id="c71">Neal, Derek and William R. Johnson, “The Role of Premarket Factors in Black-White Wage Differences,” Journal of Political Economy, 1996, 104 (5), 869–895.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r72">
            <mixed-citation id="c72">Oreopoulos, Philip, “The Compelling Effects of Compulsory Schooling: Evidence from Canada,” Canadian Journal of Economics, 2006, 39 (1), 22–52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r73">
            <mixed-citation id="c73">Pallais, Amanda, “Inefficient Hiring in Entry-level Labor Markets,” American Economic Review, 2014, 104 (11), 3565–3599.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r74">
            <mixed-citation id="c74">Pallais, Amanda and Emily Glassberg Sands, “Why the Referential Treatment? Evidence from a Field Experiment on Referrals,” Journal of Political Economy, 2016, 124 (6), 1793–1828.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r75">
            <mixed-citation id="c75">Phelps, Edmund S, “The Statistical theory of Racism and Sexism,” American Economic Review, 1972, 62 (4), 659–661.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r76">
            <mixed-citation id="c76">Piketty, Thomas and Emmanuel Saez, “Optimal Labor Income Taxation,” in Alan J. Auerbach, Raj Chetty, Martin Feldstein, and Emmanuel Saez, eds., Handbook of Public Economics, Elsevier, 2013, chapter 7, pp. 391–474.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r77">
            <mixed-citation id="c77">Piketty, Thomas, Emmanuel Saez and Stefanie Stantcheva, “Optimal Taxation of Top Labor Incomes: A Tale of Three Elasticities,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 2014, 6 (1), 230–271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r78">
            <mixed-citation id="c78">Pinkston, Joshua C., “A Test of Screening Discrimination with Employer Learning,” Industrial and Labor Relations Review, 2006, 59 (2), 267–284.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r79">
            <mixed-citation id="c79">Prendergast, Canice, “The Role of Promotion in Inducing Specific Human Capital Acquisition,” The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1993, 108 (2), 523–534.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r80">
            <mixed-citation id="c80">Rothschild, Casey and Florian Scheuer, “Redistributive Taxation in the Roy Model,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2013, 128 (2), 623–668.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r81">
            <mixed-citation id="c81">Rothschild, Casey and Florian Scheuer , “Optimal Taxation with Rent-Seeking,” Review of Economic Studies, 2016, 83 (1), 1225–1262.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r82">
            <mixed-citation id="c82">Sachs, Dominik, Aleh Tsyvinski, and Nicolas Werquin, “Nonlinear Tax Incidence and Optimal Taxation in General Equilibrium,” SSRN Working Paper, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r83">
            <mixed-citation id="c83">Saez, Emmanuel, “Using Elasticities to Derive Optimal Income Tax Rates,” Review of Economic Studies, 2001, 68 (1), 205–229.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r84">
            <mixed-citation id="c84">Saez, Emmanuel, “Optimal Income Transfer Programs: Intensive Versus Extensive Labor Supply Responses,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2002, 117 (3), 1039–1073.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r85">
            <mixed-citation id="c85">Sarsons, Heather, “Interpreting Signals in the Labor Market: Evidence from Medical Referrals,” Working Paper, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r86">
            <mixed-citation id="c86">Shoag, Daniel and Robert Clifford, “’No More Credit Score’: Employer Credit Check Bans and Signal Substitution,” SSRN Working Paper, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r87">
            <mixed-citation id="c87">Simula, Laurent and Alain Trannoy, “Optimal Income Tax Under the Threat of Migration by Top-Income Earners,” Journal of Public Economics, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r88">
            <mixed-citation id="c88">Spence, Michael, “Job Market Signaling,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1973, 87 (3), 355–374.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r89">
            <mixed-citation id="c89">Spence, Michael, “Competitive and Optimal Responses to Signals: An Analysis of Efficiency and Distribution,” Journal of Economic Theory, 1974, 7 (3), 296–332.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r90">
            <mixed-citation id="c90">Stantcheva, Stefanie, “Optimal Income Taxation with Adverse Selection in the Labour Market,” Review of Economic Studies, 2014, 81 (3), 1296–1329.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r91">
            <mixed-citation id="c91">Stantcheva, Stefanie, “Optimal Taxation and Human Capital Policies over the Life Cycle,” Journal of Political Economy, 2017, 125 (6), 1931–1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r92">
            <mixed-citation id="c92">Stanton, Christopher T. and Catherine Thomas, “Landing the First Job: The Value of Intermediaries in Online Hiring,” Review of Economic Studies, 2016, 83 (2), 810–854.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r93">
            <mixed-citation id="c93">Stiglitz, Joseph E., “Self-selection and Pareto Efficient Taxation,” Journal of Public Economics, 1982, 17 (2), 213–240.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r94">
            <mixed-citation id="c94">Trostel, Philip A., “The Effect of Taxation on Human Capital,” Journal of Political Economy, 1993, 101 (2), 327–350.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r95">
            <mixed-citation id="c95">Wozniak, Abigail, “Discrimination and the Effects of Drug Testing on Black Employment,” Review of Economics and Statistics, 2015, 97 (3), 548–566</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Timeline of the Game</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Changes in Wages and Utility in Response to Lower τ</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>A Local Perturbation to T</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Productivity and Redistributive Effects</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Response to a Marginal Tax Rate Change</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Effect on Utility of a Marginal Tax Rate Change</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Heterogeneity in Employer Learning</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Calibrated and Implied Objects</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Equilibrium Relationships implied by the Calibration</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Optimal Non-linear Taxation</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Utility Gain from Optimal Taxation</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Equilibria and Taxation</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 11:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Approximately Optimal Taxation</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Summary Statistics for High and Low AFQT Workers</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 12:</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Comparison of Fiscal Externality</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 13:</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Comparison of Belief Externality</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 14:</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Comparison of Mechanical Effect</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 15:</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Marginal Social Welfare Weights</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 16:</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Non-linear Taxation with Alternative Parameter Values</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
