<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24909629</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>THE PRESIDENTIAL PLATFORMS</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Valuing Analysis, Valuing MORS!</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kwinn</surname>
                  <given-names>Mike</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>LTC Michael J. Kwinn, Jr., Ph.D. is an Associate Professor of Systems Engineering at the United States Military Academy at West Point where he currently directs the Systems Engineering and Operations Research programs.. Mike graduated from the United States Military Academy at West Point in 1984 and was commissioned as a Second Lieutenant in the Air Defense Artillery. He has been stationed at Fort Bliss, Texas, Germany, Fort Carson, Colorado and Camp Stanley, Korea. He has received a Master of Science from the University of Arizona, a Master of Arts in National Security and Strategic Studies (with Distinction) from the Naval War College, and a Ph.D in Management Science from the University of Texas at Austin. He has worked on systems engineering projects for over 10 years, most recently as the Director of the Operations Research Center (ORCEN) at the United States Military Academy. Some of his recent work is in the areas of acquisition simulation analysis, military recruiting process management, condition-based maintenance implementation and assessment systems development for combat operations. He is on the Executive Council for the Board of Directors for the Military Operations Research Society (MORS), is a member of the International Council on Systems Engineering (INCOSE), the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS) and has served as an advisory member for the Army Science Board. LTC Kwinn is married to LTC(R) Brigitte Kwinn (USMA ’84) and has four daughters: Cheryl (20) who is a sophomore at the Massachusetts Institute for Technology, Jasmine (4), Jade (3) and Emerald (21 mos.). His son Michael passed away three years ago and Mike is the President of the Friends4Michael Foundation named in memory of his son.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2007</year>
            <string-date>June 2007</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>40</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e24909607</issue-id>
         <fpage>24</fpage>
         <lpage>28</lpage>
         <page-range>24, 27-28</page-range>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2007, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24909629"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
