<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">29</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186500</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44437711</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Modern Headlighting Requirements</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>R. N.</given-names>
                  <surname>Falge</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1934</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>212</fpage>
         <lpage>216</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44437711"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>THE prospects for substantially improved headlighting conditions in the future look very promising, Mr. Falge concludes. Assurance of safe headlighting conditions on our roads at night involves the full cooperation of those who build the lamps, those who specify how they shall be used, those who are responsible for their maintenance, and those who use them. The automotive industry, interested technical societies and state enforcement officials have done an excellent job in establishing the fundamental requirements underlying safe headlighting and in developing test specifications to cover them. More than three-quarters of the cars on the road are equipped with headlamps capable of complying with these requirements when properly maintained, adjusted, and used. The stage is all set for the final drive to permit and induce motorists to adjust and use their headlamps in accordance with this practice. Legislation is needed to specify the multiplebeam practice in all states. The National Conference on Street and Highway Safety is considering the revision of the Uniform Vehicle Code to legalize this practice at its next meeting in May. Educational work, supplemented by active enforcement, is needed to encourage motorists to maintain their head-lamps in efficient operating condition and to use the proper beam at the right time. The National Safety Council has agreed to cooperate in putting on an intensive educational campaign.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


