<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</issue>
         <issue-id>i40038998</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40865574</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Risk and Return Characteristics of Venture Capital-Backed Entrepreneurial Companies</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Arthur</given-names>
                  <surname>Korteweg</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Morten</given-names>
                  <surname>Sorensen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2010</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>3738</fpage>
         <lpage>3772</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40865574"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Valuations of entrepreneurial companies are only observed occasionally, albeit more frequently for well-performing companies. Consequently, estimators of risk and return must correct for sample selection to obtain consistent estimates. We develop a general model of dynamic sample selection and estimate it using data from venture capital investments in entrepreneurial companies. Our selection correction leads to markedly lower intercepts and higher estimates of risks compared to previous studies. The methodology is generally applicable to estimating risk and return in illiquid markets with endogenous trading.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d62e311a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e315" publication-type="other">
Albert, J., and S. Chib. 1993. Bayesian Analysis of Binary and Polychotomous Response Data. Journal of the
American Statistical Association 88:669-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e325a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e329" publication-type="other">
Amemiya, T. 1985. Advanced Econometrics. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e336a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e340" publication-type="other">
Anderson, B., and J. Moore. 1979. Optimal Filtering. New York: Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e347a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e351" publication-type="other">
Andrews, D., and M. Schafgans. 1998. Semiparametric Estimation of the Intercept of a Sample Selection Model.
Review of Economics Studies 65:497-517.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e362a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e366" publication-type="other">
Baquero, G., J. ter Horst, and M. Verbeek. 2005. Survival, Look-Ahead Bias, and Persistence in Hedge Fund
Performance. Journal of Financial and Quatitative Analysis 40:493-517.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e376a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e380" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J., A. Lo, and A. MacKinlay. 1997. The Econometrics of Financial Markets. Princeton, NJ: Princeton
University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e390a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e394" publication-type="other">
Carter, C, and R. Kohn. 1994. On Gibbs Sampling for State Space Models. Biometrika 81:541-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e401a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e405" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. 2005. The Risk and Return of Venture Capital. Journal of Financial Economics 75:3-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e412a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e416" publication-type="other">
Davis, J., E. Fama, and K. French. 2000. Characteristics, Covariances, and Average Returns: 1929 to 1997.
Journal of Finance 55:389-406.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e426a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e430" publication-type="other">
Dimson, E. 1979. Risk Measurement When Shares Are Subject to Infrequent Trading. Journal of Financial
Economics 7:197-226.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e441a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e445" publication-type="other">
Driessen, J., T.-C. Lin, and L. Phalippou. 2007. A New Method to Estimate Risk and Return of Non-Traded
Assets from Cash Flows: The Case of Private Equity Funds. Working Paper, University of Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e455a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e459" publication-type="other">
Fama, E., and K. French. 1995. Size and Book-to-Market Factors in Earnings and Returns. Journal of Finance
50:131-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e469a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e473" publication-type="other">
Fisher, J., D. Gatzlaff, D. Geltner, and D. Haurin. 2003. Controlling for the Impact of Variable Liquidity in
Commercial Real Estate Price Indices. Real Estate Economics 31:269-303.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e483a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e487" publication-type="other">
Fruhwirth-Schnatter, S. 1994. Data Augmentation and Dynamic Linear Models. Journal of Time Series Analysis
15:183-202.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e497a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e501" publication-type="other">
Gatzlaff, D., and D. Haurin. 1997. Sample Selection Bias and Repeat-Sales Index Estimates. Journal of Real
Estate Finance and Economics 14:33-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e511a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e515" publication-type="other">
Gelfand, A., and A. Smith. 1990. Sampling Based Approaches to Calculating Marginal Densities. Journal of the
American Statistical Association 85:398-409.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e526a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e530" publication-type="other">
Gelman, A., and D. B. Rubin. 1992. Inference from Iterative Simulation Using Multiple Sequences. Statistical
Science 1 :457-511.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e540a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e544" publication-type="other">
Geman, S., and D. Geman. 1984. Stochastic Relaxation, Gibbs Distributions, and the Bayesian Restoration of
Images. IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence 6:721-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e554a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e558" publication-type="other">
Geweke, J. 1992. Evaluating the Accuracy of Sampling-Based Approaches to the Calculation of Posterior Mo-
ments. In J. Bernardo, J. Berger, A. Dawid, and A. Smith (eds.), Bayesian Statistics 4. Oxford: Oxford University
Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e571a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e575" publication-type="other">
Goetzmann, W., and L. Peng. 2006. Estimating House Price Indexes in the Presence of Seller Reservation Prices.
Review of Economics and Statistics 88:100-12.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e585a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e589" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P., and J. Lerner. 1997. Risk and Reward in Private Equity Investments: The Challenge of Performance
Assessment. Journal of Private Equity 1:5-12.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e599a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e603" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P., and J. Lerner. 1999. The Venture Capital Cycle. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e611a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e615" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P., and J. Lerner, 2000, Money Chasing Deals? The Impact of Fund Inflows on Private Equity Valua-
tions, Journal of Financial Economics 55:281-325.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e625a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e629" publication-type="other">
Heckman, J. 1979. Sample Selection Bias as a Specification Error. Econometrica 47:153-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e636a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e640" publication-type="other">
Heckman, J. 1990. Varieties of Selection Bias. American Economic Review 80:313-18.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e647a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e651" publication-type="other">
Hwang, M., and J. Quigley. 2003. Selectivity, Quality Adjustment and Mean Reversion in the Measurement of
House Values. Journal of Real Estate Finance and Economics 28: 161-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e661a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e665" publication-type="other">
Hwang, M., J. Quigley, and S. Woodward. 2005. An Index for Venture Capital, 1987-2003. Contributions to
Economic Analysis &amp; Policy 4: 1-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e675a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e679" publication-type="other">
Jagannathan, R., M. Alexey, and D. Novikov. 2009. Do Hot Hands Exist among Hedge Fund Managers? An
Empirical Evaluation. Journal of Finance, Forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e690a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e694" publication-type="other">
Johannes, M., and N. Polson. 2010. MCMC Methods for Financial Econometrics. In Y. Ait-Sahalia and
L. Hansen (eds.), Handbook of Financial Econometrics, Forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e704a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e708" publication-type="other">
Jones, C, and M. Rhodes-Kropf. 2003. The Price of Diversifiable Risk in Venture Capital and Private Equity.
Working Paper, Columbia University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e718a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e722" publication-type="other">
Kaiman, R. 1960. A New Approach to Linear Filtering and Prediction Problems. Journal of Basic Engineering
82:35-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e732a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e736" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S., and A. Schoar. 2005. Private Equity Performance: Returns, Persistence, and Capital Flows. Journal
of Finance 60:1791-823.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e746a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e750" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S., B. Sensoy, and P. Strömberg. 2002. How Well Do Venture Capital Databases Reflect Actual Invest-
ments? Working Paper, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e760a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e764" publication-type="other">
Ljungqvist, A., and M. Richardson. 2003. The Cash Row, Return and Risk Characteristics of Private Equity.
Working Paper, NYU Stern School of Business</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e775a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e779" publication-type="other">
Peng, L. 2001. Building a Venture Capital Index. Working Paper, University of Colorado, Boulder.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e786a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e790" publication-type="other">
Phalippou, L., and O. Gottschalg. 2009. The Performance of Private Equity Funds. Review of Financial Studies
22:1747-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e800a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e804" publication-type="other">
Reyes, J. 1990. Industry Struggling to Forge Tools for Measuring Risk. Venture Capital Journal 30:23-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e811a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e815" publication-type="other">
Robert, C, and G. Casella. 2004. Monte Carlo Statistical Methods. New York: Springer-Verlag.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e822a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e826" publication-type="other">
Rossi, P., G. Allenby, and R. McCulloch. 2005. Bayesian Statistics and Marketing. Chichester, UK: John Wiley
and Sons.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e836a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e840" publication-type="other">
Sahlman, W. 1990. The Structure and Governance of Venture Capital Organizations. Journal of Financial Eco-
nomics 27:473-521.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e851a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e855" publication-type="other">
Scholes, MM and J. Williams. 1977. Estimating Betas from Nonsynchronous Data. Journal of Financial Eco-
nomics 5:309-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e865a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e869" publication-type="other">
Tanner, M, and W. Wong. 1987. The Calculation of Posterior Distributions by Data Augmentation. Journal of
the American Statistical Association 82:528-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d62e879a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d62e883" publication-type="other">
ter Horst, J., and M. Verbeek. 2007. Fund Liquidation, Self-Selection, and Look-Ahead Bias in the Hedge Fund
Industry. Review of Finance 11 :605-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


