<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">16</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830312</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830317</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>ON THE REDUCTION OF INTEREST RATE MARGINS IN DEVELOPING COUNTRIES AND IMPLICATED WELFARE EFFECTS FOR PRIVATE HOUSEHOLDS / LA REDUCTION DES MARGES DES TAUX D'INTERET DANS LES PAYS EN VOIE DE DEVELOPPEMENT ET SES EFFETS ECONOMIQUES SUR LES MENAGES</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Friedrich L.</given-names>
                  <surname>Sell</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Silke</given-names>
                  <surname>Wohlgemuth</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1992</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>403</fpage>
         <lpage>420</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830317"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper derives some implications in order to improve the allocative efficiency of the financial sector in developing countries. The central hypothesis is that lowering the intermediation costs will lead to higher deposit and/or to lower lending rates — that is a reduction of the interest rate margin. As a consequence, financial intermediaries are able to extend their volume of credits and respectively to mobilize more savings. The purpose of this paper is to explore, mainly with analytical and graphical methods, the determinants of intermediation costs, the welfare effects of a decreasing interest rate margin on representative households and welfare implications of interest rate policy combined with stabilization policies. Le présent article révèle quelques implications qui pourraient aider à améliorer l'efficience d'allocation du secteur financier des pays en voie de développement. L'hypothèse centrale est qu'un abaissement des coûts intermédiaires produira des intérêts créditeurs relevés et/ou des intérêts débiteurs réduits — donc une réduction de la marge d'intérêt. Par conséquent, les intermédiaires financiers pourront élargir leur volume de crédit et stimuler l'épargne. Le but de cet article est d'éxaminer, par des méthodes analytiques et graphiques surtout, les facteurs déterminant les coûts intermédiaires, les effets économiques d'une marge d'intérêt décroissante sur des ménages représentatifs ainsi que les effets d'une politique combinée des taux d'intérêt et de stabilisation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d50e211a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e215" publication-type="other">
Acharya, S./Madhur, S., Informal Credit Markets and Black Money. Do They Frustrate Monetary Policy? In:
Economic and Political Weekly, Vol. XVIII, No. 41, 1983, pp. 1751-1756.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e225a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e229" publication-type="other">
Agabin, M.H./Lamberte, M.J., Integrative Report on the Informal Credit Markets in the Philippines. PIDS Work-
ing Paper Series No. 89-10, Manila 1989.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e239a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e243" publication-type="other">
Center for Research and Communication Institute of Industrial Economics (CRC), An Econometric Model for
Simulating Reductions in Intermediation Costs, Mimeo, Manila, October 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e253a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e257" publication-type="other">
Corbo, V./Schmidt-Hebbel, K., Public Policies and Saving in Development Countries, in: Journal of Develop-
ment Economics, Vol. 36, No. 1, 1991, pp. 89-115.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e268a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e272" publication-type="other">
Corsepius, U., Savings Mobilisation in Developing Countries, in: Intereconomics, Vol. 23, No. 1,1988, pp. 30-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e279a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e283" publication-type="other">
Corsepius, U., The Structure of Financial Savings and Loanable Funds: Evidence from Peru, in: Savings and
Development, Vol. XIV, No. 1, 1990, pp. 89-100.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e293a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e297" publication-type="other">
Fry, M.J., Money, Interest, and Banking in Economic Development, Baltimore 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e304a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e308" publication-type="other">
Giovannini, A., Savings and the Real Interest Rate in LDC's, in: Journal of Development Economics, Vol. 18,
No. 3, 1985, pp. 197-217.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e318a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e322" publication-type="other">
Gupta, K.L., Aggregate Savings, Financial Intermediation and Interest Rate, in: The Review of Economics and
Statistics, Vol. 69, No. 2, 1987, pp. 303-311.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e332a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e336" publication-type="other">
Hannan, T.H./Berger, A.N., The Rigidity of Prices: Evidence from the Banking Industry, in: AER, Vol. 81, No.
4, 1991, pp. 938-945.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e347a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e351" publication-type="other">
Haque, N.U., Fiscal Policy and Private Sector Saving Behavior in Developing Economies, in: IMF Staff Papers,
Vol. 35, No. 2, 1988, pp. 316-335.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e361a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e365" publication-type="other">
Haque, N.U./Montiel, P., Consumption in Developing Countries: Tests for Liquidity Constraints and Finite Horizons,
in: The Review of Economics and Statistics, Vol. 31, No. 3, 1989, pp. 408-415.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e375a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e379" publication-type="other">
Leiderman, L./Blejer, M.I., Modeling and Testing Ricardian Equivalence, in: IMF Staff Papers, Vol. 35, No. 1,
1988, pp. 1-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e389a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e393" publication-type="other">
Liang, M.-Y., Savings in Taiwan: An Empirical Investigation, in: Journal of Economic Development, Vol. 8, No.
2, 1983, pp. 109-129.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e403a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e407" publication-type="other">
McKinnon, R.I., Money and Capital in Economic Development, Washington, D.C, 1973.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e414a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e418" publication-type="other">
Moffitt, R., The Econometrics of Kinked Budget Constraints, in: Journal of Economic Perspectives, Vol. 4, No.
2, 1990, pp. 119-139.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e429a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e433" publication-type="other">
Olson, M./Bailey, M.J., Positive Time Preference, in: Journal of Political Economy, Vol. 89, No. 1, 1981, pp.
1-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e443a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e447" publication-type="other">
Sell, F.L., IS-LM auch in den Tropen: Zu den gesamtwirtschaftlichen Wirkungen von Zinsreformen in Ent-
wicklungslandern, in: Konjunkturpolitik, Vol. 34, No. 2, pp. 104-121.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e457a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e461" publication-type="other">
Shaw, E.S., Financial Deepening in Economic Development, New York/Oxford 1973.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e468a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e472" publication-type="other">
The World Bank, World Development Report, Washington, D.C, 1989.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e479a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e483" publication-type="other">
Thillainathan, R., Are Malaysian Bank Lending Rates too High?, ISIS Issue Paper, Kuala Lumpur 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e490a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e494" publication-type="other">
Tsiang, S.C., Interest Rate and Consumption: A Comment, in: International Economic Review, Vol. 14, No. 2,
1973, pp. 493-496.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e505a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e509" publication-type="other">
v. Wijnbergen, S., Interest Rate Management in LDC's, in: Journal of Monetary Economics, Vol. 12, No. 3,1983,
pp. 433-452.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


