<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277816</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental Investigation of Transient Response and Turbocharger Coupling for High and Low Pressure EGR Systems</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Heuwetter</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Glewen</surname>
                  <given-names>William</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Foster</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Krieger</surname>
                  <given-names>Roger</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andrie</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Wisconsin</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277784</issue-id>
         <fpage>977</fpage>
         <lpage>985</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277816"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The transient response of an engine with both High Pressure (HP) and Low Pressure (LP) EGR loops was compared by conducting step changes in EGR fraction at a constant engine speed and load. The HP EGR loop performance was shown to be closely linked to turbocharger performance, whereas the LP EGR loop was relatively independent of turbocharger performance and vice versa. The same experiment was repeated with the variable geometry turbine vanes completely open to reduce turbocharger action and achieve similar EGR rate changes with the HP and LP EGR loops. Under these conditions, the increased loop volume of the LP EGR loop prolonged the response of intake O2 concentration following the change in air-fuel ratio. The prolonged change of intake O2 concentration caused emissions to require more time to reach steady state as well. Strong coupling between the HP EGR loop and turbochargers was again observed using a hybrid EGR strategy. The potential benefit of the HP EGR loop's smaller volume and shorter residence time was largely negated by the simultaneous use of the larger LP EGR loop. Under these conditions, the intake charge oxygen concentration responded more quickly to actuation of the LP EGR valve than the HP EGR valve.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wijetunge, R., Brace, C., Hawley, J., Vaughan, N. et al., “Dynamic Behaviour of a High Speed Direct Injection Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0829, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0829.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hagena, J., Filipi, Z., and Assanis, D., “Transient Diesel Emissions: Analysis of Engine Operation During a Tip-In,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1151, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Glewen, W., Meyer, C., Foster, D., Andrie, M. et al., “Sources and Tradeoffs for Transient NO and UHC Emissions with Low Temperature Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01- 1356, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maiboom, A., Tauzia, X., Shah, S., and Hétet, J., “Experimental Study of an LP EGR System on an Automotive Diesel Engine, compared to HP EGR with respect to PM and NOx Emissions and Specific Fuel Consumption,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):597-610, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cho, K., Han, M., Wagner, R., and Sluder, C., “Mixed-Source EGR for Enabling High Efficiency Clean Combustion Modes in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):457-465, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0645.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shutty, J., “Control Strategy Optimization for Hybrid EGR Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1451, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01- 1451.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reifarth, S. and Angstrom, H., “Transient EGR in a High-Speed DI Diesel Engine for a set of different EGR-routings,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):1071-1078, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moroz, S., Bourgoin, G., Luján, J., and Pla, B., “Acidic Condensation in Low Pressure EGR Systems using Diesel and Biodiesel Fuels,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(2):305-312, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2805.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meyer, C., “Implementation and Transient Effects of Low Pressure EGR on Low Temperature Diesel Combustion”, M.S. Thesis, Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin, Madison, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heuwetter, D., Glewen, W., Meyer, C., Foster, D. et al., “Effects of Low Pressure EGR on Transient Air System Performance and Emissions for Low Temperature Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0062, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0062.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Y., Liu, Z., Zhao, J., Xu, Y. et al., “EGR Response in a Turbo-charged and After-cooled DI Diesel Engine and Its Effects on Smoke Opacity,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1677, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1677.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, F., Ferraro, C., Bernardi, M., Barbero, S. et al., “Experimental and Computational Analysis of Different EGR Systems for a Common Rail Passenger Car Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):527-538, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0672.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keller, P., Joergl, V., Kiener, T., Personal Communications, May 2009-March 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J., “Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lapuerta, M., Martos, F. J., Cardenas, M. D., “Determination of Light Extinction Efficiency of Diesel Soot from Smoke Opacity Measurements,” Measurement Science and Technology 16, 2048- 2055, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AVL. “Smoke Measurement,” AVL LIST GMBH. Graz. 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
