<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278196</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Geometric Effect of 3D Turbulent Field on Cyclic Variability</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mehrani</surname>
                  <given-names>Pouria</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Orbital Australia Pty. Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Watson</surname>
                  <given-names>Harry</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Melbourne</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>922</fpage>
         <lpage>930</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278196"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Many studies, conducted by different researchers, have shown that in a carefully controlled engine almost all of the cyclic variability, observed in one cylinder, can be attributed to the flame kernel initiation and evolution. The authors have shown that variations in the flame kernel effective area can successfully explain a significant portion of observed cyclic variability. In the search of causes of this variation in effective area, the authors simulated the flame wrinkling in a 2D kinematically simulated turbulent field. That study had shown that flame wrinkling can explain between 5% - 53% of observed variability, depending on the operating conditions. This study explores the effect of adding the third dimension, which in turn allows the addition of flame stretch and curvature effects. Eight of the torque-speed operating points of the previous study are simulated using G-Equation and a 3D kinematically simulated turbulence. The results show that while the geometries of 2D and 3D flames look different the statistics behave quite similarly. The 3D flame shows slightly less variability and can only explain between 3% - 41% of observed variability. Studying the images suggest that this can be attributed to smoothing effects of flame propagation, which is enhanced by incorporating the third dimension. Similar correlation coefficients between flame wrinkling and laminar flame speed and turbulence intensity suggest that the conclusions made for a 2D flame will still be valid for the 3D flame.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Watson, H., Baker, P., Ali Khan, M., Liew, G., Johnston, D., “SI Engine Lean-Limit Extension Through LPG Throttle- Body Injection for Low CO2 and NOx,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0495, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0495.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ozdor, N., Dulger, M. and Sher, E., “Cyclic Variability in Spark Ignition Engines A Literature Review,” SAE Technical Paper 940987, 1994, doi: 10.4271/940987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brehob, D. and Newman, C., “Monte Carlo Simulation of Cycle by Cycle Variability,” SAE Technical Paper 922165, 1992. doi: 10.4271/922165.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roberts, J. B., Peyton Jones, J. C. and Landsborough, K. J., “Cylinder Pressure Variations as a Stochastic Process,” SAE Technical Paper 970059, 1997, doi: 10.4271/970059.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ayala, F. A. and Heywood, J. B., “Lean SI Engines: The Roles of Combustion Variability in Defining Lean Limits,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0030, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-24-0030.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehrani, P. and Watson, H., “Modeling the Effect of Mixture Composition on Cyclic Variability,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0672, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0672.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehrani, P. and Watson, H., “Optimized Design of a Cyclic Variability Constrained Lean Limit SI Engine at Optimum NOx and Efficiency Using a PSO Algorithm,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-3551, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-3551.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pischinger, S., Heywood, J. B., “How Heat Losses to the Spark Plug Electrodes Affect Flame Kernel Development in An SI-Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 900021, 1990, doi: 10.4271/900021.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehrani, P. and Watson, H., “Exploring the Geometric Effects of Turbulence on Cyclic Variability,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0540, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0540.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fung, J. C. H., Vassilicos, J. C., “Two particle dispersion in turbulentlike flows”, Physical Review E, Vol 57(2), 1677 - 1690, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peters, N., “Turbulent Combustion”, Cambridge University Press, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hartmann, D., Meinke, M., Schröder, W., “Differential equation based constrained reinitialization for level set methods”, Journal of Computational Physics, Vol. 227, 6821 - 6845, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tabaczynski, R. J., Trinker, F. H., and Shannon, B. A. S.. “Further refinement and validation of a turbulent flame propagation model for sparkignition engines”. Combustion and Flame, 39:111-121, 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
