<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26562367</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development and Validation Procedure of a 1D Predictive Model for Simulation of a Common Rail Fuel Injection System Controlled with a Fuel Metering Valve</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ferrari</surname>
                  <given-names>Alessandro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Pizzo</surname>
                  <given-names>Pietro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Vitali</surname>
                  <given-names>Ruggero</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Politecnico di Torino</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>11</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26562366</issue-id>
         <fpage>401</fpage>
         <lpage>422</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26562367"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>A fully predictive one-dimensional model of a Common Rail injection apparatus for diesel passenger cars is presented and discussed. The apparatus includes high-pressure pump, high-pressure pipes, injectors, rail and a fuel-metering valve that is used to control the rail pressure level.</p> 
            <p>A methodology for separately assessing the accuracy of the single submodels of the components is developed and proposed. The complete model of the injection system is finally validated by means of a comparison with experimental high-pressure and injected flow-rate time histories.</p> 
            <p>The predictive model is applied to examine the fluid dynamics of the injection system during either steady-state or transient operations. The influence of the pump delivered flow-rate on the rail-pressure time history and on the injection performance is analysed for different energizing times and nominal rail pressure values.</p> 
            <p>A comparison between fuel metering valve and pressure-control-valve strategies is also carried out in terms of rail pressure and pump delivered flow-rate time histories. The advantages and the weak points of each strategy are highlighted: the fuel metering valve control is more efficient, due to the absence of a throttling of high-pressure fuel, but leads to poorer dynamic response during nominal rail pressure transients.</p> 
            <p>Even though the injection performance is the same under steady-state working conditions, significant differences between the two strategies can occur during engine transients.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label> 
            <kwd>High-pressure pump</kwd> 
            <kwd>High-pressure control strategy</kwd> 
            <kwd>Fuel injection system</kwd> 
            <kwd>Modelling of hydraulic systems</kwd> 
            <kwd>Fuel metering valve</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, M., Ouyang, G., and Zhou, J., “Simulation and Experimental Study on High-Pressure Common Rail Fuel System of Diesel Engine,” Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Distributed Control and Intelligent Environmental Monitoring, 2011, 586-589.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun, Z.Y., Li, G.X., Chen, C., Yu, S.Y. et al., “Numerical Investigation on Effects of nozzle’s Geometric Parameters on the Flow and the Cavitation Characteristics within Injector’s Nozzle for a High-Pressure Common-Rail DI Diesel Engine,” Energy Conversion and Management 89:843-861, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mohan, B., Yang, W., Tay, K.I., and Yu, W., “Experimental Study of Spray Characteristics of Biodiesel Derived from Waste Cooking Oil,” Energy Conversion and Management 88:622-632, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huber, B. and Ulbrich, H., “Modeling and Experimental Validation of the Solenoid Valve of a Common Rail Diesel Injector,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-0195, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-0195.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matsumoto, S., Yamada, K., and Date, K., “Concepts and Evolution of Injector for Common Rail System,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1753, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012- 01-1753.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferrari, A. and Mittica, A., “FEM Modeling of the Piezoelectric Drive System in the Design of Direct-Acting Diesel Injectors,” Applied Energy 99:471-483, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rolf, L., Parche, M., Alvarez-Avila, C., Krauß, J. et al., “Pressure-Amplified Common Rail System for Commercial Vehicles,” MTZ Worldw 70(5):10-15, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Busch, S., Zha, K., and Miles, P.C., “Investigations of Closely Coupled Pilot and Main Injections as a Means to Reduce Combustion Noise in a Small-Bore Direct-Injection Diesel Engine,” International Journal of Engine Research 16(1):13- 22, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, J.W., Choi, S.M., Yu, S., Choi, H. et al., “Comparison of the Effects of Multiple Injection Strategy on the Emissions between Moderate and Heavy EGR Rate Conditions: Part 1 - Pilot Injections,” Journal of Mechanical Science and Technology 27(4):1135-1141, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O’Connor, J. and Musculus, M., “Post Injections for Soot Reduction in Diesel Engines: A Review of Current Understanding,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):400-421, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, F., Broatch, A., Salavert, J.M., and Martín, J., “Investigation of Diesel Combustion using Multiple Injection Strategies for Idling after Cold Start of Passenger-Car Engines,” Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science 34:857- 865, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Torregrosa, A.J., Broatch, A., Garcia, A., and Monico, L.F., “Sensitivity of Combustion Noise NO and Soot Emissions to Pilot Injection in PCCI Diesel Engines,” Applied Energy 104:149-157, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">d’Ambrosio, S. and Ferrari, A., “Potential of Double Pilot Injection Strategies Optimized with the Design of Experiments Procedure to Improve Diesel Engine Emissions and Performance,” Applied Energy 155:918-932, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pogulyaev, Y.D., Baitimerov, R.M., and Rozhdestvenskii, Y.V., “Detailed Dynamic Modelling of Common Rail Piezo Injector,” Procedia Engineering 129:93-98, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, P., Zheng, D., and Tian, Y., “High Pressure Common Rail Injection System Modelling and Control,” ISA Transactions 63:265-273, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, R., Salvador, F.J., Carreres, M., and de la Morena, J., “Fuel Temperature Influence,” Energy Conversion and Management 114:376-391, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lino, P., Maione, B., and Rizzo, A., “Nonlinear Modelling and Control of a Common Rail Injection System for Diesel Engines,” Applied Mathematical Modelling 31:1770-1784, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salvador, F.J., Hoyas, S., Novella, R., and Martinez-Lopez, J., “Numerical Simulation and Extended Validation of Two- Phase Compressible Flow in Diesel Injector Nozzles,” Proc Inst Mech Eng Part D: J Automobile Eng 225(4):545-563, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun, Z.Y., Li, X., Chen, C., Yu, Y.S. et al., “Numerical Investigation on Effects of Nozzle’s Geometry Parameters on the Flow and the Cavitation Characteristics within Injector’s Nozzle for a Pressure Common-Rail DI Diesel Engine,” Energy Conversion and Management 89(1):843-861, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A.E., Ferrari, A., and Manno, M., “Development and Application of a Complete Multijet Common-Rail Injection-System Mathematical Model for Hydrodynamic Analysis and Diagnostics,” ASME Transactions, Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 130:0628091- 06280913, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salvador, F.J., Plazas, A.H., Gimeno, J., and Carreres, M., “Complete Modelling of a Piezo Actuator Last-Generation Injector for Diesel Injection Systems,” International Journal of Engine Research 15(1):3-19, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferrari, A., Mittica, A., and Spessa, E., “Benefits of Hydraulic Layout over Driving Systems in Piezo-Injectors and Proposal of a New-Concept CR Injector with an Integrated Minirail,” Applied Energy 103:245-253, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, R., Salvador, F.J., Marti-Aldiravì, P., and Martinez- Lopez, J., “Using One-Dimensional Modeling to Analyse the Influence of the Use of Biodiesels on the Dynamic Behaviour of Solenoid-Operated Injectors in Common Rail Systems: Detailed Injection System Model,” Energy Conversion and Management 54(1):90-99, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gauthier, C., Sename, O., Dugard, L., and Meissonnier, G., “Modelling of a Diesel Engine Common Rail Injection System,” Proceedings of the IFAC World Congress, Prague, July 3-8, 2005, vol. 16 (part 1), Laxenburg: IFAC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gupta, V.K., Zhang, Z., and Sun, Z., “Modeling and Control of a Novel Pressure Regulation Mechanism for Common Rail Fuel Injection Systems,” Applied Mathematical Modelling 35:3473-3483, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chiavola, O. and Giulianelli, P., “Modelling and Simulation of Common Rail Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01- 3183, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3183.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferrari, A. and Pizzo, P., “Fully Predictive Common Rail Fuel Injection Apparatus Model and its Application to Global System Dynamics Analyses,” International Journal of Engine Research 18(3), 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hong, S., Shin, H., Sohn, J., Park, I., and Sunwoo, M., “Coordinated Control Strategy for the Common Rail Pressure Using a Metering Unit and a Pressure Control Valve in Diesel Engines,” J. Auto. Eng. 1-13, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A.E. and Ferrari, A., “Experimental Analysis, Modeling, and Control of Volumetric Radial-Piston Pumps,” ASME Journal of Fluids Engineering 133:0811031- 08110312, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferrari, A., Paolicelli, F., and Pizzo, P., “The New Generation of Solenoid Injectors Equipped with Pressure Balanced Pilot- Valves for Energy Saving and Dynamic Response Improvement,” Applied Energy 151:367-376, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferrari, A. and Pizzo, P., “Optimization of an Algorithm for the Measurement of Unsteady Flow-Rates in High-Pressure Pipelines and Application of a Newly Designed Flowmeter to Volumetric Pump Analysis,” ASME Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 138(3):031604, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A.E. and Ferrari, A., “Development and Assessment of a New Operating Principle for the Measurement of Unsteady Flow-Rates in High-Pressure Pipelines,” Flow Measurement and Instrumentation 20(6):230-240, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A.E., Ferrari, A., and Spessa, E., “Temperature Variations in the Simulation of High-Pressure Injection- System Transient Flows under Cavitation,” International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer 51:2090-2107, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merrit, H.E., Hydraulic Control Systems (John Wiley &amp; Sons, 1967).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferrari, A., Pizzo, P., and Rundo, M., “Modelling and Experimental Studies on a Proportional Valve Using an Innovative Dynamic Flow-Rate Measurement in Fluid Power Systems,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part C: Journal of Mechanical Engineering Science 2404-2418, 2017, doi:10.1177/0954406217721259.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">White, F.M.,FluidMechanicsSeventhEdition(McGraw Hill,2011).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zielke, W., “Frequency-Dependent Friction in Transient Pipe Flow,” ASME Journal of Basic Eng 90, 1968.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kagawa, T., Lee, I.Y., Kitagawa, A., and Takenaka, T., “High Speed and Accurate Computing Method of Frequency- Dependent Friction in Laminar Pipe Flow for Characteristics Method,” Transactions of the Japanese Society of Mechanical Engineering, Series B 49:2638- 2644, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toro, E., Riemann Solvers and Numerical Methods for Fluid Dynamics (Berlin: Springer-Verlag, 1997).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A.E., Ferrari, A., and Spessa, E., “Numerical- Experimental Study and Solutions to Reduce the Dwell Time Threshold for Fusion-Free Consecutive Injections in a Multijet Solenoid-Type C.R. System”, ASME Transactions, Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 131:1-14, 2009, Art. No. 022804, ISSN:0742-4795.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A.E. and Ferrari, A., “Advanced Mathematical Modeling of Electronic Unit-Injector Systems for Heavy- Duty Diesel Engine Application,” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 1(1):134-151, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bosch, R., Automotive Handbook Seventh Edition (Detroit: Society of American Engineers (SAE), 2007).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
