<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i40023369</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40541991</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="pub-doi">10.1007/s10590-009-9054-9</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Generating Arabic Text in Multilingual Speech-to-speech Machine Translation Framework</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Azza Abdel</given-names>
                  <surname>Monem</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Khaled</given-names>
                  <surname>Shaalan</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ahmed</given-names>
                  <surname>Rafea</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Hoda</given-names>
                  <surname>Baraka</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2008</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>205</fpage>
         <lpage>258</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2009 Springer Science+Business Media B.V.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40541991"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The interlingual approach to machine translation (MT) is used successfully in multilingual translation. It aims to achieve the translation task in two independent steps. First, meanings of the source-language sentences are represented in an intermediate language-independent (Interlingua) representation. Then, sentences of the target language are generated from those meaning representations. Arabic natural language processing in general is still underdeveloped and Arabic natural language generation (NLG) is even less developed. In particular, Arabic NLG from Interlinguas was only investigated using template-based approaches. Moreover, tools used for other languages are not easily adaptable to Arabic due to the language complexity at both the morphological and syntactic levels. In this paper, we describe a rule-based generation approach for task-oriented Interlingua-based spoken dialogue that transforms a relatively shallow semantic interlingual representation, called interchange format (IF), into Arabic text that corresponds to the intentions underlying the speaker's utterances. This approach addresses the handling of the problems of Arabic syntactic structure determination, and Arabic morphological and syntactic generation within the Interlingual MT approach. The generation approach is developed primarily within the framework of the NESPOLE! (NEgotiating through SPOken Language in E-commerce) multilingual speech-to-speech MT project. The IF-to-Arabic generator is implemented in SICStus Prolog. We conducted evaluation experiments using the input and output from the English analyzer that was developed by the NESPOLE! team at Carnegie Mellon University. The results of these experiments were promising and confirmed the ability of the rule-based approach in generating Arabic translation from the Interlingua taken from the travel and tourism domain.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>Machine translation</kwd>
            <kwd>Interlingua</kwd>
            <kwd>Rule-based text generation</kwd>
            <kwd>Natural language generation</kwd>
            <kwd>Arabic natural language processing</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d521876e641a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d521876e648" publication-type="other">
http://www.is.cs.cmu.edu/
nespole/db/specification.html</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d521876e658a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d521876e665" publication-type="other">
http://www.statmt.org/</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d521876e681a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e685" publication-type="other">
Akiba Y, Federico M, Kando N, Nakaiwa H, Paul M, Tsujii J (2004) Overview of the IWSLT04 evalua-
tion campaign. In: Proceedings of the international workshop on spoken language translation, Kyoto,
Japan, pp 1-12</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e698a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e702" publication-type="other">
Al-Sughaiyer I, Al-Kharashi 1 (2004) Arabic morphological analysis techniques: a comprehensive survey.
J Am Soc Inform Sci Technol 55(3): 189-213</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e712a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e716" publication-type="other">
Arnold D, Balkan L, Meijer S, Humphreys L, Sadler L (1994) Machine translation: an introductory guide.
Blackwell-NCC, London</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e726a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e730" publication-type="other">
Attia M (2008) Handling Arabic morphological and syntactic ambiguities within the LFG framework with
a view to machine translation. Ph.D. Thesis, University of Manchester, Manchester, UK</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e741a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e745" publication-type="other">
Beesley K (1996) Arabic finite-state morphological analysis and generation. In: COLING-96: the 16th
international conference on computational linguistics, vol 1, Copenhagen, Denmark, pp 89-94</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e755a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e759" publication-type="other">
Buckwalter T (2002) Buckwalter Arabic morphological analyzer version 1.0, Linguistic Data Consortium,
LDC Catalog No.: LDC2002L49. University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e769a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e773" publication-type="other">
Cavalli-Sforza V, Soudi A, Mitamura T (2000) Arabic morphology generation using a concatenate strat-
egy. In: ANLP 2000, 6th Applied Natural Language Processing Conference, Seattle, WA, pp 86-93</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e783a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e787" publication-type="other">
Dorr B (1993) Machine translation. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e794a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e798" publication-type="other">
Dorr B, Hovy E, Levin L (2004) Machine translation: interlingual methods. In: Brown K (ed) Encyclopedia
of language and linguistics. 2. Elsevier, Oxford, UK</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e808a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e812" publication-type="other">
El-Desouki A, Abd Elgawwad A, Salen M (1996) A proposed algorithm for English-Arabic machine trans-
lation system. In: Proceeding of the 1st KFUPM workshop on information and computer sciences
(WICS): machine translation, Dhahran, Saudi Arabia, pp 32-39</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e826a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e830" publication-type="other">
El-Saka T, Rafea A, Rafea M, Madkour M (1999) English to Arabic knowledge base translation tool. In:
Proceedings of the 7th international conference on artificial intelligence applications (ICAIA), Cairo,
Egypt, pp 66-72</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e843a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e847" publication-type="other">
Gavaldà M (2004) SOUP: a parser for real-world spontaneous speech. In: New developments in parsing
technology, vol 23, Chap. 17. Kluwer Academic Publishers, Norwell, MA, pp 339-350 (Also pub-
lished in the Proceedings of the 6th international workshop on parsing technologies (IWPT-2000),
Trento, Italy)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e863a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e867" publication-type="other">
Geist RJ (1971) An introduction to transformation grammar. Macmillan, New York, NY</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e874a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e878" publication-type="other">
Guessoum A, Zantout R (2007) Arabic morphological generation and its impact on the quality of the
machine translation to Arabic. In: Soudi A, Bosch A, Neumann G (eds) Arabic computational mor-
phology: knowledge-based and empirical methods, text and language technology, Springer, New York,
pp 287-302</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e894a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e898" publication-type="other">
Habash N (2004) Large-scale lexeme-based Arabic morphological generation. In: Proceedings of Traite-
ment Automatique du Langage Naturel (TALN-04), Fez, Morocco, pp 45-51</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e908a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e912" publication-type="other">
Habash N, Dorr B, Monz C (2006) Challenges in building an Arabie GHMT system with SMT components.
In: AMTA 2006, Proceedings of the 7th conference of the association for machine translation in the
Americas, visions for the future of machine translation, Cambridge, MA, pp 56-65</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e926a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e930" publication-type="other">
Hiroshi U, Meiying Z (1993) Interlingua for multilingual machine translation. In: Proceedings of MT
Summit IV, Kobe, Japan, pp 157-169</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e940a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e944" publication-type="other">
Hutchins J (2003) Machine translation: general overview. In: Mitkov R (eds), The Oxford handbook of
computational linguistics, Chap. 27. Oxford University Press, Oxford, UK, pp 501-511</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e954a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e958" publication-type="other">
Hutchins J, Somers H (1992) An introduction to machine translation. Academic Press, London, UK</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e965a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e969" publication-type="other">
Ibrahim M (1991) A fast and expert machine translation system involving Arabic language. Ph.D. Thesis,
Cranfìeld Institute of Technology, Cranfìeld, UK</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e979a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e983" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Hoang H, Birch A, Callison-Burch C, Federico M, Bertoldi N, Cowan B, Shen W, Moran C, Zens
R, Dyer C, Bojar O, Constantin A, Herbst E (2007) Moses: open source toolkit for statistical machine
translation. In: Proceedings of the association for computational linguistics (ACL), demo and poster
sessions, Prague, Czech Republic, pp 177-180</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e999a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1003" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Och F, Marcu D (2003) Statistical phrase-based translation. In: Proceedings of the joint human lan-
guage technology conference and the annual meeting of the North American chapter of the association
for computational linguistics (HLT-NAACL), Edmonton, Canada, pp 127-133</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1017a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1021" publication-type="other">
Langley C (2003) Domain action classification and argument parsing for interlingua-based spoken language
translation. Ph.D. Thesis, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1031a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1035" publication-type="other">
Lavie A, Langley C, Waibel A, Lazzari G, Pianesi F, Coletti P, Balducci F, Taddei L (2001a) Architecture
and design considerations in NESPOLE!: a speech translation system for E-commerce applications.
In: Proceedings of human language technology conference (HLT 2001), San Diego, CA, pp 15-22</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1048a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1052" publication-type="other">
Lavie A, Levin L, Schultz T, Langley C, Han B, Tribble A, Gates D, Wallace D, Peterson K (2001b) Domain
portability in speech-to-speech translation. In: Proceedings of human language technology conference
(HLT 2001), San Diego, CA, pp 23-29</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1065a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1069" publication-type="other">
Lazzari G (2003) Evaluation of the NESPOLE! showcase-2a system. NESPOLE! Project deliverable D18.
Available at http://nespole.itc.it/public/deliverables/D 18_final.doc</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1079a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1083" publication-type="other">
Leavitt J (1994) MORPHE: A morphological rule compiler. Technical Report, CMU-CMT-94-MEMO,
Language Technologies Institute, School of Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University, Pitts-
burgh, PA</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1096a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1100" publication-type="other">
Levin L, Gates D, Lavie A, Waibel A (1998) An Interlingua based on domain actions for machine translation
of task-oriented dialogues. In: Proceedings of The 5th international conference on spoken language
processing (CSLP'98), vol 4, Sydney, Australia, pp 1155-1158</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1114a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1118" publication-type="other">
Levin L, Lavie A, Woszczyna M, Gates D, Gavalda M, Ko II D, Waibel A (2000) The Janus III translation
system: speech-to-speech translation in multiple domains. Mach Trans 15(1-2): 3-25</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1128a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1132" publication-type="other">
Levin L, Gates D, Wallace D, Peterson K, Lavie A (2002) Balancing expressiveness and simplicity in an
Interlingua for task-based dialogue. In: Proceedings of the workshop on speech-to-speech translation:
algorithms and systems, Association for Computational Linguistics, Philadelphia, PA, pp 52-59</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1145a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1149" publication-type="other">
Levin L, Gates D, Wallace D, Peterson K, Pianta E, Mana N (2003b) The NESPOLE! interchange format,
project deliverable D13. Language Technologies Institute, School of Computer Science, Carnegie
Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1162a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1166" publication-type="other">
Levin L, Langley C, Lavie A, Gates D, Wallace D, Peterson K (2003a) Domain specific speech acts for spo-
ken language translation. In : The Proceedings of 4th SIGDIAL workshop on discourse and dialogue
(SIGDIAL-2003), Association for Computational Linguistics, Sapporo, Japan, pp 44-49</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1179a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1183" publication-type="other">
Mace J (1998) Arabic grammar: a reference guide. Edinburgh University Press, Edinburgh, UK</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1190a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1194" publication-type="other">
Metze F, McDonough J, Soltau H, Lavie A, Levin L, Langley C, Schultz T, Waibel A, Cationi R, Lazzari G,
Mana N, Pianesi F, Pianta E, (2002) Enhancing the usability and performance of NESPOLE!: a real-
world speech-to-speech translation system. In: Proceedings of human language technology conference
(HLT 2002), San Diego, CA, pp 269-274</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1211a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1215" publication-type="other">
Mitamura T, Nyberg E, (1992) Hierarchical lexical structure and interpretive mapping in. In: Proceedings of
the fifteenth [sic] international conference on computational linguistics COLING-92, Nantes, France,
pp 1254-1258</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1228a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1232" publication-type="other">
Mokhtar H, Darwish N, Rafea A (2000) An automated system for English-Arabic translation of scientific
texts (SEATS). In : Proceedings of MT2000: machine translation and multilingual applications in the
new millennium, the British Computer Society (BCS), London, pp 1-5</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1245a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1249" publication-type="other">
Och F, Ney H (2002) Discriminative training and maximum entropy models for statistical machine transla-
tion. In: 40th annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), Philadelphia,
PA, pp 295-302</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1262a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1266" publication-type="other">
Papineni K, Roukos S, Ward T, Zhu W-J (2002) BLEU: a method for automatic evaluation of machine trans-
lation. In: 40th annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), Philadelphia,
PA, pp 311-318</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1279a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1283" publication-type="other">
Patch K (2003) PDA translates speech. Technology Research News. Available at http://www.trnmag.com/
Stories/2003/121703/PDA_translates_speech_l21703.html</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1293a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1297" publication-type="other">
Pease C, Boushaba A (1996) Towards an automatic translation of medical terminology and texts into
Arabic. In: Proceedings of the translation in the Arab world, King Fand Advanced School of Transla-
tion, Tangier, Morocco, pp 18-23</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1311a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1315" publication-type="other">
Quah CK (2006) Translation and technology. Palgrave MacMillan, Basingstoke, UK</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1322a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1326" publication-type="other">
Ryding K (2005) Reference grammar of modern standard Arabic. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge,
UK</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1336a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1340" publication-type="other">
Rafea A, Shaalan K (1993) Lexical analysis of inflected Arabic words using exhaustive search of an aug-
mented transition network. Softw Pract Exper 23(6):567-588</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1350a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1354" publication-type="other">
Rafea A, Sabry M, El-Ansary R, Samir S (1992) Al-Mutargem: a machine translator for Middle East news.
In: Proceedings of the 3rd international conference and exhibition on multi-lingual computing, The
Centre for Middle Eastern and Islamic Studies, University of Durham, Durham, UK, pp 53-60</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1367a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1371" publication-type="other">
Riezler S, Maxwell J (2006) Grammatical machine translation. In : Proceedings of human language tech-
nology conference of the North American chapter of the association for computational linguistics
annual meeting (HLT-NAACL'06), New York, NY, pp 248-255</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1384a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1388" publication-type="other">
Salem Y, Hensman A, Nolan B (2008) Towards Arabic to English machine translation. Acad J Inst Tech-
nol Blanchardstown (Dublin, Ireland) 17:20-31. Available online via http://informatics.itbresearch.
ie/~ysalenVpdf/ITB%20Journal-May-2008-v5.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1402a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1406" publication-type="other">
Shaalan K, Rafea M, Rafea A (1998) KROL: a knowledge representation object language on top of Prolog.
Expert Syst Appi 15:33-46</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1416a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1420" publication-type="other">
Shaalan K, Rafea A, Abdel Monem A, Baraka H (2004) Machine translation of English noun phrases into
Arabic. Int J Comput Process Oriental Lang (1JCPOL) 17(2): 121-134</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1430a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1434" publication-type="other">
Shaalan K (2005) An Intelligent Computer Assisted Language Learning System for Arabic Learners. Com-
put Assist Lang Learn 18:81-108</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1444a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1448" publication-type="other">
Shaalan K (2005) Arabic GramCheck: a grammar checker for Arabic. Softw Pract Exper 35(7):643-665</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1455a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1459" publication-type="other">
Shaalan K, Abdel Monem A, Rafea A (2006) Arabic morphological generation from Interlingua: a rule-
based approach. In: Shi Z, Shimohara K, Feng D (eds) Intelligent information processing III, Inter-
national Federation for information processing (IFIP). Springer, Boston, MA, pp 441-451</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1472a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1476" publication-type="other">
Shaalan K, Abdel Monem A, Rafea A, Baraka H, (2006b) Mapping Interlingua representations to feature
structures of Arabic sentences. The challenge of Arabic for NLP/MT, International Conference, the
British Computer Society, London, pp 149-159</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1490a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1494" publication-type="other">
Shaalan K, Abdel Monem A, Rafea A, Baraka H (2007) Generating Arabic text from Interlingua. In:
Proceedings of the 2nd workshop on computational approaches to Arabic script-based languages
(CAASL-2), Linguistic Institute, Stanford, CA, pp 137-144</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1507a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1511" publication-type="other">
Soudi A, Cavalli-Sforza V, Jamari A (2002) A prototype English-to-Arabic Interlingua-based MT system.
In: Proceedings of the workshop on Arabic language resources and evaluation: status and prospects,
3rd international conference on language resources and evaluation (LREC 2002), Las Palmas de Gran
Canaria, Spain, pp 18-25</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1527a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1531" publication-type="other">
Stolcke A (2002) SR1LM -an extensible language modeling toolkit. In: Proceedings of the international
conference on spoken language processing, vol 2. Denver, USA, pp 901-904</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1541a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1545" publication-type="other">
Theune M (2003) Natural language generation for dialogue: system survey. Language Engineering Group,
University of Twente, Twente, The Netherlands</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1555a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1559" publication-type="other">
Tornita M, Nyberg E (1988) Generation kit and transformation kit, version 3.2, user's manual. Technical
Report, Carnegie Mellon Center for Machine Translation, Pittsburgh, PA</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1569a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1573" publication-type="other">
Trujillo A (1999) Translation engines: techniques for machine translation. Springer Verlag, London, UK</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1581a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1585" publication-type="other">
Vauquois B (1968) A survey of formal grammars and algorithms for recognition and transformation in
machine translation. In: Proceedings of international federation for information processing congress
68, Edinburgh, UK, pp a4-260</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1598a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1602" publication-type="other">
Waibel A, Badran A, Black A, Frederking R, Gates D, Lavie A, Levin L, Lenzo K, Tomokiyo L, Reichert
J, Schultz T, Wallace D, Woszczyna M, Zhang J (2003a) Speechalator: two-way speech-to-speech
translation on a consumer PDA. In: Proceedings of EUROSPEECH 2003, Geneva, Switzerland, pp
369-372</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1618a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1622" publication-type="other">
Waibel A, Badran A, Black A, Frederking R, Gates D, Lavie A, Levin L, Lenzo K, Tomokiyo L, Reichert
J, Schultz T, Wallace D, Woszczyna M, Zhang J (2003b) Speechalator: two-way speech-to-speech
translation in your hand. In: Proceedings of the joint human language technology conference and
the annual meeting of the north American chapter of the association for computational linguistics
(HLT-NAACL), Edmonton, Canada, pp 29-30</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d521876e1641a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d521876e1645" publication-type="other">
White JS, O'Connell T, O' Mara F (1994) The ARPA MT evaluation methodologies: evolution, lessons, and
future approaches. In: Proceedings of the first conference of the association for machine translation
in the Americas (AMTA), Columbia, MD, pp 193-205</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


