<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278361</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Gasoline Fueled Pre-Chamber Jet Ignition Combustion System at Unthrottled Conditions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Attard</surname>
                  <given-names>William P.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Blaxill</surname>
                  <given-names>Hugh</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>MAHLE Powertrain</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>May 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278342</issue-id>
         <fpage>315</fpage>
         <lpage>329</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278361"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Turbulent Jet Ignition is an advanced spark initiated pre-chamber combustion system for otherwise standard spark ignition engines. Combustion in the main chamber is initiated by jets of partially combusted (reacting) pre-chamber products which provide a high energy ignition source. The resultant widely distributed ignition sites allow relatively small flame travel distances enabling short combustion durations and high burn rates. Demonstrated benefits include ultra lean operation (λ&gt;2) at part load and high load knock improvement near stoichiometric conditions.</p>
            <p>Although previous results of this combustion system have been very promising, the main hurdle of this system has been the need for a dual fuel system, with liquid gasoline used in the main combustion chamber and small fractions of gaseous propane in the pre-chamber. The purpose of this paper is to demonstrate that this combustion system can operate robustly using a sole gasoline system, with vaporized gasoline found to be a successful substitute for the pre-chamber propane over all comparable conditions. With this concept, the test engine recorded a peak net thermal efficiency of 42.8% (190 g/kWh ISFCn) and single digit engine out NOx emissions. The pre-chamber jet ignition system was also examined at unthrottled stoichiometric conditions up to 5500 rev/min, with successful operation demonstrated up to 13.2 bar IMEPn. Additionally, jet ignition combustion was also examined in order to evaluate pressure rise rate limitations for potential future high load powertrain applications.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W., Bassett, M., Parsons, P., and Blaxill, H., “A New ombustion System Achieving High Drive Cycle Fuel Economy mprovements in a Modern Vehicle Powertrain,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0664, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0664.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W. and Blaxill, H., “A Single Fuel Pre-Chamber Jet Ignition owertrain Achieving High Load, High Efficiency and Near Zero NOx missions,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-2023, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-2023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W. and Blaxill, H., “A Lean Burn Gasoline Fueled Pre-Chamber et Ignition Combustion System Achieving High Efficiency and Low Ox at Part Load,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1146, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1146.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W., Blaxill, H., Anderson, E., and Litke, P., “Knock Limit xtension with a Gasoline Fueled Pre-Chamber Jet Igniter in a Modern ehicle Powertrain,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1143, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1143.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W., Kohn, J., and Parsons, P., “Ignition Energy Development for Spark Initiated Combustion System Capable of High Load, High fficiency and Near Zero NOx Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2): 481-496, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-32-0088.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W. and Parsons, P., “A Normally Aspirated Spark Initiated ombustion System Capable of High Load, High Efficiency and Near ero NOx Emissions in a Modern Vehicle Powertrain,” SAE Int. J. ngines 3(2):269-287, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2196.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W. and Parsons, P., “Flame Kernel Development for a Spark nitiated Pre-Chamber Combustion System Capable of High Load, High fficiency and Near Zero NOx Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2): 408-427, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2260.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W., Fraser, N., Parsons, P., and Toulson, E., “A Turbulent Jet gnition Pre-Chamber Combustion System for Large Fuel Economy mprovements in a Modern Vehicle Powertrain,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):20-37, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1457.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W., Toulson, E., Huisjen, A., Chen, X. et al., “Spark Ignition and re-Chamber Turbulent Jet Ignition Combustion Visualization,” SAE echnical Paper 2012-01-0823, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0823.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toulson, E., Watson, H., and Attard, W., “The Lean Limit and missions at Near-Idle for a Gasoline HAJI System with Alternative re-Chamber Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0120, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-24-0120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toulson, E., Watson, H., and Attard, W., “Gas Assisted Jet Ignition of ltra-Lean LPG in a Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0506, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0506.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toulson, E., Schock, H., and Attard, W., “A Review of Pre-Chamber nitiated Jet Ignition Combustion Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2263, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kyaw, Z.H. and Watson, H.C., Hydrogen Assisted Jet Ignition for Near limination of NOx and Cyclic Variability in the S.I. Engine. Twenty- ourth Symposium on Combustion, 1992. 24(1): 1449-1455.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Glasson, N., Lumsden, G., Dingli, R., and Watson, H., “Development of he HAJI System for a Multi-Cylinder Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE echnical Paper 961104, 1996, doi: 10.4271/961104.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dober, G.G. and Watson, H.W., Modelling the Flame Enhancement of a AJI Equipped Spark Ignition Engine, in IPC-10 Proceedings. 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lawrence, J. and Watson, H., “Hydrocarbon Emissions from a HAJI quipped Ultra-lean Burn SI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 980044, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980044.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hamori, F. and Watson, H.C. Hydrogen Assisted Jet Ignition for the ydrogen Fuelled SI Engine. in World Hydrogen Energy Conference. 2006. Lyon, France.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toulson, E., Applying Alternative Fuels in Place of Hydrogen to the Jet gnition Process. Thesis (Ph.D.), Department of Mechanical and anufacturing Engineering, University of Melbourne, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W., Toulson, E., Hamori, F., and Watson, H., “Combustion ystem Development and Analysis of a Carbureted and PFI Normally spirated Small Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-32-0095, 2010, oi:10.4271/2010-32-0095.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toulson, E., Watson, H., and Attard, W., “Modeling Alternative rechamber Fuels in Jet Assisted Ignition of Gasoline and LPG,” SAE echnical Paper 2009-01-0721, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0721.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gussak, L.A., LAG-Process of Combustion and its Application in utomobile Engines. IMechE C257/76, 1976: 137-145.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wyczalek, F., Harned, J., Maksymiuk, S., and Blevins, J., “EFI rechamber Torch Ignition of Lean Mixtures,” SAE Technical Paper 750351, 1975, doi: 10.4271/750351.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cairns, A., Blaxill, H., and Irlam, G., “Exhaust Gas Recirculation for mproved Part and Full Load Fuel Economy in a Turbocharged Gasoline ngine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0047, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alger, T., Chauvet, T., and Dimitrova, Z., “Synergies between High GR Operation and GDI Systems,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):101-114, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lake, T., Stokes, J., Murphy, R., Osborne, R. et al., “Turbocharging oncepts for Downsized DI Gasoline Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0036, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0036.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
