<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277958</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Large Eddy Simulation of an n-Heptane Spray Flame with Dynamic Adaptive Chemistry under Different Oxygen Concentrations</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhou</surname>
                  <given-names>Lei</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tsinghua University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lu</surname>
                  <given-names>Zhen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tsinghua University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ren</surname>
                  <given-names>Zhuyin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tsinghua University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lu</surname>
                  <given-names>Tianfeng</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Connecticut</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Luo</surname>
                  <given-names>K.H</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University College London</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>April 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277951</issue-id>
         <fpage>447</fpage>
         <lpage>454</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277958"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Detailed chemical kinetics is essential for accurate prediction of combustion performance as well as emissions in practical combustion engines. However, implementation of that is challenging. In this work, dynamic adaptive chemistry (DAC) is integrated into large eddy simulations (LES) of an n-heptane spray flame in a constant volume chamber (CVC) with realistic application conditions. DAC accelerates the time integration of the governing ordinary differential equations (ODEs) for chemical kinetics through the use of locally (spatially and temporally) valid skeletal mechanisms. Instantaneous flame structures and global combustion characteristics such as ignition delay time, flame lift-off length (LOL) and emissions are investigated to assess the effect of DAC on LES-DAC results. The study reveals that in LES-DAC simulations, the auto-ignition time and LOL obtain a well agreement with experiment data under different oxygen concentrations. The produced time of NOx induced by the high temperature and a certain equivalent ratio is close to the inflection point (increasing timing) of CO2 variation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ren, Z., Liu, Y., Lu, T., Lu, L., Oluwole, O.O., Goldin, G.M. The use of dynamic adaptive chemistry and tabulation in reactive flow simulations, Combustion and Flame, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liang, L., Stevens, J.G., Farrell, J.T. A dynamic adaptive chemistry scheme for reactive flow computations, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 2009, 32 (1), pp. 527-534.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu, T., Law, C.K. A directed relation graph method for mechanism reduction, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 2005, 30 (1), pp. 1333-1341.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu, L., Pope, S.B. An improved algorithm for in situ adaptive tabulation, Journal of Computational Physics, 2009, 228 (2), pp. 361-386.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goldin, G.M., Ren, Z., Zahirovic, S. A cell agglomeration algorithm for accelerating detailed chemistry in CFD, Combustion Theory and Modelling, 2009, 13 (4), pp. 721-739.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keck, J.C. Rate-controlled constrained-equilibrium theory of chemical reactions in complex systems, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 1990, 16 (2), pp. 125-154.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bodenstein, M., Lind, S. Geschwindigkeit der Bildung des Bromwasserstoffs aus seinen Elementen, 1906, pp. 168-175.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keck, J.C., Gillespie, D. Rate-controlled partial-equilibrium method for treating reacting gas mixtures, Combustion and Flame, 1971, 17 (2), pp. 237-241.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maas, U., Pope, S.B. Simplifying chemical kinetics: Intrinsic lowdimensional manifolds in composition space, Combustion and Flame, 1992, 88 (3-4), pp. 239-264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pope, S. Computationally efficient implementation of combustion chemistry using in situ adaptive tabulation, 1997, 1 (1), pp. 41-63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Embouazza, M., Haworth, D., and Darabiha, N., “Implementation of Detailed Chemical Mechanisms into Multidimensional CFD Using in situ Adaptive Tabulation: Application to HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2773, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2773.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jia, M., Xie, M., and Peng, Z., “Implementation and Improvement of ISAT in HCCI Multidimensional Modeling with Detailed Chemical Kinetics,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0978, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008- 01-0978.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gicquel, O., Darabiha, N., Thévenin, D. Liminar premixed hydrogen/air counterflow flame simulations using flame prolongation of ILDM with differential diffusion, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 2000, 28 (2), pp. 1901-1908.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fiorina, B., Gicquel, O., Vervisch, L., Carpentier, S., Darabiha, N. Premixed turbulent combustion modeling using tabulated detailed chemistry and PDF, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute,2005, 30 (1), pp. 867-874.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Oijen, J.A., Lammers, F.A., de Goey, L.P.H. Modeling of complex premixed burner systems by using flamelet-generated manifolds, Combustion and Flame, 2001, 127 (3), pp. 2124-2134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shi, Y., Liang, L., Ge, H.-W., Reitz, R.D. Acceleration of the chemistry solver for modeling DI engine combustion using dynamic adaptive chemistry (DAC) schemes, Combustion Theory and Modelling, 2010, 14 (1), pp. 69-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, H., Ren, Z., Lu, T., Goldin, G.M. Dynamic adaptive chemistry for turbulent flame simulations, Combustion Theory and Modelling, 2013, 17 (1), pp. 167-183.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Viggiano, A., Magi, V. Dynamic Adaptive Chemistry applied to homogeneous and partially stratified charge CI ethanol engines, Applied Energy, 2014, 113, pp. 848-863.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Genzale, C., Bruneaux, G., Malbec, L. et al., “Comparison of Diesel Spray Combustion in Different High-Temperature, High-Pressure Facilities,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):156-181, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010- 01-2106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Manin, J., Genzale, C., Siebers, D. et al., “Relationship Between Diesel Fuel Spray Vapor Penetration/Dispersion and Local Fuel Mixture Fraction,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):764-799, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0686.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett LM. Engine combustion network, “http://www.sandia.gov/ecn.”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alamos, L. KIVA-3V: A block-structured Kiva program for engines with vertical or canted values. LA-18818-MS, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhou, L., Xie, M., Luo, K., Jia, M. et al., “Mixing Effects of Early Injection in Diesel Spray Using LES Model with Different Subgrid Scale Models,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1111, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013- 01-1111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Leer, B. Towards the ultimate conservative difference scheme. II. Monotonicity and conservation combined in a second-order scheme, Journal of computational physics,1974, 14 (4), pp. 361-370.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bharadwaj, N., Rutland, C., Chang, S. Large eddy simulation modelling of spray-induced turbulence effects, International Journal of Engine Research, 2009, 10 (2), pp. 97-119.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhou, L., Xie, M., Jia, M., Zhou, Q. et al., “Influences of subgrid turbulent kinetic energy and turbulent dispersion on the characteristics of fuel spray,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1839, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1839.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patterson, M. and Reitz, R., “Modeling the Effects of Fuel Spray Characteristics on Diesel Engine Combustion and Emission,” SAE Technical Paper 980131, 1998, doi:10.4271/980131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Rourke, P. and Amsden, A., “Three Dimensional Numerical Simulations of the UPS-292 Stratified Charge Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 870597, 1987, doi:10.4271/870597.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nordin, N. The KIVA Jumpstation [Online]. Available: http://www.tfd. chalmers.se/∼nordin/KJS/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoo, C.S., Lu, T., Chen, J.H., Law, C.K. Direct numerical simulations of ignition of a lean n-heptane/air mixture with temperature inhomogeneities at constant volume: Parametric study, Combustion and Flame, 2011, 158 (9), pp. 1727-1741.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hori, T., Kuge, T., Senda, J., and Fujimoto, H., “Large Eddy Simulation of Diesel Spray Combustion with Eddy-Dissipation Model and CIP Method by Use of KI VALES,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0247, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0247.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Genzale, C., Bruneaux, G., Malbec, L. et al., “Comparison of Diesel Spray Combustion in Different High-Temperature, High-Pressure Facilities,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):156-181, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010- 01-2106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Idicheria, C.A., Pickett, L.M. Effect of EGR on diesel premixed-burn equivalence ratio, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 2007, 31 (2), pp. 2931-2938.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bekdemir, C., Somers, L., de Goey, L., Tillou, J., Angelberger, C. Predicting diesel combustion characteristics with large-eddy simulations including tabulated chemical kinetics, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 2013, 34 (2), pp. 3067-3074.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
