<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26167739</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Signal Sound Positioning Alters Driving Performance</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lundkvist</surname>
                  <given-names>André</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nykänen</surname>
                  <given-names>Arne</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johnsson</surname>
                  <given-names>Roger</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Luleå University of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26167738</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>7</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26167739"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Many of the information systems in cars require visual attention, and a way to reduce both visual and cognitive workload could be to use sound. An experiment was designed in order to determine how driving and secondary task performance is affected by the use of information sound signals and their spatial positions. The experiment was performed in a driving simulator utilizing Lane Change Task as a driving scenario in combination with the Surrogate Reference Task as a secondary task. Two different signal sounds with different spatial positions informed the driver when a lane change should be made and when a new secondary task was presented. Driving performance was significantly improved when both signal sounds were presented in front of the driver. No significant effects on secondary task performance were found. It is recommended that signal sounds are placed in front of the driver, when possible, if the goal is to draw attention forward.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klauer S. G., Dingus T. A., Neale V. L., Sudweeks J. D. et al., “The Impact of Driver Inattention on Near-Crash/Crash Risk: An Analysis Using the 100-Car Naturalistic Driving Study Data,” Tech. Report, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Springfield, Virginia, April 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blanco M., Biever W. J., Gallagher J. P., and Dingus T. A., “The Impact of Secondary Task Cognitive Processing Demand on Driving Performance,” Accident Analysis and Prevention 38:895-906, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ho C. and Spence C., “Assessing the Effectiveness of Various Auditory Cues in Capturing a Driver's Visual Attention,” Journal of Experimental Psychology 11(3):157-174, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ho C., Tan H. Z., and Spence C., “The Differential Effect of Vibrotactile and Auditory Cues on Visual Spatial Attention,” Ergonomics 49(7):724-738, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee Y.-L., “The Effect of Congruency Between Sound-Source Location and Verbal Message Semantics of In-Vehicle Navigation Systems,” Safety Science 48:708-716, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cao Y., Mahr A., Castonovo S., Theune M., et al., “Local Danger Warnings for Drivers: The Effect of Modality and Level of Assistance on Driver Reaction,” in 14th ACM International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces, 239-248, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sodnik J., Tomazic S., Dicke C., and Billinghurst M., “Spatial Auditory Interface for an Embedded Communication Device in a Car,” in International Conference on Advances in Computer-Human Interaction 1:69-76, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sodnik J., Dicke C., Tomazic S., and Billinghurst M., “A User Study of Auditory Versus Visual Interfaces for Use While Driving,” International Journal of Human-Computer Studies 66:318-332, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shams L. and Kim R., “Crossmodal Influences on Visual Perception,” Physics of Life Reviews 7(3):269-284, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ngo M. and Spence C., “Crossmodal Facilitation of Masked Visual Target Identification,” Attention, Perception &amp; Psychophysics 72(7):1938-1947, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ISO 26022:2010, “Road Vehicles - Ergonomic Aspects of Transport Information and Control Systems - Simulated Lane Change Test to Assess In-vehicle Secondary Task Demand,” 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mattes S., “The Lane-Change-Task as a Tool for Driver Distraction Evaluation,” Quality of Work and Products in Enterprises of the Future, 57-60, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petzoldt T., Bär N., Ihle C., and Krems J. F., “Learning Effects in the Lane Change Task (LCT) - Evidence From Two Experimental Studies,” Transportation Research 14:1-12, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruyas M.-P., Brusque C., Tattegrain H., Auriault A., et al., “Consistency and Sensitivity of Lane Change Test According to Driving Simulator Characteristics,” Intelligent Transport Systems 2(4):306-314, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lundberg K. and Strålin A., “Förardistraktion - En studie av metoden Lane Change Test,” Master's thesis, Luleå University of Technology, 2005. Swedish.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petzoldt T., Graichen L., and Krems J. F., “Modifying the Lane Change Task - How Does Increased Unpredictability of Lane Changes Affect Performance?,” in 3rd International Conference on Driver Distraction and Inattention, Gothenburg, Sweden, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sanders M. S. and McCormick E. J., “Human Factors in Engineering and Design,” McGraw-Hill Science/Engineering/Math, 7th ed., 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blauert J., “The Psychophysics of Human Hearing,” Cambridge: MIT Press, rev. ed., 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Feddersen W. E., Sandel T. T., Teas D. C., and Jeffress L. A., “Localization of High-Frequency Tones,” Journal of the Acoustical Society of America 29:988-997, 1957.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moore B. C. J., “An Introduction to the Psychology of Hearing,” London: Academic Press, 5th ed., 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catchpole K. R., McKeown J. D., and Withington D. J., “Localizable Auditory Warning Pulses,” Ergonomics 47:748-771, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edworthy J., Loxley S., and Dennis I., “Improving Auditory Warning Design: Relationship Between Warning Sound Parameters and Perceived Urgency,” Human Factors 33:205-231, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sindhusake D., Mitchell P., Smith W., Golding M., et al., “Validation of self-reported hearing loss. The Blue Mountains Hearing Study”, International Journal of Epidemiology 30:1371-1378, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gomez M. I., Hwang S., Sobotova L., Stark A. D., et al., “A Comparison of Self-Reported Hearing Loss and Audiometry in a Cohort of New York Farmers”, Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research 44:1201-1208, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
