<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278086</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Sizing of Coolant Passages in an IC Engine Using a Design of Experiments Approach</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Annabattula</surname>
                  <given-names>Pallavi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Iqbal</surname>
                  <given-names>Owais</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sanka</surname>
                  <given-names>Manyam</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Arora</surname>
                  <given-names>Kunal</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>FCA US LLC</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>September 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278043</issue-id>
         <fpage>1898</fpage>
         <lpage>1905</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278086"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Determining coolant flow distribution in a topologically complex flow path for efficient heat rejection from the critical regions of the engine is a challenge. However, with the established computational methodology, thermal response of an engine (via conjugate heat transfer) can be accurately predicted [1, 2] and improved upon via Design of Experiment (DOE) study in a relatively short timeframe. This paper describes a method to effectively distribute the coolant flow in the engine coolant cavities and evenly remove the heat from various components using a novel technique of optimization based on an approximation model. The current methodology involves the usage of a sampling technique to screen the design space and generate the simulation matrix. Isight, a process automation and design exploration software, is used to set the framework of this study with the engine thermal simulation setup done in the CFD solver, STAR-CCM+. This is followed by the construction of a approximation model which aids in evaluating the interaction between the design variables (coolant passage dimensions). The methodology utilized here enables the prediction of the thermal map of the engine in the early stages of design and minimizes the need for expensive hardware testing, thus reducing the product development cycle time and cost.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iqbal, O., Arora, K., and Sanka, M., “Thermal Map of an IC Engine via Conjugate Heat Transfer: Validation and Test Data Correlation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(1):366-374, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iqbal O., Jonnalagedda S., Arora K., Zhong L., Gaikwad S., 2013, Comparison of 1-D vs #-D combustion boundary conditions for SI engine thermal load prediction, ICEF 2013-19227</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urip, E. and Yang, S., “An Efficient IC Engine Conjugate Heat Transfer Calculation for Cooling System Design,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01- 0147, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontanesi, S. and McAssey, E., “Experimental and Numerical Investigation of Conjugate Heat Transfer in a HSDI Diesel Engine Water Cooling Jacket,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0703, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0703.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontanesi, S., Cicalese, G., D'Adamo, A., and Pivetti, G., “Validation of a CFD Methodology for the Analysis of Conjugate Heat Transfer in a High Performance SI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0132, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0132.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontanesi, S., Cicalese, G., and Tiberi, A., “Combined In-cylinder/CHT Analyses for the Accurate Estimation of the Thermal Flow Field of a High Performance Engine for Sport Car Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1088, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1088.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ye, J., Covey, J., and Agnew, D., “Coolant Flow Optimization in a Racing Cylinder Block and Head Using CFD Analysis and Testing,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-3542, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-3542.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barros, P., Kirby, M., and Mavris, D., “Impact of Sampling Technique Selection on the Creation of Response Surface Models,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-3134, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-3134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen T.Y., Huang J.H., 2013, Application of data mining in a global optimization algorithm, Advances in Engineering Software, Vol. 66, pp 24-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, X. and Jiang, S., “A DOE Based Approach to Multi-Response Optimization,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0880, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0880.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leal, M., Borges, J., and Butkewitsch, S., “A Case Study on the Response Surface Method Applied to the Optimization of the Dynamical Behavior of Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3850, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3850.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun, S., Chang, Y., Fu, Q., Zhao, J. et al., “Aerodynamic Shape Optimization of an SUV in early Development Stage using a Response Surface Method,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 7(4):1252- 1263, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2445.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D'Errico G., Cerri T., Pertusi G., 2010, Multi-objective optimization of internal combustion engine by means of 1D fluid-dynamic models, Applied Energy, Vol. 88, pp 767-777.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ge, H., Shi, Y., Reitz, R., Wickman, D. et al., “Engine Development Using Multi-dimensional CFD and Computer Optimization,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0360, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0360.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thiel, M., Klingbeil, A., and Reitz, R., “Experimental Optimization of a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine Using Automated Genetic Algorithms,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0960, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0960.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hajireza, S., Regner, G., Christie, A., Egert, M. et al., “Application of CFD Modeling in Combustion Bowl Assessment of Diesel Engines Using DoE Methodology,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3330, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3330.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montgomery, D.C., 1991, Design and Analysis of Experiments, Wiley &amp; Sons, New York, 3rd Edition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Isight 5.8 Help Manual, 2014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kansa E.J., 1990, Multiquadrics-A scattered data approximation scheme with applications to computational fluid-dynamice-II solutions to parabolic, hyperbolic and elliptic partial differential equations, Computers &amp; Mathematics with Applications, Vol. 19, pp 147-161.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, H., Majcher, M., Chuang, C., Fu, Y. et al., “Comparative Benchmark Studies of Response Surface Model-Based Optimization and Direct Multidisciplinary Design Optimization,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01- 0400, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-0400.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weinstein, W., The Automobile Engine, 1961, Chilton Company, Philadelphia, 1961, 1st Edition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vanderplaats, G.N., 1998, “Numerical Optimizations Techniques for Engineering Design”; Vanderplaats Research and Development Inc; 2nd Edition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
