<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169078</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Synthesis of a Hybrid-Observer-Based Active Controller for Compensating Powetrain Backlash Nonlinearity of an Electric Vehicle during Regenerative Braking</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lv</surname>
                  <given-names>Chen</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
                  <given-names>Junzhi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Yutong</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yuan</surname>
                  <given-names>Ye</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>State Key Lab of ASE, Tsinghua Univ.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>May 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169060</issue-id>
         <fpage>190</fpage>
         <lpage>198</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169078"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Regenerative braking provided by an electric powertrain is far different from conventional friction braking with respect to the system dynamics. During regenerative decelerations, the nonlinear powertrain backlash would excite driveline oscillations, deteriorating vehicle drivability and blended brake performance. Therefore, backlash compensation is worthwhile researching for an advanced powertrain control of electrified vehicles during regenerative deceleration.</p>
            <p>In this study, a nonlinear powertrain of an electric passenger car equipped with a central motor is modeled using hybrid system approach. The effect of powertrain backlash gap on vehicle drivability during regenerative deceleration is analyzed. To further improve an electric vehicle's drivability and blended braking performance, an active control algorithm with a hierarchical architecture is studied for powertrain backlash compensation. Since the backlash in driveline is unable to be measured by a sensor, a high-level hybrid observer for backlash identification is designed at first. Then, based on the observation of the backlash traverse, a low-level switchingbased active controller for powertrain backlash compensation is synthesized.</p>
            <p>The proposed control algorithm is simulated and compared with a non-active baseline strategy under regeneration deceleration. The simulation results show that the nonlinear powertrain backlash is well compensated by the developed active control algorithm, and the vehicle drivability and blended braking performance are also significantly enhanced.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gao, Y. and Ehsani, M., “Electronic Braking System of EV And HEV---Integration of Regenerative Braking, Automatic Braking Force Control and ABS,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-2478, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-2478.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, J.Z., Lv, C., Gou, J.F. and Kong, D.C., “Cooperative control of regenerative braking and hydraulic braking of an electrified passenger car”, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering 2012; 226(10): 1289-1302.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sovran, G. and Blaser, D., “Quantifying the Potential Impacts of Regenerative Braking on a Vehicle's Tractive-Fuel Consumption for the U.S., European, and Japanese Driving Schedules,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0664, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0664.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lv, C., Zhang, J.Z., Li, Y.T., Sun D.S. and Yuan, Y., “Hardware-inthe- loop simulation of pressure-difference-limiting modulation of the hydraulic brake for regenerative braking control of electric vehicles”, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering 2014; 228(6): 649-662.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bayar, K., McGee, R., Yu, H., and Crombez, D., “Regenerative Braking Control Enhancement for the Power Split Hybrid Architecture with the Utilization of Hardware-in-the-loop Simulations,” SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 2(1):127-134, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1466.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lagerberg, A., and Bo E., “Backlash estimation with application to automotive powertrains”, Control Systems Technology, IEEE Trans 2007;15(3): 483-493.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Templin, P., “Simultaneous estimation of driveline dynamics and backlash size for control design”. Control Applications, IEEE International Conference on, IEEE 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamaura, H., Ishihama, M., and Togai, K., “Design and Evaluation of Output Profile Shaping of an Internal Combustion Engine for Noise &amp; Vibration Improvement,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(3):1514-1522, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1683.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baumann, J., Swarnakar, A., Kiencke, U., and Schlegl, T., “A Robust Controller Design for Anti-Jerking,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0041, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0041.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawamura, H., Ito, K., Karikomi, T., and Kume, T., “Highly-Responsive Acceleration Control for the Nissan LEAF Electric Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0397, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0397.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bottiglione, F., Sorniotti, A., Shead, L., “The effect of half-shaft torsion dynamics on the performance of a traction control system for electric vehicles”, Proc. Inst. Mech. Eng. Part D J. Automob. Eng. 2012; 226(9): 1145-1159.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, J., Lv, C., Yue, X., Li, Y., Yuan, Y., “Study on a linear relationship between limited pressure difference and coil current of on/off valve and its influential factors”, ISA Transactions 2014; 53(1): 150-161.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lv, C., Zhang, J., Li, Y., and Yuan, Y., “Regenerative Braking Control Algorithm for an Electrified Vehicle Equipped with a By-Wire Brake System,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1791, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1791.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, J., Lv, C., Yue, X., Qiu, M. et al., “Development of the Electrically-Controlled Regenerative Braking System for Electrified Passenger Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1463, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1463.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Balluchi, A., Benvenuti, L., Di Benedetto, M. D., and Sangiovanni- Vincentelli, A., “The Design of dynamical observers for hybrid systems: Theory and Application to an Automotive Control Problem”, Automatica 2013; 49(4): 915-925.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Balluchi, A., Benvenuti, L., Di Benedetto, M. D., and Sangiovanni- Vincentelli, A., “A hybrid observer for the driveline dynamics,” Proceedings of the European Control Conference, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amann, N., Bocker, J., and Prenner, F., “Active damping of drive train oscillations for an electrically driven vehicle”, Mechatronics, IEEE/ASME Transactions on 2014; 9(4): 697-700.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lv, C., Zhang, J., Li Y., “Extended-Kalman-filter-based regenerative and friction blended braking control for electric vehicle equipped with axle motor considering damping and elastic properties of electric powertrain”, Vehicle System Dynamics 2014; 52(11), 1372-1388.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
