<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275563</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Electro-Thermal Modeling of a Lithium-ion Battery System</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ma</surname>
                  <given-names>Yue</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Teng</surname>
                  <given-names>Ho</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Thelliez</surname>
                  <given-names>Marina</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>AVL Powertrain Engineering Inc.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275542</issue-id>
         <fpage>306</fpage>
         <lpage>317</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275563"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Lithium-Ion (Li-ion) batteries are becoming widely used high-energy sources and a replacement of the Nickel Metal Hydride batteries in electric vehicles (EV), hybrid electric vehicles (HEV) and plug-in hybrid electric vehicles (PHEV). Because of their light weight and high energy density, Li-ion cells can significantly reduce the weight and volume of the battery packs for EVs, HEVs and PHEVs. Some materials in the Li-ion cells have low thermal stabilities and they may become thermally unstable when their working temperature becomes higher than the upper limit of allowed operating temperature range. Thus, the cell working temperature has a significant impact on the life of Li-ion batteries. A proper control of the cell working temperature is crucial to the safety of the battery system and improving the battery life. This paper outlines an approach for the thermal analysis of Li-ion battery cells and modules. The thermal behavior was analyzed of a commercially available A123 Hymotion™ L5 PCM pack assembled with the A123-26650 Li-ion cylindrical cells using the electrothermal finite element model developed in this paper. The simulation results showed good agreement with measurements. This demonstrates that the electrothermal finite element model developed in this study can reasonably characterize the thermal behavior of a battery pack. Although only cylindrical cells are analyzed, the method for characterizing the thermal behavior of the Li-ion battery cells developed in this study can also be applied to battery cells with other geometries, such as prismatic and pouch cells.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bharathan, D., Pesaran, A., Vlahinos, A., Kim, G.-H., “Improving Battery Design with Electro-Thermal Modeling,” Vehicle Power and Propulsion, 2005 IEEE Conference Proceedings, 7-9 September 2005, Chicago, Illinois. Piscataway, NJ: Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, Inc. (IEEE) 8 pp.; NREL Report No. CP-540-41751.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inui, Y. Kobayashi, Watanabe, Y., Watase, Y., Kitamura, Y., “Simulation of Temperature Distribution in Cylindrical and Prismatic Lithium Ion Secondary Batteries,” Energy Conversion and Management, Vol.48, pp.2103-2109, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iu, H.Y. and Smart, J., “Determining PHEV Performance Potential - User and Environmental Influences on A123 Systems' Hymotion™ Plug-In Conversion Module for the Toyota Prius,” EVS24 International Battery, Hybrid and Fuel Cell Electric Vehicle Symposium, Stavanger, Norway, May 13-16, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.a123systems.com/a123/products.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A123 System, ANM24V24 Module Development Guide, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://industrial.panasonic.com/www-data/pdf/ACI4000/ACI4000PE5.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Al-Hallaj, S., Maleki, H., Hong, J. S., Selman, J.R., “Thermal Modeling and Design Considerations of Lithiumion Batteries,” J. Power Sources, Vol.83, 1 (1999).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hatchard, T. D., MacNeil, D. D., Basu, A., Dahn, J. R., “Thermal Model of Cylindrical and Prismatic Li-ion Cells,” J. Electrochem. Soc., Vol.148, 7, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Evans, T. I., White, R. E., “A Thermal Analysis of a Spirally Wound Battery Using a Simple Mathematical Model,” J. Electrochem. Soc., Vol.136, 2145, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bernardi, D., Pawlikowski, E., Newman, J., “A General Energy Balance for Battery Systems,” J. Electrochem. Soc., 132, 5(1985).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Simulia, ABAQUS/Standard documentation for version 6.8-1; www.simulia.com/support/documentation.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AVL GmbH, AVL-FIRE, Theory, Version 2009, AVL, Graz, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chu, A., et al., “Battery Cell Design and Method of Its Construction,” U.S. Patent 2007/0269685 A1, November 22, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
