<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">mathcomp</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100273</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Mathematics of Computation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>American Mathematical Society</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00255718</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">10886842</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">84</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">292</issue>
         <issue-id>i24488617</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/24488637</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>GRÖBNER BASES AND GRADINGS FOR PARTIAL DIFFERENCE IDEALS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>ROBERTO</given-names>
                  <surname>LA SCALA</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>959</fpage>
         <lpage>985</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015 American Mathematical Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24488637"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>In this paper we introduce a working generalization of the theory of Gröbner bases for algebras of partial difference polynomials with constant coefficients. One obtains symbolic (formal) computation for systems of linear or non-linear partial difference equations arising, for instance, as discrete models or by the discretization of systems of differential equations. From an algebraic viewpoint, the algebras of partial difference polynomials are free objects in the category of commutative algebras endowed with the action by endomorphisms of a monoid isomorphic to ℕr. Then, the investigation of Gröbner bases in this context contributes also to the current research trend consisting in studying polynomial rings under the action of suitable symmetries that are compatible with effective methods. Since the algebras of difference polynomials are not Noetherian, we propose in this paper a theory for grading them that provides a Noetherian subalgebra filtration. This implies that the variants of Buchberger's algorithm we developed for difference ideals terminate in the finitely generated graded case when truncated up to some degree. Moreover, even in the non-graded case, we provide criterions for certifying completeness of eventually finite Gröbner bases when they are computed within sufficiently large bounded degrees. We generalize also the concepts of homogenization and saturation, and related algorithms, to the context of difference ideals. The feasibility of the proposed methods is shown by an implementation in Maple that is the first to provide computations for systems of non-linear partial difference equations. We make use of a test set based on the discretization of concrete systems of non-linear partial differential equations.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d3079e114a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e121" publication-type="other">
Matthias Aschenbrenner and Christopher J. Hillar, Finite generation of symmetric ideals,
Trans. Amer. Math. Soc. 359 (2007), no. 11, 5171-5192, DOI 10.1090/S0002-9947-07-04116-
5. MR2327026 (2008g:13030)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e134a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e141" publication-type="other">
George M. Bergman, The diamond lemma for ring theory, Adv. in Math. 29 (1978), no. 2,
178-218, DOI 10.1016/0001-8708(78)90010-5. MR506890 (81b:16001)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e151a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e158" publication-type="other">
A. M. Bigatti, M. Caboara, and L. Robbiano, Computing inhomogeneous Grobner bases, J.
Symbolic Comput. 46 (2011), no. 5, 498-510, DOI 10.1016/j.jsc.2010.10.002. MR2781934
(2012c:13061)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e171a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e178" publication-type="other">
Andries B. Brouwer and Jan Draisma, Equivariant Grobner bases and the Gaussian two-
factor model, Math. Comp. 80 (2011), no. 274, 1123-1133, DOI 10.1090/S0025-5718-2010-
02415-9. MR2772115 (2012g:13049)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e192a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e199" publication-type="other">
B. Buchberger, Ein algorithmisches Kriterium fur die Losbarkeit eines algebraischen Gle-
ichungssystems (German), Aequationes Math. 4 (1970), 374-383. MR0268178 (42 #3077)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e209a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e216" publication-type="other">
Richard M. Cohn, Difference Algebra, Interscience Publishers John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York-
London-Sydeny, 1965. MR0205987 (34 #5812)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e226a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e233" publication-type="other">
W. Decker, G.-M. Greuel, G. Pfister, and H. Schonemann, Singular 3-1-5 — A computer
algebra system for polynomial computations (2012). http://www.singular.uni-kl.de</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e243a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e250" publication-type="other">
David Eisenbud, Commutative Algebra, Graduate Texts in Mathematics, vol. 150, Springer-
Verlag, New York, 1995. With a view toward algebraic geometry. MR1322960 (97a:13001)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e260a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e267" publication-type="other">
V. P. Gerdt, Consistency analysis of finite difference approximations to PDE systems. In:
Adam G. et al. (Eds.), Proc. of Mathematical Modeling and Computational Physics. MMCP
2011, 28-42, Lecture Notes in Comput. Sci., 7175, Springer, Heidelberg, 2012.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e280a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e287" publication-type="other">
V. P. Gerdt and Y. A. Blinkov, Involution and difference schemes for the Navier-Stokes
equations. In: Gerdt V.P. et al. (Eds.), Proc. of Computer Algebra in Scientific Computing.
CASC 2009, 94-105, Lecture Notes in Comput. Sci., 5743, Springer, Berlin, 2009.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e301a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e308" publication-type="other">
Vladimir P. Gerdt, Yuri A. Blinkov, and Vladimir V. Mozzhilkin, Grbbner bases and genera-
tion of difference schemes for partial differential equations, SIGMA Symmetry Integrability
Geom. Methods Appl. 2 (2006), Paper 051, 26, DOI 10.3842/SIGMA.2006.051. MR2240724
(2007h:65084)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e324a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e331" publication-type="other">
V. P. Gerdt and D. Robertz, A Maple package for computing Grobner bases for linear re-
currence relations. Nucl. Instrum. Methods, 599 (2006), 215—219. http://wwwb.math.rwth-
aachen.de/Janet</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e344a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e351" publication-type="other">
Michel Gondran and Michel Minoux, Graphs, Dioids and Semirings, New Models and Al-
gorithms. Operations Research/Computer Science Interfaces Series, vol. 41, Springer, New
York, 2008. MR2389137 (2009g: 16066)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e364a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e371" publication-type="other">
E. A. Grove and G. Ladas, Periodicities in Nonlinear Difference Equations, Advances in
Discrete Mathematics and Applications, vol. 4, Chapman &amp; Hall/CRC, Boca Raton, FL,
2005. MR2193366 (2006j:39002)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e384a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e391" publication-type="other">
Graham Higman, Ordering by divisibility in abstract algebras, Proc. London Math. Soc. (3)
2 (1952), 326-336. MR0049867 (14,238e)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e401a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e408" publication-type="other">
Christopher J. Hillar and Abraham Martin del Campo, Finiteness theorems and algorithms
for permutation invariant chains of Laurent lattice ideals, J. Symbolic Comput. 50 (2013),
314-334, DOI 10.1016/j.jsc.2012.06.006. MR2996883</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e422a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e429" publication-type="other">
E. R. Kolchin, Differential Algebra and Algebraic Groups, Academic Press, New York, 1973.
Pure and Applied Mathematics, Vol. 54. MR0568864 (58 #27929)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e439a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e446" publication-type="other">
R. La Scala, Extended letterplace correspondence for nongraded noncommutative ideals and
related algorithms, preprint (2012), 1—20. arXiv:1206.6027</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e456a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e463" publication-type="other">
Roberto La Scala and Viktor Levandovskyy, Letterplace ideals and non-commutative Grobner
bases, J. Symbolic Comput. 44 (2009), no. 10, 1374-1393, DOI 10.1016/j.jsc.2009.03.002.
MR2543425 (2010m:16031)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e476a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e483" publication-type="other">
Roberto La Scala and Viktor Levandovskyy, Skew polynomial rings, Grobner bases and the
letterplace embedding of the free associative algebra, J. Symbolic Comput. 48 (2013), 110-131,
DOI 10.1016/j.jsc.2012.05.003. MR2980469</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e496a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e503" publication-type="other">
V. Levandovskyy and B. Martin, A symbolic approach to generation and analysis of finite
difference schemes of partial differential equations. In: Langer U. et al. (Eds.), Numerical
and Symbolic Scientific Computing: Progress and Prospects. Springer (2012), 123-156.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e516a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e523" publication-type="other">
Decio Levi, Lie symmetries for lattice equations, Note Mat. 23 (2004/05), no. 2, 139—156.
MR2141114 (2006b:37157)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e534a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e541" publication-type="other">
Alexander Levin, Difference Algebra, Algebra and Applications, vol. 8, Springer, New York,
2008. MR2428839 (2009m:12010)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e551a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e558" publication-type="other">
David A. Meyer and Noland Wallach, Invariants for multiple qubits: the case of 3 qubits,
Mathematics of quantum computation, Comput. Math. Ser., Chapman &amp; Hall/CRC, Boca
Raton, FL, 2002, pp. 77-97. MR2007943 (2004h:81034)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e571a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e578" publication-type="other">
J. F. Ritt, Differential Equations From the Algebraic Standpoint. Amer. Math. Soc. Collo-
quium Publ., Vol. 14, AMS, New York, 1932.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e588a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e595" publication-type="other">
Joseph Fels Ritt, Differential Algebra, American Mathematical Society Colloquium Publica-
tions, Vol. XXXIII, American Mathematical Society, New York, N. Y., 1950. MR0035763
(12,7c)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3079e608a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3079e615" publication-type="other">
Werner M. Seiler, Involution, The formal theory of differential equations and its applications
in computer algebra. Algorithms and Computation in Mathematics, vol. 24, Springer-Verlag,
Berlin, 2010. MR2573958 (2011h:35003)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


