<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">105</volume>
         <issue-id>i40198805</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44725622</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>High Power Induction Motor for Aircraft Spoiler</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Pete</given-names>
                  <surname>Fizer</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1996</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1335</fpage>
         <lpage>1347</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1997 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44725622"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper presents the design, fabrication, and testing of a 50HP, 30000 rpm induction motor for a next generation large aircraft spoiler. The motor is characterized by high power density, developing over 8.5 pounds per square inch of airgap surface area with only 13 pounds electromagnetic weight. Detailed designs, including magnetic material selection, electromagnetic parameters, and finite element thermal analyses are presented and compared to test data. Testing was obtained using a high speed hydraulic dynamometer with digital data acquisition. The motor and actuator are designed and built by AlliedSignal for participation in the NASA Redundant Effector Program and NASA Power-by-Wire Electromechanical Actuation (EMA) Spoiler Program. The program emphasizes the demonstration of power electronic motor drive and actuation technologies for aerospace applications. In addition to NASA LeRC other participants include Lockheed Martin Astronautics, Advanced Launch Systems (program management), General Electric Corporate Research (Auxiliary Resonant Commutated Pole Inverter, DSP digital motor control technology, laboratory drive testing), Lockheed Martin Controls Systems (actuator control electronics, system integration), and Boeing Commercial Aircraft Company (spoiler actuation and aircraft requirements).</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


