<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277553</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>xD+1D Catalyst Simulation-A Numerical Study on the Impact of Pore Diffusion</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Edelbauer</surname>
                  <given-names>Wilfried</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kutschi</surname>
                  <given-names>Susanne</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wurzenberger</surname>
                  <given-names>Johann C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>AVL LIST GmbH</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>1459</fpage>
         <lpage>1476</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277553"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper presents a numerical study on the impact of washcoat diffusion on the overall conversion performance of catalytic converters. A comprehensive transient 1D pore diffusion reaction model is embedded in state-of-the-art 1D and 3D catalytic converter models. The pore diffusion model is discussed with its model equations and the applied diffusive transport approaches are summarized. The diffusion reaction model is validated with the help of two available analytical solutions. The impact of basic washcoat characteristics such as pore diameters or thickness on overall conversion performance is investigated by selected 1D+1D calculations. This model is also used to highlight the impact of boundary layer transfer, pore diffusion and reaction on the overall converter conversion performance. The interaction of pore diffusion and flow non-uniformities is demonstrated by 3D+1D CFD simulations.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konstandopoulos, A., Kostoglou, M., Vlachos, N., and Kladopoulou, E., “Progress in Diesel Particulate Filter Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0946, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0946.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pfeifer, M., Votsmeier, M., Kögel, M., Spurk, P. et al., “The Second Generation of Catalyzed Diesel Particulate Filter Systems for Passenger Cars - Particulate Filters with Integrated Oxidation Catalyst Function-,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1756, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1756.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mizuno, T. and Suzuki, J., “Development of a New DPNR Catalyst,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0578, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0578.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, Y., Brown, D., Lu, S., Paratore, M. et al., “Opportunities and Challenges for Blended 2-Way SCR/DPF Aftertreatment Technologies,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0274, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0274.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chandler, G., Cooper, B., Harris, J., Thoss, J. et al., “An Integrated SCR and Continuously Regenerating Trap System to Meet Future NOx and PM Legislation,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0188, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-0188.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Votsmaier, M., “Simulation of NH3-Slip Catalysts”, CLEERS DOE Crosscut Workshop on Lean Emissions Reduction Simulation, UofM, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ottaviani, E., Jean, E., Albert, H., Amon, B. et al., “Dual Line Exhaust Design Optimisation to Maximize SCR Catalyst Efficiency thru Improved Ammonia Distribution,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0914, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0914.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Henrichsen, Lars, “Expanding Use of AVL BOOST for Aftertreatment Modeling at Cummins”, presented at AVL Advanced Simulation Technologies International Users Conference 2011, Graz, Austria, June 28th-30th,2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wurzenberger, J., Bardubitzki, S., Bartsch, P., and Katrasnik, T., “Real Time Capable Pollutant Formation and Exhaust Aftertreatment Modeling-HSDI Diesel Engine Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1438, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1438.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Depcik, C. and Assanis, D., “One-dimensional automotive catalyst modeling”, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 31 (4): 308-369, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Froment, G. F., Bishoff, K. B., “Chemical Reactor Analysis and Design”, John Wiley &amp; Sons Inc., New York, London, Sydney, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tavera, E. M., “Analytical expression of the non-isothermal effectiveness factor: the n'th order reaction in a slab geometry”, Chemical Engineering Science 60 (2005): 907-916, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dadvar, M. and Sahimi, M., “The effectiveness diffusivities in porous media with and without nonlinear reactions”, Chemical Engineering Science 62 (2007): 1466-1476, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, D. H. and Lee, J., “A robust iterative method of computing effectiveness factors in porous catalysts”, Chemical Engineering Science 59 (2004): 2253-2263, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hayes, R.E. and Kolackowski, S. T., “Mass and Heat Transfer Effects in Catalytic Monolith Reactions”, Chemical Engineering Science 49 (1994): pp 3587-3599, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Papadias, D., Edsberg, L. and Björnbom, P., “Simplified method for effectiveness factor calculation in irregular geometries of washcoats”, Chemical Engineering Science 55 (2000): 1447-1459, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hayes, R. E. Liu, B. and Votsmeier, M., “Calculating effectiveness factors in non-uniform washcoat shapes”, Chemical Engineering Science 60 (2005): 2037-2050, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dieterich, E. E., “Systematische Bilanzierung und modulare Simulation verfahrenstechnischer Apparate”, Ph.D. thesis, Wissenschaftsverlag Aachen, Ph.D. thesis, The University of Stuttgart, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Massing, E., Brilhac, J.F., Brillard, A., Gilot, P., Prado, G., “Modelling of the behavior of a three way catalytic converter at steady state. Influence of the propene diffusion inside the catalytic layer”, Chemical Engineering Science 55 (2000): 1707-1716, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wurzenberger, J. C., Wallner, S., Raupenstrauch, K. and, Khinast, J., “Biomass Gasification - Comprehensive Reactor and Particle Modelling”, AIChE Journal 48 (2002) 10: 2398-2411, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AVL List GmbH, “BOOST Aftertreatment Manual v2011”, AVL List GmbH, Graz, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AVL List GmbH, “FIRE Aftertreatment Manual v2011”, AVL List GmbH, Graz, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hayes, R.E. and Kolackowski, S. T., “Introduction to Catalytic Combustion”, Gordon and Breach Science Publishers, Amsterdam, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wendland, D. W., “The Segmented Oxidizing Monolith Catalytic Converter, Theory and Performance”, Transactions to ASME 12 (1980): 194-198, 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wanker, R., Raupenstauch, H., and Staudinger, G., “A fully distributed model for the simulation of a catalytic combustor”, Chemical Engineering Science 55 (2000): 4709-4718, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wurzenberger, J., Wanker, R., and Schüßler, M., “Simulation of Exhaust Gas Aftertreatment Systems - Thermal Behavior During Different Operating Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0865, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0865.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dubien, C., Schweich, D., Mabilon, G., Martin, B. and Prigent, M., “Three-way catalytic converter modelling: fast and slow-oxidizing hydrocarbons, inhibition species, and steam reforming reactions”, Chemical Engineering Science 53 (1998): 471-481, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koltsakis, G. and Stamatelos, A. M., “Modeling dynamic phenomena in 3-way catalytic converters”, Chemical Engineering Science 54 (1999): 4567-4578, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khinast, J., “Kinetik, Reaktionsmechanismus und Simulation eines trockenen Rauchgasentschwefelungsverfahren”, PhD-thesis, Graz University of Technology, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wheeler, A., In, Emmett, P.H. (Ed.), Catalysis, Reinhold New York, Vol II: 105, 1955.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wakao, W., Smith, J.M., “Diffusion in catalyst pellets”, Chemical Engineering Science 17 (1962): 825-834, 1962.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hayes, R.E., Kolackowski, S.T., Li, P.K.C., Awdry, S., “Evaluating the effective diffusivity of methane in the washcoat of a honeycomb monolith”, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental 25 (2000): 93-104, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zill, D. G., Cullen, M. R., “Advanced Engineering Mathematics”, 2nd Edition, Jones and Bartlett Publishers, ISBN 0-7637-1357-0: 697:699, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baehr, H. D. and Stephan, K., “Wärme- und Stoffübertragung”, Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg, ISBN 3-540-55086-0: 246-251, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Voltz, S. E., Morgan, C. R., Liederman, D., Jacob, S. M., “Kinetic Study of Carbon Monoxide and Propylene Oxidation on Platinum Catalysts”, Industrial and Engineering Chemistry Product Research and Development 12 (4): 294-301, 1973.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AVL List GmbH, “FIRE Main Solver Manual v2011”, AVL List GmbH, Graz, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
