<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26649147</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Optical Investigation of Sooting Propensity of <italic>n</italic>-Dodecane Pilot/Lean-Premixed Methane Dual-Fuel Combustion in a Rapid Compression-Expansion Machine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Srna</surname>
                  <given-names>Ales</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bruneaux</surname>
                  <given-names>Gilles</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Von Rotz</surname>
                  <given-names>Beat</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bombach</surname>
                  <given-names>Rolf</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">11</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26649117</issue-id>
         <fpage>1049</fpage>
         <lpage>1068</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26649147"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The sooting propensity of dual-fuel combustion with <italic>n</italic>-dodecane pilot injection in a lean-premixed methane-air charge has been investigated using an optically accessible Rapid Compression-Expansion Machine (RCEM) to achieve engine-relevant pressure and temperature conditions at the start of pilot injection. A Diesel injector with a 100 μm single-hole coaxial nozzle, mounted at the cylinder periphery, has been employed to admit the pilot fuel.</p> 
            <p>The aim of this study was to enhance the fundamental understanding of soot formation and oxidation processes of <italic>n</italic>-dodecane in the presence of methane in the air charge by parametric variation of methane equivalence ratio, charge temperature, and pilot fuel injection duration. The influence of methane on ignition delay and flame extent of the pilot fuel jet has been determined by simultaneous excited-state hydroxyl radical (OH*) chemiluminescence and Schlieren imaging. The sooting behavior of the flame has been characterized using the 2D-DBI imaging methodology. The apparent soot black-body temperature has been measured 1D resolved along the injector axis by applying an imaging spectrograph.</p> 
            <p>Addition of methane into the air charge considerably prolongs the ignition delay with an increasing effect under less reactive conditions and with higher methane equivalence ratios. Therefore, the influence of methane on the formation of soot is twofold: in case of short pilot injection, the presence of methane was found to decrease the soot formation due to the leaner pilot fuel mixture at the time of ignition. For longer pilot fuel injections, methane enhances the soot production by decreasing oxygen availability and introducing additional carbon. In all cases, methane strongly defers the oxidation of soot due to the lower availability of oxygen.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Khan, M.I., Yasmeen, T., Khan, M.I., Farooq, M. et al., “Research Progress in the Development of Natural Gas as Fuel for Road Vehicles: A Bibliographic Review (1991-2016),” Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 66:702-741, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.rser.2016.08.041.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Shah, A., Thipse, S.S., Tyagi, A., Rairikar, S.D. et al., “Literature Review and Simulation of Dual Fuel Diesel-CNG Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-26-0001, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-26-0001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Wei, L. and Geng, P., “A Review on Natural Gas/Diesel Dual Fuel Combustion, Emissions and Performance,” Fuel Processing Technology 142(Supplement C):264-278, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.fuproc.2015.09.018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Rochussen, J., Yeo, J., and Kirchen, P., “Effect of Fueling Control Parameters on Combustion and Emissions Characteristics of Diesel-Ignited Methane Dual-Fuel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0792, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0792.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Yang, B., Xi, C., Wei, X., Zeng, K. et al., “Parametric Investigation of Natural Gas Port Injection and Diesel Pilot Injection on the Combustion and Emissions of a Turbocharged Common Rail Dual-Fuel Engine at Low Load,” Applied Energy 143(Supplement C):130-137, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2015.01.037.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Liu, J., Yang, F., Wang, H., Ouyang, M. et al., “Effects of Pilot Fuel Quantity on the Emissions Characteristics of a CNG/Diesel Dual Fuel Engine with Optimized Pilot Injection Timing,” Applied Energy 110(Supplement C):201-206, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2013.03.024.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Egusquiza, J.C., Braga, S.L., and Braga, C.V.M., “Performance and Gaseous Emissions Characteristics of a Natural Gas/Diesel Dual Fuel Turbocharged and Aftercooled Engine,” Journal of the Brazilian Society of Mechanical Sciences and Engineering 31:142-150, 2009, doi:10.1590/S1678-58782009000200007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Abdelaal, M.M. and Hegab, A.H., “Combustion and Emission Characteristics of a Natural Gas-Fueled Diesel Engine with EGR,” Energy Conversion and Management 64(Supplement C):301-312, 2012, doi:10.1016/j. enconman.2012.05.021.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Sun, L., Liu, Y., Zeng, K., Yang, R. et al., “Combustion Performance and Stability of a Dual-Fuel Diesel-Natural-Gas Engine,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering 229(2):235-246, 2014, doi:10.1177/0954407014537814.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Zhou, L., Liu, Y.-F., Wu, C.-B., Sun, L. et al., “Effect of the Diesel Injection Timing and the Pilot Quantity on the Combustion Characteristics and the Fine-Particle Emissions in a Micro-Diesel Pilot-Ignited Natural-Gas Engine,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering 227(8):1142-1152, 2013, doi:10.1177/0954407013480452.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Papagiannakis, R.G. and Hountalas, D.T., “Experimental Investigation Concerning the Effect of Natural Gas Percentage on Performance and Emissions of a DI Dual Fuel Diesel Engine,” Applied Thermal Engineering 23(3):353-365, 2003, doi:10.1016/S1359-4311(02)00187-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Papagiannakis, R.G. and Hountalas, D.T., “Combustion and Exhaust Emission Characteristics of a Dual Fuel Compression Ignition Engine Operated with Pilot Diesel Fuel and Natural Gas,” Energy Conversion and Management 45(18):2971-2987, 2004, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2004.01.013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Lounici, M.S., Loubar, K., Tarabet, L., Balistrou, M., et al., "Towards Improvement of Natural Gas-Diesel Dual Fuel Mode: An Experimental Investigation on Performance and Exhaust Emissions." Energy, 2014. 64(Supplement C): 200- 211, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2013.10.091.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Abd Alla, G.H., Soliman, H.A., Badr, O.A., and Abd Rabbo, M.F., “Effect of Pilot Fuel Quantity on the Performance of a Dual Fuel Engine,” Energy Conversion and Management 41(6):559-572, 2000, doi:10.1016/S0196-8904(99)00124-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Nithyanandan, K., Gao, Y., Wu, H., Lee, C.-F. et al., “An Optical Investigation of Multiple Diesel Injections in CNG/Diesel Dual-Fuel Combustion in a Light Duty Optical Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-0755, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0755.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Pettinen, R., Kaario, O., and Larmi, M., “Dual-Fuel Combustion Characterization on Lean Conditions and High Loads,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-0759, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0759.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Dronniou, N., Kashdan, J., Lecointe, B., Sauve, K. et al., “Optical Investigation of Dual-Fuel CNG/Diesel Combustion Strategies to Reduce CO 2 Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7:873-887, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1313.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Zhang, Y., Ghandhi, J., and Rothamer, D., “Effects of Fuel Chemistry and Spray Properties on Particulate Size Distributions from Dual-Fuel Combustion Strategies,” SAE Int. J. Engines 10(4):1847-1858, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01- 1005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Schlatter, S., Schneider, B., Wright, Y.M., and Boulouchos, K., “N-Heptane Micro Pilot Assisted Methane Combustion in a Rapid Compression Expansion Machine,” Fuel 179:339- 352, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2016.03.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Schlatter, S., Schneider, B., Wright, Y., and Boulouchos, K., “Experimental Study of Ignition and Combustion Characteristics of a Diesel Pilot Spray in a Lean Premixed Methane/Air Charge Using a Rapid Compression Expansion Machine,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0825, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0825.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Salaun, E., Apeloig, J., Grisch, F., Yvonnet, C.-E. et al., “Optical Investigation of Ignition Timing and Equivalence Ratio in Dual-Fuel CNG/Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0772, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0772.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Paykani, A., Kakaee, A.-H., Rahnama, P., and Reitz, R.D., “Progress and Recent Trends in Reactivity-Controlled Compression Ignition Engines,” Int. J. Engine Res. 17(5):481- 524, 2015, doi:10.1177/1468087415593013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Carlucci, A.P., Laforgia, D., Saracino, R., and Toto, G., “Study of Combustion Development in Methane-Diesel Dual Fuel Engines, Based on the Analysis of In-Cylinder Luminance,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1297, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1297.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Nakamura, M. and Ohashi, H., “Study of Diesel Spray Combustion in an Ambient Gas Containing Hydrocarbon Using a Rapid Compression Machine,” SAE Technical Paper 980899, 1997, doi:10.4271/980899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Pickett, L.M., Kook, S., and Williams, T.C., “Visualization of Diesel Spray Penetration, Cool-Flame, Ignition, High- Temperature Combustion, and Soot Formation Using High- Speed Imaging,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):439-459, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0658.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Idicheria, C.A. and Pickett, L.M., “Soot Formation in Diesel Combustion under High-EGR Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3834, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3834.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Manin, J., Pickett, L.M., and Skeen, S.A., “Two-Color Diffused Back-Illumination Imaging as a Diagnostic for Time-Resolved Soot Measurements in Reacting Sprays,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6:1908-1921, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013- 01-2548.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Westlye, F.R., Penney, K., Ivarsson, A., Pickett, L.M. et al., “Diffuse Back-Illumination Setup for High Temporally Resolved Extinction Imaging,” Applied Optics 56(17):5028- 5038, 2017, doi:10.1364/AO.56.005028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Skeen, S., Manin, J., Pickett, L., Dalen, K. et al., “Quantitative Spatially Resolved Measurements of Total Radiation in High-Pressure Spray Flames,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01- 1252, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1252.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Kook, S. and Pickett, L.M., “Soot Volume Fraction and Morphology of Conventional and Surrogate Jet Fuel Sprays at 1000-K and 6.7-MPa Ambient Conditions,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 33:2911-2918, 2011, doi:10.1016/j. proci.2010.05.073.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Pastor, J.V., Javier Lopez, J., Garcia, J.M., and Pastor, J.M., “A 1D Model for the Description of Mixing-Controlled Inert Diesel Sprays,” Fuel 87(13):2871-2885, 2008, doi:10.1016/j. fuel.2008.04.017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Schlatter, S., Schneider, B., Wright, Y.M., and Boulouchos, K., “Comparative Study of Ignition Systems for Lean Burn Gas Engines in an Optically Accessible Rapid Compression Expansion Machine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0112, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Kammermann, T., Koch, J., Wright, Y.M., Soltic, P. et al., “Generation of Turbulence in a RCEM towards Engine Relevant Conditions for Premixed Combustion Based on CFD and PIV Investigations,” SAE Int. J. Engines 10(4), 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-24-0043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Skeen, S.A., Manin, J., and Pickett, L.M., “Simultaneous Formaldehyde PLIF and High-Speed Schlieren Imaging for Ignition Visualization in High-Pressure Spray Flames,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 35:3167-3174, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2014.06.040.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Bardi, M., Payri, R., Malbec, L.M.C., Bruneaux, G. et al., “Engine Combustion Network: Comparison of Spray Development, Vaporization, and Combustion in Different Combustion Vessels,” Atomization and Sprays 22(10):807- 842, 2012, doi:10.1615/AtomizSpr.2013005837.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Pickett, L.M., “Engine Combustion Network,” http://www.sandia.gov/ecn/dieselSprayCombustion.php, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <label>37.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Musculus, M.P.B., “Measurements of the Influence of Soot Radiation on In-Cylinder Temperatures and Exhaust NOx in a Heavy-Duty DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2005- 01-0925, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0925.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <label>38.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Gaydon, A.G., The Spectroscopy of Flames (Dordrecht: Netherlands: Springer, 1974).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <label>39.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Tautschnig, G., Hampel, B., Hirsch, C., and Sattelmayer, T., “Experimental Investigation of OH* and CH* Chemiluminescence under Varying Operating Conditions,” ASME Turbo Expo, Volume 1B: Combustion, Fuels and Emissions, 2013, doi:10.1115/GT2013-95850.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <label>40.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Hwang, W., Dec, J., and Sjoberg, M., “Spectroscopic and Chemical-Kinetic Analysis of the Phases of HCCI Autoignition and Combustion for Single- and Two-Stage Ignition Fuels,” Combustion and Flame 154(3):387-409, 2008, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2008.03.019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <label>41.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Iijima, A. and Shoji, H., “A Study of HCCI Combustion Characteristics Using Spectroscopic Techniques,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1886, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1886.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <label>42.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Musculus, M.P.B., Singh, S., and Reitz, R.D., “Gradient Effects on Two-Color Soot Optical Pyrometry in a Heavy- Duty DI Diesel Engine,” Combustion and Flame 153(1):216- 227, 2008, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2007.10.023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <label>43.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Desantes, J.M., Pastor, J.V., Garcia-Oliver, J.M., and Pastor, J.M., “A 1D Model for the Description of Mixing-Controlled Reacting Diesel Sprays,” Combustion and Flame 156(1):234- 249, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2008.10.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <label>44.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Pastor, J.V., Payri, R., Garcia-Oliver, J.M., and Nerva, J.-G., “Schlieren Measurements of the ECN-Spray a Penetration under Inert and Reacting Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0456, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0456.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <label>45.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Pastor, J.V., Garcia-Oliver, J.M., Pastor, J.M., and Vera- Tudela, W., “One-Dimensional Diesel Spray Modeling of Multicomponent Fuels,” 25(6):485-517, 2015, doi:10.1615/AtomizSpr.2014010370.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <label>46.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Schlichting, H. and Gersten, K., Boundary-Layer Theory (Berlin Heidelberg: Springer, 2016).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <label>47.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Idicheria, C.A. and Pickett, L.M., “Ignition, Soot Formation, and End-of-Combustion Transients in Diesel Combustion under High-EGR Conditions,” International Journal of Engine Research 12(4):376-392, 2011, doi:10.1177/1468087411399505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <label>48.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Musculus, M.P. and Kattke, K., “Entrainment Waves in Diesel Jets,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2:1170-1193, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <label>49.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Saito, H., Sakurai, T., Sakonji, T., Hirashima, T. et al., “Study on Lean Burn Gas Engine Using Pilot Oil as the Ignition Source,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0143, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0143.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <label>50.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Yeo, J., Rochussen, J., and Kirchen, P., “Application of an In-Cylinder Local Infrared Absorption Fuel Concentration Sensor in a Diesel-Ignited Dual-Fuel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-2310, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-2310.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <label>51.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Weissman, M. and Benson, S.W., “Mechanism of Soot Initiation in Methane Systems,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 15(4):273-285, 1989, doi:10.1016/0360- 1285(89)90016-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <label>52.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Sarathy, S.M., Westbrook, C.K., Mehl, M., Pitz, W.J. et al., “Comprehensive Chemical Kinetic Modeling of the Oxidation of 2-Methylalkanes from C7 to C20,” Combustion and Flame 158:2338-2357, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2011.05.007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <label>53.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Kamimoto, T., Uchida, N., Aizawa, T., Kondo, K. et al., “Diesel Flame Imaging and Quantitative Analysis of in- Cylinder Soot Oxidation,” International Journal of Engine Research 18(5-6):422-435, 2016, doi:10.1177/1468087416629282.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <label>54.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Skeen, S.A., Manin, J., Dalen, K., and Pickett, L.M., “Extinction-Based Imaging of Soot Processes over a Range of Diesel Operating Conditions,” 8th US National Combustion Meeting, Park City, Utah, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <label>55.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Lee, D. and Hochgreb, S., “Rapid Compression Machines: Heat Transfer and Suppression of Corner Vortex,” Combustion and Flame 114(3):531-545, 1998, doi:10.1016/S0010-2180(97)00327-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <label>56.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Mederer, T., Wensing, M., and Leipertz, A., “GE2-2 Laser-Induced Fluorescence to Visualize Gas Mixture Formation in an Optically Accessible Hydrogen Engine(GE: Gas Engine, General Session Papers),” The Proceedings of the International Symposium on Diagnostics and Modeling of Combustion in Internal Combustion Engines, 2012, 374-379, doi:10.1299/jmsesdm.2012.8.374.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Sectional view of the RCEM and schematic of the operation principle of the oil-coupled free-floating working and balancing piston. Adapted from [33]. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>RCEM combustion chamber geometry. Dimensions in mm. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>General specifications of the RCEM. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Piston position and in-cylinder pressure trace averaged over 100 nonreactive cycles. 1×σ variability of both traces is demonstrated by the shaded regions. Stroke of an engine running at 1200 rpm is shown with the gray-dashed line. Injection timing is marked with a green line. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Overview of the operating conditions. Values in the middle column relate to trigger pressure threshold of 25 bar (dataset 1, 770-850 K TSOI); conditions in the right column relate to PSOI = 45 bar (dataset 2, 1000 K TSOI). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Optical setup for simultaneous Schlieren and OH* chemiluminescence imaging. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Optical setup for simultaneous DBI imaging and 1D flame spectroscopy acquisition. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>1D-spectroscopy processing approach: Raw and corrected spectrum (sp.) of a sooting combustion (left). The dashed lines represent the Planck fit of the black-body luminosity and the spline fit of the chemiluminescence intensity. Raw and corrected spectrum from a non-sooting combustion event (right). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Ignition delay dependence on the methane equivalence ratio ϕ<sub>CH4</sub>, variation of T<sub>SOI</sub>, and injection duration (error bars, ET = 700 <sub>μs</sub>; crosses, ET = 500 <sub>μs</sub>; circles, ET = 400 <sub>μs</sub>). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Evolution of soot cloud optical thickness for three cases with similar ignition delay: 770 K Φ<sub>CH4</sub> = 0 (upper row), 810 K Φ<sub>CH4</sub> = 0.33 (middle row), and 850 K Φ<sub>CH4</sub> = 0.59 (lower row). Pilot injection: ET = 700 μs, p<sub>inj</sub> = 600 bar. The black-dashed contour shows the boundary of the FoV as well as the ensemble-averaged Schlieren contours. The bottom plot shows the evolution of the total soot quantity in arbitrary units, estimated by integration of the DBI signal across the FoV. The time instant when part of the soot leaves the FoV is indicated with a black-dashed line. No extrapolation of the soot quantity outside the FoV has been attempted. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Evolution of soot cloud optical thickness for variation of the premixed methane equivalence ratio at constant TSOI = 850 K: Φ<sub>CH4</sub> = 0 (upper row), Φ<sub>CH4</sub> = 0.33 (middle row), and Φ<sub>CH4</sub> = 0.59 (lower row). Pilot injection: ET = 700 μs, p<sub>inj</sub> = 600 bar. The black-dashed contour shows the boundary of the FoV as well as the ensemble-averaged Schlieren contours. The bottom plot shows the evolution of the total soot quantity in arbitrary units, estimated by integration of the DBI signal across the FoV. The time instant when part of the soot leaves the FoV is indicated with a black-dashed line. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Temporal evolution of the soot quantity within FoV, at T<sub>SOI</sub> = 850 K, for a variation of the background equivalence ratio for three different injection durations: ET = 400 μs (dotted line, quantity multiplied by 10), ET = 500 μs (dashed line, quantity multiplied by 10), and ET = 700 μs (full line). The range of ignition delays for different ϕ<sub>CH4</sub> and the EOI time instants are marked with arrows. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>1D spray model predicted quantity of the fuel exceeding the threshold equivalence ratio for a variation of injection duration (full line, ϕ = 1.5; dashed line, ϕ = 2; dash-dotted line, ϕ = 2.5). The time instants of the EOI are marked with vertical arrows. Horizontal arrows show the experimentally determined ignition delay range (ϕ<sub>CH4</sub> variation) for different T<sub>SOI</sub>. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Evolution of soot cloud optical thickness for variation of the premixed methane equivalence ratio (T<sub>SOI</sub> = 1000 K): Φ<sub>CH4</sub> = 0 (upper row), Φ<sub>CH4</sub> = 0.33 (middle row), and Φ<sub>CH4</sub> = 0.47 (lower row). Ensemble-averaged Schlieren contours are overlaid (black-dashed line). Pilot injection: ET = 300 μs, p<sub>inj</sub> = 1000 bar. The bottom diagram shows the evolution of the total soot quantity in arbitrary units, estimated by integration of the DBI signal across the visible field. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Temporal evolution of the 1D-resolved line-of-sight T<sub>s-app</sub> along the injector axis for a variation of premixed methane equivalence ratio. Conditions: T<sub>SOI</sub> = 1000 K, ET = 300 μs, and p<sub>inj</sub> = 1000 bar. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Adiabatic flame temperature dependence on pilot fuel equivalence ratio (ϕ<sub>n-C12</sub>) and ϕ<sub>CH4</sub> for T<sub>SOI</sub> = 1000 K conditions. The soot formation range for Diesel fuel (reproduced from [37]) is marked in gray. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Left: Schematic of the two-layer soot cloud model for the estimation of the apparent temperature bias. Right: Model-based approximation of the apparent temperature bias relative to the mass-averaged soot temperature. Upper plot: Bias for a thin soot cloud (layer L1, KL = 0.1; layer L2, KL = 0.3). Lower plot: Bias for a thick soot core (layer L1, KL = 0.1; layer L2, KL = 2). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Temporal evolution of the 1D-resolved line-of-sight T<sub>s_app</sub> along the injector axis for a variation of premixed methane equivalence ratio. Pilot injection: ET = 700 μs, p<sub>inj</sub> = 600 bar. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Dependence of average T<sub>s-app</sub> on T<sub>SOI</sub>, ϕ<sub>CH4</sub>, and injection duration (ET). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Geometry of the test setup for the characterization of the methane distribution in the RCEM prior to compression. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE A.2</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Single-shot mixing evolution for six times after SOI (5 ms, 100 ms, 200 ms, 500 ms, 1500 ms, 4000 ms) normalized to the homogeneous concentration signal. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE A.3</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Average (50 repetitions) distribution of methane 4 s after injection, normalized with a fully homogeneous concentration. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE A.4</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Histogram of detected methane concentrations at a time 4 s after SOI, normalized to fully homogeneous concentration. Red line indicated the standard deviation of the histogram (σ = 0.068). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE B.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Optical and quantum efficiency of the relevant elements in the 1D-spectroscopy optical path. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
