<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466844</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466852</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Regression Discontinuity and the Price Effects of Stock Market Indexing</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Yen-Cheng</given-names>
                  <surname>Chang</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Harrison</given-names>
                  <surname>Hong</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Inessa</given-names>
                  <surname>Liskovich</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>212</fpage>
         <lpage>246</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466852"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The Russell 1000 and 2000 stock indexes comprise the first 1000 and next 2000 largest firms ranked by market capitalization. Small changes in the capitalizations of firms ranked near 1000 move them between these indexes. Because the indexes are value-weighted, more money tracks the largest stocks in the Russell 2000 than the smallest in the Russell 1000. Using this discontinuity, we find that additions to the Russell 2000 result in price increases and deletions result in price declines. We then identify time trends in indexing effects and the types of funds that provide liquidity to indexers.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1624324e266a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624324e273" publication-type="other">
For instance, Denis et al. (2003) find that additions to the S&amp;P 500 are associated with an increase in earnings
forecasts and improvements in realized earnings. Announcements of S&amp;P 500 membership are also widely
covered in the press and might generate investor recognition (see, e.g., Merton 1987) or attention (see, e.g.,
Barber and Odean 2008 or Hirshleifer, Lim, and Teoh 2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624324e289a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624324e296" publication-type="other">
Other such studies include Greenwood (2008), who used the idiosyncratic weighting schemes in the Japanese
stock exchange, and Boyer (2011), who used BARRA definitions of value and growth to establish comovement
of prices of index members. The one exception is Wurgler and Zhuravskaya (2002), who used a difference-in-
difference estimate to compare the addition price effects of S&amp;P 500 stocks with close substitutes to those without
close substitutes. However, these methods do not identify the mean index premium for the average addition.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624324e315a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624324e322" publication-type="other">
Chen, Noronha, and Singal (2004), the study with the largest sample of deletions, find that stocks that get deleted
have no permanent negative price effect. If the observed positive price effect of addition is due to indexing or
benchmarking by institutional investors, one should see a negative price effect for deletion when such demand is
no longer necessary. Instead, this asymmetric price reaction seems more consistent with an investor recognition
effect whereby added stocks get recognized but recognition does not go away with deletion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624324e341a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624324e348" publication-type="other">
Also, in contrast to the S&amp;P 500, where additions are widely covered in the media, index membership in the
Russell 2000 does not receive much attention, thus lessening the concern that addition might also lead to higher
prices because of broader recognition due to media coverage. Consistent with this perspective, we find symmetric
price effects of additions and deletions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624324e365a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624324e372" publication-type="other">
To illustrate the effect of banding on index addition, consider the example of the stock ranked 1210 at the end
of May 2007. This stock was in the Russell 1000 in the year leading up to May 2007. At the end of May its
market capitalization was $1.8 billion while the stock with rank 1000 had a market capitalization of $2.47 billion.
This put the cumulative market capitalization of stock 1210 at 8% of the Russell 3000E while the cumulative
market capitalization of the cutoff stock was 10%. In previous years this stock would have been added to the
Russell 2000. However, the implementation of the banding policy meant that a member of the Russell 1000
could switch to the Russell 2000 only if its cumulative market capitalization was less than 7.5% of the Russell
3000E. Therefore the stock remained in the Russell 1000 for the following year.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624324e401a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624324e408" publication-type="other">
We thank Mark Paris of Russell for his help.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624324e415a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624324e422" publication-type="other">
This report is online at http://www.russell.com/JP/PDF/Index/2008_US_BenchmarkSurvey_E.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624324e429a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624324e436" publication-type="other">
We thank the referee for suggesting the following decomposition.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624324e443a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624324e450" publication-type="other">
Note that we are presenting raw returns. Stocks on either side of the 1000 cutoff in this addition exercise were
Russell 1000 stocks in the prior year whose values fell. These stocks had negative June returns over our sample
period. But just-added stocks received a positive price shock due to indexing, thereby bringing their raw returns
closer to zero.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624324e466a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624324e473" publication-type="other">
Note that we are again presenting raw returns.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624324e481a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624324e488" publication-type="other">
Note that the price elasticity estimates obtained using passive assets will be smaller in absolute value compared
to when we use total benchmarked assets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624324e498a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624324e505" publication-type="other">
For example, Barberis, Shleifer, and Wurgler (2005) find stocks added to the S&amp;P 500 have extra comovement
of 0.214. Using BARRA value/growth swithers, Boyer (2011) shows extra comovement can be as high as 0.485.
Greenwood (2008) uses Nikkei 225 overweightings and estimates this measure to be 0.22.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1624324e518a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1624324e525" publication-type="other">
In the Internet Appendix, we compare the fund performance of indexers and liquidity providers and find evidence
consistent with indexers under-performing liquidity providers in the month of the Russell 2000 reconstitution.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1624324e544a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e548" publication-type="other">
Barber, B. M., and T. Odean. 2008. All that glitters: The effect of attention and news on the buying behavior of
individual and institutional investors. Reivew of Financial Studies 21:785-818.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e558a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e562" publication-type="other">
Barberis, N., A. Shleifer, and J. Wurgler. 2005. Comovement. Journal of Financial Economics 75:283-317.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e569a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e573" publication-type="other">
Basak, S., and A. Pavlova. 2013. Asset prices and institutional investors. American Economic Review
103:1728-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e583a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e587" publication-type="other">
Beneish, M. D., and R. E. Whaley. 1996. An anatomy of the 'S&amp;P game': The effects of changing the rules.
Journal of Finance 51:1909-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e598a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e602" publication-type="other">
Boyer, B. H. 2011. Style-related comovement: Fundamentals or labels? Journal of Finance 66:307-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e609a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e613" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., S. J. Grossman, and J. Wang. 1993. Trading volume and serial correlation in stock returns.
Quarterly Journal of Finance 108:905-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e623a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e627" publication-type="other">
Chen, H., G Noronha, and V. Singal. 2004. The price response to S&amp;P 500 index additions and deletions:
Evidence of asymmetry and a new explanation. Journal of Finance 59:1901-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e637a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e641" publication-type="other">
Chen, H.-L. 2006. On Russell index reconstitution. Review of Quantitative Finance and Accounting
26:409-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e651a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e655" publication-type="other">
Chen, J., H. Hong, M. Huang, and J. Kubik. 2004. Does fund size erode mutual fund performance? The role of
liquidity and organization. American Economic Review 94:1276-1302.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e665a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e669" publication-type="other">
Daniel, K., D. Hirshleifer, and A. Subrahmanyam. 1998. Investor psychology and security market under- and
overreactions. Journal of Finance 53:1839-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e680a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e684" publication-type="other">
Denis, D. K., J. J. McConnell, A. V. Ovtchinnikov, and Y. Yu. 2003. S&amp;P 500 index additions and earnings
expectations. Journal of Finance 58:1821-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e694a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e698" publication-type="other">
Gao, X., and J. R. Ritter. 2010. The marketing of seasoned equity offerings. Journal of Financial Economics
97:33-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e708a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e712" publication-type="other">
Gervais, S., and T. Odean. 2001. Learning to be overconfident. Review of Financial Studies 14:1-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e719a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e723" publication-type="other">
Green, T. C., and R. Jame. 2011. Strategic trading by index funds and liquidity provision around S&amp;P 500 index
additions. Journal of Financial Markets 14:605-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e733a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e737" publication-type="other">
Greenwood, R. 2008 Excess comovement of stock returns: Evidence from cross-sectional variation in Nikkei
225 weights. Review of Financial Studies 21:1153-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e747a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e751" publication-type="other">
Grossman, S. J., and M. H. Miller. 1988. Liquidity and market structure. Journal of Finance 43:617-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e759a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e763" publication-type="other">
Hahn, J., P. Todd, and W. van der Klaauw. 2001. Identification and estimation of treatment effects with a
regression-discontinuity design. Econometrica 69:201-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e773a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e777" publication-type="other">
Hanson, S. G, and A. Sunderam. 2014. The growth and limits to arbitrage: Evidence from short interest. Review
of Financial Studies 27:1238-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e787a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e791" publication-type="other">
Harris, L. E., and E. Gurel. 1986. Price and volume effects associated with changes in the S&amp;P 500 list: New
evidence for the existence of price pressures. Journal of Finance 41:815-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e801a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e805" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, D., S. S. Lim, and S. H. Teoh. 2009. Driven to distraction: Extraneous events and underreaction to
earnings news. Journal of Finance 64:2289-2325.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e815a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e819" publication-type="other">
Kaul, A., V. Mehrotra, and R. Morck. 2000. Demand curves for stocks do slope down: New evidence from an
index weights adjustment. Journal of Finance 55:893-912.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e829a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e833" publication-type="other">
Lee, D. S., and T. Lemieux. 2010. Regression discontinuity designs in economics. Journal of Economic Literature
48:281-355.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e844a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e848" publication-type="other">
Lynch, A. W., and R. R. Mendenhall. 1997. New evidence on stock price effects associated with changes in the
S&amp;P 500 index. Journal of Business 70:351-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e858a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e862" publication-type="other">
Madhavan, A. 2003. The Russell reconstitution effect. Financial Analysts Journal 59:51-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e869a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e873" publication-type="other">
McCrary, J. 2008. Manipulation of the running variable in the regression discontinuity design: A density test.
Journal of Econometrics 142:698-714.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e883a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e887" publication-type="other">
Merton, R. C. 1987. A simple model of capital market equilibrium with incomplete information. Journal of
Finance 42:483-510.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e897a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e901" publication-type="other">
Morck, R., and F. Yang. 2002. The mysterious growing value of S&amp;P 500 membership. Working Paper, University
of Alberta.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e911a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e915" publication-type="other">
Petajisto, A. 2011. The index premium and its hidden cost for index funds. Journal of Empirical Finance
18:271-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e926a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e930" publication-type="other">
Shleifer, A. 1986. Do demand curves for stocks slope down? Journal of Finance 41:579-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e937a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e941" publication-type="other">
Vayanos, D., and P. Woolley, 2011. Fund flows and asset prices: A baseline model. FMG Discussion Papers
dp667, Financial Markets Group.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e951a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e955" publication-type="other">
Weimers, R. 2000. Mutual fund performance: An empirical decomposition into stock-picking talent, style,
transaction costs, and expenses. Journal of Finance 55:1655-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e965a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e969" publication-type="other">
Wurgler, J. 2011. One the economic consequences of index-linked investing. In G Rosenfeld, J. W. Lorsch, and
R. Khurana, eds., Challenges to Business in the Twenty-First Century: The Way Forward. American Academy of
Arts and Sciences.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1624324e982a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1624324e986" publication-type="other">
Wurgler, J., and E. Zhuravskaya. 2002. Does arbitrage flatten demand curves for stocks? Journal of Business
75:583-608.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


