<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278232</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Study of High Speed Gasoline Direct Injection Compression Ignition (GDICI) Engine Operation in the LTC Regime</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ra</surname>
                  <given-names>Youngchul</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Wisconsin</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Loeper</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Wisconsin - Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Rolf</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Wisconsin</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andrie</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Wisconsin</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Krieger</surname>
                  <given-names>Roger</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Wisconsin - Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Foster</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Wisconsin</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Durrett</surname>
                  <given-names>Russ</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors LLC</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gopalakrishnan</surname>
                  <given-names>Venkatesh</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors LLC</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Plazas</surname>
                  <given-names>Alejandro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors LLC</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Peterson</surname>
                  <given-names>Richard</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors LLC</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Szymkowicz</surname>
                  <given-names>Patrick</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors LLC</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1412</fpage>
         <lpage>1430</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278232"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>An investigation of high speed direct injection (DI) compression ignition (CI) engine combustion fueled with gasoline (termed GDICI for Gasoline Direct-Injection Compression Ignition) in the low temperature combustion (LTC) regime is presented. As an aid to plan engine experiments at full load (16 bar IMEP, 2500 rev/min), exploration of operating conditions was first performed numerically employing a multi-dimensional CFD code, KIVA-ERC-Chemkin, that features improved sub-models and the Chemkin library. The oxidation chemistry of the fuel was calculated using a reduced mechanism for primary reference fuel combustion. Operation ranges of a light-duty diesel engine operating with GDICI combustion with constraints of combustion efficiency, noise level (pressure rise rate) and emissions were identified as functions of injection timings, exhaust gas recirculation rate and the fuel split ratio of double-pulse injections. Parametric variation of the operation ranges was also investigated with respect to initial gas temperature, boost pressure and injection pressure. Following the modeling, experiments were performed under the conditions suggested by the numerical results in order to confirm the feasibility of GDICI operation at full load, as well as to validate the numerical simulations.</p>
            <p>The results showed good agreement between the experiments and the model predictions. Due to the high volatility and low cetane index of gasoline combined with reduction of combustion temperature through utilization of EGR, both PM and NOx emissions could be reduced to levels of about 0.1 g/kg-f while maintaining experimental gross ISFC at about 180 g/kw-hr. The numerical simulations helped to explain the in-cylinder spray combustion behavior and to identify characteristics of GDICI that differ from those of diesel-fueled operation. Maps of operable conditions were generated that allow extension of low-emission engine concepts to full load operation in high speed GDICI engine operation with fuel efficiencies comparable to those of corresponding diesel fuel operation while meeting emissions mandates in-cylinder.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iwabuchi, Y., Kawai, K., Shoji, T., and Takeda, Y., “Trial of New Concept Diesel Combustion System: Premixed Compression-Ignited Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0185, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0185.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kanda, T., Hakozaki, T., Uchimoto, T., Hatano, J., Kitayama, N., and Sono, H., “PCCI Operation with Early Injection of Conventional Diesel Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0378, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0378.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Opat, R., Ra, Y., Gonzalez, M.A., Krieger, R.B., Reitz, R.D., Foster, D.E., Durrett, R.P., and Siewert, R.M., “Investigation of Mixing and Temperature Effects on HC/CO Emissions for Highly Dilute Low Temperature Combustion in a Light Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0193, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krieger, R.B., Siewert, R.M., Pinson, J.A., Gallopoulos, N.A., et al., “Diesel Engines: One Option to Power Future Personal Transportation Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 972683, 1997, doi: 10.4271/972683.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Ogawa, H., Muranaka, S., and Enomoto, Y., “New Combustion Concept for Ultra-Clean and High-Efficiency Small DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3681, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3681.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Kitahara, Y. and Aiyoshizawa, E., “Ultra-Clean Combustion Technology Combining a Low- Temperature and Premixed Combustion Concept for Meeting Future Emission Standards,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0200, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Ogawa, H., Matsui, Y., and Enomoto, Y., “An experimental analysis of low temperature and premixed combustion for simultaneous reduction of of NOx and particulate emissions in DI diesel engines,” Int. J. Engine Research, 3, 249-259, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hashizume, T., Miyamoto, T., Akagawa, H., and Tsujimura, K., “Combustion and Emission Characteristics of Multiple Stage Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 980505, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neely, G.D., Sasaki, S., Huang, Y., Leet, J.A. and Stewart, D.W., “New Diesel Emission Control Strategy to Meet US Tier 2 Emissions Regulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1091, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1091.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shimazaki, N., Tsurushima, T. and Nishimura, T., “Dual Mode Combustion Concept with Premixed Diesel Combustion by Direct Injection Near Top Dead Center,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0742, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-0742.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Risberg, P., Kalghatgi, G. and Ångström, H-E, and Wåhlin, F., “Auto-Ignition Quality of Diesel-Like Fuels in HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2127, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2127.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G.T., “Auto-Ignition Quality of Practical Fuels and Implications for Fuel Requirements of Future SI and HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0239, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G. T., Risberg, P., and Ångström, H-E., “Advantages of Fuels with High Resistance to Auto-Ignition in Late-Injection, Low-Temperature, Compression Ignition Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3385, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3385.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G. T., Risberg, P., and Ångström, H-E., “Partially Pre-Mixed Auto-Ignition of Gasoline to Attain Low Smoke and Low NOx at High Load in a Compression Ignition Engine and Comparison with a Diesel Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0006, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weall, A.J. and Collings, N., “Investigation into Partially Premixed Combustion in a Light Duty Multi-Cylinder Diesel Engine Fuelled with a Mixture of Gasoline and Diesel,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4058, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-4058.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hildingsson, L., Kalghatgi, G., Tait, N., Johansson, B. and Harrison, A., “Fuel Octane Effects in the Partially Premixed Combustion Regime in Compression Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2648, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-2648.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra, Y., Yun, J. E., and Reitz, R.D. “Numerical simulation of diesel and gasoline-fueled compression ignition combustion with high pressure late direct injection,” Int. J. Vehicle Design, Vol. 50, Nos. 1/2/3/4. pp. 3-34, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra, Y., Yun, J.E., and Reitz, R.D., Numerical Parametric Study of Diesel Engine Operation with Gasoline, Combust. Sci. and Tech., 181: 350-378, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden, A.A., “KIVA-3V, Release 2, Improvements to KIVA-3V,” LA-UR-99-915, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kee, R.J., Rupley, F.M., Miller, J.A., “CHEMKIN-II: A FORTRAN Chemical Kinetics Package for the Analysis of Gas Phase Chemical Kinetics,” Sandia Report SAND 89-8009, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beale, J.C., and Reitz, R.D., “Modeling Spray Atomization with the Kelvin-Helmholtz/Rayleigh-Taylor Hybrid Model. Atomization and Sprays, 9, 623-650, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, A.B., Mather, D., and Reitz, R.D. “Modeling the Effects of Drop Drag and Breakup on Fuel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 930072, 1993, doi: 10.4271/930072.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra, Y., and Reitz, R.D., “A vaporization model for discrete multi-component fuel sprays,” Int. J. Multiphase Flow 35, 101-117, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Rourke, P.J., and Amsden, A.A. “A Particle Numerical Model for Wall Film Dynamics in Port-Injected Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 961961, 1996, doi: 10.4271/961961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z., and Reitz, R.D., “Turbulence Modeling of Internal Combustion Engines Using RNG k-e models,” Comb. Sci. Tech., 106, 267-295, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra, Y., and Reitz, R.D., “A Reduced Chemical Kinetic Model for IC Engine Combustion Simulations with Primary Reference Fuels,” Combustion and Flame, 155, 713-738, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hessel, R. P., Foster, D. E., Aceves, S. M., Davisson, M. L., Espinosa-Loza, F., Flowers, D. L., Pitz, W. J., Dec, J. E., Sjöberg, M., and Babajimopoulos, A. “Modeling Iso-octane HCCI using CFD with Multi-Zone Detailed Chemistry; Comparison to Detailed Speciation Data over a Range of Lean Equivalence Ratios,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0047, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Genzale, C. L., Reitz, R. D., and Musculus, M. P. B., “Measurements of Mixture Effects on Late-Injection Low- Temperature Diesel Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):913-937, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-1330.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fieweger, K., Blumenthal, R., and Adomeit, G., “Serf- Ignition of S.I. Engine Model Fuels: A Shock Tube Investigation at High Pressure,” Combustion and Flame, 109, 599-619, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H. and Kadota, T., “Models for Combustion and Formation of Nitric Oxide and Soot in DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 760129, 1976, doi: 10.4271/760129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koci, C.P., Ra, Y., Krieger, R., Andrie, M., et al., “Detailed Unburned Hydrocarbon Investigations in a Highly Dilute Diesel Low Temperature Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):858-879, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0928.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Private communication with Russell Durrett, August, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A.B., and Reitz, R.D., “Computational Optimization of a Heavy-Duty Compression Ignition Engine Fueled with Conventional Gasoline” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1): 352-373, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
