<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277628</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Impact of Spark Discharge Pattern on Flame Initiation in a Turbulent Lean and Dilute Mixture in a Pressurized Combustion Vessel</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
                  <given-names>Anqi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan Technological Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cung</surname>
                  <given-names>Khanh</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan Technological Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lee</surname>
                  <given-names>Seong-Young</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan Technological Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Naber</surname>
                  <given-names>Jeffrey</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan Technological Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Huberts</surname>
                  <given-names>Garlan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Co</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Czekala</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Co</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Qu</surname>
                  <given-names>Qiuping</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Co</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277593</issue-id>
         <fpage>435</fpage>
         <lpage>446</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277628"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>An operational scheme with fuel-lean and exhaust gas dilution in spark ignited engines increases thermal efficiency and decreases NOx emission, while these operations inherently induce combustion instability and thus large cycle-to-cycle variation in engine. In order to stabilize combustion variations, the development of an advanced ignition system is becoming critical. To quantify the impact of spark-ignition discharge, ignitability tests were conducted in an optically accessible combustion vessel to characterize the flame kernel development of lean methane-air mixture with CO₂ simulating exhaust diluent. A shrouded fan was used to generate turbulence in the vicinity of J-gap spark plug and a Variable Output Ignition System (VOIS) capable of producing a varied set of spark discharge patterns was developed and used as an ignition source. The main feature of the VOIS is to vary the secondary current during glow discharge including naturally decaying and truncated with multiple strikes. These discharge patterns were studied to characterize the interaction of discharge phases and initial flame formation. High-speed schlieren optical setup was employed for visualization with synchronous measurement of discharge waveforms. The results showed that multi-strike discharge was able to generate multiple flame kernels whose interactions affect flame initiation. With proper timing of each discharge event the individual kernels merge and lead to propagating flame. However, this flame initiation is highly subjected to the flow field in the vicinity of spark plug. Based on these observations, a mathematical description of the discharge timing requirements is formulated to describe the multi-kernel flame initiation under turbulence.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">World Vehicle Population Tops 1 Billion Units. Available from: http://wardsauto.com/ar/world_vehicle_population_110815.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sperling, D. and Gordon, D., Two billion cars: driving toward sustainability 2009: Oxford University Press, USA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, JB, Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals 1988: McGraw-Hill, New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kutlar, O.A., Arslan, H., and Calik, A.T., “Methods to improve efficiency of four stroke, spark ignition engines at part load,” Energy conversion and management, 2005. 46(20): p. 3202-3220.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alger, T., Gingrich, J., Mangold, B., and Roberts, C., “A Continuous Discharge Ignition System for EGR Limit Extension in SI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):677-692, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0661.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Czekala, M., Johnston, B., Morganti, C., and McRoy, G., “Matching Ignition System Multi-Spark Calibration to the Burn-Rate of an Engine to Extend Ignitability Limits,” SAE Technical Paper 981046, 1998, doi: 10.4271/981046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Drake, MC and Haworth, DC, “Advanced gasoline engine development using optical diagnostics and numerical modeling,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 2007. 31(1): p. 99-124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maly, R.R. and Herweg, R., Spark Ignition and Combustion in Four- Stroke Gasoline Engines, in Flow and Combustion in Reciprocating Engines 2009. p. 1-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pancheshnyi, S.V., Lacoste, D.A., Bourdon, A., and Laux, C.O., “Ignition of propane-air mixtures by a repetitively pulsed nanosecond discharge,” Plasma Science, IEEE Transactions on, 2006. 34(6): p. 2478-2487.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanoue, K., Kuboyama, T., Moriyoshi, Y., Hotta, E. et al., “Extension of Lean and Diluted Combustion Stability Limits by Using Repetitive Pulse Discharges,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0173, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010- 01-0173.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eichenberger, DA and Roberts, WL, “Effect of unsteady stretch on spark-ignited flame kernel survival,” Combustion and flame, 1999. 118(3): p. 469-478.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xiong, Y., Roberts, WL, Drake, MC, and Fansler, TD, “Investigation of pre-mixed flame-kernel/vortex interactions via high-speed imaging,” Combustion and flame, 2001. 126(4): p. 1827-1844.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ko, Y., Anderson, RW, and Arpaci, V.S., “Spark ignition of propane-air mixtures near the minimum ignition energy: Part I. An experimental study,” Combustion and flame, 1991. 83(1): p. 75-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, W., Madison, D., Dice, P., Naber, J. et al., “Impact of Ignition Energy Phasing and Spark Gap on Combustion in a Homogenous Direct Injection Gasoline SI Engine near the EGR Limit,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1630, 2013, doi: 10.4271/2013-01-1630.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
