<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000476</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40009035</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Target-Text Mediated Interactive Machine Translation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>George</given-names>
                  <surname>Foster</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Pierre</given-names>
                  <surname>Isabelle</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Pierre</given-names>
                  <surname>Plamondon</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1997</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>175</fpage>
         <lpage>194</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1997 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40009035"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>The use of Machine Translation as a tool for professional or other highly skilled translators is for the most part currently limited to postediting arrangements in which the translator invokes MT when desired and then manually cleans up the results. A theoretically promising but hitherto largely unsuccessful alternative to postediting for this application is interactive machine translation (IMT), in which the translator and MT system work in tandem. We argue that past failures to make IMT viable as a tool for skilled translators have been the result of an infelicitous mode of interaction rather than any inherent flaw in the idea. As a solution, we propose a new style of IMT in which the target text under construction serves as the medium of communication between an MT system and its user. We describe the design, implementation, and performance of an automatic word completion system for translators which is intended to demonstrate the feasibility of the proposed approach, albeit in a very rudimentary form.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>Machine-Assisted Human Translation</kwd>
            <kwd>interactive MT</kwd>
            <kwd>target-text mediation</kwd>
            <kwd>word completion</kwd>
            <kwd>statistical translation models</kwd>
            <kwd>statistical language models</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>Notes</title>
            <ref id="d3301918e242a1310">
               <label>6</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e249" publication-type="other">
A similar phenomenon is reported in Brousseau et al. (1995).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d3301918e265a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e269" publication-type="other">
Blanchon, Hervé.: 1994, Perspectives of DBMT for Monolingual Authors on the Basis of LIDIA-1,
an Implemented Mock-up, in COLING-94: The 15th International Conference on Computational
Linguistics, Kyoto, pp. 115-119.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e282a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e286" publication-type="other">
Boitet, Christian.: 1990, Towards Personal MT: General Design, Dialogue Structure, Potential Role of
Speech, in COLING-90: Papers presented to the 13th International Conference on Computational
Linguistics, Helsinki, Vol. 3, pp. 30-35.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e299a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e303" publication-type="other">
Brousseau, J., C. Drouin, G. Foster, P. Isabelle, R. Kuhn, Y. Normandin, and P. Plamondon: 1995,
French Speech Recognition in an Automatic Dictation System for Translators: the TransTalk
Project, in Eurospeech 95, Madrid, pp. 193-196.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e316a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e320" publication-type="other">
Brown, Peter F., Stephen A. Delia Pietra, Vincent J. Delia Pietra, and Robert L. Mercer: 1993, The
Mathematics of Statistical Machine Translation: Parameter Estimation, Computational Linguis-
tics 19: 263-312.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e334a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e338" publication-type="other">
Brown, Ralf D. and Sergei Nirenburg: 1990, Human-Computer Interaction for Semantic Disambigua-
tion, in COLING-90: Papers presented to the 13th International Conference on Computational
Linguistics, Helsinki, Vol. 3, pp. 42-47.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e351a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e355" publication-type="other">
Darragh, John J. and Ian H. Witten: 1992, The Reactive Keyboard. Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e362a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e366" publication-type="other">
Derouault, A.-M. and B. Merialdo: 1986, Natural Language Modeling for Phoneme-to-text Tran-
scription, IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, PAMI-8: 742-743.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e376a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e380" publication-type="other">
Eurolang: 1995, Eurolang Optimizer, Product Description.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e387a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e391" publication-type="other">
Frederking, Robert, Dean Grannes, Peter Cousseau, and Sergei Nirenburg: 1993, An MAT Tool and
its Effectiveness, in Human Language Technology, Princeton, NJ, pp. 196-201.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e401a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e405" publication-type="other">
IBM: 1995, IBM Translation Manager, Product Description.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e413a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e417" publication-type="other">
Jelinek, F.: 1990, Self-organized Language Modeling for Speech Recognition, in A. Waibel and
K. Lee (eds) Readings in Speech Recognition, Morgan Kaufmann: San Mateo, California, pp.
450-506.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e430a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e434" publication-type="other">
Katz, Slava M.: 1987, Estimation of Probabilities from Sparse Data for the Language Model Com-
ponent of a Speech Recognizer, IEEE Transactions on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing,
ASSP-35: 400-401.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e447a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e451" publication-type="other">
Kay, Martin: 1973, The Mind System, in R. Rustin (ed.) Natural Language Processing, Algorithmics
Press, NY, pp. 155-188.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e461a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e465" publication-type="other">
Kugler, M., G. Heyer, R. Kese, B. von Kleist-Retzow, and G. Winkelmann: 1991, The Translator's
Workbench: An Environment for Multi-Lingual Text Processing and Translation, in Proceedings
of Machine Translation Summit III. Washington, D.C. pp. 81-83.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e478a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e482" publication-type="other">
Kuhn, Roland and Renato De Mori: 1990, A Cache-based Natural Language Model for Speech
Recognition, IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence 12: 570-583.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e492a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e496" publication-type="other">
Maruyama, Hiroshi and Hideo Watanabe: 1990, An Interactive Japanese Parser for Machine Trans-
lation, in COLING-90: Papers presented to the 13th International Conference on Computational
Linguistics, Helsinki, Vol. 2, pp. 257-262.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e510a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e514" publication-type="other">
Melby, Alan: 1987, On Human-machine Interaction in Translation, in Sergei Nirenburg (ed.) Machine
Translation, Theoretical and Methodological Issues. Cambridge University Press, pp. 145-154.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e524a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e528" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, Sergei: 1992, Tools for Machine-Aided Translation: The CMU TWS, Meta 37: 709-720.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e535a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e539" publication-type="other">
Picchi, Eugenio, Carol Peters, and Elisabetta Marinai: 1992, A Translator's Workstation, in Pro-
ceedings of the Fifteenth International Conference on Computational Linguistics COLING-92,
Nantes, pp. 972-976.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e552a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e556" publication-type="other">
Simard, Michel, George F. Foster, and Pierre Isabelle: 1992, Using Cognates to Align Sentences in
Bilingual Corpora, in Fourth International Conference on Theoretical and Methodological Issues
in Machine Translation: TMI-92, Montreal, Canada, pp. 67-81.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e569a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e573" publication-type="other">
Tomita, Masaru: 1985, Feasibility Study of Personal/Interactive Machine Translation Systems, in
Proceedings of the Conference on Theoretical and Methodological Issues in Machine Translation
of Natural Languages, Colgate University, Hamilton, NY, pp. 289-297.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e586a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e590" publication-type="other">
Trados: 1995, Trados Translators Workbench, Product Description.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e598a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e602" publication-type="other">
Whitelock, P. J., M. McGee Wood, B. J. Chandler, N. Holden, and H. J. Horsfall: 1986, Strate-
gies for Interactive Machine Translation: The Experience and Implications of the UMIST
Japanese Project, in 11th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Proceedings of
COLING'86, Bonn, pp. 329-334.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e618a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e622" publication-type="other">
Zajac, Rémi: 1988, Interactive Translation: A New Approach, in COLING-Budapest: Proceedings of
the 12th International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Budapest, pp. 785-790.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3301918e632a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3301918e636" publication-type="other">
Zipf, G. K.: 1949, Human Behavior and the Principle of Least Effort. Addison-Wesley: Reading,
MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
