<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308378</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effect of New Cooling System in a Diesel Engine on Engine Performance and Emission Characteristics</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Choi</surname>
                  <given-names>Kyung-Wook</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kim</surname>
                  <given-names>Ki-Bum</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lee</surname>
                  <given-names>Ki-Hyung</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Hanyang University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>77</fpage>
         <lpage>82</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308378"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Automotive manufacturers and engineers have paid attention to promoting engine performance with low emissions satisfying many emission regulations. With such goals in mind, we have investigated new cooling strategies such as high coolant temperature control, fast warm-up and post cooling using an automotive cooling system controlled by electronic actuators. The cooling system in a 2.7 liter HSDI engine was modified for the purpose of this study, and an engine experiment was carried out on a New European Drive Cycle (NEDC). The conventional water pump was decoupled from the engine and electronically controlled by a BLDC motor. Valves were installed at the coolant pathways between the engine and cooling components. Overall, this modification led to a reduction in both fuel consumption and exhaust gas emissions (e.g. THC, CO). The reduction was particularly considerable at the low speed and low load-drive conditions by controlling high temperature of the coolant. In addition, independent operation of the water pump along with the coolant flow control using valves reduced warm-up time during cold start which contributed to a decrease in harmful emissions and fuel consumption.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">John B. Heywood, “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, McGraw-Hill International Editions.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. Revereault, B. Gessier, M. Chanfreau, 2003, “Intelligent vehicle system thermal management in a mild hybrid-diesel vehicle”, IMechE 2003, pp.545~560.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Chanfreau, A. Joseph, D. Butler, R. Swiatek, 2001,“Advanced Engine Cooling Thermal Management System on a Dual Voltage 42V-14V Minivan”, VTMS5 SAE 2001-01-1742</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">John R. Wagner, Venkat Srinivasan, Darren M. Dawson, 2003, “Smart Thermostat and Coolant Pump Control for Engine Thermal Management Systems”, SAE technical paper 2003-01-0272</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Franz W. Koch, Frank G. Haubner, 2000, “Cooling system Development and Optimization for DI Engines”, SAE 2000-01-0283</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ngy-Srun Ap, Philippe Jouanny, Michel Potier, Jerome Genoist, 2005, “UltimateCooling System for New Generation of Vehicle”, SAE 2005-01-2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allen, D.J., Lasecki, M.P., “Thermal Management Evolution and Controlled Coolant Flow,” SAE Paper 2001-01-1732, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cortona, E., Onder, C.H., Guzzella, L., “Engine Thermomanagement with Electrical Components for Fuel Consumption Reduction”, International Journal of Engine Research, Vol. 3 No. 3, September 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner, J.R., Srinivasan, V., Dawson, D.M.,”Smart Thermostat and Coolant Pump Control for Engine Thermal Management Systems”, SAE Paper 2003- 01-0272, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chalgren, R.D., “Development and Verification of a Heavy Duty 42/14V Electric Powertrain Cooling System,” SAE Paper 2003-01-3416.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robert D. Chalgren Jr., “Thermal Comfort and Engine Warm-Up Optimization of a Low-Flow Advanced Thermal Management System”, SAE Paper 2004-01-0047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N-S AP, P. Guerrero, P. Jouanny, M. Potier, J. Genoist, J. L.Thuez., “UltimateCooling new cooling system concept using the same coolant to cool all vehicle fluids”, IMechE 2003 p.661~p.674</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sebastien Potteau, Philippe Lutz, Samuel Leroux, Stephanie Moroz, Eva Tomas, 2007, “Cooled EGR for Turbo SI Engine to Reduce Knocking and Fuel Consumption”, Powertrain &amp; Fluid Systems Conference &amp; Exhibition, SAE 2007-01-3978</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krüger, U., Edwards, S., Pantow, E., Lutz, R., et al., “High Performance Cooling and EGR Systems as a Contribution to Meeting Future Emission Standards”, SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):756-769, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. REVEREAULT, B. GESSIER, M. CHANFREAU, 2003, “Intelligent vehicle system thermal management in a mild hybrid – diesel vehicle”, IMechE, C599/059/2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
