<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422546</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Particle Number Reduction in Automotive Exhausts Using Acoustic Metamaterials</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
                  <given-names>Zhe</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>KTH-Royal Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Abom</surname>
                  <given-names>Mats</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>KTH-Royal Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Boden</surname>
                  <given-names>Hans</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>KTH-Royal Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Karlsson</surname>
                  <given-names>Mikael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>KTH-Royal Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Katoshevski</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ben Gurion University of the Negev</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>October 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422530</issue-id>
         <fpage>1566</fpage>
         <lpage>1572</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422546"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Air pollution caused by exhaust particulate matter (PM) from vehicular traffic is a major health issue. Increasingly strict regulations of vehicle emission have been introduced and efforts have been put on both the suppression of particulate formation inside the engine cylinders and the development of after-treatment technologies such as filters. With modern direct injected engines that produce a large number of really small sub-micron particles, the focus has increased even further and now also includes a number count.</p>
            <p>The problem of calculating particle trajectories in flow ducts like vehicle exhaust systems is challenging but important to further improve the technology. The interaction between particles and oscillating flows may lead to the formation of particle groups (regions where the particle concentration is increased), yielding a possibility of realizing particle agglomeration. The oscillating flow may simply be hydrodynamic or as assumed here: the flow oscillations are created by sound propagation rather than hydrodynamic approaches. An analysis is presented which gives the relationship between the speed of sound, the mean flow velocity and the amplitude of the acoustic particle velocity for particle agglomeration to be feasible. It is shown that it can be achieved if the convective speed of sound is reduced to the same order as the mean flow velocity. It is therefore suggested to use the so-called acoustic metamaterials, which can help control, direct and manipulate sound waves. At this stage a phenomenological 1D model is used for the analysis, which allows the authors to build an understanding of the effect of the sound waves and flow oscillations on particle motion and paves the way for further analysis on particle agglomeration.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Katoshevski David, Ruzal Michal, Shakked Tal, Sher Eran, “Particle grouping, a new method for reducing emission of submicron particles from diesel engines,” Fuel 89: 2411-2416, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruzal-Mendelevich Michal, Katoshevski David, Sher Eran, “Controlling nanoparticles emission with particle-grouping exhaust-pipe,” Fuel 166: 116-123, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Purchas Derek, Surtherland Ken, “Handbook of filter media (2nd edition),” Elsevier Science, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittleson David, “Engines and nanoparticles: a review,” Journal of Aerosol Science 29 (5-6): 575-588, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Katoshevski David, Shakked Tal, “Particle grouping in standing and moving wave velocity fields,” Int. J. Engineering Systems Modelling and Simulation 2 (3): 177-182, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Katoshevski David, Shakked Tal, Sazhin Sergei S., Crua Cyril, Heikal Morgan R. “Grouping and trapping of evaporating droplets in an oscillating gas flow,” International Journal of Heat and Fluid Flow 29: 415-426, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Townsend R.J., Hill M., Harris N.R., White N.M., “Modelling of particle paths passing through an ultrasonic standing wave,” Ultrasonics 42: 319-324, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sazhin Sergei, Shakked Tal, Sobolev Vladimir, Katoshevski David, “Particle grouping in oscillating flows,” European Journal of Mechanics B/Fluids 27: 131-149, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang G., Wen X., Wen J. H., Shao L. H. and Liu Y. Z., “Two-dimensional locally resonant phononic crystals with binary structures,” Physical Review Letters 93 (15): 154302, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farooqui M., Elnady T. and Akl W., “Low frequency noise attenuation inside ducts using locally resonant periodic flush mounted steel patches,” Proceedings of EuroNoise 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu Z. Y., Zhang X. X., Mao Y. W., Zhu Y. Y., Yang Z. Y., Chan C. T., Sheng P., “Locally resonant sonic materials,” Science 289: 1734-1736, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee S. H., Park C. M., Seo Y. M., Wang Z. G., Kima C. K., “Acoustic metamaterial with negative density,”Physics Letters A 373: 4464-4469, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Katoshevski, D., Dodin, Z., Zinkind, G., “Aerosol clustering in oscillating flows: mathematical analysis,” Atomization and Sprays 15: 401-412, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang Zhe, Åbom Mats, Bodén Hans, “Acoustic Metamaterials seen from the perspective of Duct Acoustics,” Baltic Nordic Acoustic Meeting 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee Sam Hyeon, Park Choon Mahn, Seo Yong Mun, Wang Zhi Guo, Kim Chul Koo, “Acoustic metamaterial with negative density,” Physics Letters A 373: 4464-4469, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fang Nicholas, Xi Dongjuan, Xu Jianyi, Mbati Muralidhar, Srituravanich Werayut, Sun Cheng and Zhang Xiang, “Ultrasonic metamaterials with negative modulus,” Nature Materials 5: 452-456, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fokin V., Ambati M., Sun C. and Zhang X., “Method for Retrieving Effective Properties of Locally Resonant Acoustic Metamaterials,” Physical Review B 76: 144302, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boden, H., "IC-Engine Exhaust and Intake System Acoustic Source Characterization," SAE Int. J. Engines 7(3):1579-1584, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2061.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
