<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3/4</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000477</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40009042</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Acquisition of Large Lexicons for Practical Knowledge-Based MT</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Deryle</given-names>
                  <surname>Lonsdale</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Teruko</given-names>
                  <surname>Mitamura</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Eric</given-names>
                  <surname>Nyberg</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1994</year>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1995</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>251</fpage>
         <lpage>283</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1994 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40009042"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>Although knowledge-based MT systems have the potential to achieve high translation accuracy, each successful application system requires a large amount of hand-coded lexical knowledge. Systems like KBMT-89 and its descendents have demonstrated how knowledge-based translation can produce good results in technical domains with tractable domain semantics. Nevertheless, the magnitude of the development task for large-scale applications with tens of thousands of domain concepts precludes a purely hand-crafted approach. The current challenge for the "next generation" of knowledge-based MT systems is to utilize on-line textual resources and corpus analysis software in order to automate the most laborious aspects of the knowledge acquisition process. This partial automation can in turn maximize the productivity of human knowledge engineers and help to make large-scale applications of knowledge-based MT an viable approach. In this paper we discuss the corpus-based knowledge acquisition methodology used in KANT, a knowledge-based translation system for multilingual document production. This methodology can be generalized beyond the KANT interlingua approach for use with any system that requires similar kinds of knowledge.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>knowledge-based machine translation</kwd>
            <kwd>conceptual coverage</kwd>
            <kwd>on-line lexical acquisition</kwd>
            <kwd>lexical mapping</kwd>
            <kwd>phrasal substructure</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>Notes</title>
            <ref id="d2796460e205a1310">
               <label>1</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e212" publication-type="other">
(Mitamura, Nyberg, and
Carbonell, 1993).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e222a1310">
               <label>3</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e229" publication-type="other">
Church, 1988;</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e235" publication-type="other">
Bourigault, 1992;</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e241" publication-type="other">
Chen and Chen, 1994).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e248a1310">
               <label>5</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e255" publication-type="other">
(Grishman, Macleod, and Meyers,
1994),</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d2796460e274a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e278" publication-type="other">
Bauer, L., editor. 1978. The Grammar of Nominal Compounding with Special
Reference to Danish, English, and French. Odense University Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e288a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e292" publication-type="other">
Bédard, C. 1986. La Traduction Technique: Principes et Pratique. Linguatech.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e299a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e303" publication-type="other">
Bourigault, D. 1992. Surface Grammatical Analysis for the Extraction of Termi-
nological Noun Phrases. In Proceedings of COLING-92.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e313a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e317" publication-type="other">
Brown, R.D. 1991. Automatic and Interactive Augmentation. In A Case Study in
Knowledge-Based Machine Translation. Morgan Kaufmann, San Mateo, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e328a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e332" publication-type="other">
Chen, K. and H. Chen. 1994. Extracting Noun Phrases form Large-Scale Texts: A
Hybrid Approach and Its Automatic Evaluation. In Proceedings of ACL-94.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e342a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e346" publication-type="other">
Church, K. 1988. A Stochastic Parts Program and Noun Phrase Parser for Un-
restricted Text. In Proceedings of the Second Conference on Applied Natural
Language Processing.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e359a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e363" publication-type="other">
Francis, W. and H. Ku era, editors. 1982. Frequency Analysis of English Usage.
Houghton Mifflin, Boston, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e373a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e377" publication-type="other">
Galinski, C. 1988. Advanced Terminology Banks Supporting Knowledge- Based
MT. In D. Maxwell, K. Schubert, and A. Witkam, editors, New Directions in
Machine Translation. Foris.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e390a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e394" publication-type="other">
Goodman, K. and S. Nirenburg, editors. 1991. A Case Study in Knowledge-Based
Machine Translation. Morgan Kaufmann, San Mateo, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e404a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e408" publication-type="other">
Grishman, R., C. Macleod, and A. Meyers. 1994. Comlex Syntax: Building a
Computational Lexicon. In Proceedings of COLING-94.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e419a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e423" publication-type="other">
Leavitt, J., D. Lonsdale, K. Keck, and E. Nyberg. 1994. Tooling the Lexicon
Acquisition Process for Large-Scale KBMT. In Proceedings of IEEE Tools for
AI.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e436a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e440" publication-type="other">
Lonsdale, D. 1994. Extraction d'un Vocabulaire Bilingue: Outils et Méthodes. In
A. Clas and P. Bouillon, editors, Actes du Colloque Lexicologie, Terminologie et
Traduction. Les Presses de l'Université de Montréal.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e453a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e457" publication-type="other">
Lonsdale, D., A. Franz, and J. Leavitt. 1994. Large-scale Machine Translation: An
Inter lingua Approach. In Proceedings of IEA/AIE-94.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e467a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e471" publication-type="other">
Mitamura, T. 1989. The Hierarchical Organization of Predicate Frames for In-
terpretive Mapping in Natural Language Processing. Ph.D. thesis, University of
Pittsburgh.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e484a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e488" publication-type="other">
Mitamura, T. and E. Nyberg. 1992. Hierarchical Lexical Structure and Interpretive
Mapping in MT. In Proceedings of COLING 1992, Nantes, France, July.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e498a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e502" publication-type="other">
Mitamura, T., E. Nyberg, and J. Carbonell. 1991. An Efficient Interlingua Trans-
lation System for Multi-lingual Document Production. In Proceedings of Machine
Translation Summit III, Washington, DC, July.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e516a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e520" publication-type="other">
Mitamura, T., E. Nyberg, and J. Carbonell. 1993. Automated Corpus Analysis and
the Acquisition of Large, Multi-Lingual Knowledge Bases for MT. In Proceedings
of TMI-93.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e533a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e537" publication-type="other">
Nyberg, E. and T. Mitamura. 1992. The KANT System: Fast, Accurate, High-
Quality Translation in Practical Domains. In Proceedings of COLING-92, Nantes,
France, July.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e550a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e554" publication-type="other">
Nyberg, E., T. Mitamura, and J. Carbonell. 1994. Evaluation Metrics for
Knowledge- Based Machine Translation. In Proceedings of COLING-94.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e564a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e568" publication-type="other">
Tomita, M., M. Kee, T. Mitamura, and J. Carbonell. 1987. Linguistic and Do-
main Knowledge Sources for the Universal Parser Architecture. In H. Czap and
C. Galinski, editors, Terminology and Knowledge Engineering. INDEKS Verlag,
Frankfurt, Germany, pages 191-203.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e584a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e588" publication-type="other">
Tsujii, T. 1988. What is a Cross-linguistically Valid Interpretation of Discourse?
In D. Maxwell, K. Schubert, and A. Witkam, editors, New Directions in Machine
Translation. Foris.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796460e601a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796460e605" publication-type="other">
Warren, B. 1978. Semantic Patterns of Noun-Noun Compounds. Technical report,
Acta Universitatis Gothoburgensis.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
