<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275530</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Preliminary Investigation into the Mitigation of Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicle Tailpipe Emissions Through Supervisory Control Methods</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Smith</surname>
                  <given-names>David E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Oak Ridge National Laboratory</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lohse-Busch</surname>
                  <given-names>Henning</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Argonne National Laboratory</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Irick</surname>
                  <given-names>David K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Tennessee, Knoxville</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>996</fpage>
         <lpage>1011</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275530"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Plug-in hybrid electric vehicle (PHEV) technologies have the potential for considerable petroleum consumption reductions, possibly at the expense of increased tailpipe emissions due to multiple “cold” start events and improper use of the engine for PHEV specific operation. PHEVs operate predominantly as electric vehicles (EVs) with intermittent assist from the engine during high power demands. As a consequence, the engine can be subjected to multiple cold start events. These cold start events may have a significant impact on the tailpipe emissions due to degraded catalyst performance and starting the engine under less than ideal conditions. On current hybrid electric vehicles (HEVs), the first cold start of the engine dictates whether or not the vehicle will pass federal emissions tests. PHEV operation compounds this problem due to infrequent, multiple engine cold starts.</p>
            <p>This research experimentally verifies a vehicle supervisory control system for a pre-transmission parallel PHEV powertrain architecture. Energy management strategies are evaluated and implemented in a virtual environment for preliminary assessment of petroleum displacement benefits and rudimentary drivability issues. This baseline vehicle supervisory control strategy, developed as a result of this assessment, is implemented and tested on actual hardware in a controlled laboratory environment over a baseline test cycle.</p>
            <p>Engine cold start events are aggressively addressed in the development of this control system, which leads to enhanced pre-warming and energy-based engine warming algorithms that provide substantial reductions in tailpipe emissions over the baseline supervisory control strategy. The flexibility of the PHEV powertrain allows for decreased emissions during any engine starting event through powertrain “torque shaping” algorithms.</p>
            <p>The results of the research show that PHEVs do have the potential for substantial reductions in fuel consumption. Tailpipe emissions from a PHEV test platform have been reduced to acceptable levels through the development and refinement of vehicle supervisory control methods only. Impacts on fuel consumption were minimal for the emissions reduction techniques implemented.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Advanced Energy Initiative. The White House National Economic Council, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carlson, R.W., Duoba, M.J., Bohn, T.P., and Vyas, A.D., “Testing and Analysis of Three Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0283, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gonder, Jeffrey, and Simpson Andrew. “Measuring and Reporting Fuel Economy of Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles.” EVS-22. Yokohama, Japan, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gonder, J. and Markel, T., “Energy Management Strategies for Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0290, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karbowski, Dominick, Haliburton Chris, and Rousseau Aymeric. Impact of Component Size on Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicle Energy Consumption Using Global Optimization. Argonne National Laboratory, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lohse-Busch, Henning. “A Modular Automotive Hybrid Testbed Designed to Evaluate Various Components in the Vehicle System.” 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Muta, K., Yamazaki, M., and Tokieda, J., “Development of New-Generation Hybrid System THS II - Drastic Improvement of Power Performance and Fuel Economy,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0064, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Keefe, M.P., and Markel Tony. Dynamic Programming Applied to Investigate Energy Management Strategies for a Plug-In HEV. NREL/CP-540-40376, National Renewable Energy Laboratory, November 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicle R&amp;D Plan. Washington D.C.: US Department of Energy Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy Vehicle Technologies Program, February 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rajagopalan, G. Washington, G. Rizzoni, and Guezennec Y.. Development of Fuzzy Logic and Neural Network Control and Advanced Emissions Modeling for Parallel Hybrid Vehicles. NREL/SR-540-32919, Ohio State University, December 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rousseau, Aymeric and Sylvain, Gao, Pagerit David. Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicle Control Strategy Parameter Optimization. Argonne National Laboratory, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sharer, Phil, Rousseau Aymeric, Pagerit Sylvain, and Karbowski Dominick. “Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicle Control Strategy: Comparison between EV and Charge- Depleting Options.” Presentation to US DOE. Argonne National Laboratory, May 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stone, R., “Introduction to Internal Combustion Engines: Second Edition,” SAE International, Warrendale, PA, ISBN 978-1560913900, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">United States Department of Energy Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy Vehicle Technologies Program. Vehicle Technologies Program: Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles. 2008. http://www1.eere.energy.gov/vehiclesandfuels/technologies/systems/phev.html (accessed 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
