<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">6</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466863</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466868</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>When Less Is More: The Benefits of Limits on Executive Pay</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Peter</given-names>
                  <surname>Cebon</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Benjamin E.</given-names>
                  <surname>Hermalin</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1667</fpage>
         <lpage>1700</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466868"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We derive conditions under which limits on executive compensation can enhance efficiency and benefit shareholders (but not executives). Having its hands tied in the future allows a board of directors to credibly enter into relational contracts with executives that are more efficient than performance-contingent contracts. This has implications for the ideal composition of the board. The analysis also offers insights into the political economy of executive-compensation reform.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d925898e126a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e133" publication-type="other">
Say-on-pay provisions are requirements that shareholders vote on executive compensation plans. These laws
vary across jurisdictions, in particular with respect to the consequences if shareholders vote against plans. In
addition to the United States and Switzerland, there are say-on-pay laws in Australia (Corporations Amendment
Act 2011) and the United Kingdom (Companies Act 2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e149a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e156" publication-type="other">
As true, e.g., of Grossman and Hart (1983), Holmstrom (1979), Sappington (1983), and Shavell (1979).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e163a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e170" publication-type="other">
The literature distinguishes between observable information, known to the contracting parties only, and verifiable
information, which the party who adjudicates contractual disputes can learn. A formal contract cannot be
contingent on un verifiable information because there is no way for the adjudicating party to enforce such a
contingency.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e186a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e193" publication-type="other">
See, e.g., Jensen and Murphy (1990), Bebchuk and Fried (2004, 2005), or Bertrand and Mullainathan (2001,
2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e204a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e211" publication-type="other">
As the editor, Itay Goldstein, remarked, this also provides a rational-actor explanation for less-than-desired
governance, in contrast to explanations that rely on mistakes (e.g., Kerr 1975) or psychological factors (e.g.,
Fehr and Gächter 2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e224a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e231" publication-type="other">
Schmidt and Schnitzer (1995) show that, as the cost of formal contracting falls, the harder it will be to sustain
relational contracts. A related literature considers improvements in the legal system or other formal institutions:
see, e.g., Kranton (1996), Kranton and Swamy (1999), and McMillan and Woodruff (1999a,b).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e244a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e251" publication-type="other">
In keeping with the literature's convention that an agent is a he, we use masculine pronouns for the executive;
were there a single principal, she would be a she.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e261a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e268" publication-type="other">
Baker, Gibbons, and Murphy (1994) assume the correlation, /i, between the objective and subjective measures
varies randomly across periods and the agent privately learns each period's /z before he acts.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e278a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e285" publication-type="other">
Setting c'(0)=0 entails some loss of generality, but greatly simplifies the analysis. An earlier version—available
from the corresponding author upon request—allowed for the possibility that c'(0) &gt; 0.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e295a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e302" publication-type="other">
The rationale for labeling the surplus-maximizing action p*(g) will become clear shortly.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e310a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e317" publication-type="other">
By exit rate, we include incapacitation, retirement, and simply death.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e324a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e331" publication-type="other">
As will be evident, often the analysis requires no condition on y versus 8—we highlight below where use is
made of y &lt;8.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e341a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e348" publication-type="other">
See Kreps (1990) for an analysis of how long-lived institutions can maintain long-term reputations even when
composed of short-lived members (e.g., individual directors).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e358a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e365" publication-type="other">
Although we refer to b as a bonus, it should be understood that it could be stock-based compensation (e.g., stock
options). The critical feature is that it is compensation contractually linked to a verifiable measure of performance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e375a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e382" publication-type="other">
In light of Hermalin and M. Katz (1991), could renegotiation be another means for the parties to contract
effectively on this other information? The answer is no: the reason being that, in Hermalin and M. Katz, the
value of renegotiation is that it eliminates the insurance-incentive trade-off that arises in agency models with
risk-averse agents. Here the agent (the CEO) is risk neutral and the contractual friction is, instead, due to his
limited liability; that is, the impossibility of making him pay the firm. Note this also explains why we do not use
a standard moral-hazard model with a risk-averse agent (i.e., as in Grossman and Hart 1983; Holmstrom 1979; or
Shavell 1979): given our assumption that the board observes the CEO's action, the first best would be attainable
via renegotiation; see Hermalin and M. Katz (1991) for details.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e411a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e420" publication-type="other">
A subtle issue is how might a subsequently hired CEO learn that the board reneged given that information is
unverifiable. Some possibilities are that, once on the job, a new CEO would receive evidence that indicated his
predecessor had been cheated (this is especially plausible if the new CEO comes from within the firm). Another
is that industry insiders—such as a new CEO—would know, but such knowledge is so difficult and expensive
to communicate to outsiders—such as judges—that it is infeasible to contract directly on it (this is a standard
assumption in the incomplete-contracts literature—see, e.g., Hermalin, A. Katz, and Craswell, Section 4, for
discussion). Finally, if the CEO is long-lived but wholly myopic (i.e., y=0), then this issue disappears: the
efficiency-wage effect, discussed infra and which relies on the threat of dismissal, does not arise and, therefore,
one could assume the same board and CEO play against each other every period regardless of past play.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e453a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e460" publication-type="other">
As will become evident, even with a formal contract, the board might use its knowledge of p when deciding
whether to retain or fire the CEO.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e470a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e477" publication-type="other">
It is straightforward to prove this by redoing the proof of Lemma 1 with b in place of g.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e484a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e491" publication-type="other">
This logic is similar to that of efficiency wages (see, e.g., Shapiro and Stiglitz 1984).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e498a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e505" publication-type="other">
An earlier version of this paper showed that the first best can be obtained with formal contracts in the limit as
Y1. Details available from the corresponding author upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e515a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e522" publication-type="other">
If y-0, then 7TpC=0 and it directly follows that 8gp*(8g)—c[p*(8g)) &gt;87TpC because, by the definition of an
optimum, Sgp*(Sg) — c(p*(Sg)) &gt;Sg x0—c(0)=0.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e532a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e539" publication-type="other">
Recall JTpC is maximum expected profit using a formal contract only (i.e., without restriction on bonuses).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e547a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e554" publication-type="other">
The board's optimization program when limited to formal contracts, expression (A5) in the Appendix, is not
necessarily concave in b and w hence, it is conceivable that more than one expected-profit-maximizing contract
exists. Even if the optimal contract is not unique, by appeal to the Maximum Theorem (see, e.g., Sundaram 1996,
p. 235), &amp;fc is well defined (i.e., a minimum—as opposed to just an infimum—optimal bonus must exist).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e570a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e577" publication-type="other">
Calculations for all examples are available from the corresponding author upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e584a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e591" publication-type="other">
For large U.S. companies, compensation corresponding to what we are calling b here appears to be in the
neighborhood of 28-36% of total compensation (the lower estimate is from Core, Holthausen, and Larcker 1999;
the larger from Goergen and Renneboog 2011).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e604a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e611" publication-type="other">
The law severely limits the ability of entities to bind their future selves contractually. For instance, it is not legally
possible for parties to commit never to renegotiate or change the terms of their contract: if the parties wish to
change the contract, the courts will let them do that regardless of whatever attempts they may have previously
made to make the contract ironclad (see, e.g., Hermalin, A. Katz, and Craswell 2007, especially Sections 1.1.4,
2.5.2,4.3.2, and 5.4.3).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e630a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e637" publication-type="other">
For more on amending corporate charters, see Hansmann (2006). Inter alia, Hansmann also discusses why
corporations have typically been hesitant to adopt charters that differ from the default charter of their state of
incorporation—yet another factor to consider with respect to the question of whether private action can substitute
for state action.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e653a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e660" publication-type="other">
According to the Seward &amp; Kissell LLP website, in a discussion of proxy fights: "Solicitation, printing and mailing
fees and costs are dependent on the company's shareholder base. It is not unusual for aggregate costs to exceed $ 1
million" (accessed April 24,2014). Adam Kimmel, in the web article "Proxy Fight Fees and Costs Now Collected
by SharkRepellent: Mackenzie Partners and Carl Icahn Involved in Largest Fights" (SharkRepellent.net, February
20, 2013: accessed April 24, 2014), reports the average total cost of a proxy fight for a large corporation to be
around $1.3 million.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e684a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e691" publication-type="other">
Additionally, evidence suggests that management has considerable control over the proxy process (see, e.g.,
Pound 1988). As we have noted elsewhere, management would prefer there be no restrictions on pay and, thus,
would presumably be biased toward repeal even if doing so did not have positive net present value (i.e., even if
(16) held).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e707a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e714" publication-type="other">
We thank the editor, Itay Goldstein, for this observation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e721a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e728" publication-type="other">
In this regard, also recall footnote 29 supra.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e735a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e742" publication-type="other">
An earlier version of this paper explored this issue utilizing a different approach than the one pursued here. We
thank an anonymous referee for encouraging us to rethink the approach in order to have a model that is both
more tractable and more general.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e755a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e762" publication-type="other">
The following proposition can be extended to allow for an impatient, but long-lived CEO; that is, y &gt; 0 but not
too large. It can also be extended to permit a less severe cap on bonuses. Doing so would not change the basic
insights of the proposition. So, for the sake of brevity, we restrict attention to this simplest case.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e775a1310">
            <label>34</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e782" publication-type="other">
Because p*(8g) uniquely maximizes gp—c(p)/8, it follows that
gP*(&amp;g)~ jc(p*(Sg))&gt;gxO- ^c(0)=0;
hence, the contract must satisfy the no-negative-payment constraint.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e796a1310">
            <label>35</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e803" publication-type="other">
See, e.g., Peter Teuwsen, "Minders Kampf," Die Zeit, January 24, 2013. Retrieved from Zeit Online on May 28,
2013.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e813a1310">
            <label>36</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e820" publication-type="other">
See, e.g., Del Jones,"CEOs Openly Oppose Push for Say-on-Pay by Shareholders," USA Today, July 17, 2009.
Retrieved from USA Today website on May 28, 2013.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e830a1310">
            <label>37</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e837" publication-type="other">
We hasten to note, however, that, while an increase in 8 - y facilitates the use of informal contracts ceteris paribus,
it is not necessary that 8 — y be large for the firm to wish to utilize an informal component and to benefit from
restrictions on bonuses—see, in particular, Corollary 3 and Proposition 4.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e850a1310">
            <label>38</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e857" publication-type="other">
Hall and Liebman (1998) document the rapid increase of the 1990s. Kaplan (2012) suggests that this increase
in executive pay—at least relative to other high-income groups—"leveled off" after the 1990s. We do not wish
to enter into that debate per se: but Kaplan's data do indicate that top executives continue to be compensated
at real levels well above their long-run average. A recent New York Times article by Gretchen Morgenson,
"That Unstoppable Climb in C.E.O. Pay," page 1 of the Business Section, June 29, 2013, suggests that CEO
compensation could again be on the rise.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e880a1310">
            <label>39</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e887" publication-type="other">
See Walker and Wang (2010) for evidence on the relation between dismissal and recessions and Allgood and
Farrell (2003) for evidence on the relation between dismissal and tenure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e897a1310">
            <label>40</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e904" publication-type="other">
For instance, Grossman and Hart (1983), Holmstrom (1979), or Shavell (1979).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e912a1310">
            <label>41</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e919" publication-type="other">
See, e.g., Hermalin (1992, Proposition 4) for a model with that property.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e926a1310">
            <label>42</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e933" publication-type="other">
An earlier working paper, available from the corresponding author upon request, considered this implication in
greater detail.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e943a1310">
            <label>43</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e950" publication-type="other">
The operator a (the meet) denotes the pairwise minimum and the operator v (the join) denotes the pairwise
maximum.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e960a1310">
            <label>44</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e967" publication-type="other">
The derivative of
(1 -y)((o(b)+R(b))
with respect to b is, using the envelope theorem,
(1 -Y)(p*(b)-p).
At b=b(_), the sign of the derivative is negative because p&gt; p*(bQ) in equilibrium.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925898e986a1310">
            <label>45</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925898e993" publication-type="other">
When in=0, it must be that p*(b) &gt; 0 if p(b) &gt; 0. To see this, suppose not: the right-hand side of (2) is then zero;
hence, from Lemma 3, bp(b)—c(p{b))= 0. Because p(b)&gt;0 and bp — c(p) is strictly concave in p, it follows
that bp—c(p) &gt; 0 for any p e (0, /?(&amp;)), which contradicts the claim that p*(b)=0.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d925898e1015a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1019" publication-type="other">
Allgood, S., and K. A. Farrell. 2003. The match between the CEO and firm. Journal of Business 76:317-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1026a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1030" publication-type="other">
Bainbridge, S. M. 2011. Dodd-Frank: Quack federal corporate governance round II. Minnesota Law Review
95:1779-821.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1040a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1044" publication-type="other">
Baker, G P., R. Gibbons, and K. J. Murphy. 1994. Subjective performance measures in optimal incentive contracts.
Quarterly Journal of Economics 109:1125-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1054a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1058" publication-type="other">
Bebchuk, L. A. 2007. Written testimony submitted by Professor Lucian A. Bebchuk. In Empowering Shareholders
on Executive Compensation: H.R. 1257, the Shareholder Vote on Executive Compensation Act, 110-10, 65-73.
U.S. House of Representatives. Hearing before the House Committee on Financial Services, 110th Congress.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1072a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1076" publication-type="other">
Bebchuk, L. A., and J. M. Fried. 2003. Executive compensation as an agency problem. Journal of Economic
Perspectives 17:71-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1086a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1090" publication-type="other">
. 2004. Pay without performance. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1097a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1101" publication-type="other">
. 2005. Pay without performance: Overview of the issues. Journal of Applied Corporate Finance 17:8-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1108a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1112" publication-type="other">
Bertrand, M., and S. Mullainathan. 2001. Are CEOs rewarded for luck? The ones without principals are. Quarterly
Journal of Economics 116:901-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1122a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1126" publication-type="other">
. 2003. Enjoying the quiet life? Corporate governance and managerial preferences. Journal of Political
Economy 111:1043-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1136a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1140" publication-type="other">
Bushee, B. J. 2001. Do institutional investors prefer near-term earnings over long-run value? Contemporary
Accounting Research 18:207-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1151a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1155" publication-type="other">
Core, J. E., R. W. Holthausen, and D. F. Larcker. 1999. Corporate governance, chief executive officer
compensation, and firm performance. Journal of Financial Economics 51:371-406.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1165a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1169" publication-type="other">
Fehr, E., and S. Gächter. 2002. Do incentive contracts undermine voluntary cooperation? Zurich IEER Working
Paper No. 34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1179a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1183" publication-type="other">
Frydman, C., and D. Jenter. 2010. CEO compensation. Annual Review of Financial Economics 2:75-102.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1190a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1194" publication-type="other">
Gibbons, R. S., and K. J. Murphy. 1992. Optimal incentive contracts in the presence of career concerns: Theory
and evidence. Journal of Political Economy 100:468-505.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1204a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1208" publication-type="other">
Goergen, M., and L. Renneboog. 2011. Managerial compensation. Journal of Corporate Finance 17:1068-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1215a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1219" publication-type="other">
Grossman, S. J., and O. D. Hart. 1983. An analysis of the principal-agent problem. Econometrica 51:7-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1227a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1231" publication-type="other">
Hall, B. J., and J. B. Liebman. 1998. Are CEOs really paid like bureaucrats? Quarterly Journal of Economics
CXin:653-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1241a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1245" publication-type="other">
Hansmann, H. 2006. Corporation and contract. American Law and Economic Review 8:1-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1252a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1256" publication-type="other">
Hermalin, B. E. 1992. The effects of competition on executive behavior. RAND Journal of Economics 23:350-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1263a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1267" publication-type="other">
. 2005. Trends in corporate governance. Journal of Finance 60:2351-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1274a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1278" publication-type="other">
Hermalin, B. E., A. W. Katz, and R. Craswell. 2007. Contract law. In A. M. Polinsky and S. Shavell, eds.,
Handbook oflMw and Economics, vol. 1. Amsterdam: North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1288a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1292" publication-type="other">
Hermalin, B. E., and M. L. Katz. 1991. Moral hazard and verifiability: The effects of renegotiation in agency.
Econometrica 59:1735-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1303a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1307" publication-type="other">
Hermalin, B. E., and M. S. Weisbach. 1998. Endogenously chosen boards of directors and their monitoring of
the CEO. American Economic Review 88:96-118.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1317a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1321" publication-type="other">
Holmstrom, B. 1979. Moral hazard and observability. Bell Journal of Economics 10:74-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1328a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1332" publication-type="other">
Jensen, M. C., and K. J. Murphy. 1990. Performance pay and top-management incentives. Journal of Political
Economy 98:225-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1342a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1346" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S. N. 2007. Testimony of Steven N. Kaplan: Are US CEOs overpaid? In Empowering Shareholders
on Executive Compensation: H.R. 1257, the Shareholder Vote on Executive Compensation Act, 110-10,
120-47. U.S. House of Representatives. Hearing before the House Committee on Financial Services, 110th
Congress.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1362a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1366" publication-type="other">
. 2012. Executive compensation and corporate governance in the U.S.: Perceptions, facts and challenges.
Unpublished working paper, University of Chicago, Booth School of Business.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1376a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1380" publication-type="other">
Kerr, S. 1975. On the folly of rewarding a, while hoping for b. Academy of Management Journal 18:769-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1388a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1392" publication-type="other">
Kranton, R. E. 1996. Reciprocal exchange: A self-sustaining system. American Economic Review 86:830-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1399a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1403" publication-type="other">
Kranton, R. E., and A. V. Swamy. 1999. The hazards of piecemeal reform: British civil courts and the credit
market in colonial India. Journal of Development Economics 58:1-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1413a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1417" publication-type="other">
Kreps, D. M. 1990. Corporate culture and economic theory. In J. E. Alt and K. A. Shepsle (Eds.), Perspectives
on Positive Political Economy. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1427a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1431" publication-type="other">
Kumar, P., and K. Sivaramakrishnan. 2008. Who monitors the monitor? The effect of board independence on
executive compensation and firm value. Review of Financial Studies 21:1371-401.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1441a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1445" publication-type="other">
Larcker, D. F., A. McCall, G Ormazabal, and B. Tayan. 2012. Ten myths of 'say on pay.' Tech. Rep. CGRP-26,
Stanford Graduate School of Business.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1455a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1459" publication-type="other">
Malcomson, J. M. 2013. Relational incentive contracts. In R. S. Gibbons and J. Roberts (Eds.). The Handbook
of Organizational Economics. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1470a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1474" publication-type="other">
McMillan, J., and C. Woodruff. 1999a. Dispute prevention without courts in Vietnam. Journal of Law, Economics,
and Organization 15:637-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1484a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1488" publication-type="other">
. 1999b. Interfirm relationships and informal credit in Vietnam. Quarterly Journal of Economics
114:1285-320.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1498a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1502" publication-type="other">
Pound, J. 1988. Proxy contests and the efficiency of shareholder oversight. Journal of Financial Economics
20:237-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1512a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1516" publication-type="other">
Sappington, D. E. 1983. Limited liability contracts between principal and agent. Journal of Economic Theory
29:1-21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1526a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1530" publication-type="other">
Schmidt, K. M., and M. Schnitzer. 1995. The interaction of explicit and implicit contracts. Economics Letters
48:193-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1540a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1544" publication-type="other">
Shapiro, C., and J. E. Stiglitz. 1984. Equilibrium unemployment as a worker discipline device. American
Economic Review 74:433—44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1555a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1559" publication-type="other">
Shavell, S. 1979. Risk sharing and incentives in the principal and agent relationship. Bell Journal of Economics
10:55-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1569a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1573" publication-type="other">
Sundaram, R. K. 1996. A first course in optimization theory. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925898e1580a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925898e1584" publication-type="other">
Walker, M., and J. Wang. 2010. CEO turnover and industry downturns. Working paper, North Carolina State
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


