<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308301</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Macroscopic Behavior of Diesel Sprays in the Near-Nozzle Field</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Payri</surname>
                  <given-names>R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Salvador</surname>
                  <given-names>F. J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gimeno</surname>
                  <given-names>J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>de la Morena</surname>
                  <given-names>J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Universidad Politécnica de Valencia</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>528</fpage>
         <lpage>536</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308301"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The objective of the paper is the characterization of the macroscopic behavior of Diesel sprays by focusing in at the first instants of the injection process at which the spray is clearly affected by the injector needle dynamic.</p>
            <p>There are several works dealing with the characterization of Diesel sprays in stationary conditions. Most of them conclude with empirical correlations which predict spray tip penetration as a function of the most important parameters involved in the injection process, such as: injection pressure, gas ambient density, hole diameter and time elapsed from the start of injection. In all these experiments, authors find similar power law dependencies with more or less high level of confidence. Nevertheless, few works have tried to validate or to obtain new correlations for the first instants of the injection process where the spray develops in not stationary conditions because of the influence of injector needle lift.</p>
            <p>In this paper, a wide parametrical study based on a zoomed visualization in the nozzle near-field including the first 15 millimeters of the spray has been carried out. The research has permitted the quantification of effects of the main injection parameters on spray tip penetration and spray cone angle at the initial stages of the injection process. From this study, significant differences have been found when comparing results with previous analysis based on sprays in stationary conditions especially in time dependence of spray tip penetration and injection pressure.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rife, J., Heywood, J.B., “Photographic and erformance studies of Diesel combustion with a apid compression machine”, SAE Paper 740948; 1974.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H., Arai, M. “Structures of fuel sprays in iesel engines”, SAE Paper 900475, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hay, N., Jones, P.L. “Comparison of the various orrelations for spray penetration”. SAE Paper 720776, 1972.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dent, J.C., “A basis for the comparison of various xperimental methods for studying spray enetration”. SAE Paper 710571, 1971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wakuri, Y., Fujii, M., Amitani, T. and Tsuneya, R., “Studies of the penetration of a fuel spray in a Diesel ngine”. Bull. J.S.M.E. 3(9), pp. 123-130, 1960.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J.M., Payri, R., Salvador, F.J, Soare, V., “Study of the Influence of Geometrical and Injection arameters on Diesel Sprays Characteristics in sothermal conditions.”. SAE Paper 2005-01-0913, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cheong, S.-K., Liu, J., Shu, D., Wang, J., Powell, C. . “Effects of ambient pressure on dynamics of nearnozzle iesel sprays studied by ultrafast XRadiography”. AE Paper 2004-01-2026, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sazhin, S., Crua, C., Kennaird, D., Heikal, M., “The nitial stage of fuel penetration”, Fuel, vol. 82, pp 875-885, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hattori, H., Narumiya, K., Tsue, M., Kadota, T., “Analysis of initial breakup mechanism of diesel pray injected into high-pressure ambience”, SAE aper 2004-01-0528, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber, J., Siebers, D.L., “Effects of gas density and aporisation on penetration and dispersion of Diesel prays”. SAE Paper 960034, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J.M., Payri, R., Salvador, F.J., Gil, A. “Development and validation of a theoretical model or diesel spray penetration”, FUEL, vol. 85 (7-8), pp. 910-917, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J.M, Payri, R., Salvador, F.J., Gimeno, J., “Prediction of spray penetration by means of spray omentum”, SAE Paper 2006-01-1387, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pastor, J.V., Arrègle, J., García, J.M., Zapata, L.D., “Segmentation of diesel spray images with loglikelihood atio test algorithm for non-gaussian istributions”, Applied Optics, vol. 46, No. 6, pp. 888- 899, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flaig, U., Polach, W. Zieglet G., “Common rail ystem (CR-System) for passenger car DI Diesel ngines; Experiences with applications for series roductions projects”, SAE Paper 1999-01-0191, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, R., Climent, H., Salvador, F.J., Favennec, .G. “Diesel injection system modelling. ethodology and application for a first-generation ommon rail system”. Proc. Instn. Mech. Engrs. vol. 218, Part D: Automobile Engineering, pp. 81-91, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, R., Tormos, B., Salvador, F.J., Plazas, A.H., “Using one-dimensional modelling codes to analyse he influence of diesel nozzle geometry on injection ate characteristics”, Int. J. Vehicle Design, vol. 38, o 1, pp 58-78, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
