<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275447</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental Study of an LP EGR System on an Automotive Diesel Engine, compared to HP EGR with respect to PM and NOx Emissions and Specific Fuel Consumption</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Maiboom</surname>
                  <given-names>Alain</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tauzia</surname>
                  <given-names>Xavier</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shah</surname>
                  <given-names>Samiur Rahman</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hétet</surname>
                  <given-names>Jean-François</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Ecole Centrale de Nantes</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275401</issue-id>
         <fpage>597</fpage>
         <lpage>610</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275447"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Previous experimental studies on Diesel engines have demonstrated the potential of high-pressure exhaust gas recirculation (HP EGR) as an in-cylinder NOx control method. With ever more stringent emissions standards, the use of a low pressure EGR loop (LP EGR) seems to be an interesting method to further reduce NOx emissions while maintaining PM emissions at a low level. Actually, contrary to HP EGR, the gas flow through the turbine is unchanged while varying the EGR rate. Thus, by closing the variable geometry turbine (VGT) vanes, higher boost pressure can be reached, allowing the use of high rates of supplemental EGR.</p>
            <p>Some experiments are conducted on a 2.0 l HSDI common-rail DI Diesel engine equipped with HP and LP EGR loops on a test bench under low and part load conditions, as those encountered in the European emissions test cycle for light-duty vehicles. The dilution ratio, boost pressure, as well as injection pressure are modified using the LP EGR loop to study the influence of boost pressure and injection pressure on combustion (instantaneous rate of heat release) and the NOx-PM trade-off (while varying EGR rate at a given boost pressure level), thus giving optimal boost pressure and injection pressure for each operating point in terms of NOx and PM emissions. In particular, higher boost pressures and EGR rates are studied, as compared with the original HP EGR loop. Finally, the impact on LP and HP IMEP, as well as ISFC, when increasing boost pressure by closing VGT vanes with the LP EGR loop is studied.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng M, Reader GT, Hawley JG. Diesel Engine Exhaust Gas Recirculation – A Review on Advanced and Novel Concepts. Energy Conversion and Management 2004; 45: 883-900.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maiboom A, Tauzia X, Hétet J-F. Experimental study of various effects of exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) on combustion and emissions of an automotive direct injection Diesel engine. Energy 2008; 33: 22- 34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ladommatos N, Abdelhalim SM, Zhao H, Hu Z. The Dilution, Chemical, and Thermal Effects of Exhaust Gas Recirculation on Diesel Engine Emissions – Part 4: Effects of Carbon Dioxide and Water Vapor. SAE Paper no. 971660, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ladommatos N, Abdelhalim SM, Zhao H, Hu Z. Effects of EGR on Heat Release in Diesel Combustion. SAE paper no. 980184, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacobs T, Assanis D, Filipi Z. The Impact of Exhaust Gas Recirculation on Performance and Emissions of a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine. SAE paper no. 2003- 01-1068, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Egnell R. The Influence of EGR on Heat Release Rate and NO Formation in a DI Diesel Engine. SAE paper no. 2000-01-1807, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus MPB. On the Correlation Between NOx Emissions and the Diesel Premixed Burn. SAE paper no. 2004-01-1401, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nitu B, Singh I, Zhong L, Badreshany K, Henein NA, Bryzik W. Effect of EGR on Autoignition , Combustion, Regulated Emissions, and Aldehydes in DI Diesel Engines. SAE paper no. 2002-01-1153, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Torregrosa AJ, Olmeda P, Martin J, Degraeuwe B. Experiments on the influence of inlet charge and coolant temperature on performance and emissions of a DI Diesel engine. Experimental Thermal and Fluid Sciences 2006; 30: 633-641</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tree DR, Svensson KI. Soot processes in compression ignition engines. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 2007; 33: 272-309.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ladommatos N, Abdelhalim S, Zhao H. Control of Oxides of Nitrogen from Diesel Engines Using Diluents While Minimizing the Impact on Particulate Pollutants. Applied Thermal Engineering 1998; 18: 963-980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kouremenos DA, Hountalas DT, Binder KB. The Effect of EGR on the Performance and Pollutant Emissions of Heavy-Duty Diesel Engines Using Constant and Variable AFR. SAE paper no. 2001-01- 0198, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hountalas DT. Controlling Nitric Oxide and Soot in Heavy Duty Diesel Engines Using Internal Measures. FISITA World Automotive Congress, Barcelona, Spain, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hountalas DT, Benajes J, Pariotis EG, Gonzalez CA. Combination of High Injection Pressure and EGR to Control Nitric Oxide and Soot in DI Diesel Engines. THIESEL Conference on Thermo- and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines, Valencia, Spain, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Munz S, Romuss C., Schmidt P, Brune K-H, Schiffer H-P. Diesel engine with low-pressure exhaust gas recirculation – challenges for the turbocharger. MTZ 2008; 69: 20-26</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wenzel W, Joergl V, Keller P, Weber O. EGR Systems for Diesel engines – the road ahead. SIA conference, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moroz S, Bourgoin G, Lujan JM, Pla B. A 2.0 litre Diesel engine with low pressure exhaust gas recirculation and advanced cooling systems. SIA conference, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lujan JM, Pla B, Moroz S, Bourgoin G. Effect of low pressure EGR on gas exchange processes and turbocharging of a HSDI engine. Thiesel 2008 Conference on Thermo-and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abu-Hamdeh NH. Effect of cooling the recirculated exhaust gases on diesel engine emissions. Energy Conversion and Management 2003; 44: 3113-3124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hountalas DT, Mavropoulos GC, Binder KB. Effect of exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) temperature for various EGR rates on heavy duty DI diesel engine performance and emissions. Energy 2008; 33: 272- 283.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maiboom A, Tauzia X, Hétet JF. Influence of high rates of supplemental cooled EGR on NOx and PM emissions of an automotive HSDI engine using an LP EGR loop, International journal of Energy Research 2008; 32: 1383-1398.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosslein M., Williams A. Quantifier l’incertitude dans les measures analytiques, Guide Eurachem/CITAC 2nd edition, SLR Ellison.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber JD., Siebers DL. Effects of gas density and vaporization on penetration and dispersion of Diesel sprays. SAE paper no. 960034, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maiboom A, Tauzia X, Shah SR, Hétet JF. New phenomenological six-zone combustion model for direct-injection Diesel engines. Energy and Fuels 2009; 23(2): 690-703.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec JE. A conceptual model of DI diesel combustion based on laser-sheet imaging. SAE paper no. 970873, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers DL. Scaling liquid-phase fuel penetration in Diesel sprays based on mixing-limited vaporization. SAE paper no. 1999-01-0528, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins BS, Mueller CJ, Siebers DL. Measurements of fuel effects on liquid-phase penetration in DI sprays. SAE paper no. 1999-01-0519, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers DL, Higgins B, Pickett LM. Flame lift-off on direct-injection Diesel fuel jets: oxygen concentration effects. SAE paper no. 2002-01-0890, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett LM, Siebers DL. Non-sooting, low-flame temperature mixing-controlled DI Diesel combustion. SAE paper 2004-01-1399, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett LM, Siebers DL. Soot in Diesel fuel jets: effects of ambient temperature, ambient density, and injection pressure. Combust. Flame 2004, 138, 114- 135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett LM, Idicheria CA. Effects of Ambient Density and Temperature on Soot Formation under High- EGR Conditions. 12th Annual Diesel Engine Emissions Reduction (DEER) Conference, Detroit, USA, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cormerais M, Hétet J-F, Chesse P, Maiboom A. Heat transfer analysis in a turbocharger compressor: modeling and experiments - SAE paper no. 2006-01-0023, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
