<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26169322</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Fire Suppression Modeling &amp; Simulation Framework for Ground Vehicles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Korivi</surname>
                  <given-names>Vamshi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>US Army TARDEC</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>McCormick</surname>
                  <given-names>Steven</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>US Army TARDEC</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hodges</surname>
                  <given-names>Steven</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Alion Science &amp; Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>5</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e26169316</issue-id>
         <fpage>58</fpage>
         <lpage>67</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169322"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The US Army Tank Automotive Research, Development and Engineering Center (TARDEC) has developed a unique physics based modeling &amp; simulation (M&amp;S) capability using Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) techniques to optimize automatic fire extinguishing system (AFES) designs and complement vehicle testing for both occupied and unoccupied spaces of military ground vehicles.</p>
            <p>The modeling techniques developed are based on reduced global kinetics for computational efficiency and are applicable to fire suppressants that are being used in Army vehicles namely, bromotrifluoromethane (Halon 1301), heptafluoropropane (HFC-227ea, trade name FM200), sodium-bicarbonate (SBC) powder, water + potassium acetate mixture, and pentafluoroethane (HFC-125, trade name, FE-25). These CFD simulations are performed using High Performance Computers (HPC) that enable the Army to assess AFES designs in a virtual world at far less cost than physical-fire tests.</p>
            <p>This methodology is applied to vehicle crew compartments for multiple scenarios using HFC227e + SBC powder which is the suppressant combination used in most US combat and tactical vehicles with crew fire protection systems. Predicted and test results match qualitatively very well for overall suppression time as well as for soldier survivability from thermal injury, blast overpressure and inhalation toxicity risks.</p>
            <p>After gaining confidence with crew compartment simulations, this fire suppression modeling methodology is now being applied to the geometrically-more-complex military vehicle engine compartments with HFC-125 fire suppressant that is widely used for unoccupied spaces. Challenges associated with the fire suppression simulations are discussed along with future developments that are being proposed to enhance the overall accuracy of the simulation methodology.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Joint Trauma Analysis and Prevention of Injury in Combat (JTAPIC), RFI 2013 N0131, Thermal Injuries, 04 Oct 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hodges, S. E. and McCormick, S. J., "Fire Extinguishing Agents for Protection of Occupied Spaces in Military Ground Vehicles," Fire Technology, Springer Science (DOI: 10.1007/s10694-012-0271-z), May 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Williams, B.A. and Fleming, J. W., “Global Reaction Kinetics of Inhibition of JP-8 Combustion by Heptafluoropropane and Sodiumbicarbonate,” NRL 6180/0222A, 19th November 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Korivi, V. M., Williams, B. A., McCormick, S. J. and Deshmukh, K. “Fire Suppression Modeling Using CFD”, presented at 2014 GVSETS conference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hodges, S. E., “Effective Fire Protection Systems for Vehicles”, SAE 2006-01-0792.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santrock, J. and Hodges, S., "Evaluation of Automatic Fire Suppression Systems in Full Scale Vehicle Fire Tests and Static Vehicle Fire Tests," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1788, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1788.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“NFPA 2001 Standard on Clean Agent Fire Extinguishing Systems 2012 Edition,” National Fire Protection Agency (NFPA), Quincy, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Forssell, E. W., “U.S. Army Flow Model Enhancement”, Hughes Associates, August 15, 2014. (Contract # N00173-12-D-2002)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Garrison, P.W, Klein, G.A., Moran, K.M., and Zydowicz, M.P., “Flow of Nitrogen-Pressurized Halon 1301 in Fire Extinguishing Systems”, JPL Publication 84-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skaggs, R., #x201c;Experimental Characterization of Water and Diesel Fuel Sprays.” ARL-TR-2486, U.S. Army Research Laboratory, Aberdeen Proving Ground, MD, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">STAR-CCM+ Version 11.02 Theory &amp; User Manual.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Department of Defense High Performance Computing Modernization Program, https://www.hpc.mil/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
