<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">26</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">11</issue>
         <issue-id>i24464772</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24464777</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Do Private Equity Fund Managers Earn Their Fees? Compensation, Ownership, and Cash Flow Performance</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>David T.</given-names>
                  <surname>Robinson</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Berk A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Sensoy</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2013</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2760</fpage>
         <lpage>2797</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24464777"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We study the relations between management contract terms and performance in private equity using new data for 837 funds from 1984–2010. We find no evidence that higher fees or lower managerial ownership are associated with lower net-of-fee performance. Nevertheless, compensation rises and shifts to performance-insensitive components during fundraising booms. Further, the behavior of distributions around contractual fee triggers is consistent with an underlying agency conflict between investors and fund managers. Our evidence suggests that managers with higher fees deliver higher gross performance, and highlights that agency costs are an inevitable consequence of the information frictions endemic to agency relationships.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d64e208a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e215" publication-type="other">
See, for example, "Private equity firms reap big fees, report says," New York Times DealBook, November 1,
2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e225a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e232" publication-type="other">
For example, this would mean that a $100 million fund would generate $2 million in annual fees (depending
on the basis for calculating fees, as we discuss at length below), plus 20% of overall profits from investments
as revenue for the general partners. To obtain their 1% ownership stake, the general partners would make a $1
million investment in the fund.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e248a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e255" publication-type="other">
See, for example, "Skin in the game is crucial, but how much?" Financial Times, November 18, 2012.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e262a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e269" publication-type="other">
For example, if $ 100 million had been returned to limited partners to clear the 8% preferred return, the GP would
earn 100% of the next $20 million in exits, and then they would share on an 80/20 basis any returns in excess of
the hurdle rate thereafter.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e283a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e290" publication-type="other">
See, for example, "Private equity trapped in 'Zombie Funds.' " Financial Times, December 11, 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e297a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e304" publication-type="other">
All 837 funds are bona fide funds. There are no side-car or coinvestment vehicles in our data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e311a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e318" publication-type="other">
The most common basis change is to "net invested capital," defined as the total (equity) capital invested in
portfolio companies to date minus the (equity) cost basis of all realized investments. The change to net invested
capital has the effect that fees are earned only on active, and not on already harvested investments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e331a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e338" publication-type="other">
We choose the risk-free rate over the contracted life of the fund as the discount rate because management fees
are a contractual obligation over this horizon.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e348a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e355" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Kaplan and Strömberg's (2009) analysis of buyout funds. In untabulated results we confirm
this finding for both buyout and venture funds in our sample.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e365a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e372" publication-type="other">
In untabulated robustness tests we confirm that the initial management fee and the undiscounted lifetime fees
also respond positively to industry fundraising flows. We also confirm that fees are not more responsive to flows
when flows are high compared with when they are low.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e386a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e393" publication-type="other">
The fact that fund size and fees are jointly determined as a function of the GP's ability does not confound
this interpretation. In the absence of any trade-off, the direct effect of ability on both size and fees should be
positive, which by itself would induce a positive correlation between size and fees in the data. Thus, the fact that
we cannot observe and control for ability biases us away from finding the negative correlation (trade-off) that
we do.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e412a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e419" publication-type="other">
See Robinson and Sensoy (2011) or Kaplan and Strömberg (2009) for evidence on the relation between absolute
performance and fundraising cycles.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e429a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e436" publication-type="other">
These portfolios are constructed using NYSE size breakpoints at the 30th and 70th percentiles and are available
on Ken French's Web site. Our results are similar using instead the categorization in our data of whether the fund
is focused on small, middle, or large buyouts.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e449a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e456" publication-type="other">
Our results are robust to using a VC ß of 2.7 as estimated by Driessen, Lin, and Phalippou (2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e463a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e470" publication-type="other">
In unreported analysis, we have repeated Table 4 for two subsamples: liquidated funds, defined analogously to
Kaplan and Schoar (2005) as funds with vintage years prior to 2005 and with no cash flow activity for the last six
quarters of our sample period, and funds with vintage years prior to 2001. In both cases, performance evaluations
primarily are based on actual cash flows. These results are qualitatively identical to those reported in Table 4.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e486a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e493" publication-type="other">
However, in the liquidated sample, VC carried interest is negatively associated with tailored PME and levered
PME.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e504a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e511" publication-type="other">
These analyses focus on indicator variables for whether GP ownership is above or below the modal 1 % because
the ownership distribution is bounded below at 0%, and the resulting compressed distribution below 1 % obscures
these findings in linear specifications.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e524a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e531" publication-type="other">
Of course, our results do not imply that performance of low-GP ownership funds would not improve further if
ownership were exogenously forced to be higher, holding all else equal.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e541a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e548" publication-type="other">
We have explored alternative specifications, including splitting the sample into performance terciles, to try to
identify settings in which there is a negative relation between net-of-fee performance and fees. We find no such
evidence. If anything, there is some evidence of a positive fee/performance relation among high-performing
funds, but this evidence is weak.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e564a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e571" publication-type="other">
The 2012 10-K filings of Blackstone and KKR corroborate these differences. Blackstone reports (page 92) 2012
base management fees of $348,594,000 and "transaction and other fees" of $100,080,000, so the latter is 28.7%
of the former. For KKR (from the "private markets" segment data, page 210) the analogous percentage is 27.3%.
Given the prominence of these partnerships, it is likely they charge among the highest transaction and monitoring
fees in the industry.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e590a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e597" publication-type="other">
Put differently, a systematic tendency to call capital in bad times when it is costly for LPs to provide it, and to
distribute capital in good times when it is less valuable because other investments are paying off as well, suggests
greater systematic riskiness from an LP's perspective.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e610a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e617" publication-type="other">
Our conclusions are unaffected by instead using indicator variables for whether management fee is above the
fund-type specific median, for whether the carry is less than, equal to, or greater than 20%, and for whether
GP ownership is less than 0.99%, greater than 1.01%, or in between. Further, although the specifications in
Table 5 include all cash flow observations, conclusions are unaffected by restricting the call specifications
to observations in which the fund has some uncalled capital, and restricting the distribution specifications to
observations for which some capital has previously been called. Conclusions are also unaffected by examining
calls and distributions separately.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e644a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e651" publication-type="other">
Another way to evaluate risk, that may be appropriate given the GP's option-like compensation structure, is to
evaluate the standard deviation of performance in a loss region. We find no evidence that among funds with PME
less than one, higher-fee funds have a greater cross-sectional standard deviation of PME.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e664a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e671" publication-type="other">
In Table 6, we focus on the full sample of funds because many buyout funds from the most recent boom have
not yet liquidated by the end of the sample period. Results are similar in the liquidated sample. Also, in Table 6,
we include the contract terms as continuous (demeaned) variables. Results are similar using instead indicator
variables for whether the management fee is above the fund-type specific median, for whether the carry is less
than, equal to, or greater than 20%, and for whether GP ownership is less than 0.99%, greater than 1.01%, or in
between. The conclusions of Table 7, presented below, are also robust to all of these.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e694a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e701" publication-type="other">
These issues are related to the "grandstanding" incentives explored by Gompers (1996), by which GPs have
incentives to exit investments too early to aid in raising their next fund.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e711a1310">
            <label>2^</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e718" publication-type="other">
Waterfall dates vary considerably across funds in calendar time, so systematic patterns in behavior around
waterfall dates are unlikely to be driven by market conditions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e728a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e735" publication-type="other">
Unlike capital calls, distributions are not capped at 100% of fund size.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e742a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e749" publication-type="other">
See, for example, "Private Equity Trapped in 'Zombie Funds.'" Financial Times, December 11, 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e757a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e764" publication-type="other">
It also potentially would be consistent with the notion that funds that expect to make longer-term investments are
more likely to have a fee basis change to invested capital. However, the impact of such a change on total fees paid
would be smaller for such funds (as invested capital is closer to committed capital for a longer period of time),
so it is equally plausible that a fee basis change is more likely in funds that are expected to have shorter-term
investments. Indeed, venture capital investments tend to be longer lived than buyout ones, yet our data show that
buyout funds are more likely to have a fee basis change to invested capital.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d64e796a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e800" publication-type="other">
Agrawal, V., N. Daniel, and N. Naik. 2009. Role of managerial incentives and discretion in hedge fund
performance. Journal of Finance 64:2221-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e810a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e814" publication-type="other">
Berk, J., and R. Green. 2004. Mutual fund flows and performance in rational markets. Journal of Political
Economy 112:1269-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e824a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e828" publication-type="other">
Berk, J., and J. van Binsbergen. 2011. Measuring skill of active managers. Working Paper, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e835a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e839" publication-type="other">
Busse, J. A., A. Goyal, and S. Wahal. 2010. Performance persistence in institutional investment management.
Journal of Finance 65:765-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e850a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e854" publication-type="other">
Choi, W., A. Metrick, and A. Yasuda. 2011. A model of private equity fund compensation. Working Paper, Yale
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e864a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e868" publication-type="other">
Carhart, M. M. 1997. On persistence in mutual fund performance. Journal of Finance 52:57-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e875a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e879" publication-type="other">
Carlin, B. A. 2009. Strategic price complexity in retail financial markets. Journal of Financial Economics
91:278-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e889a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e893" publication-type="other">
Chung, J.-W., B. A. Sensoy, L. Stern, and M. S. Weisbach. 2012. Pay for performance from future fund flows:
The case of private equity. Review of Financial Studies 25:3259-304.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e903a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e907" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. 2005. The risk and return of venture capital. Journal of Financial Economics 75:3-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e914a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e918" publication-type="other">
Da Rin, M., T. Hellmann, and M. Puri. Forthcoming. A survey of venture capital research. In Handbook of the
economics of finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e929a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e933" publication-type="other">
Driessen, J., T.-C. Lin, and L. Phalippou. 2012. A new method to estimate risk and return of non-traded assets
from cash flows: The case of private equity funds. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 47:511-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e943a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e947" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and K. R. French. 2010. Luck versus skill in the cross-section of mutual fund returns. Journal of
Finance 65:1915-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e957a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e961" publication-type="other">
Gabaix, X., and D. Laibson. 2006. Shrouded attributes, consumer myopia, and information suppression in
competitive markets. Quarterly Journal of Economics 121:505-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e971a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e975" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P. 1996. Grandstanding in the venture capital industry. Journal of Financial Economics
42:133-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e985a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e989" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P., and J. Lerner. 1999. An analysis of compensation in the U.S. venture capital partnership. Journal
of Financial Economics 51:3-44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e999a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1003" publication-type="other">
Hochberg, Y., A. Ljungqvist, and A. Vissing-Jorgensen. Forthcoming. Informational hold-up and performance
persistence in venture capital. Review of Financial Studies.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1014a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1018" publication-type="other">
Harris, R. S., T. Jenkinson, and S. N. Kaplan. Forthcoming. Private equity performance: What do we know?
Journal of Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1028a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1032" publication-type="other">
Harris, R. S., T. Jenkinson, and R. Stucke. 2010. A White Paper on private equity data and research. Working
Paper, UAI Foundation Consortium.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1042a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1046" publication-type="other">
Jensen, M., and W. Meckling. 1976. Theory of the firm: Managerial behavior, agency costs and ownership
structure. Journal of Financial Economics 3:305-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1056a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1060" publication-type="other">
Jones, C., and M. Rhodes-Kropf. 2003. The price of diversifiable risk in venture capital and private equity.
Working Paper, Columbia University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1070a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1074" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S. N., and A. Schoar. 2005. Private equity performance: Returns, persistence, and capital flows. Journal
of Finance 60:1791-823.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1084a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1088" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S. N., and P. Strömberg. 2009. Leveraged buyouts and private equity. Journal of Economic Perspectives
23:121-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1099a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1103" publication-type="other">
Khorana, A., H. Servaes, and L. Wedge. 2007. Portfolio manager ownership and fund performance. Journal of
Financial Economics 85:179-204.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1113a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1117" publication-type="other">
Korteweg, A., and S. Nagel. 2013. Risk-adjusting the returns to venture capital. Working Paper, Stanford
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1127a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1131" publication-type="other">
Korteweg, A., and M. Sprensen. 2010. Risk and return characteristics of venture capital-backed entrepreneurial
companies. Review of Financial Studies 23:3738-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1141a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1145" publication-type="other">
Lerner, J., A. Schoar, and W. Wongsunwai. 2007. Smart institutions, foolish choices? The limited partner
performance puzzle. Journal of Finance 62:731-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1155a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1159" publication-type="other">
Litvak, K. 2009. Venture capital partnership agreements: Understanding compensation arrangements. University
of Chicago Law Review 76:161-218.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1169a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1173" publication-type="other">
Ljungqvist, A., M. Richardson, and D. Wolfenzon. 2007. The investment behavior of buyout funds: Theory and
evidence. Working Paper, NYU Stern School of Business.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1184a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1188" publication-type="other">
Metrick, A., and A. Yasuda. 2010a. The economics of private equity funds. Review of Financial Studies
23:2303-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1198a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1202" publication-type="other">
. 2010b. Venture capital and the finance of innovation. Hoboken: Wiley &amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1209a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1213" publication-type="other">
. 2011. Venture capital and other private equity: A survey. European Financial Management 17:619-654.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1220a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1224" publication-type="other">
Morris, P., and L. Phalippou. 2012. A new approach to regulating private equity. Journal of Corporate Law
Studies 12:59-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1234a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1238" publication-type="other">
Phalippou, L. 2009. Beware of venturing into private equity. Journal of Economic Perspectives 23:1647-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1245a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1249" publication-type="other">
Phalippou, L., and O. Gottschalg. 2009. The performance of private equity funds. Review of Financial Studies
22:1747-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1260a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1264" publication-type="other">
Robinson, D. T., and B. A. Sensoy. 2011. Cyclicality, performance measurement, and cash flow liquidity in
private equity. Working Paper, Duke University and Ohio State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1274a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1278" publication-type="other">
Sensoy, B. A., Y. Wang, and M. S. Weisbach. 2013. Limited partner performance and the maturing of the private
equity industry. Working Paper, California State University at Fullerton and Ohio State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1288a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1292" publication-type="other">
S0rensen, M., and R. Jangannathan. 2013. The public market equivalent and private equity performance. Working
Paper, Columbia University and Northwestern University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


