<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">17</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830321</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830327</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE IDDIR: A STUDY OF AN INDIGENOUS INFORMAL FINANCIAL INSTITUTION IN ETHIOPIA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Dejene</given-names>
                  <surname>Aredo</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1993</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>77</fpage>
         <lpage>90</lpage>
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830327"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>In societies where modern financial intermediaries are underdeveloped, indigenous institutions remain indispensable. Such institutions can be considered as national resources capable of evolving into modern financial institutions appropriate to the particular socio-economic and historical backgrounds of a country. This study highlights the socio-economic importance of the iddir, an indigenous informal insurance scheme popular among urban-dwellers in Ethiopia. Using empirical evidence from surveys undertaken in Addis Ababa, the study examines the linkages between the iddir and the formal financial sector, characterizes the socio-economic status of participating households, and explains the structure of the iddir. The study has made contributions to the literature by undertaking an economic analysis of areas so far neglected by researchers. The major reasons why people prefer the iddir to the modern insurance schemes are investigated. It has been shown that the iddir has strong linkage with the commercial banking system rather than with the insurance enterprises. The place of the iddir in the financial flows system in Ethiopia has been schematically presented. The study has suggested that, in recent years, the popularity of the iddir among people from all walks of life has been growing. New types of iddir are emerging in Addis Ababa, perhaps, in response to the ever-growing social and economic insecurity in the country. The study suggests that policy-makers should create the enabling environment towards the realization of the great potentials of the iddir. Researchers have to explore more closely the yet untapped potentials of this culture-appropriate institution endemic to Ethiopia.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d57e126a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e130" publication-type="other">
AAU (1990). Recent Events and Activities, Issues No. 8 and 9 September and October.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e137a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e141" publication-type="other">
Alemayehu Seifu (1969). "Edir in Addis Ababa: A Sociological Study" Ethiopian Observer, Vol. 12 No. 1.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e148a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e152" publication-type="other">
Aleme Feyissa (1973). A Study of Like Mequas Abebe Sefer Edir (Senior Paper, School of Social Work, Addis
Ababa University).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e162a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e166" publication-type="other">
Bouman F.J. A. (1977). "Indigenous Savings and Credit Societies in the Third World", Savings and Develop-
ment' n. 4, Vol I pp. 181-219.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e177a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e181" publication-type="other">
Bouman F.J.A. and A.R. Houtman (1988). "Pawnbroking as an Instrument of Rural Banking in the Third World",
Economic Development and Cultural Change, Vol. 37 n. 1.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e191a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e195" publication-type="other">
Chandavarkar (1985). "The Non-Institutional Financial Sector in Developing Countries: Macro-economic Implica-
tions for Savings and Policies", Savings and Development n. 2 vol. XX pp. 81-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e205a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e209" publication-type="other">
Cohen and Koehn (1980). Ethiopian Provincial and Municipal Government (Michigan State University).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e216a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e220" publication-type="other">
Fekadu Gedamu (1974). "Urbanization, Polyethnic Group Voluntary Associations and National Integration in
Ethiopia". Ethiopian Journal of Development Research Vol. 1, No. 1, April pp. 71-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e230a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e234" publication-type="other">
Hammer, J.H. (1976). "Prerequisites and Limitations in the Development of Voluntary Self-Help Associations:
A Case Study and Comparison". Anthropological Quarterly Vol. 49, No. 2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e244a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e248" publication-type="other">
Landuber Araya (1983). The Development of Savings and Credit Co-operatives in Ethiopia (Senior Paper, Depart-
ment of Economics AAU).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e259a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e263" publication-type="other">
Levine, Donald N. (1972). Wax and Gold: Tradition and Innovation in Ethiopian Culture (University of Chicago
Press).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e273a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e277" publication-type="other">
Mamo Wudneh (1989). Iddirtegnoch (Addis Ababa: in Amharic. Kuraz Publishing Agency).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e284a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e288" publication-type="other">
Mauri (1987). The Role of Financial Intermediation in the Mobilization and Allocation of Household Saving in
Developing Countries: Interlinks between Organized and Informal Circuits: The Case of Ethiopia (Interna-
tional Experts Meeting on the Domestic Savings Mobilization. East-West Centre, Honolulu, 2-4 June 1987).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e301a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e305" publication-type="other">
Mekuria Balcha (1973). Edir: Its Role in Development and Social Change in Addis Ababa (Senior Paper, School
of Social Work, Addis Ababa University).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e319" publication-type="other">
Miracle, M.P., D. Miracle and Cohen (1980). "Informal Savings Mobilization in Africa", Economic Development
and Cultural Change, Vol. 28, No. 4 (July) pp. 701-724.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e329a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e333" publication-type="other">
Salole, G. (1986). Ekub, Edir and Meredaja Mahber as Potential Development Tools in Addis Ababa (Symposium
on the Centenary of Addis Ababa November 24-25, IES, AAU).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


