<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90007202</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Original Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Evaluation of wind resource potential in mountainous region considering morphometric terrain characteristics</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kim</surname>
                  <given-names>Hyun-Goo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kang</surname>
                  <given-names>Yong-Heack</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kim</surname>
                  <given-names>Jin-Young</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>New and Renewable Energy Resource Center, Korea Institute of Energy Research, Daejeon, Korea</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>41</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e90007199</issue-id>
         <fpage>114</fpage>
         <lpage>123</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© SAGE Publications Ltd, 2017</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90007202"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>In South Korea, where 64% of the national territory is mountainous, good wind resources in inland areas are mostly situated in high mountain regions. To develop a wind farm in a mountain region, the sloping of mountains and their shielding from wind by the surrounding topology should be considered. It is generally most advantageous to install wind turbines along a ridge that is open in all directions. This article presents a methodology for evaluating suitable sites for wind farm development by identifying suitable ridges using morphometric analysis, while excluding the geographical and social environmental exclusion factors and superposing them on the wind resource map to find the area having a specific level or higher wind power density. The result of the proposed suitable site analysis and existing wind farms was assessed to verify the feasibility of the method of analyzing suitable sites on ridges. The wind resource potential in Gangwon Province when calculated using a method based on conventionally suitable site and the method based on ridge analysis was 9 and 5 GW, respectively. The result confirmed that the conventional area-based potential calculation without consideration of the morphometric terrain characteristics overestimated wind resource potential by around 80% compared to the ridge analysis method of calculation presented in this article.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label>
            <kwd>Wind resource potential</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>morphometric terrain characteristics</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>wind turbine spacing</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>wind turbine capacity density</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>South Korea</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grassi S, Chokani N and Abhari RS (2012) Large scale technical and economical assessment of wind energy potential with a GIS tool: Case study Iowa. Energy Policy 45: 73–85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoogwijk M, Vries B and Turkenburg W (2004) Assessment of the global and regional geographical, technical and economic potential of onshore wind power. Energy Economics 26: 889–919.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim H-G and Kang Y-H (2010) The 2010 wind resource map of the Korean Peninsular. Journal of the Wind Engineering Institute of Korea 16: 167–172.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim H-G, Kang Y-H, Hwang H-J, et al. (2014) Evaluation of inland wind resource potential of South Korea according to environmental conservation value assessment. Energy Procedia 57: 773–781.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim J-S, Kim H-G and Park H-D (2016) Surface wind regionalization based on similarity of time-series wind vectors. Asian Journal of Atmospheric Environment 10: 80–89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Korea Environment Institute (2012) Environmental assessment guidelines for the mountain ridges of Gimaek of Backdudaegan in Korea. Policy Report for the Korean Ministry of Environment. Report no. 2012-11, December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Korea Forest Service (2011) Management of Mountainous Districts Act, Act no.10977.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Korea Forest Service (2012) Baekdudaegan Mountain Range Protection Act, Act no.11565.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mari R, Bottai L, Busillo C, et al. (2011) A GIS-based interactive web decision support system for planning wind farms in Tuscany (Italy). Renewable Energy 56: 754–763.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nguyen KQ (2007) Wind energy in Vietnam: Resource assessment, development status and future implications. Energy Policy 35: 1405–1413.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wood J (2009) The LandSerf Manual. London: City University London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
