<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">jfinance</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j100221</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00221082</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15406261</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25094469</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Blurring Firm Boundaries: The Role of Venture Capital in Strategic Alliances</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Laura</given-names>
                  <surname>Lindsey</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date>
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2008</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">63</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25094464</issue-id>
         <fpage>1137</fpage>
         <lpage>1168</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2008 The American Finance Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25094469"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This study documents a new value-added role of venture capitalists and addresses important questions about how resources are combined to create firms. As part of the nexus of contracts surrounding a firm, strategic alliances can be viewed as relational contracts that blur firm boundaries. This paper provides evidence that alliances are more frequent among companies sharing a common venture capitalist. The effect is concentrated in alliances in which contracting problems are more pronounced, consistent with venture capitalists utilizing informational and other advantages in providing resources to firms. Further, these alliances improve the probability of exit for venture-backed firms.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group>
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d80e134a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d80e141" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, Sensoy, and Stromberg (2002)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d80e148a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d80e155" publication-type="other">
Gulati, Nohria, and Zaheer
(2000)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d80e165a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d80e172" publication-type="other">
Allen and Phillips (2000)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d80e188a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e192" publication-type="other">
Admati, Anat, and Paul Pfleiderer, 1994, Robust financial contracting and the role of venture
capitalists, Journal of Finance 49, 371-402.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e202a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e206" publication-type="other">
Allen, Jeffrey, and Gordon Phillips, 2000, Corporate equity ownership, strategic alliances, and
product market relationships, Journal of Finance 55, 2791-2815.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e216a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e220" publication-type="other">
Aoki, Masahiko, 2000, Information and governance in the Silicon Valley model, in Xavier Vives, ed.:
Corporate Governance: Theoretical and Empirical Perspectives (Cambridge University Press,
Cambridge, UK).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e233a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e237" publication-type="other">
Baker, George, Robert Gibbons, and Kevin Murphy, 2002, Relational contracts and the theory of
the firm, Quarterly Journal of Economics 117, 39-83.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e248a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e252" publication-type="other">
Baker, Malcolm, and Paul Gompers, 2003, The determinants of board structure at the initial public
offering, Journal of Law and Economics 46, 569-598.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e262a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e266" publication-type="other">
Barry, Christopher, Chris Muscarella, John Peavey, and Michael Vetsuypens, 1990, The role of
venture capital in the creation of public companies, Journal of Financial Economics 27, 447-
471.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e279a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e283" publication-type="other">
Chamberlain, Gary, 1980, Analysis of covariance with qualitative data, Review of Economic Studies
47, 225-238.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e293a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e297" publication-type="other">
Chan, Su, John Kensinger, Arthur Keown, and John Martin, 1997, Do strategic alliances create
value? Journal of Financial Economics 46, 199-221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e307a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e311" publication-type="other">
Coase, Ronald, 1937, The nature of the firm, Economica 4, 386-405.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e318a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e322" publication-type="other">
Das, Somnath, Pradyot Sen, and Sanjit Sengupta, 1998, Impact of strategic alliances on firm
valuation, The Academy of Management Journal 41, 27-41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e333a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e337" publication-type="other">
Eisenhardt, Kathleen, and Claudia Schoonhoven, 1996, Resource-based view of strategic alliance
formation: Strategic and social explanations in entrepreneurial firms, Organization Science 7,
136-150.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e350a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e354" publication-type="other">
Garvey, Gerald, 1995, Why reputation favors joint ventures over vertical and horizontal integration:
A simple model, Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization 28, 387-397.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e364a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e368" publication-type="other">
Gomes-Casseres, Benjamin, Adam Jaffe, and John Hagedoorn, 2006, Do alliances promote knowl-
edge flows? Journal of Financial Economics 80, 5-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e378a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e382" publication-type="other">
Gompers, Paul, 1995, Optimal investment, monitoring, and the staging of venture capital, Journal
of Finance 50, 1461-1489.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e392a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e396" publication-type="other">
Gompers, Paul, 1996, Grandstanding in the venture capital industry, Journal of Financial Eco-
nomics 42, 133-156.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e406a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e410" publication-type="other">
Gompers, Paul, Anna Kovner, Josh Lerner, and David Scharfstein, 2007, Venture capital invest-
ment cycles: The impact of public markets, Journal of Financial Economics 87, 1-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e421a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e425" publication-type="other">
Gompers, Paul, and Josh Lerner, 1998, Venture capital distributions: Short-run and long-run re-
actions, Journal of Finance 53, 2168-2183.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e435a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e439" publication-type="other">
Gompers, Paul, and Josh Lerner, 2000, The determinants of corporate venture capital success: Or-
ganizational structure, incentives, and complementarities, in Randall Morck, ed.: Concentrated
Ownership (University of Chicago Press, Chicago, IL).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e452a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e456" publication-type="other">
Gompers, Paul, Josh Lerner, and David Scharfstein, 2005, Entrepreneurial spawning: Public cor-
porations and the genesis of new ventures, 1986-1999, Journal of Finance 60, 577-614.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e466a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e470" publication-type="other">
Gorman, Michael, and William Sahlman, 1989, What do venture capitalists do? Journal of Business
Venturing 4, 231-248.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e480a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e484" publication-type="other">
Grossman, Sanford, and Oliver Hart, 1986, The costs and benefits of ownership: A theory of lateral
and vertical integration, Journal of Political Economy 94, 691-719.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e494a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e498" publication-type="other">
Gulati, Ranjay, 1998, Alliances and networks, Strategic Management Journal 19, 293-317.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e506a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e510" publication-type="other">
Gulati, Ranjay, 1999, Network location and learning: The influence of network resources and firm
capabilities on alliance formation, Strategic Management Journal 20, 397-420.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e520a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e524" publication-type="other">
Gulati, Ranjay, Nitin Nohria, and Akbar Zaheer, 2000, Strategic networks, Strategic Management
Journal 21, 203-215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e534a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e538" publication-type="other">
Hart, Oliver, and John Moore, 1990, Property rights and the nature of the firm, Journal of Political
Economy 98, 1119-1158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e548a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e552" publication-type="other">
Hellmann, Thomas, 2002, A theory of strategic venture investing, Journal of Financial Economics
64, 285-314.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e562a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e566" publication-type="other">
Hellmann, Thomas, and Manju Puri, 2002, Venture capital and the professionalization of start-up
firms: Empirical evidence, Journal of Finance 57, 169-197.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e576a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e580" publication-type="other">
Hochberg, Yael, 2004, Venture capital and corporate governance in the newly public firm, Working
paper, Northwestern University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e591a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e595" publication-type="other">
Hochberg, Yael, Yang Lu, and Alexander Ljungqvist, 2007, Whom you know matters: Venture
capital networks and investment performance, Journal of Finance 62, 251-301.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e605a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e609" publication-type="other">
Hsu, David, 2004, Do entrepreneurs pay for affiliation? Journal of Finance 59, 1805-1844.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e616a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e620" publication-type="other">
Jensen, Michael, and William Meckling, 1976, Theory of the firm: Managerial behavior, agency
costs and ownership structure, Journal of Financial Economics 3, 305-360.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e630a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e634" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, Steven, and Antoinette Schoar, 2005, Private equity performance: Returns, persistence
and capital flows, Journal of Finance 60, 1791-1823.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e644a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e648" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, Steven, Berk Sensoy, and Per Stromberg, 2002, How well do venture capital databases
reflect actual investments? Working paper, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e658a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e662" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, Steven, and Per Stromberg, 2003, Financial contracting meets the real world: An empirical
study of venture capital contracts, Review of Economic Studies 70, 281-315.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e673a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e677" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, Steven, and Per Stromberg, 2004, Contracts, characteristics, and actions: Evidence from
venture capital analyses, Journal of Finance 59, 2177-2210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e687a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e691" publication-type="other">
Koh, Jeongsuk, and N. Venkat Venkatraman, 1991, Joint venture formations and stock market
reactions: An assessment in the information technology sector, The Academy of Management
Journal 34,869-892.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e704a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e708" publication-type="other">
Larson, Andrea, 1992, Network dyads in entrepreneurial settings: A study of the governance of
exchange relationships, Administrative Science Quarterly 37, 76-104.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e718a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e722" publication-type="other">
Lerner, Josh, 1995, Venture capitalists and the oversight of private firms, Journal of Finance 50,
302-318.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e732a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e736" publication-type="other">
Lerner, Josh, and Robert Merges, 1998, The control of strategic alliances: An empirical analysis of
biotechnology collaborations, Journal of Industrial Economics 46, 125-156.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e746a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e750" publication-type="other">
Lerner, Josh, Hilary Shane, and Alexander Tsai, 2003, Do equity financing cycles matter? Evidence
from biotechnology alliances, Journal of Financial Economics 67, 411-446.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e761a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e765" publication-type="other">
McConnell, John, and Timothy Nantell, 1985, Corporate combinations: The case of joint ventures,
Journal of Finance 40, 519-526.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e775a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e779" publication-type="other">
Megginson, William, and Kathleen Weiss, 1991, Venture capital certification in initial public offer-
ings, Journal of Finance 46, 879-903.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e789a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e793" publication-type="other">
Robinson, David, and Toby Stuart, 2007, Network effects in the governance of strategic alliances,
Journal of Law, Economics, and Organizations 23, 242-273.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e803a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e807" publication-type="other">
Santhanakrishnan, Mukunthan, 2003, The impact of complementarity on the performance of en-
trepreneurial companies, Working paper, Arizona State University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e817a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e821" publication-type="other">
Sørensen, Morten, 2007, How smart is smart money? An empirical two-sided matching model of
venture capital, Journal of Finance 62, 2725-2762.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d80e831a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d80e835" publication-type="other">
Williamson, Oliver, 1991, Comparative economic organization: The analysis of discrete structural
alternatives, Administrative Science Quarterly 36, 269-296.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
