<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186480</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44437148</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PART II</subject>
               <subj-group>
                  <subject>Engines, Fuels, Lubricants, Supercharging</subject>
               </subj-group>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Notes on Valve-Spring Design</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>W. T.</given-names>
                  <surname>Donkin</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1928</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>404</fpage>
         <lpage>408</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44437148"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>APAPER on Valve-Spring Surge, by Mr. Donkin and H. H. Clark, which was presented at the Semi-Annual Meeting of the Society in May, 1927, was presented during the last season by Mr. Donkin at Section meetings in Buffalo, Chicago and Milwaukee. At a meeting of the Cleveland Section he delivered a paper on Valve-Spring Design, part of which is printed herewith. The remainder was a duplication of the Semi-Annual Meeting paper. At each of these Section meetings the subjects of valve-spring surge and valve-spring design were discussed. Some of the discussion was upon part of the original paper in which were compared two valve-springs, the original design vibrating noisily and the improved design being satisfactory. The redesigned spring was smaller and the material was subject to higher apparent stress, according to static formulas, but it was less liable to breakage and was subject to lower actual stress because free from the surging that caused more than the calculated static stress in the original spring. Several of the discussers confirmed points in the paper, and additional information was contributed on multiple and concentric springs and on methods of testing. Discussion at the various Section meetings is included herewith.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


