<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26956199</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Wind Tunnel Tests on Floating Offshore Wind Turbines</article-title>
            <subtitle>A Proposal for Hardware-in-the-Loop Approach to Validate Numerical Codes</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bayati</surname>
                  <given-names>I.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Belloli</surname>
                  <given-names>M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Facchinetti</surname>
                  <given-names>A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Giappino</surname>
                  <given-names>S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">37</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26956197</issue-id>
         <fpage>557</fpage>
         <lpage>568</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26956199"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper describes the realization of a 2-DoF experimental rig, performed at Politecnico di Milano Wind Tunnel, aimed at simulating the motion of a floating wind turbine scale model, due to combined effect of hydrodynamic and aerodynamic loads. As floating offshore wind farms are becoming objects of interest among the international scientific community, experimental tests have been increasingly demanded to support dynamic and structural numerical simulations. Furthermore measurements on real prototypes are very complex and expensive and it is difficult to use these data to validate prediction models because of the uncertainties in the definition of the environmental data, such as sea state and incoming wind. The motivation of this project is to provide an experimental set-up working in a fully controlled test environment (with measurable input/output) in order to validate numerical codes. The paper describes the features of the experimental rig, the results coming from the validation tests on the rig, through a dedicated “off-line” experimental campaign and, conclusively, a proposal for a “Hardware-In-The-Loop” real time functioning mode.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>[1]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">S. Butterfield, W. Musial, and J. Jonkman, P. Sclavounos, “Engineering Challenges for Floating Offshore Wind Turbines”, Tech. rep. NREL/CP-500-38776, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>[2]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">D. Matha, “Model Development and Loads Analysis of an Offshore Wind Turbine on a Tension Leg platform with a Comparison to Other Floating Turbine Concepts”, Tech. rep. NREL/SR-500-45891, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>[3]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">J. Jonkman, “Dynamics Modeling and Loads Analysis of an Offshore Floating Wind Turbine”, Tech. rep. National Renewable Energy Laboratory, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>[4]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">J. Jonkman, S. Butterfield, W. Musial, and G. Scott, “Definition of a 5-MW Reference Wind Turbine for Offshore System Development”, Tech rep. NREL/TP-500-38060, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>[5]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">J. Jonkman, “Definition of the Floating System for Phase IV of OC3”, NREL/TP-500-47535, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>[6]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">B. Skaare, T.D. Hanson, F.G. Nielsen, R. Yttervik, A.M. Hansen, K. Thomsen, and T.J. Larsen “Integrated Dynamic Analysis of Floating Offshore Wind Turbines”, European Wind Energy Conference, Milan, Italy, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>[7]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">D. Roddier, C. Cermelli, A. Aubault, A. Weinstein, “Windfloat: a floating foundation for offshore wind turbines”, Journal of Renewable and Sustainable Energy, 2(3), art. No. 033104, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>[8]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">J.-P. Xiao, J. Wu, L. Chen, Z.-Y. Shi, “Particle image velocimetry (PIV) measurements of tip vortex wake structure of wind turbine”, Applied Mathematics Mechanics (English Edition), 32(6), 729-738, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>[9]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">L. P. Chamorro, F. Porté-Agel, “A Wind-Tunnel Investigation of Wind-Turbine Wakes: Boundary-Layer Turbulence Effects”, Boundary-Layer Meteorology, 132, 129-149, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>[10]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">J. Jonkman, “Loads Analysis of a Floating Offshore Wind Turbine Using Fully Coupled Simulation”, Tech rep. NREL/CP-500-41714, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>[11]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Wind turbines - Design requirements for offshore wind turbines. BS EN 61400-3:2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>[12]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">S. Butterfield J. Jonkman W. Musial E.N. Wayman P.D. Sclavounos, “Coupled Dynamic Modeling of Floating Wind Turbine Systems”, Tech. rep. National Renewable Energy Laboratory, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>[13]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">G. Diana, F. Resta, A. Zasso, M. Belloli, D. Rocchi, “Forced motion and free motion aeroelastic tests on a new concept dynamometric section model of the Messina suspension bridge”, Journal of wind engineering and industrial aerodynamics, 94(5), 341−363, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>[14]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">C. Lugni, E. Marino, C. Borri, “Influence of wind-waves energy transfer on the impulsive hydrodynamic loads acting on offshore wind turbines”, Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics, 99(6−7), 767−775, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Wind turbine 1/25 scale model on the test rig in the wind tunnel BL test section.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Top view sketch of wind tunnel turntable.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>2-DOF mechanism.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Details of the test rig: surge/sway actuation.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5.</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Details of the test rig: roll/pitch actuation.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Details of the test rig: slider-crank and balance support.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>2D-sketch of wind tunnel tests.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Test parameters of the “pure-surge” experimental validation campaign</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Motor torque for “static” inflow conditions</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Motor torque as function of apparent wind for a sinusoidal imposed surge motion of 0.6 Hz at various amplitudes.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Torque at the base of the tower generated by drag force on the rotor as function of apparent wind: sinusoidal imposed surge motion with 0.6 Hz frequency and various amplitudes</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 11:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Motor torque: amplitudes and phases as functions of reduced velocity, for a sinusoidal imposed surge motion of 0.6 Hz.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 12:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Hardware In The Loop scheme.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 13:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Matlab/Simulink implementation of the HIL procedure.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
