<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014366</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>English Language Learners’ Strategies for Reading Computer-Based Texts at Home and in School</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Park</surname>
                  <given-names>Ho-Ryong</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>a</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Ho-Ryong Park is Assistant Professor of Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages (TESOL) in the Department of English and Philosophy at Murray State University. His research interests focus on TESOL/ESOL education, second language and literacy acquisition, and technology incorporation in diverse learning contexts.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kim</surname>
                  <given-names>Deoksoon</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>b</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Deoksoon Kim is Associate Professor in the Lynch School of Education, Department of Teacher Education, Special Education, Curriculum and Instruction at Boston College. Her research focuses on second language literacy, sociocultural theory in language learning, and incorporating instructional technologies into teacher education through social media. She has published in Computers and Education, Language Learning Journal, TESOL Journal, CALICO Journal, IALLT Journal, English Leadership Quarterly, Journal of Reading Education, Journal of Educational Computing Research, and Multilingual Education, among others. She has done research, teaching, and professional development in South Korea, the UK, Canada, and the USA.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>a</sup>Murray State University.</aff>
            <aff id="a2">
               <sup>b</sup>Lynch School of Education, Boston College.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>33</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014360</issue-id>
         <fpage>380</fpage>
         <lpage>409</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2016, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014366"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>This study investigated four elementary-level English language learners’ (ELLs’) use of strategies for reading computer-based texts at home and in school. The ELLs in this study were in the fourth and fifth grades in a public elementary school. We identify the ELLs’ strategies for reading computer-based texts in home and school environments. We present a taxonomy of five reading-strategy categories, which includes 15 total strategies that they pursued at home and in school. We describe the central role of dialogue in helping ELLs learn to read computer-based texts: The learners engaged in real and virtual dialogues with adults, peers, authors, and themselves, in ways that enhanced their development of effective reading strategies. We discuss pedagogical implications of our findings, describing how parents and teachers might work separately and together to facilitate ELLs’ reading in today’s learning contexts that include electronic literacies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>ELLs’ reading of computer-based texts</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>ELLs’ reading strategies</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>electronic literacies</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>hybrid reading and learning</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>dialogism</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ACTFL. (2012). ACTFL proficiency guidelines 2012. Retrieved from http://www.actfl.org/publications/guidelines-and-manuals/actfl-proficiency-guidelines-2012/english</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Afflerbach, P., &amp; Cho, B. Y. (2008). Identifying and describing constructively responsive comprehension strategies in new and traditional forms of reading. In S. Israel &amp; G. Duffy (Eds.), Handbook of reading comprehension research (pp. 69–90). Mahwah, NJ: Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akbulut, Y. (2007). Effects of multimedia annotations on incidental vocabulary learning and reading comprehension of advanced learners of English as a foreign language. Instructional Science, 35(6), 499–517. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11251-007-9016-7</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Al-Seghayer, K. (2001). The effect of multimedia annotation modes on L2 vocabulary acquisition: A comparative study. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 5(11), 202–232.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anstey, M., &amp; Bull, G. (2006). Teaching and learning multiliteracies: Changing times, changing literacies. Newark, DE: International Reading Association.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bakhtin, M. M. (1981). The dialogic imagination: Four essays by M. M. Bakhtin (C. Emerson &amp; M. Holquist, Trans.). Austin, TX: University of Texas Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bakhtin, M. M. (1986). Speech genres and other late essays (V. W. McGee, Trans.). Austin, TX: University of Press. (Original work published 1979)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bannert, M., &amp; Reimann, P. (2012). Supporting self-regulated hypermedia learning through prompts. Instructional Science, 40(1), 193–211. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11251-011-9167-4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beatty, K. (2010). Teaching and researching: Computer-assisted language learning (2nd ed.). New York, NY: Taylor &amp; Francis.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Becker, H. J., &amp; Ravitz, J. (1999). The influence of computer and Internet use on teachers’ pedagogical practice and perceptions. Journal of Research on Computing in Education, 31(4), 356–384. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/08886504.1999.10782260</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berkeley, S., Marshak, L., Mastropieri, M. A., &amp; Scruggs, T. E. (2011). Improving student comprehension of social studies text: A self-questioning strategy for inclusive middle school classes. Remedial and Special Education, 32(2), 105–113. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0741932510361261</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blanchard, J. (1997). The family–school connection and technology. Proceedings of the Families, Technologies, and Education Conference. Retrieved from http://ceep.crc.uiuc.edu/eecearchive/books/fte/links/blanchard.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carrell, P. L., &amp; Eisterhold, J. C. (1983). Schema theory and ESL reading pedagogy. TESOL Quarterly, 17(4), 553–573. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.2307/3586613</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chatel, R. (2002). New technology, new literacy: Creating a bridge for English language learners. New England Reading Association Journal, 38(3), 45–49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, M., Ferdig, R., &amp; Wood, A. (2003). Understanding technology-enhanced storybooks and their roles in teaching and learning: An investigation of electronic storybooks in education. Journal of Literacy and Technology, 3. Retrieved from http://www.researchgate.net/profile/Richard_Ferdig/publication/249725276_Understanding_technology-enhanced_storybooks_and_their_roles_in_teaching_and_learning_An_investigation_of_electronic_storybooks_in_education/links/00b7d52af9d434089a000000.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cho, B.-Y. (2013). Adolescents’ constructively responsive reading strategy use in a critical Internet reading task. Reading Research Quarterly, 48(4), 329–332. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/rrq.49</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cho, B.-Y., &amp; Afflerbach, P. (2015). Reading on the Internet: Realizing and constructing potential texts. Journal of Adolescent &amp; Adult Literacy, 58(6), 504–517. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/jaal.387</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chou, I.-C. (2012). Understanding on-screen reading behaviors in academic contexts: A case study of five graduate English-as-a-second-language students. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 25(5), 411–433. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2011.597768</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chun, D. M., &amp; Plass, J. L. (1996). Effects of multimedia annotations on vocabulary acquisition. Modern Language Journal, 80(2), 183–198. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.1996.tb01159.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cohen, A. D. (2011). Second language learner strategies. In E. Hinkel (Ed.), Handbook of research in second language teaching and learning (pp. 563–579). New York, NY: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coiro, J. (2003). Exploring literacy on the Internet. The Reading Teacher, 56(5), 458–464.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coiro, J. (2011). Predicting reading comprehension on the Internet: Contributions of offline reading skills, online reading skills, and prior knowledge. Journal of Literacy Research, 43(4), 352–392. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1086296X11421979</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coiro, J., &amp; Dobler, E. (2007). Exploring the online reading comprehension strategies used by sixth-grade skilled readers to search for and locate information on the Internet. Reading Research Quarterly, 42(2), 214–257. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1598/RRQ.42.2.2</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cummins, J. (1991). Interdependence of first- and second-language proficiency in bilingual children. In E. Bialystok (Ed.), Language processing in bilingual children (pp. 70–89).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">New York, NY: Cambridge University Press. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/CBO9780511620652.006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cummins, J. (2011). Literacy engagement: Fueling academic growth for English learners. The Reading Teacher, 65(2), 142–146. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/TRTR.01022</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davey, B., &amp; McBride, S. (1986). Effects of question-generation training on reading comprehension. Journal of Educational Psychology, 78, 256–262. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/0022-0663.78.4.256</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dillon, P. M., &amp; Leonard, D. C. (1998). Multimedia and the Web from A to Z (2nd ed.). Phoenix, AZ: Oryx Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elshair, H. M. (2002). The strategies used by students to read educational websites and their relation to website usability and text design (Unpublished doctoral dissertation). University of Pittsburgh, PA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ericsson, K. A., &amp; Simon, H. A. (1993). Protocol analysis: Verbal reports as data (2nd ed.). Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eskey, D. E. (2005). Reading in a second language. In E. Hinkel (Ed.), Handbook of research in second language teaching and learning (pp. 563–579). Mahwah, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fitzgerald, J. (1995). English-as-a-second-language learners’ cognitive reading processes: A review of research in the United States. Review of Educational Research, 65(2), 145–190. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.3102/00346543065002145</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Freire, P. (2000). Pedagogy of the oppressed. New York, NY: Continuum International. Gambrell, L. B. (2011). Seven rules of engagement: What’s most important to know about motivation to read. The Reading Teacher, 65(3), 172–178. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/ 10.1002/TRTR.01024</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Garris, R., Ahlers, R., &amp; Driskell, J. E. (2002). Games, motivation, and learning: A research and practice model. Simulation &amp; Gaming, 33(4), 441–467. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1046878102238607</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goodman, K. (1984). Unity in reading. In A. Purves &amp; O. Niles (Eds.), Becoming readers in a complex society: 83rd yearbook of the National Society for the Study of Education (pp. 79–114). Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hartman, D. K. (1995). Eight readers reading: The intertextual links of proficient readers reading multiple passages. Reading Research Quarterly, 30(3), 520–561. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.2307/747631</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heller, R. S. (1990). The role of hypermedia in education: A look at the research issues. Journal of Research on Computing in Education, 22(4), 431–441. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/08886504.1990.10781932</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hsieh, P., &amp; Dwyer, F. (2009). The instructional effect of online reading strategies and learning styles on student academic achievement. Educational Technology &amp; Society, 12(2), 36–50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, H. (2013). Online reading strategies at work: What teachers think and what students do. ReCALL, 25(3), 340–358. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0958344013000153</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, H., Chern, C., &amp; Lin, C. (2009). EFL learners’ use of online reading strategies and comprehension of texts: An exploratory study. Computers &amp; Education, 52(1), 13–26. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2008.06.003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacobs, G. M., Dufon, P., &amp; Hong, C. H. (1994). L1 and L2 vocabulary glosses in L2 reading passages: Their effectiveness for increasing comprehension and vocabulary knowledge. Journal of Research in Reading, 17(1), 19–28. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10. 1111/j.1467-9817.1994.tb00049.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kellner, D. (2001). New technologies/new literacies: Reconstructing education for the new millennium. Teaching Education, 11(3), 245–265. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/713698975</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, D. (2011). Dialogic meaning construction and emergent reading domains among four young English language learners in second-language reading. Multilingual Education, 1, Article 2. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/2191-5059-1-2</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kohl, G. O., Lengua, L. J., &amp; McMahon, R. J. (2000). Parental involvement in school: Conceptualizing multiple dimensions and their relations with family and demographic risk factors. Journal of School Psychology, 38(6), 501–523. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0022-4405(00)00050-9</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kommers, P. A. M., Grabinger, S., &amp; Dunlap, J. C. (1996). Hypermedia learning environments: Instructional design and integration. Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuiper, E., Volman, M., &amp; Terwel, J. (2005). The web as an information resource in K–12 education: Strategies for supporting students in searching and processing information. Review of Educational Research, 75(3), 285–328. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.3102/00346543075003285</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lau, K. (2006). Reading strategy use between Chinese good and poor readers: A thinkaloud study. Journal of Research in Reading, 29(4), 383–399. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9817.2006.00302.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lawson, M. A. (2003). School–family relations in context: Parent and teacher perceptions of parent involvement. Urban Education, 38(1), 77–133. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0042085902238687</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, J. (2006). Exploring the relationship between electronic literacy and heritage language maintenance. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 10(2), 93–113.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, O., &amp; Buxton, C. A. (2010). Diversity and equity in science education: Research, policy, and practice. New York, NY: Teachers College Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, S., &amp; Chae, Y. (2007). Children’s Internet use in a family context: Influence on family relationships and parental mediation. CyberPsychology &amp; Behavior, 10(5), 640–644. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1089/cpb.2007.9975</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lincoln, Y. S., &amp; Guba, E. G. (1985). Naturalistic inquiry. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, M., Navarrete, C. C., &amp; Wivagg, J. (2014). Potentials of mobile technology for K–12 education: An investigation of iPod touch use for English language learners in the United States. Educational Technology &amp; Society, 17(2), 115–126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Livingstone, S., &amp; Bober, M. (2004). UK children go online: Surveying the experiences of young people and their parents. LSE Research Online. Retrieved from http://eprints.lse.ac.uk/395/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Loeb, M. (2002). Literacy marriage: A study of intertextuality in a series of short stories by Joyce Carol Oates. Bern, Switzerland: Peter Lang.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martin, E. J., &amp; Hagan-Burke, S. (2002). Establishing a home–school connection: Strengthening the partnership between families and schools. Preventing School Failure, 46(2), 62–65. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10459880209603347</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McKnight, C., Dillon, A., &amp; Richardson, J. (1996). User-centered design of hypertext/hypermedia for education. In D. H. Jonassen (Ed.), Handbook of research for educational communications and technology (pp. 622–633). New York, NY: Macmillan Library Reference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McNabb, M., Hassel, B., &amp; Steiner, L. (2002). Literacy learning on the Net: An exploratory study. Reading Online. Retrieved from http://www.readingonline.org/articles/art_index.asp?HREF=mcnabb/index.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McPherson, K. (2005). Reading the Internet. Teacher Librarian, 32(5), 60–61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merriam, S. B. (1998). Qualitative research and case study applications in education: Revised and expanded from case study research in education. San Francisco, CA: Jossey-Bass.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merriam, S. B. (2009). Qualitative research: A guide to design and implementation. San Francisco, CA: Jossey-Bass.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Myers, D. (1990). Computer game genres. Play &amp; Culture, 3, 286–301.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nation, I. S. P. (2001). Learning vocabulary in another language. Cambridge, England: Cambridge University Press. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781139524759</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oakhill, J., &amp; Cain, K. (2007). Issues of causality in children’s reading comprehension. In D. S. McNamara (Ed.), Reading comprehension strategies: Theories, interventions, and technologies (pp. 47–71), New York, NY: Lawrence Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O’Malley, J. M., &amp; Chamot, A. U. (1990). Learning strategies in second language acquisition. New York, NY: Cambridge University Press. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781139524490</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oxford, R. L. (1990). Language learning strategies: What every teacher should know. New York, NY: Newbury House.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oxford, R. L., &amp; Crookall, D. (1989). Research on language learning strategies: Methods, findings, and instructional issues. Modern Language Journal, 73(4), 404–419. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.1989.tb05321.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, H.-R. (2012). Four English language learners’ experiences and strategy use in learning environments of multiliteracies (Unpublished doctoral dissertation). University of South Florida, FL.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, H.-R., &amp; Helsel, C. (2008). Differences between reading electronic and book-based text: Suggestions and implications for literacy teachers and literacy teacher educators. Journal of Reading Education, 33(3), 28–31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, H.-R., &amp; Kim, D. (2011). Reading-strategy use by English as a second language learners in online reading tasks. Computers &amp; Education, 57(3), 2156–2166. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2011.05.014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref71">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patton, M. Q. (2002). Qualitative research and evaluation methods. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref72">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Perez, B. (1998). Sociocultural contexts of language and literacy. Mahwah, NJ: Erlbaum. Pintrich, P. R. (2004). A conceptual framework for assessing motivation and self-regulated learning in college students. Educational Psychology Review, 16(4), 385–407. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10648-004-0006-x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref73">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Richards, J. C., &amp; Anderson, N. A. (2003). How do you know? A strategy to help emergent readers make inferences. The Reading Teacher, 57(3), 290–294.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref74">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rogers, R. R. H., &amp; Wright, V. H. (2008). Assessing technology’s role in communication between parents and middle schools. Electronic Journal for the Integration of Technology in Education, 7, 36–58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref75">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roschelle, J. M., Pea, R. D., Hoadley, C. M., Gordin, D. N., &amp; Means, B. M. (2000). Changing how and what children learn in school with computer-based technologies. The Future of Children, 10(2), 76–101. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.2307/1602690</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref76">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosenblatt, L. M. (1978). The reader, the text, the poem: The transactional theory of the literary work. Carbondale, IL: Southern Illinois University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref77">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosenblatt, L. M. (1982). The literacy transaction: Evocation and response. Theory into Practice, 21(4), 268–277. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00405848209543018</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref78">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosenblatt, L. M. (1986). The aesthetic transaction. The Journal of Aesthetic Education, 20(4), 122–128. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.2307/3332615</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref79">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosenshine, B., Meister, C., &amp; Chapman, S. (1996). Teaching students to generate questions: A review of the intervention studies. Review of Educational Research, 66(2), 181–221. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.3102/00346543066002181</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref80">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosenthal, D. M., &amp; Sawyers, J. Y. (1996). Building successful home/school partnerships: Strategies for parent support and involvement. Childhood Education, 72(4), 194–200. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00094056.1996.10522652</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref81">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rossing, J. P., Miller, W. M., Cecil, A. K., &amp; Stamper, S. E. (2012). iLearning: The future of higher education? Student perceptions on learning with mobile tablets. Journal of the Scholarship of Teaching and Learning, 12(2), 1–26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref82">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rossman, G. B., &amp; Rallis, S. F. (2012). Learning in the field: An introduction to qualitative research (3rd ed.). Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref83">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rumelhart, D. E. (1980). Schemata: The building blocks of cognition. In R. J. Spiro, B. C. Bruce, &amp; W. F. Brewer (Eds.), Theoretical issues in reading comprehension: Perspectives from cognitive psychology, linguistics, artificial intelligence, and education (pp. 33–58). Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref84">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sandberg, K. E. (2013). Hypertext: Its nature and challenges for college students. Journal of College Reading and Learning, 44(1), 51–71. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10790195.2013.10850372</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref85">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scheiter, K., Gerjets, P., &amp; Heise, E. (2014). Distraction during learning with hypermedia: Difficult tasks help to keep task goals on track. Frontiers in Psychology, 5, 1–12. Retrived from http://dx.doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2014.00268</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref86">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serafini, F. (2010). Reading multimodal texts: Perceptual, structural and ideological perspectives. Children’s Literature in Education, 41(2), 85–104. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10583-010-9100-5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref87">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serafini, F. (2012). Reading multimodal texts in the 21st century. Research in the Schools, 19(1), 26–32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref88">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shamir, A., &amp; Korat, O. (2007). Developing an educational e-book for fostering kindergarten children’s emergent literacy. Computers in the Schools, 24(1/2), 125–143. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1300/J025v24n01_09</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref89">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shang, H.-F., &amp; Chang-Chien, I.-J. (2010). The effect of self-questioning strategy on EFL learners’ reading comprehension development. International Journal of Learning, 17(2), 41–54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref90">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Simpson, J. (2005). Learning electronic literacy skills in an online language learning community. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 18(4), 327–435.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref91">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Solomon, G., &amp; Schrum, L. (2010). Web 2.0: How-to for educators. Eugene, OR: International Society for Technology in Education.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref92">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stewart, R. A., &amp; Cross, T. L. (1991). The effect of marginal glosses on reading comprehension and retention. Journal of Reading, 35, 4–12.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref93">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thomas, P. (2014). A case study of using a hypermedia pedagogy in a secondary English classroom. English in Australia, 49(1), 53–62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref94">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Topping, K. J. (1997). Electronic literacy in school and home: A look into the future. Retrieved from http://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED416437.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref95">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsai, Y.-R., Ernst, C., &amp; Talley, P. C. (2010). L1 and L2 strategy use in reading comprehension of Chinese EFL readers. Reading Psychology, 31(1), 1–29. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/02702710802412081</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref96">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Türk, E., &amp; Erçetin, G. (2014). Effects of interactive versus simultaneous display of multimedia glosses on L2 reading comprehension and incidental vocabulary learning. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 27(1), 1–25. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2012.692384</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref97">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van den Bulck, J., &amp; Van den Bergh, B. (2000). The influence of perceived parental guidance patterns on children’s media use: Gender differences and media displacement. Journal of Broadcasting &amp; Electronic Media, 44(3), 329–348. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1207/s15506878jobem4403_1</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref98">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wallace, R. M., Kupperman, J., Krajcik, J., &amp; Soloway, E. (2000). Science on the web: Students online in a sixth-grade classroom. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 9(1), 75–104. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1207/s15327809jls0901_5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref99">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Warschauer, M. (1999). Electronic literacies: Language, culture, and power in online education. Mahwah, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref100">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Warschauer, M. (2002). A developmental perspective on technology in language education. TESOL Quarterly, 36(3), 453–475. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.2307/3588421</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref101">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Warschauer, M., &amp; Matuchniak, T. (2010). New technology and digital worlds: Analyzing evidence of equity in access, use, and outcomes. Review of Research in Education, 34(1), 179–225. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.3102/0091732X09349791</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref102">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wilson, N. S., &amp; Smetana, L. (2011). Questioning as thinking: A metacognitive framework to improve comprehension of expository text. Literacy, 45(2), 84–90. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1741-4369.2011.00584.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref103">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Windschitl, M., &amp; Sahl, K. (2002). Tracing teachers’ use of technology in a laptop computer school: The interplay of teacher beliefs, social dynamics, and institutional culture. American Educational Research Journal, 39(1), 165–205. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.3102/00028312039001165</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref104">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zenotz, V. (2012). Awareness development for online reading. Language Awareness, 21(1/2), 85–100. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09658416.2011.639893</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref105">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, M. (2013). Supporting middle school students’ online reading of scientific resources: Moving beyond cursory, fragmented, and opportunistic reading. Journal of Computer Assisted Learning, 29(2), 138–152. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2729.2012.00478.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref106">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zimmerman, B. J., &amp; Schunk, D. H. (2011). Self-regulated learning and performance: An introduction and an overview. In B. J. Zimmerman &amp; D. H. Schunk (Eds.), Handbook of self-regulation of learning and performance (pp. 1–12). New York, NY: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
