<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939523</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Post-secondary Education Access and Returns</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Estimating the Perceived Returns to College</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Harris</surname>
                  <given-names>Clint M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>54</lpage>

         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939523"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The primary determinant of an individual's college attendance is their perceived return to college. I develop a method for inferring agents' perceived returns to college from observed attendance decisions without fully specifying their knowledge of actual returns. Using NLSY79 data, I estimate a distribution of perceived returns with an order of magnitude lower standard deviation than has been estimated with methods that specify agents' knowledge of returns. My results suggest that a universal annual tuition subsidy of $1,000 would increase college attendance by 2.6%, which is consistent with estimates of e ects of student aid policies on attendance from natural experiments.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Ahn, H. and Manski, C. F. (1993). Distribution theory for the analysis of binary choice under uncertainty with nonparametric estimation of expectations. Journal of Econometrics, 56(3):291-321.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Aiyagari, S. R., Greenwood, J., and Seshadri, A. (2002). Efficient investment in children. Journal of Economic Theory, 102(2):290-321.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Andrews, D. W. and Soares, G. (2010). Inference for parameters defined by moment inequalities using generalized moment selection. Econometrica, 78(1):119-157.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Arnott, R. and Rowse, J. (1987). Peer group effects and educational attainment. Journal of Public Economics, 32(3):287-305.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Attanasio, O. and Kaufmann, K. (2009). Educational choices, subjective expectations, and credit constraints. No. w15087. National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Becker, G. S. (1962). Investment in human capital: A theoretical analysis. Journal of political economy, 70(5):9-49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Becker, G. S. and Tomes, N. (1986). Human capital and the rise and fall of families. Journal of labor economics, 4(3):S1-S39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Belzil, C. (2007). Subjective beliefs and schooling decisions.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Bettinger, E. P., Long, B. T., Oreopoulos, P., and Sanbonmatsu, L. (2012). The role of application assistance and information in college decisions: Results from the h&amp;r block fafsa experiment. The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 127(3):1205-1242.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Black, D. A. and Smith, J. A. (2006). Estimating the returns to college quality with multiple proxies for quality. Journal of labor Economics, 24(3):701-728.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Cameron, S. V. and Taber, C. (2004). Estimation of educational borrowing constraints using returns to schooling. Journal of political Economy, 112(1):132-182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Card, D. (1993). Using geographic variation in college proximity to estimate the return to schooling. Technical report, National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Card, D. (2001). Estimating the return to schooling: Progress on some persistent econometric problems. Econometrica, 69(5):1127-1160.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Carneiro, P., Hansen, K. T., and Heckman, J. J. (2001). Educational attainment and labor market outcomes: estimating distributions of the returns to educational interventions. Paper presented as Klein Lecture, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Carneiro, P., Hansen, K. T., and Heckman, J. J. (2003). Estimating Distributions of Treatment effects with an Application to the Returns to Schooling and Measurement of the effects of Uncertainty on College. No. w9546. National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Carneiro, P. and Heckman, J. J. (2002). The evidence on credit constraints in postsecondary schooling. The Economic Journal, 112(482):705-734.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Carneiro, P., Heckman, J. J., and Vytlacil, E. J. (2011). Estimating marginal returns to education. American Economic Review, 101(6):2754-81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Cunha, F. and Heckman, J. (2006). The Evolution of Labor Earnings Risk in the US Economy. In 2006 Meeting Papers, no. 665. Society for Economic Dynamics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Cunha, F. and Heckman, J. (2008). A new framework for the analysis of inequality. Macroeco- nomic Dynamics, 12(S2):315-354.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Cunha, F. and Heckman, J. (2016). Decomposing trends in inequality in earnings into forecastable and uncertain components. Journal of labor economics, 34(S2):S31-S65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Cunha, F., Heckman, J., and Navarro, S. (2005). Separating uncertainty from heterogeneity in life cycle earnings. oxford Economic papers, 57(2):191-261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Cunha, F. and Heckman, J. J. (2007). Identifying and estimating the distributions of ex post and ex ante returns to schooling. Labour Economics, 14(6):870-893.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Cunha, F., Heckman, J. J., and Navarro, S. (2006). Counterfactual analysis of inequality and social mobility. Mobility and inequality: Frontiers of research in sociology and economics :, pages 290-348.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">De Fraja, G. (2002). The design of optimal education policies. The Review of Economic Studies, 69(2):437-466.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Dearden, L., McGranahan, L., and Sianesi, B. (2004). The role of credit constraints in educational choices: Evidence from ncds and bcs70. CEE DP, 48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Deming, D. and Dynarski, S. (2010). College aid. In Targeting investments in children: Fighting poverty when resources are limited, pages 283-302. University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Dickstein, M. J. and Morales, E. (2015). What do exporters know?. No. w21351. National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Dillon, E. W. and Smith, J. A. (2017). Determinants of the match between student ability and college quality. Journal of Labor Economics, 35(1):45-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Dominitz, J. (1998). Earnings expectations, revisions, and realizations. Review of Economics and statistics, 80(3):374-388.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Dynarski, S. M. (2003). Does aid matter? measuring the e ect of student aid on college attendance and completion. American Economic Review, 93(1):279-288.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Grodsky, E. and Jones, M. T. (2007). Real and imagined barriers to college entry: Perceptions of cost. Social Science Research, 36(2):745-766.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Hansen, K. T., Heckman, J. J., and Mullen, K. J. (2004). The e ect of schooling and ability on achievement test scores. Journal of econometrics, 121(1-2):39-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Hartog, J. (2000). Over-education and earnings: where are we, where should we go? Economics of education review, 19(2):131-147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Heckman, J. J. (1977). Sample selection bias as a specification error (with an application to the estimation of labor supply functions).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Heckman, J. J., Humphries, J. E., Urzua, S., and Veramendi, G. (2011). The effects of educational choices on labor market, health, and social outcomes. Unpublished manuscript, University of Chicago, Department of Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Heckman, J. J., Humphries, J. E., and Veramendi, G. (2018). Returns to education: The causal effects of education on earnings, health, and smoking. Journal of Political Economy, 126(S1):S197-S246.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Heckman, J. J. and Navarro, S. (2007). Dynamic discrete choice and dynamic treatment effects. Journal of Econometrics, 136(2):341-396.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Hogan, V. and Walker, I. (2007). Education choice under uncertainty: Implications for public policy. Labour Economics, 14(6):894-912.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Hoxby, C., Turner, S., et al. (2013). Expanding college opportunities for high-achieving, low income students. Stanford Institute for Economic Policy Research Discussion Paper, (12-014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Hoxby, C. M. (2010). The effects of class size and composition on student achievement: new evidence from natural population variation. no. w6869. National bureau of economic research, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Iranzo, S. and Peri, G. (2009). Schooling externalities, technology, and productivity: Theory and evidence from us states. The Review of Economics and Statistics, 91(2):420-431.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Jensen, R. (2010). The (perceived) returns to education and the demand for schooling. The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 125(2):515-548.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Kane, T. J. and Rouse, C. E. (1995). Labor-market returns to two-and four-year college. The American Economic Review, 85(3):600-614.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Keane, M. P. and Wolpin, K. I. (1997). The career decisions of young men. Journal of political Economy, 105(3):473-522.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Kohn, M. G., Mansk, C. F., and Mundel, D. S. (1976). An empirical investigation of factors which inuence college-going behavior. In Annals of Economic and Social Measurement, 5:391-419.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Lochner, L. and Monge-Naranjo, A. (2011). Credit constraints in education. No. w17435. National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Lucas, R. E. (1988). On the mechanics of economic development. Journal of monetary eco- nomics, 22(1):3-42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Manski, C. (1991). Nonparametric estimation of expectations in the analysis of discrete choice under uncertainty. Nonparametric and semiparametric methods in econometrics and statistics :, pages 259-275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Manski, C. F. (1993). Adolescent econometricians: How do youth infer the returns to schooling? In Studies of supply and demand in higher education, . University of Press, pages 43-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Manski, C. F. (2004). Measuring expectations. Econometrica, 72(5):1329-1376.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Miyagiwa, K. (1991). Scale economies in education and the brain drain problem. International Economic Review :, pages 743-759.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Navarro, S. (2005). Understanding schooling: using observed choices to infer agent's information in a dynamic model of schooling choice when consumption allocation is subject to borrowing constraints.'. PhD thesis, University of Chicago Ph. D. thesis.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Nguyen, T. (2008). Information, role models and perceived returns to education: Experimental evidence from madagascar. Unpublished manuscript 6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Oreopoulos, P. and Salvanes, K. G. (2011). Priceless: The nonpecuniary benefits of schooling. Journal of Economic perspectives, 25(1):159-84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Pakes, A. (2010). Alternative models for moment inequalities. Econometrica, 78(6):1783-1822.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Pakes, A., Porter, J., Ho, K., and Ishii, J. (2015). Moment inequalities and their application. Econometrica, 83(1):315-334.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Rivers, D. and Vuong, Q. H. (1988). Limited information estimators and exogeneity tests for simultaneous probit models. Journal of econometrics, 39(3):347-366.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Roy, A. D. (1951). Some thoughts on the distribution of earnings. Oxford economic papers, 3(2):135-146.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Sanders, C. (2015). Reading skills and earnings: Why do doing words good hurt you're wages. Technical report, Working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Trautmann, S. T. and van de Kuilen, G. (2015). Belief elicitation: A horse race among truth serums. The Economic Journal, 125(589):2116-2135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Willis, R. J. and Rosen, S. (1979). Education and self-selection. Journal of political Economy, 87(5):S7-S36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <mixed-citation id="c62">Wiswall, M. and Zafar, B. (2015). How do college students respond to public information about earnings? Journal of Human Capital, 9(2):117-169.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Zafar, B. (2011). How do college students form expectations? Journal of Labor Economics, 29(2):301-348.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Description of the Primary Variables</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>List of Variables Included and Excluded in Each System</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Perceived Returns Estimates, 2018 Dollars, Principal Components</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Perceived Returns to College, IV Probit, Principal Components</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Perceived Returns to College, Moment Inequalities, Principal Components</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Perceived Returns Estimates, Unscaled, Principal Components</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Perceived Returns Estimates, 2018 Dollars, All Controls</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Unscaled Confidence Set for 2 Parameters, Moment Inequalities</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Unscaled Confidence Set for 3 Parameters, Moment Inequalities</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Perceived Returns to College, IV Probit, All Controls</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Effect of Universally Applied Aid Equivalent to Social Security Student Benefit</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Cost-Minimizing Aid for Attendance Target</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>The score function from the MLE estimation perfectly intersects both of the oddsbased moment inequalities, which are simply algebraic transformations of the score when we assume agents have perfect information on x₁. The point identified by MLE such that the score is equal to zero corresponds to the knife edge region in which both odds-based moment inequalities are satisfied only in the case of full information.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>The estimates from MLE with a full information assumption (where the score function is equal to zero) suffers from attenuation bias. The red region designates the area where the first moment inequality is satisfied while the blue designates the area where the second inequality is satisfied. The overlapping region (purple) shows the area where both are satisfied and contains the true parameter value β₁= 0.3.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>List of Variables Included and Excluded in Principal Component Analysis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Principal Component Loadings</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Effect on Percentage of Tuition Paid</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Tuition Imputation</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Scholarship Imputation</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 11:</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Perceived Returns Estimates, Unscaled, All Controls</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 12:</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>First Stage Estimates, Effect of Instruments on Tuition</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
