<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Wiley</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26604813</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Original Articles</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Employment Quota System and Labour Market Outcomes of Individuals with Disabilities</article-title>
            <subtitle>Empirical Evidence from South Korea</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nazarov</surname>
                  <given-names>Zafar</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kang</surname>
                  <given-names>Dongug</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Von Schrader</surname>
                  <given-names>Sarah</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">36</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26604808</issue-id>
         <fpage>99</fpage>
         <lpage>126</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26604813"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>To date, only a few studies have attempted to evaluate the effectiveness of disability employment quota systems using structural changes in policies. This study exploits the structural changes in South Korea’s disability employment quota system that took place in 2004 and 2006 to expand the current disability policy evaluation literature. We separate the effect of these changes in the quota system into their effect on the probability of labour force participation and their effect on the probability of employment (after controlling for selection into the labour market). We also study the extent to which the changes – which included increasing the number of employers covered by the quota system, the number of jobs available to individuals with disabilities and the financial incentives for employing individuals with disabilities - have affected job satisfaction among individuals with disabilities. Our results suggest that the changes in the quota system may have increased labour force participation but have had a limited positive impact on the probability of employment among people with disabilities in South Korea. Further, compulsory hiring and expanded opportunities have not substantially affected the level of job satisfaction observed among employees with disabilities relative to their non-disabled counterparts.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Acemoglu, D. and Angrist, A. (2001), ‘Consequences of employment protection? The case of the Americans with Disabilities Act’, Journal of Political Economy, vol. 109, pp. 915–57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Beegle, K. and Stock, W. (2003), ‘The labor market effects of disability discrimination laws’, Journal of Human Resources, vol. 38, pp. 806–59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Bell, D. and Heitmueller, A. (2005), ‘The Disability Discrimination Act in the UK: helping or hindering employment amongst the disabled?’, Institute for the Study of Labor (IZA), Discussion Paper no. 1476.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Braddock, D. (2010), Public Spending for Disability in the United States: 1997–2006, Boston, MA: Federal Reserve Bank of Boston. Proceedings from a conference on housing for people with disabilities held on 4–5 February 2010, at the Federal Reserve Bank of the United States, Washington DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Cameron, C. and Trivedi, P. (2010), Microeconometrics Using Stata, revised edition, College Station, TX: Stata Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Chun, Y-P. and Yi, K. (2002), ‘Interpreting the implementation process of employment policy for the disabled by means of a policy sailing and anchoring effect metaphor’, Korean Public Administration Review, vol. 36, pp. 60–76 (in Korean).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">DeLeire, T. (2000), ‘The wage and employment effects of the Americans with Disabilities Act’, Journal of Human Resources, vol. 35, pp. 693–715.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Erickson, W., Lee, C. and von Schrader, S. (2012), 2011 Disability Status Report: United States, Ithaca, NY: Cornell University Employment and Disability Institute (EDI).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Hale, T., Hayghe, H. and McNeil, J. (1998), ‘Persons with disabilities: labor market activity, 1994’, Monthly Labor Review, vol. 121, no. 9, pp. 3–12.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Hotchkiss, J. (2004), ‘A closer look at the employment impact of the Americans with Disabilities Act’, Journal of Human Resources, vol. 39, pp. 887–911.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Jolls, C. and Prescott, J. (2004), ‘Disaggregating employment protections: the case of disability discrimination’, National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER), Working Paper no. 10740.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Kim, C-K. (2010), ‘Comparative perspectives on disability employment policy’, International Review of Public Administration, vol. 15, no. 3, pp. 27–35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Korean Labour Institute (2013), User’s Guide: Korean Labour and Income Panel Study (KLIPS), Waves 1–10. Retrieved from http://www.kli.re.kr/klips/en/about/introduce.jsp.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Kruse, D. and Schur, L. (2003), ‘Employment of people with disabilities following the ADA’, Industrial Relations, vol. 42, pp. 31–66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Lalive, R., Wuellrich, J-P. and Zweimüller, J. (2009), ‘Do financial incentives for firms promote employment of disabled workers? A regression discontinuity approach’, Centre for Economic Policy Research (CEPR), Discussion Paper no. 7373.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Lechner, M. and Vazquez-Alvarez, R. (2003), ‘The effect of disability on labour market outcomes in Germany: evidence from matching’, Institute for the Study of Labor (IZA), Discussion Paper no. 967.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">OECD (2009), ‘Sickness, disability and work: keeping on track in the economic downturn’, Background Paper, High-Level Forum, Stockholm, 14–15 May 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">OECD (2014), ‘Ageing and employment policies: statistics on average effective age of retirement’, http://www.oecd.org/employment/emp/ageingandemploymentpolicies-statisticsonaverageeffectiveageofretirement.htm, accessed 7 February 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Ryu, J., Jun, Y., Nam, Y. and Park, C. (2010), Evaluation of Disability Employment Policy in Korea and Future Strategies, Employment Development Institute, Korea Employment Agency for the Disabled (KEAD).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Statistics Korea (2014), ‘Statistical terms: unemployment rate &amp; economically active population’.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Verick, S. (2004), ‘Do financial incentives promote the employment of the disabled?’, Institute for the Study of Labor (IZA), Discussion Paper no. 1256.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Wittenburg, D. and Nelson, S. (2006), A Guide to Disability Statistics from the Survey of Income and Program Participation, Disability Statistics User Guide Series, Ithaca, NY: Rehabilitation Research and Training Center on Disability Demographics and Statistics, Cornell University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Wooldridge, J. (2010), Econometric Analysis of Cross Section and Panel Data, second edition, Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Wuellrich, J-P. (2010), ‘The effects of increasing financial incentives for firms to promote employment of disabled workers’, Economics Letters, vol. 107, pp. 173–6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Yoo, W., Jang, C., Kim, Y., Byeon, M., Hong, J. and Yoon, H. (2010), The Evolution of Disability Employment Policy and a Development Direction for the Mandatory Employment System in Korea, Employment Development Institute, Korea Employment Agency for the Disabled (KEAD).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Laws, amendments and changes in regulations related to the disability quota system in South Korea</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Construction of the key variables</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Disability prevalence in the analytical sample</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Labour force participation rate in the analytical sample, by disability status</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Unemployment rate in the analytical sample, by disability status</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Descriptive statistics for the analytical sample</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Simulated probabilities of employment (taking selection into the labour market into account) and labour force participation for disabled individuals</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Simulated probability of labour force participation, by disability status</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Simulated probability of employment (taking selection into the labour market into account), by disability status</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Results of bivariate probit model with selection</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Results of bivariate probit model with selection</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Overall job satisfaction before and after the changes in the quota system</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>

