<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90007201</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Original Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Analysis of the power law exponent applied to Lake Erie wind shear</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Corrigan</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Matthiesen</surname>
                  <given-names>David H</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>1</sup>Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Department, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH, USA</aff>
            <aff id="a2">
               <sup>2</sup>Department of Materials Science and Engineering and The Great Lakes Energy Institute, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH, USA</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>41</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e90007199</issue-id>
         <fpage>103</fpage>
         <lpage>113</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© SAGE Publications Ltd, 2017</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90007201"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>An investigation of power law exponents (wind shear coefficients) was conducted using LiDAR data collected offshore in Lake Erie. The purpose was to investigate discrepancies found by previous studies between calculated power law exponents from measurements and recommended values from international standards. In this study, power law exponents were evaluated using the LiDAR measurements at heights of 80–200 m. The average power law exponent during the study period was found to be 0.09, which was lower than the 0.14 standard assumed by international standards. A detailed investigation of the distribution of power law exponents revealed a bi-modal distribution comprising the two most frequent exponent ranges between 0.01–0.02 and 0.19–0.20. The gap between these peaks was found to be dependent on the atmospheric stability of the boundary layer. Average power law exponents of 0.02 and 0.14 were found for atmospheric conditions indicating unstable regimes and neutral/stable regimes, respectively. Regime stability also showed directional dependence where winds from the 180° ± 45° directions were prevailing during neutral/stable conditions and winds from the 326° ± 67° directions were prevailing during unstable conditions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label>
            <kwd>Wind energy</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>power law</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>wind shear</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>offshore</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>LiDAR</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Lake Erie</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Antoniou I, Jorgensen H, Mikkelsen T, et al. (2006) Offshore wind profile measurements from remote sensing instruments. In: European wind energy association (EWEA 2006), Athens, 27 February–2 March 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Argyriadis K. (2004) Recommendations for Design of Offshore Wind Turbines: External Conditions (RECOFF). Hamburg: Germanischer Lloyd.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bailey BH, McDonald SL, Bernadett DW, et al. (1997) Wind Resource Assessment Handbook. Available at: http://www.nrel.gov/docs/legosti/fy97/22223.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Driedger-Marschall B, Endres PK, Kruger RM, et al. (2009) Great Lakes wind energy center feasibility study. JW Great Lakes Wind LLC. Available at: http://development.cuyahogacounty.us/pdf_development/en-US/GLWEC_Final%20Feasibility%20Report_4-28-09.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dykes K, Miller F, Weinberg B, et al. (2008) A Wind Resource Assessment for Near-Shore Lake Erie: Cleveland Water Crib Monitoring Site Two-Year Report. Cleveland, OH: Green Energy Ohio.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Emeis S (2005) How well does a power law fit to a diabatic boundary-layer wind profile. DEWI Magazine, German Wind Energy Institute, 26 February 2005, pp. 59–62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrugia R (2003) The wind shear exponent in a Mediterranean island climate. Renewable Energy 28: 647–653.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gualtieri G and Secci S (2010) Wind shear coefficients, roughness length and energy yield over costal locations in Southern Italy. Renewable Energy 36: 1081–1094.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC) (2005) Wind Turbines—Part 1: Design Requirements (International Electrotechnical Commission International Standard 61400-1) (3rd edn). Geneva: IEC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC) (2009) Wind Turbines—Part 3: Design Requirements for Offshore Wind Turbines (International Electrochemical Commission International Standard 61400-3) (1st edn). Geneva: IEC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Locker I and Harris M (2007) Wind resource measurement by laser anemometry. Windtech International, 10 July, p. 3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Newman JF and Klein PM (2014) The impacts of atmospheric stability on the accuracy of wind speed extrapolation methods. Resources 3: 81–105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pena A, Hasager C, Gryning S, et al. (2009) Offshore wind profiling using light detection and ranging measurements. Wind Energy 12: 105–124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pichugina Y, Banta R, Brewer A, et al. (2012) Doppler Lidar-based wind profile measurement for offshore wind energy and other marine boundary layer applications. Journal of Applied Meteorology and Climatology 51: 327–349.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Richards TL and Dragert H (1966) Influence of atmospheric stability and over-water fetch on winds over the lower great lakes. Monthly Weather Review 94: 448–453.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sucevic N and Djurisic Z (2012) Influence of atmospheric stability variation on uncertainties of wind farm production estimation. In: European wind energy association (EWEA 2012), Copenhagen, 16–19 April 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
