<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284975</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Boosted Premixed-LTGC / HCCI Combustion of EHN-doped Gasoline for Engine Speeds Up to 2400 rpm</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ji</surname>
                  <given-names>Chunsheng</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dec</surname>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dernotte</surname>
                  <given-names>Jeremie</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cannella</surname>
                  <given-names>William</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chevron Energy Technology Company</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>December 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284959</issue-id>
         <fpage>2166</fpage>
         <lpage>2184</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284975"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Previous work has shown that conventional diesel ignition improvers, 2-ethylhexyl nitrate (EHN) and di-tert-butyl peroxide (DTBP), can be used to enhance the autoignition of a regular-grade E10 gasoline in a well premixed low-temperature gasoline combustion (LTGC) engine, hereafter termed an HCCI engine, at naturally aspirated and moderately boosted conditions (up to 180 kPa absolute) with a constant engine speed of 1200 rpm and a 14:1 compression ratio. In the current work the effect of EHN on boosted HCCI combustion is further investigated with a higher compression ratio (16:1) piston and over a range of engine speeds (up to 2400 rpm). The results show that the higher compression ratio and engine speeds can make the combustion of a regular-grade E10 gasoline somewhat less stable. The addition of EHN improves the combustion stability by allowing combustion phasing to be more advanced for the same ringing intensity. The high-load limits of both the straight (unadditized) and additized fuels are determined, and the additized fuel is found to achieve a higher maximum load at all engine speeds and intake pressures tested, if it is not limited by lack of oxygen. The results reveal that the higher loads with EHN are the result of either reduced intake temperature requirements at naturally aspirated conditions or a reduction in heat release rate at higher intake pressures. Such effects are also found to increase the thermal efficiency, and a maximum indicated thermal efficiency of 50.1% is found for 0.15% EHN additized fuel at 1800 rpm and 180 kPa intake pressure. Similar to previous studies, the nitrogen in EHN increases NOx emissions, but they remain well below US-2010 standards. Higher engine speeds are found to have slightly lower NOx emissions for additized fuel at intake boosted conditions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., Yang, Y., Dernotte, J., and Ji, C., “Effects of Gasoline Reactivity and Ethanol Content on Boosted, Premixed and Partially Stratified Low-Temperature Gasoline Combustion (LTGC),” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(3):935-955, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0813.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Johansson, B., Amnéus, P., and Mauss, F., “Supercharged Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 980787, 1998, doi:10.4271/980787.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M. and Johansson, B., “Supercharged Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) with Exhaust Gas Recirculation and Pilot Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1835, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1835.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., and Yang, Y., “Boosted HCCI for high power without engine knock and with ultra-low NOx emissions - using conventional gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1): 750-767, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-1086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J, Yang, Y., and Dronniou, N., “Boosted HCCI - controlling pressure-rise rate for performance improvements using partial fuel stratification with conventional gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1): 1169-1189, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0897.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., Yang, Y., and Dronniou, N., “Improving Efficiency and Using E10 for Higher Loads in Boosted HCCI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1009-1032, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “Smoothing HCCI Heat-Release Rates Using Partial Fuel Stratification with Two-Stage Ignition Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0629, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0629.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J., Dronniou, N., Sjöberg, M., “Tailoring HCCI heat release rates with partial fuel stratification: Comparison of two-stage and single-stage ignition fuels,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 33 (2): 3047-3055, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2010.06.114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J., Dronniou, N., Sjöberg, M. et al., “Partial Fuel Stratification to Control HCCI Heat Release Rates: Fuel Composition and Other Factors Affecting Pre-Ignition Reactions of Two- Stage Ignition Fuels,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1903-1920, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1359.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Sjöberg, M., “A Parametric Study of HCCI Combustion - the Sources of Emissions at Low Loads and the Effects of GDI Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0752, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0752.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., “Advanced compression-ignition engines-understanding the incylinder processes,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 32(2): 2727-2742, 2009, doi: 10.1016/j.proci.2008.08.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Machrafi, H., Cavadias, S., Gilbert, P., “An experimental and numerical analysis of the HCCI auto-ignition process of primary reference fuels, toluene reference fuels and diesel fuel in an engine, varying the engine parameters,” Fuel Processing Technology 89(11): 1007-1016, 2008, doi: 10.1016/j.fuproc.2008.03.007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu, X., Shen, Y., Zhang, Y., Zhou, X., Ji, L., Yang, Z., Huang, Z., “Controlled three-stage heat release of stratified charge compression ignition (SCCI) combustion with a two-stage primary reference fuel supply,” Fuel 90(5): 2026-2038, 2011, doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2011.01.026.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J., Dronniou, N., and Cannella, W., “Boosted HCCI Combustion Using Low-Octane Gasoline with Fully Premixed and Partially Stratified Charges,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1075-1088, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Fuel Effects on Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Combustion at Low Load,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):394-411, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01- 0361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaddatz, J., Andrie, M., Reitz, R., and Kokjohn, S., “Light-Duty Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition Combustion Using a Cetane Improver,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1110, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A., Walker, N., and Reitz, R., “Effect of Cetane Improvers on Gasoline, Ethanol, and Methanol Reactivity and the Implications for RCCI Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2013; 6(1):170-87. doi:10.4271/2013-01-1678.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hosseini, V., Neill, W.S., Guo, H., Chippior, W.L., Fairbridge, C., and Mitchell, K., “Effects of different cetane number enhancement strategies on HCCI combustion and emissions,” Int. J. Engine Res. 12: 89-108, 2011, doi: 10.1177/1468087410395873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ji, C., Dec, J., Dernotte, J., and Cannella, W., “Effect of Ignition Improvers on the Combustion Performance of Regular-Grade E10 Gasoline in an HCCI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2014; 7(2). doi:10.4271/2014-01-1282.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ickes, A., Bohac, S., and Assanis, D., “Effect of 2-ethylhexyl nitrate cetane improver on NOx emissions from premixed low-temperature diesel combustion. Energy and Fuels,” 2009;23(10):4943-48. doi: 10.1021/ef900408e.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “Combined Effects of Fuel-Type and Engine Speed on Intake Temperature Requirements and Completeness of Bulk- Gas Reactions for HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01- 3173, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3173.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “Effects of Engine Speed, Fueling Rate, and Combustion Phasing on the Thermal Stratification Required to Limit HCCI Knocking Intensity,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2125, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2125.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “EGR and Intake Boost for Managing HCCI Low-Temperature Heat Release over Wide Ranges of Engine Speed,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0051, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0051.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “Ethanol Autoignition Characteristics and HCCI Performance for Wide Ranges of Engine Speed, Load and Boost,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):84-106, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0338.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aroonsrisopon, T., Foster, D., Morikawa, T., and Iida, M., “Comparison of HCCI Operating Ranges for Combinations of Intake Temperature, Engine Speed and Fuel Composition,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01- 1924, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1924.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals. New York: McGraw-Hill; 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J., “Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dernotte, J., Dec, J., and Ji, C., “Investigation of the Sources of Combustion Noise in HCCI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1272.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “An Investigation of the Relationship Between Measured Intake Temperature, BDC Temperature, and Combustion Phasing for Premixed and DI HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1900, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1900.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “An investigation into lowest acceptable combustion temperatures for hydrocarbon fuels in HCCI engines,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 30(2):2179-2726, 2005, doi: 10.1016/j.proci.2004.08.132.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J. E., “Influence of Fuel Autoignition Reactivity on the High-Load Limits of HCCI Engines”, SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1): 39- 58, SAE paper 2008-01-0054, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J. E., and Cernansky, N. P., “The Potential of Thermal Stratification and Combustion Retard for Reducing Pressure-Rise Rates in HCCI Engines, based on Multi-Zone Modeling and Experiments,” SAE Transactions, Vol. 114, Sec. 3, pp. 236-251, SAE paper 2005-01- 0113, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
