<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">95</volume>
         <issue-id>i40187915</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44470547</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Servicing of User Payload Equipment in the Space Station Pressurized Environment</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Joel</given-names>
                  <surname>Levy</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ruth</given-names>
                  <surname>Whitman</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Thomas A.</given-names>
                  <surname>LaVigna</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>John E.</given-names>
                  <surname>Oberright</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1986</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>324</fpage>
         <lpage>331</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1987 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44470547"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>One of the major contributions which the permanently manned Space Station will make to the user community is the ability to extend the useful life of hardware through various forms of servicing. Servicing support facilities will include both unpressurized and pressurized work areas. The unpressurized area will permit astronauts operating in an Extravehicular Activity (EVA) mode or aided by robotics to accomplish Orbital Replacement Unit (ORU) and instrument changeout, test and verification, assembly, refueling, and limited repair. The pressurized facilities will provide the capability for astronauts operating in an Intravehicular Activity (IVA) mode to service ORUs and instruments brought into a module through an airlock, and also service user payload equipment located within the pressurized modules. Vigorous analysis of the requirements for servicing laboratory equipment, externally attached payloads, and satellite or platform ORUs is being conducted by the Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC). Various forms of servicing are being considered, including repair, maintenance, and upgrading of equipment associated with user-defined payloads. For all of these potential servicing operations GSFC is also studying the associated contamination monitoring and control issues. It should be noted that maintenance of Space Station equipment is being studied by the Johnson Space Center (JSC). This paper describes the facilities and capabilities being provided within the Space Station pressurized modules to support IVA servicing. Baseline accommodations include provisions for: a) a staging/assembly area for ORUs which may be brought into the the module from satellites, platforms, or attached payloads; b) a workstation for monitor and control of the external Servicing Bay facility; c) a large laminar flow workbench which would provide Class 100 (or 1000) controlled conditions; d) a moderately sized glove box which enables up to two crewmen to simultaneously conduct delicate servicing operations within an enclosed environment; and e) an assortment of handtools and test equipment which will enable a broad variety of servicing tasks to be carried out. A Teleservicing Facility is also under study, and will be described below.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d120e250a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d120e257" publication-type="other">
"Satellite Servicing at the Space Station." Thomas A. Lavigna.
Presented at Satellite Servicing Workshop; Johnson Space Center,
Houston, TX; November 6-8, 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


