<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26897918</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Modelling and Numerical Simulation of Dual Fuel Lean Flames Using Local Burning Velocity and Critical Chemical Timescale</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Muppala</surname>
                  <given-names>Siva</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Vendra</surname>
                  <given-names>C. Madhav Rao</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Aluri</surname>
                  <given-names>Naresh K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>


         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2019</year>
            <string-date>2019</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26897916</issue-id>
         <fpage>373</fpage>
         <lpage>386</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2019 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26897918"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Addition of hydrogen to hydrocarbons in premixed turbulent combustion is of technological interest due to their increased reactivity, flame stability and extended lean extinction limits. However, such flames are a challenge to reaction modelling, especially as the strong preferential diffusion effects modify the physical processes, which are of importance even for highly turbulent high-pressure conditions. In the present work, Reynolds-averaged Navier-Stokes (RANS) modelling is carried out to investigate pressure and hydrogen content on methane/hydrogen/air flames. For this purpose, four different subclosures, used in conjunction with an algebraic reaction model, are compared with two independent sets of experimental data: (1) Orléans data consists of pressures up to 9 bar, with addition of hydrogen content by up to 20% in hydrogen/methane mixture, for moderate turbulence intensities. 2) The Paul Scherrer Institute data includes same fuels with higher volume proportion of hydrogen (40%), at much higher turbulent intensities at 5 bar. The first model Model I is based solely on the increased reactivity of the hydrogen/methane mixture under laminar conditions. It shows that the increase of unstretched laminar burning velocity (<italic>S</italic>
               <sub>L0</sub>) is not sufficient to describe the increased reactivity in turbulent situations. This non-corroboration proves the importance of preferential diffusion effects in highly turbulent flames. Models II and III are formulated based on the localized increase in <italic>S</italic>
               <sub>L0</sub>, local burning velocity which is a strong function of local curvature and flow strain. Model II overpredicts the reactivity for higher pressures. Model III accurately predicts for nearly all studied flame conditions. Model IV is based on the leading point concept (LPC) that the leading part of the turbulent flame brush is more important than the rear part of premixed flame with the Lewis number less than unity. This model in its present formulation underpredicts the average reaction rate compared with experiments.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Lipatnikov, A.N. and Chomiak, J., “Molecular Transport Effects on Turbulent Flame Propagation and Structure,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 31:1-73, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Blarigan, P.V. and Keller, J.O., “A Hydrogen Fuelled Internal Combustion Engine Designed for Single Speed/Power Operation,” Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 23(7):603-609, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Griebel, P., Boschek, E., and Jansohn, P., “Flame Stability and NOx Emission Improvements due to H2 Enrichment of Turbulent, Lean Premixed, High-Pressure, Methane/Air Flames,” In: The Future of Gas Turbine Technology. (Belgium, Brussels, 2006).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Jackson, G.S., Sai, R., Plaia, J.M., Boggs, C.M., and Kiger, K.T., “Erratum to “Influence of H2 on the Response of Lean Premixed CH4 Flames to High Strained Flows” Combust. Flame 132(3)(2003)503-511,” Combustion and Flame 135(3):363, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Halter, F., “Caracterisation des effets de l’ajout d’hydrogene et de la haute pression dans les flammes turbulentes de premelange methane/air,” In: Energetique - Mecanique des fluides. (Orleans, France, l’Universite d’Orleans, 2005), 1-251.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Lafay, Y., Renou, B., Cabot, C., and Boukahlfa, M., “Experimental and Numerical Investigation of the Effect of H2 Enrichment on Laminar Methane-Air Flame Thickness,” Combustion and Flame 153:540-561, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Shy, S.S., Chen, Y.C., Yang, C.H., Liu, C.C., and Huang, C.M., “Effects of H2 or CO2 Addition, Equivalence Ratio, and Turbulent Straining on Turbulent Burning Velocities for Lean Premixed Methane Combustion,” Combustion and Flame 153:510-524, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Kido, H., Nakahara, M., Hashimoto, J., and Barat, D., “Turbulent Burning Velocities of Two-Component Fuel Mixtures of Methane, Propane and Hydrogen,” JSME International Journal, Series B 45(2), 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Cheng, R.K., Littlejohn, D., Strakey, P.A., and Sidwell, T., “Laboratory Investigations of a Low-Swirl Injector with H2 and CH4 at Gas Turbine Conditions,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 32(2):3001-3009, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Schefer, R.W., “Combustion of Hydrogen-Enriched Methane in a Lean Premixed Swirl Burner,” in DOE Hydrogen Program Review, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Halter, F., Cohe, C., Chauveau, C., and Gokalp, I., “Characterization of the Effects of Hydrogen Addition in Lean Premixed Methane/Air Turbulent Flames at High Pressure, in Proceedings of the European Combustion Meeting, Orleans, France, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Law, C.K., Jomaas, G., and Bechtold, J.K., “Cellular Instabilities of Expanding Hydrogen/Propane Spherical Flames at Elevated Pressure: Theory and Experiment,” Proceeding of the Combustion Institute 30:159-167, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Hawkes, E.R. and Chen, J.H., “Direct Numerical Simulation of Hydrogen-Enriched Lean Premixed Methane-Air Flames,” Combustion and Flame 138(3):242- 258, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Lipatnikov, A. and Chomiak, J., “A Theoretical Study of Premixed Turbulent Flame Development,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 30:843, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Kido, H., Nakashima, K., Nakahara, M., and Hashimoto, J., “Experimental Study on the Configuration and Propagation Characteristics of Premixed Turbulent Flame,” JSME International Journal 22:131-138, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Bechtold, J.K. and Matalon, M., “The Dependence of the Markstein Length on Stoichiometry,” Combustion and Flame 127(1-2):1906-1913, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Bray, K.N.C. and Peters, N., “Laminar Flamelets in Turbulent Flames,” In: Libby P.A., Williams A., editors. Turbulent Reactive Flows. (London, Academic Press, 1994), 63-113.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Bradley, D., Gaskell, P.H., Sedaghat, A., and Gu, X.J., “Generation of PDFS for Flame Curvature and for Flame Stretch Rate in Premixed Turbulent Combustion,” Combustion and Flame 135(4):503-523, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Bray, K.N.C. and Cant, R.S., “Some Applications of Kolmogorov's Turbulence Research in the Field of Combustion,” Proc R Soc Lond A434:217-240, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Muppala, S.P.R., Aluri, N.K., Dinkelacker, F., and Leipertz, A., “Development of an Algebraic Reaction Rate Closure for the Numerical Calculation of Turbulent Premixed Methane, Ethylene and Propane/Air Flames for Pressures up to 1.0 MPa,” Combustion and Flame 140:257- 266, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Dinkelacker, F., Manickam, B., and Muppala, S.P.R., “Modelling and Simulation of Turbulent Methane/Hydrogen/Air Flames with an Effective Lewis Number Approach,” Combustion and Flame, 158(9):1742-1749, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Bray, K.N.C., Libby, P.A., and Moss, J.B., “Flamelet Crossing Frequencies and Mean Reaction Rates in Premixed Turbulent Combustion,” Combust. Sci. Technol. 41:143- 172, 1984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Duclos, J.M., Veynante, D., and Poinsot, T., “A Comparison of Flamelet Models for Premixed Turbulent Combustion,” Combustion and Flame 95:101-117, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Kobayashi, H., Kawabata, Y., and Maruta, K., “Experimental Study on General Correlation of Turbulent Burning Velocity at High Pressure,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 27:941-948, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Muppala, S.P.R. and Dinkelacker, F., “Numerical Modelling of the Pressure Dependent Reaction Source Term for Premixed Turbulent Methane/Air Flames,” Progress in Computational Fluid Dynamics 4(6):328- 336, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Aluri, N.K., Muppala, S.P.R., and Dinkelacker, F., “Large- Eddy Simulation of Lean Premixed Turbulent Flames of Three Different Combustion Configurations Using a Novel Reaction,” Flow Turbulence and Combustion 80(2):207- 224, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Chen, Y.-C. and Bilger, R.W., “Experimental Investigation of Three-Dimensional Flame-Front Structure in Premixed Turbulent Combustion: II. Lean Hydrogen/Air Bunsen Flames,” Combustion and Flame 138(1-2):155- 174, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Matalon, M. and Matkowsky, B.J., “Flames as Gas Dynamic Discontinuities,” Journal Fluid Mechanics 124:239- 260, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Kolmogorov, A.N., Petrovsky, E.G., and Piskounov, N.S., “A Study of the Diffusion Equation with a Source Term and Its Application to a Biological Problem, in Dokl. Akad. Nauk SSSR, 1937 (in Russian; English translation In: Pelce P, Ed., Dynamics of Curved Fronts (San Diego, CA: Academic Press, 1988), Bjulleten' MGU, Moscow State University, USSR, Section A.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Zeldovich, Y.B., “Flame Propagation in a Substance Reacting at Initial Temperature,” Combustion and Flame 39:219- 224, 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Betev, A.S., Karpov, V.P., Lipatnikov, A., and Vardosanidze, Z.P., “Hydrogen Combustion in Engines and Preferential Diffusion Effects in Laminar and Turbulent Flames,” Archivum Combustionis 15(3-4):188-215, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Lipatnikov, A., Private Communication.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Kido, H., Nakahara, M., and Nakashima, K., “A Study on the Local Flame Displacement Velocity of Premixed Turbulent Flames,” JSME International Journal Series B 48(1):164-171, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Ansys Incorporated, FLUENT, Canonsburg, PA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Unstretched laminar burning velocity (S<sub>L0</sub>) with variation of (from left to right) equivalence ratio, hydrogen concentration, pressure and temperature. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Halter experimental data points marked in the Borghi diagram. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>PSI experimental data plotted on the Borghi diagram. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Simulated normalized mean local burning velocity S<sub>L</sub>/S<sub>L0</sub> for variation of hydrogen concentration and pressure variation. Solid lines, Model II; dashed lines, Model III.© 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Calculated Markstein number and mean local burning velocity, presented for Orléans Bunsen flame experimental data. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Simulated and measured Bunsen flame height (c̄ = 0.5) comparison for 0, 10 and 20% hydrogen concentration and 1, 5 and 9 bar pressure. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Simulated and measured turbulent burning velocity normalized by unstretched laminar burning velocity S<sub>T</sub>/S<sub>L0</sub> for 0, 10 and 20% hydrogen addition. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Orléans Bunsen flame contours. Shown are the three cases at 5 bar pressure with 0, 10 and 20% hydrogen in methane. On the left is the experimental flame, followed by the simulated flames with Models I to IV. The contour values (mean reaction progress) range from 0 (blue, unburned) to 1 (red, burned). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Calculated Markstein number and mean local burning velocity, presented for PSI experimental data. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>The calculated normalized local burning velocity for variation of hydrogen concentration and 5 bar pressure: solid lines, Model II; dashed lines, Model III. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Simulated and measured flame height (c̄ = 0.5) from the three subclosures are compared with PSI experimental data for 0 to 40 vol% hydrogen. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Simulated turbulent burning velocities from the three subclosures are compared with PSI experimental data for 0 to 40 vol% hydrogen. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>PSI test flames. Simulated premixed turbulent methane/hydrogen/air flames in Reynolds-averaged reaction progress contours from the AFSW reaction model with the four Models I, II, III and IV are shown in comparison with the measured flames, for 0, 20 and 40% hydrogen at 5 bar. The contour values range between 0 (blue, unburned) and 1 (red, burned). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
