<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">18</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830362</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830369</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A CHALLENGING FINANCING STRATEGY FOR THE BANKING SYSTEM IN EGYPT / UNE STRATEGIE AUDACIEUSE DE FINANCE POUR LE SYSTEME BANCAIRE EN EGYPTE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ahmad A.H.</given-names>
                  <surname>Aly</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1994</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>105</fpage>
         <lpage>122</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830369"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Egypt is in an awkward predicament. The country is facing a peculiar problem of persistent imbalance between fast growing population and less expandable settled area. Other things remain unchanged, this would eventually end in an unavoidable ecological catastrophe. A choiceless way out is to get excess population transplanted in the vast empty desert within the framework of a comprehensive resettlement-cum-development process. Given the scarcity of both entrepreneurial skills and financing requirements, the banking system comes to the fore as a prospective propeller of the process, a role more or less similar to that previously played by German banks in the 19th century and Bank Misr in the second quarter of the 20th century. In theory, the challenging strategy involves three main contrivances: restructuring banking financing in favour of direct investment, allocating the latter in such a way as to place priority on industry, and relocating economic activity at large and industry in particular in the distant provinces. This aggressive pattern of financing is to be put into practice through two major initiatives by banks operating in Egypt: identification and evaluation of new investment opportunities in the selected places, and initiation of new projects therein. The workability of the conceived scenario is conditional, however, on, inter alia, the removal of bureaucratic swelling from the government administrative body. L'Egypte est dans une situation difficile. Elle souffre un déséquilibre chronique entre la croissante population et la zone occupée invariable, qui conduira, toutes choses égales d'ailleurs, a une catastrophe écologique inévitable. Une solution obligatoire c'est de transplanter l'excédent de la population dans l'immense désert vide dans le cadre d'un plan global de développement. Etant donné que l'esprit d'entreprise ainsi que les ressources financières sont peu abondants, le système bancaire se met en evidence come un arbre d'hèlice en perspective du processus, un rôle plus ou moins comparable a celui auparavant joué par les banques allemandes dans le 19ème siècle ainsi que par la Bank Misr dans les années 1920s. En théorie, cette stratégie audacieuse de finance s'attache a trois idées principales; à savoir, la restructuration de la finance bancaire en faveur de l'investissement direct, l'allocation de celui-ci en donnant la priorité a l'industrie, et la relocation de l'activité économique en général et l'industrie en particulier dans les provinces lointaines. Ce mode aggressif de finance peut être mis en pratique via deux initiatives; l'identification et l'évaluation des nouvelles chances d'investissement dans les regions désertiques, et l'établissement de projets dedans, le succès de ce scenario depend, cependant, sur, entre autres choses, l'enlevement du gonflement bureaucratique du corps administratif gouvernemental.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d57e162a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e169" publication-type="other">
The Herald Tribune, July 7, 1987.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e176a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e183" publication-type="other">
Hemdan, Gamal: Personality of Egypt, Part 4, p 192 (in Arabic).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e190a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e197" publication-type="other">
Hemdan, Gamal: Personality of Egypt, part. 4, p. 221.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e204a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e211" publication-type="other">
Hemdan, Gamal: Personality of Egypt, Part three, p. 456.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e219a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e226" publication-type="other">
Al-Wafd Newspaper, August 17, 1992.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e233a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e240" publication-type="other">
Mokhtar, Ibrahim: Investment
Banks, Anglo Egyptian Library, Cairo, Egypt, 1987 (in Arabic).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e250a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e257" publication-type="other">
Islamic International Bank for Investment and Development: official information bulletin, 1989.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e264a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e271" publication-type="other">
Mokhtar, Ibrahim: Investment banks... op. cit. pp. 314-318</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e278a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e285" publication-type="other">
Mokhar, Ibrahim: In-
vestment banks... op cit. pp. 234-236</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e294" publication-type="other">
Mottwally, Mahmoud: Historical origins and evolution of Egyptian capitalism,
Egyptian Authority for Book, Cairo, 1974, pp. 177-217 (in Arabic).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e304a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e311" publication-type="other">
Status quo and horizons of development in the New Valley Governorate. Series of development issues,
Report no. 70, January 1992.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e320" publication-type="other">
Some production and services sectors in Mersa Matroh Province. Series of development issues, Report
no. 65, Oct 1991.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e329" publication-type="other">
A social and economic survey of Red Sea Governorate and possible investment opportunities therein. Series
of development issues, Report no. 50, March 1990.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e339" publication-type="other">
North Lakes between cultivation and fishing. Series of development issues, Report no. 25 Oct. 1985.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e345" publication-type="other">
An analytical study on potentials of regional development in Upper Egypt. Series of development issues,
Report no. 04, June 1978.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e354" publication-type="other">
Detailed studies on potentials of regional development in Upper Egypt. Series of development issues, Report
no. 03, April 1978.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e363" publication-type="other">
Ministry of Construction. Prof. Mustapha, Samir, Al-Wafd Newspaper,
June 14, 1992.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e372" publication-type="other">
Hemdan,
Gamal: Personality of Egypt, Part 4, pp. 350-351.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e383a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e390" publication-type="other">
Mohsen Khan and Abbas Mirakhor: Islamic banking: experiences in the Islamic Republic of Iran and Pakistan,
IMF working paper WP/89/12, January 30, 1989.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e399" publication-type="other">
Mokhtar, Ibrahim: Investment banks... op. cit.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e406a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e413" publication-type="other">
Islamic International Bank for Investment and Development: Official information bulletin 1989.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e420a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e427" publication-type="other">
Faissal Islamic Bank of Egypt: Annual Report, 1990.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
  </back>
</article>


