<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275467</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Quasi-Dimensional Modeling of CI-Combustion with Multiple Pilot- and Post Injections</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rether</surname>
                  <given-names>Dominik</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IVK Univ. of Stuttgart</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Grill</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FKFS</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schmid</surname>
                  <given-names>Andreas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IVK Univ. of Stuttgart</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bargende</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FKFS</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>12</fpage>
         <lpage>27</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275467"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A new phenomenological CI combustion model was developed. Within this model the given injection rate may contain an arbitrary number of injections during one cycle. Another target was a short computation time of one second per cycle on average. The new approach should also have the ability to simulate a wide engine spectrum from passenger-car engines through to marine engines.</p>
            <p>The ignition delay is calculated separately for each single injection. In this way the model depicts the influence of pilot injections on the ignition delay of proximate injections. Each pilot injection is modeled as a single air-fuel mixture cloud with air entrainment. The burn rate of the pilot injection is modeled as a function of flame propagation and of the current local excess air ratio. If the local excess air ratio becomes too lean the pilot combustion stops or does not start at all.</p>
            <p>Main and post-injections are calculated by means of a slice approach. The slices are generated isochronously as a function of the injection rate. They propagate through the combustion chamber in the direction of injection. Along the way the entrainment of air into the slices is computed by means of a statistical lambda distribution. The premixed and diffusion combustions are calculated by different approaches. Within the diffusion approach there is a distinction between the fast, nearly stoichiometric combustion and the slow lean combustion, which is responsible for the characteristic burn-out of CI combustion.</p>
            <p>The approach will be shown in detail. On the basis of measurements and simulations, the forecast capability and the limitations of the model are discussed in full.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grill, M., Bargende, M., Schmid, A., and Rether, D., “Quasi-Dimensional and Empirical Modeling of Compression Ignition Engine Combustion and Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0151, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GRILL, M., “Objektorientierte Prozessrechnung von Verbrennungsmotoren”, Dissertation, Universität Stuttgart, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grill, M. and Bargende, M., “The Development of an Highly Modular Designed Zero-Dimensional Engine Process Calculation Code,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):1-11, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BARBA, C., “Erarbeitung von Verbrennungskennwerten aus Indizierdaten zur verbesserten Prognose und rechnerischen Simulation der Verbrennungsablaufes bei PKW-DE-Dieselmotoren mit Common-Rail-Einspritzung”, Dissertation, ETH Zürich, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pirker, G., Chmela, F., and Wimmer, A., “ROHR Simulation for DI Diesel Engines Based on Sequential Combustion Mechanisms,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0654, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barba, C., Burkhardt, C., Boulouchos, K., and Bargende, M., “A Phenomenological Combustion Model for Heat Release Rate Prediction in High-Speed DI Diesel Engines with Common Rail Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2933, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">HIROYASU, H., KADOTA, T., ARAI, M., “Development and Use of a Spray Combustion Modeling to Predict Diesel Engine Efficiency and Pollutant Emissions (Part 1: Combustion Modeling)”, Bulletin of the JSME, Vol. 26, Paper No. 214-12, 1983</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">STIESCH, G., “Phänomenologisches Multizonen-Modell der Verbrennung und Schadstoffbildung im Dieselmotor”, Dissertation, Universität Hannover, 1999</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jung, D. and Assanis, D.N., “Multi-Zone DI Diesel Spray Combustion Model for Cycle Simulation Studies of Engine Performance and Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1246, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CUI, Y., DENG, K., WU, J., “A direct injection diesel combustion model for use in transient condition analysis”, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering, Volume 215, Number 9, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chiatti, G., Chiavola, O., and Palmieri, F., “Phenomenological Multi-Step Modeling of Diesel Injection and Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-24-0007, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
