<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277604</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Concept of “Temperature Swing Heat Insulation” in Combustion Chamber Walls, and Appropriate Thermo-Physical Properties for Heat Insulation Coat</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kosaka</surname>
                  <given-names>Hidemasa</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Central R&amp;D Labs Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wakisaka</surname>
                  <given-names>Yoshifumi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Central R&amp;D Labs Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nomura</surname>
                  <given-names>Yoshihiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Central R&amp;D Labs Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hotta</surname>
                  <given-names>Yoshihiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Central R&amp;D Labs Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Koike</surname>
                  <given-names>Makoto</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Central R&amp;D Labs Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nakakita</surname>
                  <given-names>Kiyomi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Central R&amp;D Labs Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kawaguchi</surname>
                  <given-names>Akio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Motor Corp</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277593</issue-id>
         <fpage>142</fpage>
         <lpage>149</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277604"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The aim of this work is to investigate the possibility of heat insulation by “Temperature Swing”, that is temperature fluctuation, on combustion chamber walls coated with low-heat-conductivity and low-heat-capacity materials.</p>
            <p>Adiabatic engines studied in the 1980s, such as ceramic coated engines, caused constantly high temperature on combustion wall surface during the whole cycle including the intake stroke, even if it employed ceramic thermal barrier coating methods. This resulted in increase in NOx and Soot, decrease in volumetric efficiency and combustion efficiency, and facilitated the occurrence of engine knock.</p>
            <p>On the other hand, “Temperature Swing” coat on the combustion chamber walls leads to a large change in surface temperature. In this case, the surface temperature with this insulation coat follows the transient gas temperature, which decreases heat loss with the prevention of intake air heating, and also which is expected to prevent NOx and Soot from increasing. In our calculations, the increase of the surface temperature fluctuation, “Temperature Swing” results from the coat of lower heat conductivity and lower heat capacity. Particularly in Gasoline engines, the coat with the appropriate thickness can reduce the heat flux from the wall to the working gas during intake stroke and can avoid engine knock.</p>
            <p>Based on our calculations, it is clarified that both the prevention of intake air heating and the low heat rejection were successfully possible with the material of appropriate thermo-physical properties.</p>
            <p>In addition to the calculations, a preliminary test-piece experiment was executed. It was demonstrated that the surface temperature of a porous coat, that is a candidate of “Temperature Swing” coat, immediately follows the transient gas temperature, and also the proposed insulation coat can exactly reduce the heat flux in the single-cylinder engine.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bryzik, W. and Kamo, R., “TACOM/Cummins Adiabatic Engine Program,” SAE Technical Paper 830314, 1983, doi: 10.4271/830314.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G., Spindler, W., and Kolesa, K., “Heat Insulation of Combustion Chamber Walls - A Measure to Decrease the Fuel Consumption of I.C. Engines?,” SAE Technical Paper 870339, 1987, doi: 10.4271/870339.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Assanis, D. and Badillo, E., “Transient Heat Conduction in Low-Heat- Rejection Engine Combustion Chambers,” SAE Technical Paper 870156, 1987, doi: 10.4271/870156.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, J. and Borman, G., “Measurements of Instantaneous Heat Flux to Metal and Ceramic Surfaces in a Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 870155, 1987, doi: 10.4271/870155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Assanis, D. and Mathur, T., “The Effect of Thin Ceramic Coatings on Spark-Ignition Engine Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 900903, 1990, doi: 10.4271/900903.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Assanis, D., Wiese, K., Schwarz, E., and Bryzik, W., “The Effects of Ceramic Coatings on Diesel Engine Performance and Exhaust Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 910460, 1991, doi: 10.4271/910460.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Osawa, K., Kamo, R., and Valdmanis, E., “Performance of Thin Thermal Barrier Coating on Small Aluminum Block Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 910461, 1991, doi: 10.4271/910461.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawamura, H. and Akama, M., “Development of an Adiabatic Engine Installed Energy Recover Turbines and Converters of CNG Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-2265, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-2265.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wong, V., Bauer, W., Kamo, R., Bryzik, W. et al., “Assessment of Thin Thermal Barrier Coatings for I.C. Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 950980, 1995, doi: 10.4271/950980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wakisaka Yoshifumi, Kosaka Hidemasa, Inayoshi Minaji, Hotta Yoshihiro, Nakakita Kiyomi, Iida Shinya, Nomura Yoshihiro, WOPatent 09/020206 A1</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miyagawa Hiroshi, Nomura Yoshihiro, and Koike Makoto, “Numerical simulation of combustion process in Homogenious and stratified charge spark ignition engines, Smart control of turbulence,” Springer Veriag, Tokyo, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamamoto Seiji, Nagaoka Makoto, Ueda Reiko, Wakisaka Yoshifumi, and Noda Susumu, “Numerical simulation of diesel combustion with high EGR rate,” Proceedings of the COMODIA (2008)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
