<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277882</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Development of a Superheated Liquid Flash, Boiling (S.L.F.B) Engine for Waste Heat Recovery from Reciprocating Internal Combustion Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hewavitarane</surname>
                  <given-names>Dhaminda</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>The University of Kitakyushu</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yoshiyama</surname>
                  <given-names>Sadami</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>The University of Kitakyushu</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wadahama</surname>
                  <given-names>Hisashi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Okayama Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Xin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Production Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>October 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277873</issue-id>
         <fpage>1705</fpage>
         <lpage>1721</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277882"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>High temperature liquids held in a subcooled state are capable of storing large amounts of energy and then explosively releasing this energy when depressurized in a phase change process known as “Flashing”. The rapid volume expansion that results from this flashing has been harnessed to drive an expansion engine working on a cycle called “The Superheated Liquid Flash, Boiling” (S.L.F.B) cycle. The first stage showed that multiphase convective boiling of the unflashed water off the heated walls of the expansion unit supplemented the Flash work output. Furthermore, Flashing was seen to improve the effectiveness of convective boiling off the walls. The results were shown to be repeatable in a modified piston engine. Convective boiling was again shown to be able to supplement the power output under specific conditions. Engine power was seen to be directly related to the peak In-Cylinder pressure, which in turn was directly related to the mass and temperature of the injected subcooled water. The efficiency of the engine was directly related to the mass and level of subcooling of injected working fluid up to a boiling plate temperature of 215°C but inverted in relationship at boiling plate temperatures between 289°C and 297°C. This is hypothesised to be due to the effects of residual liquid mass caused by the Leidenfrost effect. The effective removal of the residual liquid mass during the exhaust stroke is expected to improve the overall efficiency of the engine.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saidur R., Rezaei M., Muzammil W.K., Hassan M.H., Paria S., Hasanuzzaman M., “Technologies to recover exhaust heat from internal combustion engines”, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, Volume 16, Issue 8, October 2012, Pages 5649-5659, ISSN 1364-0321, doi:10.1016/j.rser.2012.05.018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steffen Michael, Löffler Michael, Schaber Karlheinz, “Efficiency of a new Triangle Cycle with flash evaporation in a piston engine”, Energy, Volume 57, 1 August 2013, Pages 295-307, ISSN 0360- 5442, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2012.11.054.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lai Ngoc Anh, Fischer Johann, “Efficiencies of power flash cycles”, Energy, Volume 44, Issue 1, August 2012, Pages 1017- 1027, ISSN 0360-5442, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2012.04.046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fischer Johann, “Comparison of trilateral cycles and organic Rankine cycles”, Energy, Volume 36, Issue 10, October 2011, Pages 6208-6219, ISSN 0360-5442, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2011.07.041.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Öhman Henrik, Lundqvist Per, “Theory and method for analysis of low temperature driven power cycles”, Applied Thermal Engineering, Volume 37, May 2012, Pages 44-50, ISSN 1359- 4311, doi:10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2011.12.046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sher Eran, Bar-Kohany Tali, Rashkovan Alexander, “Flash-boiling atomization”, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, Volume 34, Issue 4, August 2008, Pages 417-439, ISSN 0360- 1285, doi:10.1016/j.pecs.2007.05.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Günther A., Wirth K.-E., “Evaporation phenomena in superheated atomization and its impact on the generated spray”, International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer, Volume 64, September 2013, Pages 952-965, ISSN 0017-9310, doi:10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2013.05.034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fu Jianqin, Liu Jingping, Ren Chengqin, Wang Linjun, Deng Banglin, Xu Zhengxin, “An open steam power cycle used for IC engine exhaust gas energy recovery”, Energy, Volume 44, Issue 1, August 2012, Pages 544-554, ISSN 0360-5442, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2012.05.047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xie Hui, Yang Can, “Dynamic behavior of Rankine cycle system for waste heat recovery of heavy duty diesel engines under driving cycle”, Applied Energy, Volume 112, December 2013, Pages 130-141, ISSN 0306-2619, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2013.05.071.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhu Sipeng, Deng Kangyao, Qu Shuan, “Energy and exergy analyses of a bottoming Rankine cycle for engine exhaust heat recovery”, Energy, Volume 58, 1 September 2013, Pages 448- 457, ISSN 0360-5442, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2013.06.031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pandiyarajan V., Chinna Pandian M., Malan E., Velraj R., Seeniraj R.V., “Experimental investigation on heat recovery from diesel engine exhaust using finned shell and tube heat exchanger and thermal storage system”, Applied Energy, Volume 88, Issue 1, January 2011, Pages 77-87, ISSN 0306-2619, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2010.07.023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boretti Alberto, “Recovery of exhaust and coolant heat with R245fa organic Rankine cycles in a hybrid passenger car with a naturally aspirated gasoline engine”, Applied Thermal Engineering, Volume 36, April 2012, Pages 73-77, ISSN 1359- 4311, doi:10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2011.11.060</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim Jungho, “Spray cooling heat transfer: The state of the art”, International Journal of Heat and Fluid Flow, Volume 28, Issue 4, August 2007, Pages 753-767, ISSN 0142-727X, doi:10.1016/j.ijheatfluidflow.2006.09.003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oliphant K., Webb B.W., McQuay M.Q., “An experimental comparison of liquid jet array and spray impingement cooling in the non-boiling regime”, Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science, Volume 18, Issue 1, September 1998, Pages 1-10, ISSN 0894- 1777, doi:10.1016/S0894-1777(98)10013-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buyevich Yu.A., Mankevich V.N., “Cooling of a superheated surface with a jet mist flow”, International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer, Volume 39, Issue 11, July 1996, Pages 2353- 2362, ISSN 0017-9310, doi:10.1016/0017-9310(95)00249-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen Ruey-Hung, Chow Louis C, Navedo Jose E, “Effects of spray characteristics on critical heat flux in subcooled water spray cooling”, International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer, Volume 45, Issue 19, September 2002, Pages 4033-4043, ISSN 0017- 9310, doi:10.1016/S0017-9310(02)00113-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
