<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278339</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Study of HCCI Combustion Using Spectroscopic Measurements and Chemical Kinetic Simulations</article-title>
            <subtitle>Effects of Fuel Composition, Engine Speed and Cylinder Pressure on Low-temperature Oxidation Reactions and Autoignition</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Takahashi</surname>
                  <given-names>Yusuke</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nihon University Graduate School</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Suyama</surname>
                  <given-names>Kenta</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nihon University Graduate School</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Iijima</surname>
                  <given-names>Akira</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nihon University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yoshida</surname>
                  <given-names>Koji</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nihon University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shoji</surname>
                  <given-names>Hideo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nihon University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>January 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278335</issue-id>
         <fpage>25</fpage>
         <lpage>33</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE Japan and Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278339"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The Homogenous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) engine is positioned as a next-generation internal combustion engine and has been the focus of extensive research in recent years to develop a practical system. One reason is that this new combustion system achieves lower fuel consumption and simultaneous reductions of nitrogen oxide (NOx) and particulate matter (PM) emissions, which are major issues of internal combustion engines today. However, the characteristics of HCCI combustion can prevent suitable engine operation owing to the rapid combustion process that occurs accompanied by a steep pressure rise when the amount of fuel injected is increased to obtain higher power output. A major issue of HCCI is to control this rapid combustion so that the quantity of fuel injected can be increased for greater power. Controlling the ignition timing is also an issue because it is substantially influenced by the chemical reactions of the fuel. Various approaches are being researched for expanding the range of stable engine operation, including the application of turbocharging, the use of residual combustion gas, stratification of the fuel concentration, and the use of a blend of two types of fuel having widely different ignition characteristics.</p>
            <p>Experiments and chemical kinetic simulations were conducted using a blended fuel of n-heptane (0 RON), which autoignites easily, and iso-octane (100 RON) that is not conducive to autoignition. The results revealed the possibility o f increasing the fuel injection quantity while controlling the ignition timing. It was also found that varying the engine speed influenced the cool flame activity level, with the result that the ignition timing differed. These results provide insights for controlling the autoignition process leading to HCCI combustion.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Einewall, P. and Johansson, B.: omogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) sing Isooctane, Ethanol and natural Gas-A ompression With Spark-Ignition Operation, SAE aper 972874 (1997).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishibashi, Y., and Asai, M.: Improving the Exhaust missions o f Two -Stroke Engines by Applying the ctivated Radical Combustion, SAE paper 960742 (1996).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iida, N.: A Study of Autoignition and Combustion in wo-Stroke ATAC Engine - Compression Ignition haracteristics of Low Carbon Alternative Fuels, SAE aper 1999-01-3274 (1999).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shibata, G., Oyama, K., Urushihara, T., and Nakano, .: Correlation o f Low Temperature Heat Release With uel Composition and HCCI Engine Combustion, SAE aper 2005-01-0138 (2005).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuboyama, T., Moriyoshi, Y., Hatamura, K., Takahashi, ., Urata, Y., and Yamada, T.: Extension of Operating ange of a Multi-Cylinder Gasoline HCCI Engine using he Blowdown Supercharging System, SAE paper 201101- 0896 (2011).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J. A., Leppard, W. R., and Sloane, T. M.: The ffect o f POx on the Autoignition Chemistry of n- eptane and Isooctane in an HCCI Engine, SAE paper 2002-01-2861 (2002).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaydon, A. G.: The Spectroscopy of Flame-2nd Edition, ondon, Chapman and Hall Ltd, pp.412 (1974).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iijima, A., Yoshida, K. and Shoji, H., A spectroscopic tudy of ignition in an HCCI engine, Transactions of the apan Society of Mechanical Engineers (in Japanese), ol. B, Vol. 74, No. 742, pp. 1433-1442 (2008).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, H. J., P., Pitz, W. J., Westbrook, C. K., allahan, C. V., and Dryer, F. L.: Oxidation of utomotive Primary Reference Fuels at Elevated ressures, Proc. Combust. Inst., Vol. 27, pp. 379-387 (1998).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuwahara, K., and Ando, H.: Effects of different gnitability fuel addition on the hydrocarbon chemical inetic mechanism, Automotive Engineers of Japan (in apanese), Vol. 41, No. 3, pp. 697-702 (2010).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
