<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277729</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Strategy for Mode Transition between Low Temperature Combustion and Conventional Combustion in a Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Han</surname>
                  <given-names>Sangwook</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Korea Automotive Technology Institute</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kim</surname>
                  <given-names>Hyunchul</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Korea Automotive Technology Institute</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bae</surname>
                  <given-names>Choongsik</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Korea Advanced Inst. of Science &amp; Tech.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>September 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277710</issue-id>
         <fpage>1706</fpage>
         <lpage>1715</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277729"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Mode transition between low temperature combustion (LTC) and conventional combustion was performed by changing the exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) rate from 60% to 0% or vice versa in a light duty diesel engine. The indicated mean effective pressure (IMEP) before mode transition was set at 0.45 MPa, representing the maximum load of LTC in this research engine. Various engine operating parameters (rate of EGR change, EGR path length, and residual gas) were considered in order to investigate their influence on the combustion mode transition. The characteristics of combustion mode transition were analyzed based on the in-cylinder pressure and hydrocarbon (HC) emission of each cycle.</p>
            <p>The general results showed that drastic changes of power output, combustion noise, and HC emission occurred during the combustion mode transition due to the improper injection conditions for each combustion mode. Therefore, a strategy for smooth combustion mode transition was developed by controlling the injection parameters such as injection timing, injection duration, and the number of injections on a cycle-by-cycle basis. As a consequence of gradually retarding the injection timing, gradually decreasing the injection duration, and adding a pilot injection, the differences in power output and combustion noise between the periods before and after mode transition were reduced by up to 100% and 225%, respectively, compared to those values for the case without controlling the injection parameters.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E., “Advanced Compression-Ignition Engines - Understanding the In-Cylinder Processes,” Proceedings of Combustion Institute, 2009, 32(2), 2727-2742.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yao, M., Zheng, Z. and Liu, H., “Progress and Recent Trends in Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Engines,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 2009, 35(5), 398-437.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koci, C., Ra, Y., Krieger, R., Andrie, M. et al., “Multiple-Event Fuel Injection Investigations in a Highly-Dilute Diesel Low Temperature Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):837-857, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0925.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S., Bae, C., Miles, P., Choi, D. et al., “The Influence of Charge Dilution and Injection Timing on Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion and Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3837, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-3837.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ogawa, H., Miyamoto, N., Shimizu, H., and Kido, S., “Characteristics of Diesel Combustion in Low Oxygen Mixtures with Ultra-High EGR,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1147, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, S., Shim, E., Jang, J., Park, J. et al., “Operating Range of Low Temperature Diesel Combustion with Supercharging,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1440, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1440.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Butts, R., Foster, D., Krieger, R., Andrie, M. et al., “Investigation of the Effects of Cetane Number, Volatility, and Total Aromatic Content on Highly-Dilute Low Temperature Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0337, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0337.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, T., Suzuki, M. and Ogawa, H., “Effect of Two-Stage Injection on Unburned Hydrocarbon and Carbon Monoxide Emissions in Smokeless Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion with Ultra-High Exhaust Gas Recirculation,” Int. J. Engine Res., 2010, 11(5), 345-354.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colban, W., Miles, P., and Oh, S., “Effect of Intake Pressure on Performance and Emissions in an Automotive Diesel Engine Operating in Low Temperature Combustion Regimes,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4063, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-4063.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sarangi, A., McTaggart-Cowan, G., and Garner, C., “The Effects of Intake Pressure on High EGR Low Temperature Diesel Engine Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2145, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-2145.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ogawa, H., Li, T., Miyamoto, N., Kido, S. et al., “Dependence of Ultra- High EGR and Low Temperature Diesel Combustion on Fuel Injection Conditions and Compression Ratio,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3386, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3386.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santoso, H., Matthews, J., and Cheng, W., “Managing SI/HCCI Dual- Mode Engine Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0162, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0162.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Milovanovic, N., Blundell, D., Gedge, S., and Turner, J., “SI-HCCI-SI Mode Transition at Different Engine Operating Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0156, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0156.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Narayanaswamy, K. and Rutland, C., “A Modeling Investigation of Combustion Control Variables During DI-Diesel HCCI Engine Transients,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1084, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-1084.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, Y., Xie, H. and Zhao, H., “Investigation of SI-HCCI Hybrid Combustion and Control Strategies for Combustion Mode Switching in a Four-Stroke Gasoline Engine,” Combust. Sci. and Tech., 2009, 181(5), 782-799.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cong, S., Garner, C. P., and McTaggart-Cowan, G. P., “The Effects of Exhaust Back Pressure on Conventional and Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion,” Proc. IMechE, Part D: J. Automobile Engineering, 2011, 225(2), 222-235.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
