<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="other"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">3663716</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/338561</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB750208</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Notes</article-title>
            <subtitle>University Schools of Business</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>04</month>
            <year>2002</year>
            <string-date>April 2002</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>75</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2002.75.issue-2</issue-id>
         <fpage>377</fpage>
         <lpage>385</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/338561"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <title>Appointments</title>
         <p>Julie Agnew, visiting asst. prof., William and Mary, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Manju Ahuja, asst. prof., information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Olugbenga Ajilore, lecturer, economics, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Gordon J. Alexander, visiting prof., UCLA, Jan. 2002.</p>
         <p>Bruce Alford, assoc. prof., marketing, Louisiana Tech, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Hassan Aljifri, asst. prof., Univ. Miami, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Jonlee Andrews, clinical assoc. prof., marketing, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Deborah J. Armstrong, asst. prof., Arkansas, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Todd Arnold, asst. prof., marketing, Washington State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Alex Ashwal, lecturer, accounting, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Reginald Audibert, lecturer, management, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Murray R. Barrick, Stanley M. Howe Chair in Leadership, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Ronald J. Beckman, assoc. prof., accounting, South Dakota, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Hendrik H. Bessembinder, prof., and A. Blaine Huntsman Presidential Chair in Finance, Univ. Utah, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Anu Bhayana, lecturer, economics, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Benjamin Bishin, asst. prof., Univ. Miami, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Walter E. Block, prof., and Harold E. Wirth Eminent Scholar Chair in Economics, Loyola (New Orleans), Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Thomas Boyd, assoc. prof., marketing, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Samuel A. Burer, asst. prof., management sciences, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Andrew E. Burke, visiting assoc. prof., UCLA, Apr. 2002.</p>
         <p>Robin Burke, assoc. prof., information systems and decision sciences, California State, Fullerton, Jan. 2001.</p>
         <p>Jeff Buszkiewicz, lecturer, finance, Indiana, Jan. 2001.</p>
         <p>Rene Caldentey, asst. prof., operations management, NYU, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Tamara Carbone, lecturer, business writing, California State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Gary Caton, asst. prof., Washington State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Todd Chiles, asst. prof., Missouri—Columbia, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Alan Chmura, visiting asst. prof., Wyoming, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Rohan Christie‐David, assoc. prof., finance, Louisiana Tech, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Neil C. Churchill, visiting prof., UCLA, Oct. 2001.</p>
         <p>Doreen Ciletti, visiting instructor, marketing, Duquesne, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Alex Citura, asst. prof., decision and information analysis, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Nina Collum, visiting instructor, Mississippi State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>James G. Combs, asst. prof., Florida State, August 2001.</p>
         <p>Suraj Commuri, asst. prof., Columbia—Missouri, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Brad Crisp, convertible lecturer, accounting and information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Robert L. Cross, asst. prof., Virginia, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Kirsten Daniel, visiting asst. prof., economics, Loyola (New Orleans), Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Antony Davies, asst. prof., Duquesne, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Keith Dayton, lecturer, management, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>William Donoher, asst. prof., management and decision science, Washington State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Caesar Douglas, asst. prof., Florida State, August 2001.</p>
         <p>Garland B. Durham, asst. prof., economics, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Andrew Ellul, asst. prof., finance, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Ted Englebrecht, prof., and Smolinski Chair, accounting, Louisiana Tech, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Mauricio Featherman, asst. prof., management information systems, Washington State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Kathy Fletcher, lecturer, business communication, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Gary J. Gaeth, Cedar Rapids Area Business Chair, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Shelby Gerking, prof., Wyoming, May 2001.</p>
         <p>Treena Gillespie, lecturer, management, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Andreas Gintschel, visiting prof., finance, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Pedro Gomis‐Proqueros, asst. prof., Univ. Miami, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Jerry R. Goolsby, prof., marketing, and Hilton/Baldridge Eminent Scholar Chair in Music Industry, Loyola (New Orleans), Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Mike Goree, instructor, marketing, Mississippi State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Prem Gupta, lecturer, information systems and decision sciences, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Haresh Gurroni, assoc. prof., Univ. Miami, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Dogan Gursoy, asst. prof., hotel and restaurant administration, Washington State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>David Hardesty, asst. prof., Univ. Miami, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Brent A. Hathaway, assoc. prof. and chair, Wyoming, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Rod Haywood, lecturer, business communication, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Janet Heidewald, lecturer, business communication, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Ronald L. Hess, Jr., asst. prof., William and Mary, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Traci J. Hess, asst. prof., William and Mary, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Keisuke Hirano, assoc. prof., Univ. Miami, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Wayne Hochwarter, asst. prof., Florida State, August 2001.</p>
         <p>Nicole Hoffman, asst. prof., marketing, Mississippi State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Susan Hogan, asst. prof., marketing, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Darby Holsing, visiting asst. prof., South Dakota, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Kewei Hou, asst. prof., Ohio State, Oct. 2001.</p>
         <p>Mark Houston, asst. prof., Missouri—Columbia, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Wayne W. Huang, assoc. prof., Ohio Univ., Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Jerry James, lecturer, finance, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Sandy D. Jap, assoc. prof., marketing, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Vaidy Jayaraman, assoc. prof., Univ. Miami, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Bing Jing, asst. prof., information systems, NYU, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Joseph Johnson, asst. prof., Univ. Miami, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Timothy A. Judge, Matherly‐McKethan Eminent Scholar, Univ. Florida, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Velitchka Kaltcheva, asst. prof., Univ. Miami, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Dewan (Reza) Karim, lecturer, management, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Burak Kazaz, asst. prof., Univ. Miami, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Jaehwan Kim, asst. prof. marketing, Univ. Colorado, Fall 2001.</p>
         <p>Sei‐Wan Kim, asst. prof., economics, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Dong Gil Ko, convertible lecturer, accounting and information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Timothy A. Kruse, asst. prof., Arkansas, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Giuseppe Labianca, asst. prof., organization and management, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Manuel Laguna, assoc. prof. and chair, operations, Univ. Colorado, Fall 2001.</p>
         <p>Byung (Brian) Lee, assoc. prof., management, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Tanya M. Lee, asst. prof., Univ. North Texas, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Natalia Levina, asst. prof., information systems, NYU, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>William Lindsay, visiting prof., management, Miami Univ., Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Cornelis Los, assoc. prof., Kent State, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Jason Lueg, asst. prof., marketing, Mississippi State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Christian Lundblad, asst. prof., finance, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Dalia Marciukaityte, asst. prof., finance, Louisiana Tech, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Johan Marklund, asst. prof., operations management, Univ. Colorado, Fall 2001.</p>
         <p>Stanimir Markov, senior lecturer, accounting, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Kimball P. Marshall, prof., marketing, Loyola (New Orleans), August 2001.</p>
         <p>Bruce May, acting assoc. dean, South Dakota, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Gene McClain, lecturer, operations and decision technology, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Josetta McLaughlin, director, School of Management and Marketing, Roosevelt, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Molly Mercer, asst. prof., accounting, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Richard Metters, assoc. prof., decision and information analysis, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Tom Meyvis, asst. prof., marketing, NYU, July 2001.</p>
         <p>John Micetich, adjunct lecturer, Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Jan. 2002.</p>
         <p>Darius Miller, asst. prof., finance, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>David Miller, asst. prof., Oregon State, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Matthew F. Mitchell, asst. prof., economics, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Lisa Mohanty, lecturer, economics, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Peter Moore, asst. prof., Univ. Miami, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Michael G. Morris, asst. prof., Virginia, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Akm Mabub Morshed, asst. prof., economics, Washington State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Jim Moshinskie, assoc. prof., information systems, and Accenture Professor of Human Performance Improvement, Baylor, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Lynn F. Muller, asst. prof., marketing, South Dakota, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Peter Mykytyn, prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>D. J. Nayakankuppam, asst. prof., marketing, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>James Nelson, asst. prof., Ohio State, Oct. 2001.</p>
         <p>Kay Nelson, research scientist and assoc. prof., Ohio State, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Richard G. Netemeyer, prof., Virginia, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>John Nofsinger, asst. prof., finance, Washington State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Donald Norris, assoc. prof., marketing, Miami Univ., Fall 2001.</p>
         <p>Philip O'Connor, visiting asst. prof., Wyomimg, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Greg R. Oldham, assoc. dean of research, Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Sandra Owen, lecturer, business communication, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Lisa Owens, asst. prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Pramod Pandya, lecturer, information systems and decision sciences, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Yun Park, assoc. prof., finance, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>John Pearson, assoc. prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Lasse Heje Pedersen, asst. prof., finance, NYU, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Monica Perry, assoc. prof., marketing, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>David Petrie, assoc. prof., information systems and decision sciences, California State, Fullerton, Jan. 2002.</p>
         <p>Mark Pingle, assoc. prof. and department chair, Nevada—Reno, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Michael Prietula, prof., decision and information analysis, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Dennis Redding, senior lecturer, organization and management, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Craig G. Rennie, asst. prof., Arkansas, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Wai‐Pen (Jenny) Resnick, lecturer, accounting, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Bruce L. Reynolds, prof., Virginia, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Christopher Robert, asst. prof., Missouri—Columbia, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Piper Roundtree, visiting asst. prof., Roosevelt, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Rudy Sanchez, asst. prof., California State, Fresno, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Nancy Scherer, asst. prof., Univ. Miami, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>James Schmidtke, asst. prof., California State, Fresno, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Kenneth Schultz, asst. prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Arijit Sengupta, asst. prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Mohsen Sharifi, lecturer, accounting, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Kristina Sheeler, lecturer, business communication, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Aamer Sheikh, asst. prof., William and Mary, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Nagaraj Sivasubramaniam, asst. prof., Duquesne, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Charles Smith, lecturer, management, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Dwight Sneathen, asst. prof., accounting, Mississippi State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Roy Suddaby, asst. prof., management and organizations, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Amrit Tiwana, asst. prof., decision and information analysis, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Peter A. Todd, prof., Virginia, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Mehmet Tosun, research asst. prof., West Virginia, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Valerie Trott, asst. prof., Duquesne, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Daniel Turban, prof., Missouri—Columbia, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>David van Hoose, prof., economics, and Herman Lay Chair of Private Enterprise, Baylor, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Anand M. Vijh, Marvin and Rose Lee Pomerantz Chair in Business Administration, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Albert Sa Vinhas, asst. prof., marketing, Emory, Jan. 2002.</p>
         <p>Gary Wagner, asst. prof., Duquesne, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>John Waltner, Distinguished Executive‐in‐Residence, South Dakota, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Merrill Warkentin, assoc. prof., information systems, Mississippi State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>John Waters, visiting asst. prof., Wyoming, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Jeanne M. Wilson, asst. prof., William and Mary, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Nicholas X. Wonder, asst. prof., Wyoming, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Jeffrey Wong, asst. prof., Oregon State, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Xuemin Yan, asst. prof., Missouri—Columbia, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Michelle H. Yetman, asst. prof., accounting, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Mann Yoon, visiting assoc. prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Keven Yost, visiting asst. prof., Univ. Miami, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Bassam Yousif, lecturer, economics, California State, Fullerton, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Xiaoyun Yu, convertible lecturer, finance, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Jaime Zender, asst. prof., finance, Univ. Colorado, Fall 2001.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <title>Grants</title>
         <p>Kathryn Bartol, prof., Maryland; 2001; $673,959; National Science Foundation; for research project entitled “Understanding Female and Minority Retention and Success in the Information Technology Workplace: Total Rewards and Social Network Perspective.”</p>
         <p>Terry L. Boles, assoc. prof., management and organizations, Iowa; Aug. 2001; Charles A. Taff Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Janet Buelow, assoc. prof., South Dakota; July 2001–June 2003; $82,500; U.S. Department of Education; to study “Globalization of Health Care Services Internships and Faculty.”</p>
         <p>Michael Fu, prof., Maryland; 2001; Semiconductor Research Corporation; for research project, “Preventative Maintenance in Semiconductor Manufacturing Labs.”</p>
         <p>Amy L. Kristof‐Brown, asst. prof., management and organizations, Iowa; Aug. 2001; Henry B. Tippie Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Bruce May, acting assoc. dean, South Dakota; July 2001–June 2003; $82,500; U.S. Department of Education; to study “Globalization of Health Care Services Internships and Faculty.”</p>
         <p>Robert Rosacker, assoc. prof., South Dakota; October 2001; $50,000; Americas University Alliance Program; plug‐and‐play curriculum development grant to support development of innovative curricula that incorporate technology as a core component of classroom instruction.</p>
         <p>Gary J. Russell, prof., marketing, Iowa; Aug. 2001; Henry B. Tippie Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Minet Schindehutte, asst. prof., entrepreneurship, Miami. Univ.; Spring 2002; $31,250; Ohio State University Research Foundation; for development of two web‐based courses in partnership with the engineering department.</p>
         <p>Alberto M. Segre, prof., management sciences, Iowa; Aug. 2001; Henry B. Tippie Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Ted P. Temzelides, asst. prof., economics, Iowa; Aug. 2001; Henry B. Tippie Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Jeffery Thompson, asst. prof., management, Miami Univ.; 2001; William H. Newman Award for best research based on a dissertation.</p>
         <p>Steven Trach, asst. prof, and director, Business Research Bureau, South Dakota; Oct. 2002; $50,000; Americas University Alliance Program; plug‐and‐play curriculum development grant to support development of innovative curricula that incorporate technology as a core component of classroom instruction.</p>
         <p>Viswanath Venkatesh, asst. prof., Maryland; 2001; $673,959; National Science Foundation; for research project entitled “Understanding Female and Minority Retention and Success in the Information Technology Workplace: Total Rewards and Social Network Perspective.”</p>
         <p>Toni M. Whited, assoc. prof., finance, Iowa; Aug. 2001; Martha and Dennis Hesse Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Ian Williamson, asst. prof., Maryland; 2001; $673,959; National Science Foundation; for research project entitled “Understanding Female and Minority Retention and Success in the Information Technology Workplace: Total Rewards and Social Network Perspective.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <title>Leaves</title>
         <p>Gabriel Biehal, assoc. prof., Maryland; Jan. 2002–May 2002; to do research on the topic of shoppers' multiple‐item buying.</p>
         <p>Amelia Carr, asst. prof., Ohio State; Oct. 2001–Sept. 2002; personal leave.</p>
         <p>Terry Dworkin, prof., business law, Indiana; Fall 2001; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Michael Fu, prof., Maryland; Jan. 2002–May 2002; to write a book on Monte Carlo simulation, and to collaborate on stochastic dynamic programming research.</p>
         <p>Mike Groomer, prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana; Fall 2001; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>W. Harvey Hegarty, prof., management, Indiana; Spring 2002; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Narasimhan Jegadeesh, Harry A. Brandt Distinguished Professor, Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign; Aug. 2001–Jan. 2002; to pursue projects on stock market bubbles and information content of stock analyst recommendations.</p>
         <p>Robert Jennings, prof., finance, Indiana; Fall 2001; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>P. K. Kannan, assoc. prof., Maryland; Aug. 2001–Jan. 2002; to do research on the pricing of information products.</p>
         <p>Shanker Krishnan, assoc. prof., marketing, Indiana; academic year 2001–2; sabbatical and leave without pay.</p>
         <p>Ronald Lau, assoc. prof., production, South Dakota; Aug. 2001–May 2002; visiting professor at Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.</p>
         <p>David A. Lins, prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign; Aug. 2001–Jan. 2002; to study issues related to mergers, acquisitions, business valuations, real options, and corporate restructurings.</p>
         <p>Vince Mabert, prof., operations and decision technology, Indiana; Spring 2002; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>David MacKay, prof., marketing, Indiana; Spring 2002; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>John Maxwell, assoc. prof., business economics and public policy, Indiana; Spring 2002; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Martin McCrory, assoc. prof., business law, Indiana; Fall 2001; leave without pay.</p>
         <p>Terry Obert, assoc. prof., Mississippi State; Aug. 2001–Aug. 2002; to work for Union Planters Bank as a treasury analyst (professional development).</p>
         <p>Linda Pastor, lecturer, business communication, Indiana; academic year 2001–2; leave without pay.</p>
         <p>Neil D. Pearson, assoc. prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign; Aug. 2001–Jan. 2002; to continue research.</p>
         <p>Gordon Phillips, assoc. prof., Maryland; Aug. 2001–Aug. 2002; visiting professor at MIT Sloan School of Management.</p>
         <p>Gerald Salamon, prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana; academic year 2001–2; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Venkatesh Shankar, assoc. prof., Maryland; Aug. 2001–Dec. 2001; to be visiting professor at MIT, Sloan School of Management, and to continue research.</p>
         <p>Michael Simkowitz, prof., finance, Indiana; Fall 2001; leave without pay.</p>
         <p>Ronald Stephenson, prof., marketing, Indiana; Spring 2002; leave without pay.</p>
         <p>Susan Taylor, prof., Maryland; Sept. 2001–Dec. 2001; to pursue research on the nature of internal labor markets and individual careers in the “New Economy.”</p>
         <p>Haluk Unal, assoc. prof., Maryland; Jan. 2002–June 2002; to do research at the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</p>
         <p>Robert Windle, prof., Maryland; Jan. 2002–June 2002; to do research on the impact of customer characteristics on airline route demand.</p>
         <p>Wayne Winston, prof., operations and decision technology, Indiana; Fall 2001; sabbatical.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <title>Promotions</title>
         <p>Penne Ainsworth, prof., Wyoming, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Eli Bartov, prof., accounting, NYU, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Daniel Beneish, prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Terry L. Boles, assoc. prof. (tenured), management and organizations, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Catherine Daily, prof., management, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Rohit Deo, assoc. prof., statistics and operations research, NYU, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>John Fraedrich, prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Roberto Garcia, clinical prof., international business, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>James Grandorf, clinical assoc. prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana; Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Dan Greiner, clinical asst. prof., finance, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Paul Grimes, department head, finance and economics, Mississippi State, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Stephen Hayford, prof., business law, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>M. Beth Ingram, prof., economics, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Oliver Kim, prof., Maryland, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Mark Lehman, assoc. prof., accounting, Mississippi State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Marvin B. Lieberman, prof., UCLA, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Rebecca Long, assoc. prof., management, Mississippi State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Anthony Lynch, assoc. prof., finance, NYU, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Laureen Maines, assoc. prof. (tenured), accounting and information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>George Marakas, assoc. prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Michael A. Mayo, assoc. prof., Kent State, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Martin McCrory, assoc. prof., business law, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>William McKinley, prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Elizabeth Morrison, prof., management, NYU, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Harry J. Paarsch, prof., economics, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Kevin Rogers, assoc. prof., finance and economics, Mississippi State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>David Rubinstein, clinical asst. prof., management, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Mariko Sakakibara, assoc. prof., UCLA, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Alberto M. Segre, prof., management sciences, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Scott Shane, prof., Maryland, August 2001.</p>
         <p>David Vance, asst. prof., information systems, Mississippi State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Kenton Walker, prof., Wyoming, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Gregory White, prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Toni M. Whited, assoc. prof. (tenured), finance, Iowa, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Robert Windle, prof., Maryland, Aug. 2001.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc5">
         <title>Resignations</title>
         <p>Bruce Alford, asst. prof., marketing, Mississippi State, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Jeffrey Allen, asst. prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Subramanian Balachander, asst. prof., Maryland, May 2001.</p>
         <p>Bruce Bettinghause, asst. prof., Missouri—Columbia, Jan. 2002.</p>
         <p>Cory Capps, asst. prof., economics, Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Claudia Cogliser, asst. prof., Oregon State, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Peter DaDalt, asst. prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Tom Gruen, asst. prof., marketing, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Robert Hauswald, asst. prof., finance, Indiana, May 2001.</p>
         <p>Erika James, asst. prof., organization and management, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Christine Jiang, prof., Kent State, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Mary Jones, assoc. prof., information systems, Mississippi State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>G. Keong Leong, assoc. prof., Ohio State, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Kristi Lewis‐Tyran, asst. prof., Oregon State, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Charles Litecky, prof., management and information systems, Mississippi State, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Liping Liu, asst. prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Victoria Mitchell, asst. prof., Ohio State, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Bert Morrow, asst. prof., management and information systems, Mississippi State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>John Naman, teaching prof., Maryland, May 2001.</p>
         <p>Barrie Nault, assoc. prof., Ohio State, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Jim Nelson, asst. prof., Univ. Utah, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Kay Nelson, asst. prof., Univ. Utah, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Janie Phelps, asst. prof., finance and economics, Mississippi State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>James A. Seida, asst. prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana, May 2001.</p>
         <p>Deon Strickland, asst. prof., Ohio State, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Debbie Thorne, asst. prof., marketing, Mississippi State, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Craig Tyran, asst. prof., Oregon State, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Vincent Vargas, asst. prof., decision and information analysis, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Linda Wright, asst. prof., marketing, Mississippi State, June 2001.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc6">
         <title>Retirements</title>
         <p>Lawrence Bodin, prof., Maryland, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Roy Carpenter, prof., management, Mississippi State.</p>
         <p>Shih‐fan (George) Chu, prof., Nevado—Reno, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Stan Fromowitz, assoc. prof., Maryland, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Saul Gass, prof., Maryland, June 2001.</p>
         <p>James Gentry, prof., accounting, Emory, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Bob Hershbarger, prof., finance and economics, Mississippi State, Jan. 2001.</p>
         <p>Dennis Johnson, prof., economics, South Dakota, May 2001.</p>
         <p>Richard Kolodny, prof., Maryland, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Zarrel Lambert, prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Rudolph Lamone, prof., Maryland, June 2001.</p>
         <p>William Lindsay, prof., management, Northern Kentucky, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Edwin Locke, prof., Maryland, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Frederick L. Neumann, prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Charles Neyhart, prof., Oregon State, June 2001.</p>
         <p>James A. Papke, prof., economics, Purdue, Spring 2001.</p>
         <p>James L. Perotti, prof., Ohio Univ., June 2001.</p>
         <p>Patricia Sanderson, assoc. prof., finance and economics, Mississippi State, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Mary Alice Seville, assoc. prof., Oregon State, June 2001.</p>
         <p>William Widhelm, assoc. prof., Maryland, June 2001.</p>
         <p>Richard Ziegler, assoc. prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2001.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc7">
         <title>Deaths</title>
         <p>Marvin Jolson, prof., Maryland; July 24, 2001; Baltimore, Md.</p>
      </sec>
   </body>
</article>
