<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">jeducfina</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000843</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Journal of Education Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>University of Illinois Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00989495</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19446470</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">36</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i23018060</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23018096</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Differentiated Compensation: How California School Districts Use Economic Incentives to Target Teachers</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Katharine O.</given-names>
                  <surname>Strunk</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Dara</given-names>
                  <surname>Zeehandelaar</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>268</fpage>
         <lpage>293</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2010 Board of Trustees of the University of Illinois Manufactured in the United States of America</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23018096"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Many districts and schools have trouble recruiting and retaining teachers who have the necessary credentials and skills to meet the needs of their students. This trend is particularly severe in low-income, "high-needs" schools and districts. As such, districts and schools are implementing policies that are intended to reform compensation in order to increase teacher recruitment and retention. Although much of the recent discussion surrounding teacher compensation has centered around districts' use of merit pay, many districts are already using differentiated compensation incentives to target specific kinds of teachers in an attempt to attract and retain not only the highest quality teachers, but also the teachers districts most need to teach in their specific local contexts. Using a self-collected dataset of California school districts from the 2005—2006 and 2008—2009 school years, the frequency with which districts in California use targeted economic incentives and the kinds of districts that are most likely to implement such policies are examined. While many school districts in California have economic incentive policies targeted at teachers with specific skills or credentials, most incentive policies are focused on teachers with rough proxies for "quality." Those that do target teachers in high-need subjects, for the most part, focus on rewarding those certified to teach special education students and English language learners (ELLs)—few are aimed at teachers of other hard-to-staff subjects such as math or science. In addition, there is limited evidence that particularly "hard-to-staff" districts—such as those with high proportions of minority and poor students and those with low academic achievement—are more likely to implement economic incentives that target teachers with specific subject credentials and are less likely to focus their efforts on attracting and retaining "high-quality" teachers.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d35e183a1310">
            <label>*</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d35e190" publication-type="other">
presented at the 2009 Annual Conference of the American
Education Finance Association in Nashville, TN</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d35e199" publication-type="other">
the 2009 Annual Conference of the Association for
Policy Analysis and Management in Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d35e208" publication-type="other">
the Martin School of Public Policy and
Administration in Lexington, KY, in April 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d35e227a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e231" publication-type="other">
Aaronson, D., L. Barrow, and W. Sander. 2007. Teachers and student achievement in the Chicago
public high schools. Journal of Labor Economics 25 (1):95—135.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e241a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e245" publication-type="other">
Ballou, D., and M. Podgursky. 1997. Teacher Pay and Teacher Quality: W. E. Upjohn Institute.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e252a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e256" publication-type="other">
———. 1998. The case against teacher certification. Public Interest 132:17-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e263a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e267" publication-type="other">
Baiter, D., and W. D. Duncombe. 2008. Recruiting Highly Qualified Teachers: Do District
Recruitment Practices Matter? Public Finance Review 36 (1):33-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e278a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e282" publication-type="other">
Betts, J. R., K. S. Reuben, and A. Danenberg. 2000. Equal resources, equal outcomes? The
distribution of school resources and student achievement in California. San Francisco, CA:
Public Policy Institute of California.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e295a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e299" publication-type="other">
Blair, J. 2001. Lawmakers plunge into teacher pay. Education Week 20 (23):1,16.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e306a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e310" publication-type="other">
Boyd, D., H. Lankford, and S. Loeb. 2005. The draw of home: How teachers' preferences for
proximity disadvantage urban schools. Journal of Policy Analysis and Management 24 (1): 113-
132.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e323a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e327" publication-type="other">
Bruno, J. E., and E. Negrete. 1983. Analysis of teacher wage incentive programs for promoting staff
stability in a large urban school district. The Urban Review 15 (3):139-149.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e337a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e341" publication-type="other">
Clewell, B. C., and L. B. Forcier. 2000. Increasing the Number of Mathematics and Science Teachers:
A Review of teacher recruitment programs. National Commission on Mathematics and Science
Teaching for the 21st Century.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e354a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e358" publication-type="other">
Clotfelter, C. T., E. Glennie, H. F. Ladd, and J. Vigdor. 2008. Would higher salaries keep teachers
in high-poverty schools? Evidence from a policy intervention in North Carolina. Journal of
Public Economics 92 (5-6):1352-1370.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e372a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e376" publication-type="other">
Clotfelter, C. T., H. F. Ladd, J. Vigdor, and J. Wheeler. 2006. High-poverty schools and the
distribution of teachers and principals. North Carolina Law Review 85:1345-1380.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e386a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e390" publication-type="other">
Collins, T. 1999. Attracting and retaining teachers in rural areas. Charleston, WV: ERIC
Clearinghouse on Rural Education and Small Schools.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e400a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e404" publication-type="other">
Committee for Economic Development. 2009. Teacher Compensation and Teacher Quality.
Washington, DC: Committee for Economic Development.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e414a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e418" publication-type="other">
Conant, J. 1961. Slums and suburbs. New York: McGraw-Hill.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e425a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e429" publication-type="other">
Dooley, S. 2009. Teacher Pay Raises Lead to Cuts Elsewhere. Quad-City Times, May 10.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e436a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e440" publication-type="other">
Eberts, R., K. Hollenbeck, and J. Stone. 2002. Teacher Performance Incentives and Student
Outcomes. The Journal of Human Resources 37 (4):913-927.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e451a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e455" publication-type="other">
Esch, C. E., C. M. Chang-Ross, R. Guha, D. C. Humphrey, P. M. Shields, J. D. Tiffany-Morales, M.
E. Wechsler, and K. R. Woodworth. 2005. The Status of the Teaching Profession, 2005. Santa
Cruz, CA: The Center for the Future of Teaching and Learning.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e468a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e472" publication-type="other">
Figlio, D. N. 2002. Can public schools buy better-qualified teachers? Industrial and Labor Relations
Review 55 (4):686-699.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e482a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e486" publication-type="other">
Figlio, D. N., and L. W. Kenny. 2007. Individual teacher incentives and student performance.
Journal of Public Economics 91 (5-6):901-914.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e496a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e500" publication-type="other">
Fowler, R. C. 2003. The Massachusetts Signing Bonus Program for New Teachers: A model of
teacher preparation worth copying? Education Policy Analysis Archives 11 (3):1-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e510a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e514" publication-type="other">
Guarino, C. M., L. Santibanez, and G. A. Daley. 2006. Teacher recruitment and retention: A review
of the recent empirical literature. Review of Educational Research 76 (2):173-208.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e524a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e528" publication-type="other">
Hanushek, E. A. 2007. The single salary schedule and other issues of teacher pay. Peabody Journal
of Education 82 (4):574-586.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e539a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e543" publication-type="other">
Hanushek, E. A., J. F. Kain, and S. G. Rivkin. 2004. Why public schools lose teachers. The Journal
of Human Resources 39 (2):326-354.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e553a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e557" publication-type="other">
Henke, R. R., X. Chen, S. Geis, and P. R. Knepper. 2000. Progress through the teacher pipeline:
1992-93 college graduates and elementary/secondary school teaching as of 1997. Washington,
DC: U.S. Department of Education, National Cetner for Education Statistics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e570a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e574" publication-type="other">
Hirsch, E., J. E. Koppich, and M. S. Knapp. 2001. Revisiting What States are Doing to Improve the
Quality of Teaching: An Update on Patterns and Trends. Seattle, WA: Center for the Study of
Teaching and Policy.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e587a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e591" publication-type="other">
Iatorola, P., and L. Stiefel. 2003. Intradistrict equity of public education resources and performance.
Economics of Education Review 22:69-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e601a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e605" publication-type="other">
Imazeki, J. 2010. Attracting and Retaining Teachers in High-Need Schools: Do Financial Incentives
Make Financial Sense? Working paper, January 2008 2008 [cited April 2 2010]. Available from
http://www-rohan.sdsu.edu/dept/econ/WPSeries/08_01.pdf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e618a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e622" publication-type="other">
Ingersoll, R. M. 2001. Teacher turnover and teacher shortages: An organizational analysis.
American Educational Research Journal 38 (3):499-534.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e633a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e637" publication-type="other">
Ingersoll, R. M., and L. Merrill. 2010. Who's Teaching Our Children? Educational Leadership 67
(8): 14—21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e647a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e651" publication-type="other">
Jacob, B. A. 2007. The challenges of staffing urban schools with effective teachers. The Future of
Children 17 (1):129-153.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e661a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e665" publication-type="other">
Jimerson, L. 2003. The Competitive Disadvantage: Teacher Compensation in Rural America.
Washington, DC: Rural School and Community Trust.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e675a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e679" publication-type="other">
Johnson, R. C. 2006. Teacher bonuses get high priority. Education Week 20 (18):18.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e686a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e690" publication-type="other">
Johnson, S. M. 1986. Incentives for Teachers: What Motivates, What Matters. Educational
Administration Quarterly 22 (3):54—79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e700a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e704" publication-type="other">
Johnson, S. M., and J. P. Papay. 2009. Redesigning Teacher Pay: A System for the Next Generation of
Educators. Edited by S. P. Corcoran and J. Roy, EPI Series on Alernative Teacher Compensation
Systems. Washington, DC: Economic Policy Institute.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e718a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e722" publication-type="other">
Kolbe, T., and K. O. Strunk. 2010. Economic Incentives as a strategy for responding to teacher
staffing problems: An organizational typology. Presented at the Annual Conference of the
American Education Finance Association. Richmond, VA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e735a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e739" publication-type="other">
Koski, W. S., and E. L. Horng. 2007. Facilitating the teacher quality gap? Collective bargaining
agreements, teacher hiring and transfer rules, and teacher assignment among schools in
California. Education Finance and Policy 2 (3):262-300.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e752a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e756" publication-type="other">
Lankford, H., S. Loeb, and J. Wyckoff. 2002. Teacher Sorting and the Plight of Urban Schools: A
Descriptive Analysis. Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis 24 (1 ):37—62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e766a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e770" publication-type="other">
Levin, J., and M. Quinn. 2003. Missed Opportunities: How We Keep High-Quality Teachers out of
Urban Classrooms. New York, NY: The New Teacher Project.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e780a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e784" publication-type="other">
Loeb, S., and L. C. Miller. 2006. A review of state teacher policies: what are they, what are their
effects, and what are their implications for school finance? Palo Alto: Institute for Research on
Education Policy &amp; Practice (IREPP), Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e797a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e801" publication-type="other">
Loeb, S., L. C. Miller, and K. O. Strunk. 2009. The State Role in Teacher Professional Development
and Education throughout Teachers' careers. Education Finance and Policy 4 (2):212-228.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e812a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e816" publication-type="other">
Manski, C. F. 1987. Academic Ability, Earnings, and the Decision to Become a Teacher: Evidence
from the National Longitudinal Study of the High School Class of 1972. In Public Sector
Payrolls, edited by D. A. Wise. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e829a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e833" publication-type="other">
McLeskey, J., N. C. Tyler, and S. S. Flippin. 2004. The Supply of and Demand for Special Education
Teachers: A Review of Research Regarding the Chronic Shortage of Special Education
Teachers. Journal of Special Education 38 (1):5—21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e846a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e850" publication-type="other">
Milanowski, A. T. 2002. An exploration of the pay levels needed to attract mathematics, science and
technology majors to a career in K-12 teaching. In American Education Finance Association.
Albuquerque, NM.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e863a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e867" publication-type="other">
Milanowski, A. T., H. Longwell-Grice, F. Saffold, J. Jones, K. Schomisch, and A. Odden. 2009.
Recruiting New Teachers to Urban School Districts: What Incentives Will Work? International
Journal of Education Policy &amp; Leadership 4 (8):1—13.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e880a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e884" publication-type="other">
Murnane, R. J., and R. J. Olsen. 1989. The Effect of Salaries and Opportunity Costs on Duration
in Teaching: Evidence from Michigan. The Review of Economics and Statistics 71 (2):347-352.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e894a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e898" publication-type="other">
———. 1990. The Effects of Salaries and Opportunity Costs on Length of Stay in Teaching:
Evidence from North Carolina. The Journal of Human Resources 25 (1): 106-124.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e909a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e913" publication-type="other">
Murphy, P. J., and M. M. DeArmond. 2003. From the Headlines to the Frontlines: The Teacher
Shortage and Its Implications for Recruitment Policy. Seattle, WA: Center on Reinventing Public
Education, University of Washington.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e926a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e930" publication-type="other">
National Education Association. 2003. Meeting the challenges of recruitment and retention:
A guidebook on promoting strategies to recruit and retain qualified and diverse teachers.
Washington, DC: Author.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e943a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e947" publication-type="other">
Office of the Governor of Rhode Island. 2006 State of the State Address 2006. Available from http://
www.ri.gov/GOVERNOR/view.php?rss=1&amp;id=1306.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e957a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e961" publication-type="other">
Oklahoma State Regents for Higher Education. Teacher Shortage Employment Incentive Program
2010. Available from http://www.okhighered.org/tseip/.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e971a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e975" publication-type="other">
Peske, H. G., and K. Haycock. 2006. Teaching Inequality: How Poor and Minority Students Are
Shortchanged on Teacher Quality: A Report and Recommendations by the Education Trust.
Washington, DC: Education Trust.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e988a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e992" publication-type="other">
Player, D. 2010. Nonmonetary Compensation in the Public Teacher Labor Market. Education
Finance and Policy 5 (1):82-103.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1003a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1007" publication-type="other">
Podgursky, M. 2006. Is There A "Qualified Teacher" Shortage? Education Next 6 (2).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1014a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1018" publication-type="other">
Podgursky, M„ R. Monroe, and D. Watson. 2004. The academic quality of public school teachers:
an analysis of entry and exit behavior. Economics of Education Review 23 (5):507-518.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1028a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1032" publication-type="other">
Podgursky, M., and M. G. Springer. 2006. Teacher Performance Pay: A Review. National Center on
Performance Incentives.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1042a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1046" publication-type="other">
Prince, C. D. 2003. Higher pay in hard-to-staff schools: The case for financial incentives. Lanham,
MD: Rowman &amp; Littlefield Education.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1056a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1060" publication-type="other">
Reed, D„ K. S. Rueben, and E. Barbour. 2006. Retention of new teachers in California. San Francisco,
CA: Public Policy Institute of California.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1070a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1074" publication-type="other">
Rickman, B. D., and C. D. Parker. 1990. Alternative wages and teacher mobility: A human capital
approach. Economics of Education Review 9 (l):73-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1085a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1089" publication-type="other">
Rivkin, S. G., E. A. Hanushek, and J. F. Kain. 2005. Teachers, schools, and academic achievement.
Econometrica 73 (2):417-458.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1099a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1103" publication-type="other">
Robertson, G. D. 2010. NC Senate Dems say Budget Lacks Teacher Pay Raise. The Boston Globe,
May 12.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1113a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1117" publication-type="other">
RockofF, J. E. 2004. The impact of individual teachers on student achievement: Evidence from
panel data. American Economic Review 94 (2):247-252.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1127a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1131" publication-type="other">
Sawchuck, S. 2009. Duncan Presses NEA on Merit Pay, Tenure. Education Week 28 (36).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1138a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1142" publication-type="other">
———. 2009. School Leaders Target Salary Reform toward newer teachers. Education Week.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1149a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1153" publication-type="other">
Scafidi, B., D. L. Sjoquist, and T. R. Stinebrickner. 2007. Race, poverty, and teacher mobility.
Economics of Education Review 26 (2): 145-159.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1164a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1168" publication-type="other">
Springer, M. G., and M. A. Winters. 2009. The NYC teacher pay-for-performance program: Early
evidence from a randomized trial. New York, NY: Center for Civic Innovation, The Manhattan
Institute.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1181a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1185" publication-type="other">
Steele,). L., R. J. Murnane, and J. B. Willett. 2010. Do Financial Incentives Help Low-Performing
Schools Attract and Keep Academically Talented Teachers? Evidence from California. Journal
of Policy Analysis and Management 29 (3):451—478.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1198a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1202" publication-type="other">
Taylor, L. L., and M. C. Glander. 2006. Documentation for the NCES Comparable Wage Index
Files. Washington, DC: National Center for Education Statistics, US Department of Education.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1212a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1216" publication-type="other">
United Teachers of Los Angeles. 2006-2009: UTLA/LAUSD Contract 2009. Available from http://
www.utla.net/node/2451.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1226a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1230" publication-type="other">
Weaver, R. Written Statement of Reg Weaver, Submitted to Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions
Committee, U.S. Senate, and Committee on Education and Labor, U.S. House of Representatives
2007. Available from http://www.nea.org/home/29624.htm.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d35e1243a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d35e1247" publication-type="other">
Woodworth, K., J. Bland, R. Guha, P. Shields, M. Wechsler, J. Tiffany-Morales, and V. Tse. 2009.
The status of the teaching profession 2009: Full Report. Santa Cruz, CA: The Center for the
Future of Teaching and Learning.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


