<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">35</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i24440319</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24440328</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Corporate Tax in Developing Countries: Current Trends and Design Issues</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Laura</given-names>
                  <surname>Abramovsky</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alexander</given-names>
                  <surname>Klemm</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
                  <surname>Phillips</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>559</fpage>
         <lpage>588</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2014 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440328"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper looks at corporate income taxes in developing countries from both an empirical and a theoretical perspective. Many economic principles about corporate income taxes apply equally in advanced and developing economies, but some characteristics of developing economies lead to different trade-offs. These include fewer locational rents and generally lower administrative capacity. Empirically, corporate income tax developments broadly resemble those in advanced economies, but there are important differences too, such as a greater reliance on tax incentives, reflected in a gradual narrowing – rather than broadening – of tax bases in combination with tax cuts. Detailed analysis using effective tax rates reveals various distortions including a preference for certain assets, and strong tax advantages of debt finance over equity finance, particularly in high-inflation environments. An empirical analysis of correlations between country-specific features and the likelihood of using tax incentives shows that countries offering low tax rates also tend to offer tax incentives, but that they cut their standard rates by substantially less than other countries between 1996 and 2007.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1678082e229a1310">
            <label>*</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e236" publication-type="other">
Submitted April 2014.
The views expressed in this paper are those of the authors and do not necessarily represent those of the
International Monetary Fund or the Institute for Fiscal Studies, which has no corporate views. The authors
would like to thank Ali Abbas, Stuart Adam, Steven Clark and Helen Miller for helpful comments and
discussions. Laura Abramovsky and David Phillips gratefully acknowledge financial support provided by
the Economic and Social Research Council (ESRC) under the Centre for the Microeconomic Analysis of
Public Policy (CPP) at the Institute for Fiscal Studies (grant number RES-544-2S-0001).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e262a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e269" publication-type="other">
The share of global GDP in developing and transition countries was 39.6 per cent using market
exchange rates and 51.9 per cent on a purchasing-power-parity basis in 2012, up from 21.7 per cent and
36.6 per cent respectively in 1990. The share of exports originating in developing and transition countries
has also increased substantially, from 30.4 per cent in 1995 to 48.8 per cent in 2012 (UNCTAD, 2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e285a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e292" publication-type="other">
UNCTAD, 2013.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e299a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e306" publication-type="other">
The following discussion draws heavily on Abramovsky, Johnson and Phillips (2013), which itself
draws heavily on Mirrlees et al. (2011). The Mirrlees Review is a review of the UK tax system and tax
design issues for advanced economies.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e320a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e327" publication-type="other">
For recent treatments, see Devereux and Sorensen (2006) and Mirrlees et al. (2011), for example.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e334a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e341" publication-type="other">
The precise economic incidence of CITs is likely to differ by country, industry and, indeed, company
(Mintz, 1995). Standard tax incidence theory suggests that, in an open economy, most of the tax will be
borne by the less mobile factors of production, such as labour. Hence a CIT may ultimately be borne
largely not by the owners of large companies, but by the local workers. Empirical evidence (Felix and
Hines, 2009; Dwenger, Rattenhuber and Steiner, 2011; Arulampalam, Devereux and Maffini, 2012) finds
that around 50 per cent of the CIT is incident on workers' wages. However, recent studies such as
Gravelle (2013) and Clausing (2013) have highlighted that some of the general equilibrium effects might
actually mean that capital bears a part of the burden. No such studies have been conducted for developing
countries, but it seems likely that at least as much of the burden will be bome by workers, because
location-specific rents that may reduce the mobility of capital, such as agglomeration effects as for
finance in London or technology in Silicon Valley, are less likely in developing countries, except in the
special case of natural resources.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e383a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e390" publication-type="other">
Such retained earnings can also be thought of as unrealised capital gains at the personal level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e397a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e404" publication-type="other">
Mirrlees et al., 2011. An effective system of capital gains tax is also needed to avoid incentives for
converting income into capital gains.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e414a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e421" publication-type="other">
For example, Devereux, Lockwood and Redoano (2008) and International Monetary Fund (2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e428a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e435" publication-type="other">
See also Griffith and Miller (this issue).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e443a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e450" publication-type="other">
Although there has been a surge in strengthening reforms to tax administrations in developing
countries (see, for example, Corbacho, Frétés Cibils and Lora (2013) for cases in Latin America), tax
administrations are hard to change and are not usually a priority for government attention and the
expenditure of political capital, given other urgent needs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e466a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e473" publication-type="other">
See, for instance, Schneider, Buehn and Montenegro (2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e480a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e487" publication-type="other">
According to Keen (2012), the largest 1 per cent of companies account for around 75 per cent or
more of all tax payments in many developing countries. According to Devereux and Loretz (2011), in the
UK the top 1 per cent of all companies pay 81 per cent of UK corporation tax.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e500a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e507" publication-type="other">
Abramovsky, Johnson and Phillips, 2013.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e514a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e521" publication-type="other">
See, for instance, Bucovetsky (1991) and Haufler and Wooton (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e528a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e535" publication-type="other">
There has been a recent surge of special regimes in advanced economies, targeted to income derived
from investment in intangible assets - the so-called Intellectual Property or Patent Box regimes (see, for
instance, Evers, Miller and Spengel (2014)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e549a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e556" publication-type="other">
IMF Revenue Panel Database: revenue as a percentage of GDP for IMF member countries', updated
February 2014 and described in International Monetary Fund (2010 and 2011), and IMF Fiscal Affairs
Department, 'Corporate tax rate data', updated May 2013.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e569a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e576" publication-type="other">
Raw data are mostly from Ernst &amp; Young's and PricewaterhouseCoopers's corporate tax guides.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e583a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e590" publication-type="other">
For example, Fullerton (1984).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e597a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e604" publication-type="other">
Specifically, Klemm (2012) replaces the assumption of a one-period perturbation in the capital stock
by investment over an infinite horizon. Therefore, changes in tax rates such as from the expiration of a tax
holiday are reflected in the present discounted value of net profits, while in the Devereux and Griffith
(2003) set-up the investment would be undone before the expiration of a tax holiday.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e620a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e627" publication-type="other">
These depreciation rates were initially estimated in OECD (1991) and have become a common
assumption in analysis of EMTRs and EATRs. We obtained similar results when repeating the analysis
(of Figure 3) with the alternative assumption of 17.5 per cent (machinery and equipment) and 3.1 per cent
(industrial buildings), as used for example in Elschner and Vanborren (2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e643a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e650" publication-type="other">
See also Griffith and Miller (this issue).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e658a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e665" publication-type="other">
This result is less strong when using an expanded sample including all developing countries for
which headline tax rates are available.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e675a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e682" publication-type="other">
International Monetary Fund, 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e689a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e696" publication-type="other">
If the true rate of depreciation is systematically greater in lower-income countries, the differences
across income groups shown in Figure 2 may be exaggerated. This is because effective tax rates would be
higher with a smaller difference between depreciation allowances and true economic depreciation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e709a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e716" publication-type="other">
The substantial fall in the EMTR from 2003 for lower-income countries is driven by six out of the 17
countries in this category: Egypt, Kenya, Nigeria, Pakistan, Ukraine and Zambia.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e726a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e733" publication-type="other">
There is a large fall in the EMTR in lower-income countries from 2003 for debt-financed investments
and for equity-financed investments (not so visible in Figure 4 due to the scale, but visible in Figure 2),
driven by six countries in this category: Egypt, Kenya, Nigeria, Pakistan, Ukraine and Zambia.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e746a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e753" publication-type="other">
See Devereux, Griffith and Klemm (2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e761a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e768" publication-type="other">
There is even more scope for negative effective tax rates when companies use tax-haven affiliates
(unless prevented by CFC rules) to obtain two deductions in respect of interest expense.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e778a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e785" publication-type="other">
We assume that the real interest rate is fixed, so higher inflation means higher nominal interest rates.
In countries with financial repression, the real interest rate could fall in a high-inflation environment,
which would counteract this effect.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e798a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e805" publication-type="other">
See, for instance, the CIA World Fact Book!https://www.cia.gov/librarv/publications/the-world-
factbook/rankorder/2092rank.html).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e815a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e822" publication-type="other">
There is no generally agreed naming convention, so some countries' tax laws may have investment
allowances that do reduce the stock of remaining depreciation. We treat these cases as additional
depreciation allowances, following the substance rather than the name.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e835a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e842" publication-type="other">
If we drop the switchers and consider a stable subsample of 22 countries (of the 41 countries) that
always have a special regime or never have one over the same period, we get a similar overall pattern to
that in Figure 8. However, effective rates under the standard regime for both types of countries (with and
without special regimes) are more similar. Furthermore, the gap between special and standard effective
tax rates for those countries that always have at least one special regime is even wider, particularly for
lower-income countries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e865a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e872" publication-type="other">
ur results hold with lagged rather than contemporaneous values.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e880a1310">
            <label>34</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e887" publication-type="other">
Fuest and Riedel, 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e894a1310">
            <label>35</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e901" publication-type="other">
See also Bird (2000) and Zee, Stotsky and Ley (2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e908a1310">
            <label>36</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e915" publication-type="other">
Klemm and Van Parys, 2012.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e922a1310">
            <label>37</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e929" publication-type="other">
Mirrlees et al. (2011) point out that such a tax can be mimicked by abolishing the existing CIT,
increasing existing VATs and reducing labour income taxes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e939a1310">
            <label>38</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e946" publication-type="other">
Matheson, Perry and Veung (2013) discuss the implications of the move to territoriality for
developing countries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e956a1310">
            <label>39</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e963" publication-type="other">
See, for instance, International Monetary Fund (2011 ) and Inter-American Development Bank
(2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e974a1310">
            <label>40</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e981" publication-type="other">
'Lock-in' effects arise because capital gains are taxed only if realised; there is therefore an incentive
to hold on to assets for longer than would otherwise be optimal to shield the accrued gain from tax for a
longer period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e994a1310">
            <label>41</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1001" publication-type="other">
See Klemm (2007) for an overview.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e1008a1310">
            <label>42</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1015" publication-type="other">
European Commission, 2013.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e1022a1310">
            <label>43</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1029" publication-type="other">
OECD, 2007.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1678082e1036a1310">
            <label>44</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1043" publication-type="other">
Ocampo and Stiglitz, 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1678082e1059a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1063" publication-type="other">
Abbas, S. M. A. and Klemm, A. (2013), 'A partial race to the bottom: corporate tax
developments in emerging and developing economies', International Tax and Public
Finance, vol. 20, pp. 596-617.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1076a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1080" publication-type="other">
Abramovsky, L., Johnson, P. and Phillips, D. (2013), Tax Design in Turkey and Other Middle
Income Economies: Lessons from the Mirrlees Review, Research Report, Istanbul:
Economic Research Forum.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1093a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1097" publication-type="other">
Arulampalam, W., Devereux, M. and Maffini, G. (2012), 'The direct incidence of corporate
income tax on wages', European Economic Review, vol. 56, pp. 1038-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1107a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1111" publication-type="other">
Best, M., Brockmeyer, A., Kleven, H., Spinnewijn, J. and Waseem, M. (2013), 'Production vs
revenue efficiency with limited tax capacity: theory and evidence from Pakistan', Journal
of Political Economy, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1125a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1129" publication-type="other">
Bird, R. M. (2000), 'Tax incentives for investment in developing countries', in G. Perry, J.
Whalley and G. McMahon (eds), Fiscal Reform and Structural Change in Developing
Countries, London: McMillan.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1142a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1146" publication-type="other">
Bucovetsky, S (1991), 'Asymmetric tax competition', Journal of Urban Economics, vol. 30,
pp. 167-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1156a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1160" publication-type="other">
Clausing, K. A. (2013), 'Who pays the corporate tax in a global economy?', National Tax
Journal, vol. 66, no. 6, pp. 151-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1170a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1174" publication-type="other">
Corbacho, A., Frétés Cibils, V. and Lora, E. (eds) (2013), More than Revenue: Taxation as a
Development Tool, Washington DC: Inter-American Development Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1184a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1188" publication-type="other">
Devereux, M. P. and Griffith, R. (2003), 'Evaluating tax policy for location decisions',
International Tax and Public Finance, vol. 10, pp. 107-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1198a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1202" publication-type="other">
—, — and Klemm, A. (2002), 'Corporate income tax reforms and international tax
competition', Economic Policy, vol. 17, pp. 449-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1213a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1217" publication-type="other">
—, Lockwood, B. and Redoano, M. (2008), 'Do countries compete over corporate tax rates?',
Journal of Public Economics, vol. 92, pp. 1210-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1227a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1231" publication-type="other">
— and Loretz, S. (2011), Corporation Tax in the United Kingdom, Oxford: Oxford University
Centre for Business Taxation.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1241a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1245" publication-type="other">
— and Sorensen, P. B. (2006), 'The corporate income tax: international trends and options for
fundamental reform', European Commission, Economic Paper no. 264.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1255a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1259" publication-type="other">
Diamond, P. A. and Mirrlees, J. A. (1971), 'Optimal taxation and public production I:
production efficiency', American Economic Review, vol. 61, pp. 8-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1269a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1273" publication-type="other">
Dwenger, N., Rattenhuber, P. and Steiner, V. (2011), 'Sharing the burden: empirical evidence
of corporate tax incidence', Max Planck Institute for Tax Law and Public Finance,
Working Paper no. 2011-14.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1286a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1290" publication-type="other">
Elschner, C. and Vanborren, W. (2009), 'Corporate effective tax rates in an enlarged
European Union', European Commission, Taxation Paper no. 14.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1301a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1305" publication-type="other">
European Commission (2013), Tax Reforms in EU Member States 2013: Tax Policy
Challenges for Economic Growth and Fiscal Sustainability, European Economy no. 5.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1319" publication-type="other">
Evers, L., Miller, H. and Spengel, C. (2014), 'Intellectual property box regimes: effective tax
rates and tax policy considerations', International Tax and Public Finance, DOI
10.1007/sl 0797-014-9328-x.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1332a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1336" publication-type="other">
Felix, A. and Hines, J. R., Jr (2009), 'Corporate taxes and union wages in the United States',
National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER), Working Paper no. 15263.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1346a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1350" publication-type="other">
Fuest, C. and Riedel, N. (2010), 'Tax evasion and tax avoidance in developing countries: the
role of international profit shifting', Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation,
Working Paper no. 1012.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1363a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1367" publication-type="other">
Fullerton, D. (1984), 'Comparisons of effective tax rates', in M. King and D. Fullerton (eds),
The Taxation of Income from Capital: A Comparative Study of the United States, the
United Kingdom, Sweden and West Germany, Chicago, IL: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1380a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1384" publication-type="other">
Gravelle, J. (2013), 'Corporate tax incidence: review of general equilibrium estimates and
analysis', National Tax Journal, vol. 66, no. 1, pp. 185-214.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1395a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1399" publication-type="other">
Griffith, R. and Miller, H. (2014), 'Taxable corporate profits', Fiscal Studies, vol. 35, pp.
535-57 (this issue).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1409a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1413" publication-type="other">
Gugl, E. and Zodrow, G. (2006), 'International tax competition and tax incentives in
developing countries', in J. Alm, J. Martinez-Vazquez and M. Rider (eds), The Challenge
of Tax Reform in a Global Economy, Berlin: Springer.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1426a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1430" publication-type="other">
Haufler, A. and Wooton, I. (1999), 'Country size and tax competition for foreign direct
investment', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 71, pp. 121-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1440a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1444" publication-type="other">
International Monetary Fund (2010), 'From stimulus to consolidation: revenue and
expenditure policies in advanced and emerging economies', April.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1454a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1458" publication-type="other">
— (2011), 'Revenue mobilization in developing countries', IMF Policy Paper, March.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1465a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1469" publication-type="other">
— (2014), 'Spillovers in international corporate taxation', IMF Policy Paper, May.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1477a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1481" publication-type="other">
Janeba, E. and Smart, M. (2003), 'Is targeted tax competition less harmful than its remedies?',
International Tax and Public Finance, vol. 10, pp. 259-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1491a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1495" publication-type="other">
Keen, M. (2002), 'Preferential regimes can make tax competition less harmful', National Tax
Journal, vol. 54, pp. 757-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1505a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1509" publication-type="other">
— (2012), 'Taxation and development - again', International Monetary Fund, Working Paper
no. WP/12/220.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1519a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1523" publication-type="other">
— and Simone, A. (2004), 'Is tax competition harming developing countries more than
advanced?', Tax Notes International, Special Issue 28, pp. 1317-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1533a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1537" publication-type="other">
Klemm, A. (2007), 'Allowances for corporate equity in practice', CESifo Economic Studies,
vol. 53, pp. 229-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1547a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1551" publication-type="other">
— (2010), 'Causes, benefits, and risks of business tax incentives', International Tax and
Public Finance, vol. 17, pp. 315-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1562a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1566" publication-type="other">
— (2012), 'Effective average tax rates for permanent investment', Journal of Economic and
Social Measurement, vol. 37, pp. 253-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1576a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1580" publication-type="other">
— and Van Parys, S. (2012), 'Empirical evidence on the effects of tax incentives',
International Tax and Public Finance, vol. 19, pp. 393-423.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1590a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1594" publication-type="other">
Loretz, S. (2008), 'Corporate taxation in the OECD in a wider context', Oxford Review of
Economic Policy, vol. 24, pp. 639-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1604a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1608" publication-type="other">
Matheson, T., Perry, V. and Veung, C. (2013), 'Territorial vs. worldwide corporate taxation:
implications for developing countries', International Monetary Fund, Working Paper no.
13/205.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1621a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1625" publication-type="other">
Mintz, J. (1995), 'The corporation tax: a survey', Fiscal Studies, vol. 16, no. 4, pp. 23-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1632a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1636" publication-type="other">
Mirrlees, J., Adam, S., Besley, T., Blundell, R., Bond, S., Chote, R., Gammie, M., Johnson,
P., Myles, G. and Poterba, J. (2011), Tax by Design: The Mirrlees Review, Oxford:
Oxford University Press for Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1650a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1654" publication-type="other">
Ocampo, J. A. and Stiglitz, J. E. (2008), Capital Market Liberalization and Development,
Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1664a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1668" publication-type="other">
OECD (1991), Taxing Profits in a Global Economy, Paris: Organisation for Economic
Cooperation and Development.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1678a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1682" publication-type="other">
— (2007), 'Fundamental reform of corporate income taxation", OECD Tax Policy Study no.
16.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1692a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1696" publication-type="other">
Schneider, F., Buehn, A. and Montenegro, C. E. (2010), 'New estimates for the shadow
economies all over the world', International Economic Journal, vol. 24, pp. 443-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1706a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1710" publication-type="other">
UNCTAD (2013), World Investment Report 2013 - Global Value Chains: Investment and
Trade for Development, New York and Geneva: United Nations Conference on Trade and
Development.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1678082e1723a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1678082e1727" publication-type="other">
Zee, H. H., Stotsky, J. G. and Ley, E. (2002), 'Tax incentives for business investment: a
primer for policy makers in developing countries', World Development, vol. 30, pp.
1497-516.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


