<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169245</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Finite-Element-Based Transfer Equations</article-title>
            <subtitle>Post-Mortem Human Subjects versus Hybrid III Test Dummy in Blunt Impact</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>El-jawahri</surname>
                  <given-names>Raed E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Laituri</surname>
                  <given-names>Tony R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kim</surname>
                  <given-names>Agnes S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rouhana</surname>
                  <given-names>Stephen W.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Weerappuli</surname>
                  <given-names>Para V.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Ford Motor Co.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>April 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169238</issue-id>
         <fpage>117</fpage>
         <lpage>129</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169245"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In the present study, transfer equations relating the responses of post-mortem human subjects (PMHS) to the mid-sized male Hybrid III test dummy (HIII50) under matched, or nearly-identical, loading conditions were developed via math modeling. Specifically, validated finite element (FE) models of the Ford Human Body Model (FHBM) and the HIII50 were used to generate sets of matched cases (i.e., 256 frontal impact cases involving different impact speeds, severities, and PMHS age). Regression analyses were subsequently performed on the resulting age-dependent FHBM- and HIII50-based responses. This approach was conducted for five different body regions: head, neck, chest, femur, and tibia. All of the resulting regression equations, correlation coefficients, and response ratios (PHMS relative to HIII50) were consistent with the limited available test-based results.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Donnelly, B. and Roberts, D., “Comparison of Cadaver and Hybrid III Dummy Response to Axial Impacts of the Femur,” SAE Technical Paper 872204, 1987, doi:10.4271/872204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">El-Jawahri, R., Ruan, J., Rouhana, S., Barbat, S., and Prasad, P. (2008) “Further validation of the Ford Human Body FE model and use of the model to investigate the effects of shoulder belt force limiting of 3-point and 4-point restrains in frontal impact.” ASME International Mechanical Engineering Congress and Exposition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">El-Jawahri, R., Ruan, J., Rouhana, S., and Barbat, S. (2009) “Chest deflection vs. chest acceleration as injury indicator in front impact simulations using full human body FE model.” ASME International Mechanical Engineering Congress and Exposition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">El-Jawahri, R., Ruan, J., Rouhana, S., and Barbat, S. (2010a) “Development and validation of a 50th percentile male pedestrian FE model. ASME International Mechanical Engineering Congress and Exposition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">El-Jawahri, R., Laituri, T., Ruan, J., Rouhana, S., and Barbat, S. (2010b) Development and validation of age-dependent FE human models of a mid-sized male thorax.” Stapp Car Crash Journal 54: 407-430.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">El-Jawahri, R., Laituri, T., and Ruan, J., (2011) “Further validation of the head in the Ford human body FE model.” ASME International Mechanical Engineering Congress and Exposition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">El-jawahri, R., Laituri, T., and Kim, A., “Further Validation of Age- Dependent FE Models of a Mid-Sized Male Thorax,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 5(1):552-566, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0582.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Forman, J., Lessley, D., Shaw, C., Evans, J., Kent, R., Rouhana, S., and Prasad, P., (2006) “Thoracic Response of Belted PHMS, the Hybrid III, and THOR-NT Mid-Sized Male Surrogates in Low Speed, Frontal Crashes” Stapp Car Crash Journal 50: 191-215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuppa, S., Wang, J., Haffner, M., Eppinger, R., (2001) “Lower Extremity Injuries and Associated Injury Criteria”, 17th International Technical Conference of Enhanced Safety Vehicles, Paper number 457.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laituri, T., Prasad, P., Kachnowski, B., Sullivan, K. et al., “Predictions of AIS3+ Thoracic Risks for Belted Occupants in Full-Engagement, Real-World Frontal Impacts: Sensitivity to Various Theoretical Risk Curves,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1355, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laituri, T., Prasad, P., Sullivan, K., Frankstein, M. et al., “Derivation and Evaluation of a Provisional, Age-Dependent, AIS3+ Thoracic Risk Curve for Belted Adults in Frontal Impacts,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0297, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0297.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laituri, T., Henry, S., Kachnowski, B., and Sullivan, K., “Initial Assessment of the Next-Generation USA Frontal NCAP: Fidelity of Various Risk Curves for Estimating Field Injury Rates of Belted Drivers,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0386, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0386.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laituri, T. and El-jawahri, R., “Fracture Modeling Inputs for a Human Body Model via Inference from a Risk Curve: Application for Skull Fracture Potential,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 5(1):468-486, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0562.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Masson, C., Vinel, H., Cavallero, C., and Brunet, C., (2002) “Response of the Human Pelvis-Femur-Knee Complex During Low Speed Frontal Impact” IRCOBI Conference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mertz, H.J., Irwin, A.L., Prasad, P., (2003) “Biomechanical and Scaling Bases for Frontal and Side Impact Injury Assessment Reference Values.” Stapp Car Crash Journal, 47: 155-188.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neathery, R., “Analysis of Chest Impact Response Data and Scaled Performance Recommendations,” SAE Technical Paper 741188, 1974, doi:10.4271/741188.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rouhana, S., El-Jawahri, R., and Laituri, T., (2010) “Biomechanical consideration for abdominal loading by seat belt pretensioners” Stapp Car Crash Journal 54:381-406.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruan, J., Khalil, T., and King, A., “Finite Element Modeling of Direct Head Impact,” SAE Technical Paper 933114, 1993, doi:10.4271/933114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruan, J. and Prasad, P., “Head Injury Potential Assessment in Frontal Impacts by Mathematical Modeling,” SAE Technical Paper 942212, 1994, doi:10.4271/942212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruan, J., El-Jawahri, R., Chai, L., Barbat, S., and Prasad, P. (2003a) “Prediction and analysis of human thoracic impact responses and injuries in cadaver impact using a full human body model.” Stapp Car Crash Journal 47: 299-322.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruan, J., El-Jawahri, R., Chai, L., Barbat, S., and Prasad, P. (2003b) “Development and validation of a finite element human thoraxabdomen model for side impact.” NAFEMS Congress.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruan, J., El-Jawahri, R., Barbat, S., and Prasad, P. (2005a) “Pelvic impact response and injury simulation using a full human body FE model.” NAFEMS Congress.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruan, J., El-Jawahri, R., Barbat, S., and Prasad, P. (2005b) “Biomechanical analysis of human abdominal impact responses and injuries through FE simulations of a full human body FE model.” Stapp Car Crash Journal 49: 343-366.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruan, J., El-Jawahri, R., Barbat, S., and Prasad, P. (2006) “Analysis and evaluation of the biofidelity of the human body FE model in lateral impact simulations according to ISO-TR9790 procedures.” Stapp Car Crash Journal 50: 491-508.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruan, J., El-Jawahri, R., Barbat, S., Rouhana, S. et al., “Biomechanical Analysis of Knee Impact in Frontal Collisions through Finite Element Simulations with a Full Human Body Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1887, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1887.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruan, J., El-Jawahri, R., Barbat, S., Rouhana, S., and Prasad, P. (2008b) “Impact response and biomechanical analysis of the kneethigh- hip complex in frontal impacts with a full human body FE model.” Stapp Car Crash Journal 52: 505-526.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rupp, J., Miller, C., Reed, M., Madura, H., Klinich, K., and Schneider, L., (2008) “Characterization of Knee-Thigh-Hip Response in Frontal Impacts Using Biomechanical Testing and Computational Simulations” Stapp Car Crash Journal, 52:421-474.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vezin, P., Bruyere-Garnier, K., Bermond, F., and Verriest, J., (2002) “Comparison of Hybrid III, THOR-α, and PMHS Response in Frontal Sled Tests” Stapp Car Crash Journal, 46:1-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yaguchi, M., Ono, K., and Masuda, M., “Biofidelic Responses of the THOR-NT and Hybrid III Based on Component Tests,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0520, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0520.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yaguchi, M., Ono, K., Masuda, M., Watamori, T., Seshita, T., and Hibion, T., (2009), “Comparison of dynamic responses of the THOR-NT and Hybrid III in offset frontal crash test.” 16th International Technical Conference of Enhanced Safety Vehicles, Paper number 268.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
