<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169015</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Reducing Light Duty Vehicle Fuel Consumption and Greenhouse Gas Emissions</article-title>
            <subtitle>The Combined Potential of Hybrid Technology and Behavioral Adaptation</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Santini</surname>
                  <given-names>Danilo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Burnham</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrew</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Argonne National Laboratory</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>July 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169008</issue-id>
         <fpage>314</fpage>
         <lpage>324</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169015"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>When comparing the potential of advanced versus conventional powertrains, a traditional approach is to hold glider design constant and simulate “comparable performance” to a conventional vehicle (CV). However, manufacturers have developed hybrid electric vehicle (HEV), plug-in hybrid electric vehicle (PHEV), and all-electric vehicle (EV) powertrains in gliders designed to synergistically enhance fuel saving benefits of such powertrains by further reducing road load and engine output power (or continuous power for the EV) where no conventional powertrain option is provided. In the U.S. marketplace, there are now several examples of both hybrid and plug-in hybrid electric vehicles using gliders common to top selling CVs and a few using low load gliders to further reduce fuel consumption. We use fuel consumption estimates from FuelEconomy.gov for a number of plausible CV versus HEV, PHEV, and EV comparisons to estimate the potential additional annual fuel savings and greenhouse gas (GHG) emission benefits, using Argonne National Laboratory's GREET model, obtainable when consumers make the behavioral choice to purchase various electrified powertrains in low road load gliders. When electric generation comes from natural gas, PHEVs and EVs in low load gliders can provide about the same GHG benefits as low load HEVs, with less gasoline use. If renewables are used in conjunction with natural gas, the GHG benefits increase. In comparison to HEVs in standard gliders, there will be even greater benefits.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elgowainy, A., et al., “Impacts of Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicle Charging Choices in 2030,” Paper TRB12-3800, presented at 91st Annual Meeting of the Transportation Research Board, Forthcoming, Transportation Research Record, Washington, D.C., Jan. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, C., “The Innovator's Dilemma,” Harper Business Essentials, New York, ISBN: 0060521996, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, “Light-Duty Automotive Technology and Fuel Economy Trends: 1975 Through 2008,” EPA420- R-08-015, http://www.epa.gov/oms/cert/mpg/fetrends/fetrendsarchive. htm, Sept. 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaines, L., Burnham A., Rousseau, A., and Santini, D., “Sorting Through the Many Total-Energy-Cycle Pathways Possible with Early Plug-In Hybrids,” The World Electric Vehicle Journal, 2(1):74-96, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santini, D.J., et al., “Where Is the Early Market for PHEVs?,” The World Electric Vehicle Journal, 2(4):49-98, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, “Fuel Economy Labeling of Motor Vehicle Revisions to Improve Calculation of Fuel Economy Estimates, Final Technical Support Document, EPA420-R-06-017,” http://www.epa.gov/carlabel/regulations.htm, Dec. 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meyer, M., “Understanding the Challenges in HEV 5-Cycle Fuel Economy Calculations Based on Dynamometer Test Data,” M.S. thesis, Mechanical Engineering Department, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, VA, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, “Light-Duty Automotive Technology, Carbon Dioxide Emissions, and Fuel Economy Trends: 1975 Through 2011; Appendix A Database Details and Calculation Methods,” EPA420-R-12-001a,” http://www.epa.gov/otaq/fetrends.htm, March 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santos, A., et al., “Summary of Travel Trends,” U.S. Department of Transportation, Federal Highway Administration. Report FHWAPL- 11-022, Washington D.C., June 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graham, R., et al., “Comparing the Benefits and Impacts of Hybrid Electric Vehicle Options, Final Report, EPRI 1000349,” Electric Power Research Institute, Palo Alto, CA, July 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vyas, A., Santini, D., and Johnson, L., “Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles' Potential for Petroleum Use Reduction: Issues Involved in Developing Reliable Estimates,” Journal of the Transportation Research Board, 2139, 55-63, Washington, D.C., 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santini, D., et al., “Deploying Plug-in Electric Cars Which are Used for Work: Compatibility of Varying Daily Patterns of Use with Four Electric Powertrain Architectures,” Paper TRB13-4925, presented at 92nd Annual Meeting of the Transportation Research Board, Washington D.C., Jan. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santini, D., Zhou, Y., and Vyas, A., “An Analysis of Car and SUV Daytime Parking for Potential Opportunity Charging of Plug-in Electric Powertrains,” Electric Vehicle Symposium 26, Los Angeles, CA, May 6-9, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santini, D., ZHOU, Y., Stephens, T., Vyas, A. et al., “Cost Effective Annual Use and Charging Frequency for Four Different Plug-in Powertrains,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0494, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Argonne National Laboratory, The Greenhouse Gases, Regulated Emissions, and Energy Use in Transportation Model (GREET 1_2012 Revision 2), Computer Software http://greet.es.anl.gov/. Dec. 21, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhou, Y., Vyas, A., and Santini, D., “Tracking National Household Vehicle Usage by Type, Age, and Area in Support of Market Assessments for Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” Paper TRB12-4348, presented at 91st Annual Meeting of the Transportation Research Board, Washington, D.C., Jan. 22-26, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wiser, R. and Bollinger, M., “2011 Wind Technologies Market Report: Report Summary,” Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy Wind and Water Program, U.S. Department of Energy, Washington, D.C., Aug. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dai, A. and Deser, C., “Diurnal and semidiurnal variations in global surface wind and divergence fields,” Journal of Geophysical Research, No. D24, pp. 31,109 to 31,125, Dec. 27, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jiang, X., et al., “Mechanisms of the Great Plains Low Level Jet as Simulated in an AGCM,” Journal of the Atmospheric Sciences, 64:532-547, Feb. 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dallinger, D., Wietschel, M., and Santini, D., “Effect of Demand Response on the Marginal Electricity used by Plug-in Electric Vehicles,” Electric Vehicle Symposium 26, Los Angeles, CA, May 6-9, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Garas, D., “About PEV Consumers,” presented at the National Governors' Association State and Local Plug-in Electric Vehicle Workshop. http://www.nga.org/files/live/sites/NGA/files/pdf/1207EVGaras.pdf, Washington D.C., July 10, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santini, D., “Hybrid Electric Powertrain Fuel Consumption Reduction Cost Effectiveness Trade-Offs,” presented at the Clean Vehicles and Fuels 2004 Symposium. Stockholm, Sweden, June 2-5, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moawad, A. and Rousseau, A., “Impact of Vehicle Performance on Cost Effective Way to Meet CAFE 2017-2025,” presented at the 2011 IEEE Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference, Chicago, IL, Sept. 6-9, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eberhard, M., “Tesla Motors,” presented at the California Air Resources Board ZEV Symposium, Sacramento, CA, Sept. 26, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
