<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="other"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">3663841</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/344119</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB760109</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Notes</article-title>
            <subtitle>University Schools of Business</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>01</month>
            <year>2003</year>
            <string-date>January 2003</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>76</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2003.76.issue-1</issue-id>
         <fpage>195</fpage>
         <lpage>201</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/344119"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <title>Appointments</title>
         <p>Victor F. Araman, asst. prof., information, operations, and management sciences, NYU, July 2002.</p>
         <p>T. J. Atwood, visiting asst. prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Joseph Banas, visiting asst. prof., organizational behavior, Washington Univ., July 2002.</p>
         <p>Bobby Barnes, instructor, Mississippi State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Tim Barnett, assoc. prof., Mississippi State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Philip Berger, prof., accounting, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Jeremy Berkowitz, assoc. prof., finance, Houston, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Marianne Bertrand, assoc. prof., economics, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Gary Bliss, asst. prof., Florida State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Daniel Bryan, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Randall Campbell, asst. prof., Mississippi State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Rebecca Campbell, instructor, Mississippi State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>S. Chakrabarty, asst. prof., Mississippi State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Amitav Chakravarti, asst. prof., marketing, NYU, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>James Chrisman, prof., Mississippi State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Neil C. Churchill, visiting prof., UCLA, Oct. 2002.</p>
         <p>David K. Crockett, asst. prof., South Carolina, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Ely Dahan, asst. prof., UCLA, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Kim Davis, asst. prof., Mississippi State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Richard DeFrank, assoc. prof., management, director, MBA programs, Houston, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Kristen Diehl, asst. prof., South Carolina, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Jonathan Eckhardt, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Brian Engelland, assoc. prof., Mississippi State, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Anne Farrell, asst. prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, June 2002.</p>
         <p>Michael Faulkender, asst. prof., finance, Washington Univ., July 2002.</p>
         <p>Kerry Fields, assoc. prof., finance, USC, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Ayelet Fishbach, asst. prof., behavioral science, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Paul Friga, asst. prof., management, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Srinagesh Gavirneni, asst. prof., operations and decision technologies, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Andrew H. Gold, asst. prof., South Carolina, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Susan Meyer Goldstein, visiting asst. prof., operations and manufacturing management, Washington Univ., July 2002.</p>
         <p>Shingo Goto, asst. prof., South Carolina, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>O. Finley Graves, chairman, Univ. North Texas, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Stefano Grazioli, asst. prof., commerce, Virginia, June 2002.</p>
         <p>Faruk Guder, assoc. dean, academic program administration, Loyola (Chicago), Feb. 2002.</p>
         <p>Federico Guerrero, assoc. prof., Nevada—Reno, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Il‐Horn Hann, asst. prof., USC, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Rebecca Hann, asst. prof., accounting, USC, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Zeynep Kocabiyik Hansen, asst. prof., organization and strategy, Washington Univ., July 2002.</p>
         <p>Paul Herz, assoc. prof., accounting, Wyoming, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Arlene Hibschweiler, lecturer, SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Lori Holder‐Webb, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>David Huff, asst. prof., Univ. Utah, June 2002.</p>
         <p>Larry Hunter, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, June 2002.</p>
         <p>David L. Ikenberry, prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, June 2002.</p>
         <p>Scott B. Jackson, asst. prof., South Carolina, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Jayanth Jayaram, asst. prof., South Carolina, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Nicole Jenkins, asst. prof., accounting, Washington Univ., July 2002.</p>
         <p>Christopher Jones, asst. prof., finance, USC, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Manish Kacker, asst. prof., Tulane, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Ohad Kadan, asst. prof., finance, Washington Univ., July 2002.</p>
         <p>Kathryn Kadous, assoc. prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, June 2002.</p>
         <p>Mark Kennedy, asst. prof., management and organization, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Kenneth A. Kim, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Wai Ch. Lam, instructor, Mississippi State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Augustin Landier, asst. prof., finance, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Charles A. Lankau III, temporary asst. prof., Univ. Georgia, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Robert C. Liden, prof., Univ. Georgia, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Chris Long, asst. prof., organizational behavior, Washington Univ., July 2002.</p>
         <p>Andrew Lynch, clinical prof., management, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Adam Maiga, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Milwaukee, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Michal Matejka, asst. prof., accounting, USC, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Fabio Mendez, asst. prof., Arkansas, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Lior Menzly, asst. prof., finance, USC, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Patricia Hughes Mills, assoc. prof., accounting, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Joseph Milner, asst. prof., operations and manufacturing management, Washington Univ., June 2002.</p>
         <p>Andrea Morales, asst. prof., marketing, USC, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Jaihyun Nahm, lecturer, finance, USC, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Ralitza Nikoleava, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Milwaukee, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Oguzhan Ozbas, asst. prof., finance, USC, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Parunchana Pacharn, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Karen Page, asst. prof., management, Wyoming, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Marisa Anne Pagnattaro, asst. prof., Univ. Georgia, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Robert L. Parkinson, Jr., dean, Loyola (Chicago), Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Ginger Pennington, asst. prof., marketing, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Peter Perreault, lecturer, marketing, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Mark Pingle, prof. and department chair, Nevada—Reno, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Jamie Prenkert, asst. prof., business law, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Sekar Raju, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Suresh Ramanathan, asst. prof., marketing, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Imran Rasul, instructor, economics, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Janek Ratnatunga, visiting assoc. prof., accounting, Richmond, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Luis Rayo, asst. prof., economics, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Terry Reeves, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Milwaukee, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>John Rezek, asst. prof., Mississippi State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Aric Rindfleisch, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Andrew Roper, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Robert Sanborn, visiting assoc. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>D. Paul Scarbrough, visiting assoc. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Susan Schroeder, instructor, Arkansas, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Raj Sharman, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Leiser Silva, asst. prof., decision and information sciences, Houston, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Manohar Singh, asst. prof., Nevada—Reno, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Catarina Sisnero, asst. prof., marketing, USC, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>John Reed Smith, assoc. prof. (tenured), accounting, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Robert Solomon, asst. prof., management and organization, USC, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Ramana Sonti, visiting asst. prof., Tulane, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Raja Sooriamurthi, clinical asst. prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Greys Sosic, asst. prof., USC, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Charles R. Sox, prof., and chair, manufacturing management, Alabama, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Ann Terlaak, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, Jan. 2003.</p>
         <p>Kathleen Thomas, asst. prof., Mississippi State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Steven Todd, visiting asst. prof., finance, Washington Univ., July 2002.</p>
         <p>Scott D. Vandervelde, asst. prof., South Carolina, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Markus Vodosek, asst. prof., Univ. Utah, June 2002.</p>
         <p>Mary Waller, assoc. prof., Tulane, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Matthew Waller, assoc. prof., Arkansas, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Geoff Waring, visiting assoc. prof., UCLA, Oct. 2002.</p>
         <p>John Waters, visiting asst. prof., accounting, Wyoming, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Sandra J. Wayne, prof., Univ. Georgia, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Timothy West, assoc. prof., Arkansas, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Mike Whitmore, instructor, Arkansas, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>William J. Wilhelm, prof., commerce, Virginia, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Pradeep K. Yadov, visiting prof., UCLA, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Sha Yang, asst. prof., marketing, NYU, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Xiaohang Yue, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Milwaukee, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Tzachi Zach, asst. prof., accounting, Washington Univ., Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Donghang Zhang, asst. prof., South Carolina, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Shelly Zhao, asst. prof., Kent State, July 2002.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <title>Grants</title>
         <p>Joseph Cheng, prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign; Oct. 2002; $355,000; U.S. Department of Education; for international business education and research.</p>
         <p>Cassandra Cole, asst. prof., Florida State; July 2002–June 2003; $4,000; Florida State University Committee for Black Faculty and Student Support; to examine the effect of insider ownership on pension funding levels.</p>
         <p>Dean H. Gatzlaff, prof., Florida State; Apr. 2002; $9,600; Real Estate Institute; to conduct a study of determinants of investment property transactions.</p>
         <p>Dean H. Gatzlaff, prof., real estate, Florida State; Feb. 2002; $10,000; Lincoln Institute for Land Policy, Washington, D.C.; to examine the effect of Florida's “Save Our Home” constitutional amendment on property tax incidence.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <title>Leaves</title>
         <p>Pradeep K. Chintagunta, Robert Law Professor of Marketing, Chicago; Sept. 2002–Dec. 2002.</p>
         <p>Werner DeBondt, prof., Wisconsin—Madison; Sept. 2002–June 2003; visiting at DePaul University.</p>
         <p>Philip H. Dybvig, Boatmen's Bancshares Professor of Finance, Washington Univ.; July 2002–June 2003.</p>
         <p>Sebastian Edwards, prof., UCLA; Apr. 2003–June 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Ellen Engel, assoc. prof., accounting, Chicago; Sept. 2002–June 2003.</p>
         <p>Richard Green, assoc. prof., Wisconsin—Madison; Sept. 2002–Aug. 2003; to serve as principal economist at Freddie Mac.</p>
         <p>Robert S. Hamada, Edward Eagle Brown Distinguished Service Professor of Finance, Chicago; July 2002–July 2003.</p>
         <p>Sanford M. Jacoby, prof., UCLA; Oct. 2002–Dec. 2002; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Patricia Kennedy, assoc. prof., Nebraska—Lincoln; Aug. 2002–Dec. 2002; faculty development leave.</p>
         <p>Randall Kroszner, prof., economics, Chicago; Sept. 2002–Mar. 2003.</p>
         <p>Winston Lin, prof., SUNY at Buffalo; Sept. 2002–Mar. 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Joseph Ogden, assoc. prof., SUNY at Buffalo; Sept. 2002–Mar. 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>V. Padmanabhan, Wallace Distinguished Professor of Marketing, Washington Univ., July 2002–June 2003.</p>
         <p>Amil Petrin, assoc. prof., economics and statistics, Chicago; Sept. 2002–June 2003.</p>
         <p>Phil Podsakoff, John F. Mae Chair of Management, Indiana; Spring 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Lawrence Southwick, assoc. prof., SUNY at Buffalo; Aug. 2002–Jan. 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>James Wade, assoc. prof., Wisconsin—Madison; Aug. 2002–May 2003; visiting at New York University.</p>
         <p>Michael B. Williams, asst. prof., UCLA; July 2002–June 2003; special leave.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <title>Promotions</title>
         <p>Sam Allgood, asst. prof. (tenured), Nebraska—Lincoln, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Alex Ampadu, visiting assoc. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>David Antonioni, prof., Wisconsin—Madison, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Neeraj Arora, assoc. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Yossi Aviv, assoc. prof., operations and manufacturing management, Washington Univ. July 2002.</p>
         <p>Raymond Ball, Sidney Davidson Professor of Accounting, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Karen Banks, lecturer, operations and decision technologies, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Rahul Bhargava, assoc. prof., Nevada—Reno, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Bruce K. Billings, assoc. prof., Florida State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Martin Birr, senior lecturer, accounting and information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Diana Burley‐Gant, asst. prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Mason Carpenter, assoc. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Rita H. Cheng, prof., Wisconsin—Milwaukee, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Dilip Chhajed, prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>C. Steven Cole, prof., Univ. North Texas, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Rex Cutshall, lecturer, operations and decision technologies, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Kim Donahue, senior lecturer, marketing, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Cheryl L. Dunn, assoc. prof., Florida State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Kevin L. Eastman, prof., Florida State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Kathleen Farrell, assoc. prof., Nebraska—Lincoln, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Gary Flieschman, assoc. prof., accounting, Wyoming, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Scott M. Fuess, Jr., assoc. prof., Nebraska—Lincoln, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Luis Garicano, assoc. prof., economics and strategy, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Dean H. Gatzlaff, prof., real estate, Florida State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Marta Geletkanycz, assoc. prof., Boston College, Mar. 2002.</p>
         <p>Samuel Graves, prof., Boston College, Mar. 2002.</p>
         <p>Rachel Hayes, assoc. prof., accounting, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Patrick Hopkins, assoc. prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Thomas Hubbard, assoc. prof., economics and strategy, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Mark Ippolito, senior lecturer, operations and decision technologies, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>J. Howard Keller, senior lecturer, accounting, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Amy Kinser, lecturer, operations and decision technologies, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Jane Lambert, senior lecturer, accounting, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Thomas Lyon, prof., business economics and public policy, Indiana, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Barbara Madar, lecturer, marketing, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Steve Malpezzi, prof., Wisconsin—Madison, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Mostafa Mashayekhi, assoc. prof. (tenured), Nebraska—Lincoln, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Anne Massey, prof., information systems, Indiana, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Frances J. Milliken, prof., management, NYU, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Janice S. Miller, assoc. prof., Wisconsin—Milwaukee, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Tobias Moskowitz, assoc. prof., finance, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Eli Ofek, prof., finance, NYU, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Amit Pazgal, assoc. prof., marketing, Washington Univ., July 2002.</p>
         <p>Neil D. Pearson, prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Amil Petrin, assoc. prof., economics and statistics, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Damon Phillips, assoc. prof., organization and strategy, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Timothy Riddiough, prof., Wisconsin—Madison, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Sarah Sherry, lecturer, operations and decision technologies, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Jim Smith, senior lecturer, finance, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Edward A. Snyder, George Pratt Shultz Professor of Economics, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Jan Stallaert, assoc. prof., USC, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Judy Strauss, assoc. prof., Nevada—Reno, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Akram Temimi, assoc. prof., Alabama, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Stijn van Osselaer, assoc. prof., marketing, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Rockney Walters, prof., marketing, Indiana, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Bryan Wansink, prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Arthur D. Warga, dean, Houston, March 2002.</p>
         <p>Lawrence Weatherford, prof., decision sciences, Wyoming, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Robert F. Whitelaw, prof., finance, NYU, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>James Wimbush, prof., management, Indiana, July 2002.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc5">
         <title>Resignations</title>
         <p>Jason Abrevaya, assoc. prof., econometrics and statistics, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Sulin Ba, asst. prof., USC, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Yehuda Bassok, assoc. prof., USC, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Mary Margaret Frank, asst. prof., accounting, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Mark J. Garmaise, asst. prof., finance, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Jerry Han, assoc. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Alexander Hars, asst. prof., USC, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Jens Jackwerth, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Debra Krolick, asst. prof., accounting, Washington Univ., June 2002.</p>
         <p>Margaret Lucero, assoc. prof., management, Wyoming, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Mary Malliaris, assoc. dean, Loyola (Chicago), Feb. 2002.</p>
         <p>Hans Mikkelson, asst. prof., USC, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Nada Nasr, asst. prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Brendan T. O'Connell, asst. prof., accounting, Richmond, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Per Olsson, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Fulvio Ortu, asst. prof., USC, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Venkatesh Panchapagesan, asst. prof., finance, Washington Univ., Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Timothy Pollock, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Sonja Radas, asst. prof., marketing, Washington Univ., June 2002.</p>
         <p>Surendra Rajiv, assoc. prof., marketing, Chicago, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Jeffrey Sanchez‐Burks, asst. prof., USC, May 2002.</p>
         <p>John Scruggs, asst. prof., finance, Washington Univ., June 2002.</p>
         <p>Kristy Sheeler, lecturer, business communication, Indiana, June 2002.</p>
         <p>Hyun‐Han Shin, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Riyaz Sikora, asst. prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>José Silva, asst. prof., marketing, Washington Univ., June 2002.</p>
         <p>Gordon R. “Bob” Smith, lecturer, Florida State, May 2002.</p>
         <p>J. Reed Smith, assoc. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Mark Vargus, asst. prof., USC, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Enrique (Henry) R. Venta, dean, Loyola (Chicago), July 2002.</p>
         <p>Nicholas Wonder, asst. prof., finance, Wyoming, May 2002.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc6">
         <title>Retirements</title>
         <p>Andrew Bailey, prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Michael J. Brennan, prof., UCLA, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Dennis Gensch, prof., Wisconsin—Milwaukee, June 2002.</p>
         <p>Ernest Hanson, prof., Wisconsin—Madison, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Jack Helmkamp, prof., accounting, Indiana, June 2002.</p>
         <p>Wallace Hendricks, prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Stephen Kellogg, visiting asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Anthony McGann, prof., marketing, Wyoming, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Joseph Miller, prof., marketing, Indiana, June 2002.</p>
         <p>Robert A. Mittelstaedt, prof., Nebraska—Lincoln, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>William Morgan, prof., economics, Wyoming, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Robert Pricer, prof., Wisconsin—Madison, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Donald E. Pursell, prof., Nebraska—Lincoln, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Robert Roe, assoc. prof., marketing, Wyoming, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Suzanne Roe, assoc. lecturer, accounting, Wyoming, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Michael Simkowitz, prof., finance, Indiana, June 2002.</p>
         <p>John Summers, prof., marketing, Indiana, June 2002.</p>
         <p>Harold F. Williamson, assoc. prof., economics, Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, May 2002.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc7">
         <title>Deaths</title>
         <p>Zoel W. Daughtrey, prof., Mississippi State; March 17, 2002; Tupelo, Mississippi.</p>
      </sec>
   </body>
</article>
