<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26812182</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Corporate Tax Avoidance: Over Time and the Effect of Insiders</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Overconfidence and Aggressive Corporate Tax Policy</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chyz</surname>
                  <given-names>James A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gaertner</surname>
                  <given-names>Fabio</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kausar</surname>
                  <given-names>Asad</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Watson</surname>
                  <given-names>Luke</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">107</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26812141</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>47</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26812182"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We investigate whether firms with overconfident CEOs pursue more aggressive tax positions and yet assign high expectations of their final realizability, even if these positions were to be audited by a relevant taxing authority. In our empirical tests we first document positive associations between proxies for the aggressiveness of firms’ tax positions and overconfidence. We then test for associations between overconfidence and the financial reporting of uncertain tax benefits under FIN 48. Prior tax aggressiveness research leads to the expectation of a similarly positive association with uncertain tax benefits. Instead, we find that the same group of firms with overconfident CEOs report lower uncertain tax benefits in the financial statements. This asymmetric result between tax policy choices and the financial reporting of those choices by firms with overconfident CEOs should be of interest to policy and rule makers, thus advancing the overconfidence, tax aggressiveness, and financial reporting literatures.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Ahmed, A. S., &amp; Duellman, S. (2013). Managerial Overconfidence and Accounting Conservatism. Journal of Accounting Research, 51 (1), 1-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Alicke, M. D. (1985). Global Self-Evaluation as Determined by the Desirability and Controllability of Trait Adjectives. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 49 (6), 1621-1630.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Armstrong, C. S., Blouin, J. L., &amp; Larcker, D. F. (2012). The incentives for tax planning. Journal of Accounting &amp; Economics, 53 (1/2), 391-411.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Atwood, T. J., Drake, M. S., Myers, J. N., &amp; Myers, L. A. (2012). Home country tax system characteristics and corporate tax avoidance: International evidence. Accounting Review, 87 (6), 1831-1860.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bertrand, M.,&amp; Schoar, A. (2003). Managing with style: The effect of managers on firm policies. Quarterly Journal of Economics, 118, 1169-208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Ben-David, I., Graham, J. R., &amp; Harvey, C.R. (2013). Managerial Miscalibration. Quarterly Journal of Economics, 128 (4), 1547-1584.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Billet, M.T. &amp; Qian, Y. (2008). Are overconfident CEOs born or made? Evidence of self- attribution bias from frequent acquirers. Management Science, 54 (6), 1037-1051.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Blaylock, B., Gaertner, F. B., &amp; Shevlin, T. (2014). The association between book-tax conformity and earnings management. Review of Accounting Studies, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Blouin, J., Gleason, C., Mills, L. M., &amp; Sikes, S. A. (2007). What Can We Learn about Uncertain Tax Benefits from FIN 48? National Tax Journal, 60 (3), 521-535.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Brenner, L. A., Koehler, D. J., Liberman, V., &amp; Tversky, A. (1996). Overconfidence in probability and frequency judgments: A critical examination. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes, 65 (3), 212-219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Campbell, T. C., Gallmeyer, M., Johnson, S., Rutherford, J., &amp; Stanley, B. (2011). CEO optimism and forced turnover. Journal of Financial Economics, 101, 695-712.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Chatterjee, A., &amp; Hambrick, D. C. (2007). It's all about me: Narcissistic chief executive officers and their effects on company strategy and performance. Administrative Science Quarterly, 52 (3), 351-386.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Chen, S., Chen, X., Cheng, Q., &amp; Shevlin, T. (2010). Are family firms more tax aggressive than non-family firms? Journal of Financial Economics, 95 (1), 41-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Cheng, C. S. A., Huang, H. H., Yinghua, L., &amp; Stanfield, J. (2012). The effect of hedge fund activism on corporate tax avoidance. Accounting Review, 87 (5), 1493-1526.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Chyz, J. A. (2013). Personally tax aggressive executives and corporate tax sheltering. Journal of Accounting &amp; Economics, 56 (2/3), 311-328.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Chyz, J. A., Ching Leung, W. S., Zhen Li, O., &amp; Meng Rui, O. (2013). Labor unions and tax aggressiveness. Journal of Financial Economics, 108 (3), 675-698.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Cook, K., Moser, W., &amp; Omer, T. C. (2014). Towards an optimal level of tax avoidance. Working paper: Texas Tech University, Miami University, and University of Nebraska at Lincoln.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Cordeiro, L. (2009). Managerial Overconfidence and Dividend Policy. Working paper: London Business School.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Cronqvist, H., Makhija, A. K., &amp; Yonker, S. E. (2012). Behavioral consistency in corporate finance: CEO personal and corporate leverage. Journal of Financial Economics, 103 (1), 20-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Dawes, R. M., &amp; Mulford, M. (1996). The false consensus effect and overconfidence: Flaws in judgment or flaws in how we study judgment? Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes, 65 (3), 201-211.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Dechow, P., Sloan, R., &amp; Sweeney, A. (1995). Detecting earnings management. Accounting Review, 70 (2), 193-225.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Desai, M. A., &amp; Dharmapala, D. (2006). Corporate tax avoidance and high-powered incentives. Journal of Financial Economics, 79 (1), 145-179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">De Simone, L., Robinson, J. R., &amp; Stomberg, B. (2014). Distilling the reserve for uncertain tax benefits. The revealing case of black liquor. Review of Accounting Studies, 19 (1), 156-472.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Deshmukh, S., Goel, A. M., &amp; Howe, K. M. (2013). CEO overconfidence and dividend policy. Journal of Financial Intermediation, 22, 440-463.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Dhaliwal, D., Gleason, C., &amp; Mills, L. M. (2004). Last-chance earnings management: Using the tax expense to meet analysts’ forecasts. Contemporary Accounting Research, 21 (2), 431-459.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Dittmar, A., &amp;. Duchin, R. (2014). Looking in the rear-view mirror: The effect of managers’ professional experienence on corporate financial policy. Working paper: University of Michigan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Dyreng, S. D., Hanlon, M., &amp; Maydew, E. L. (2008). Long-Run Corporate Tax Avoidance. Accounting Review, 83 (1), 61-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Dyreng, S. D., Hanlon, M., &amp; Maydew, E. L. (2010). The Effects of Executives on Corporate Tax Avoidance. Accounting Review, 85 (4), 1163-1189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Fee, C. E., Hadlock, C. J. &amp; Pierce, J. R. (2013). Managers with and without style: Evidence using exogenous variation. Review of Financial Studies, 26 (3), 567-601.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Fischhoff, B., Slovic, P., &amp; Lichtenstein, S. (1977). Knowing with certainty: The appropriateness of extreme confidence. Journal of Experimental Psychology-Human Perception and Performance, 3 (4), 552-564.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Fischhoff, B., Slovic, P., &amp; Lichtenstein, S. (1980). Knowing what you want: Measuring labile values. In T. Wallsten (Ed.), Cognitive processes in choice and decision behavior (117-141). Hillsdale, NJ: Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Frank, K. (2000). Impact of a confounding variable on a regression coefficient. SociologicalMethods &amp; Research, 29, 147-194.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Frank, M. M., Lynch, L. J., and Rego, S. O. (2009). Tax reporting aggressiveness and its relation to aggressive financial reporting. Accounting Review, 84 (2), 467-496.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Gabbionetta, C., Greenwood, R., Mazzola, P., &amp; Minoja, M. (2013). The influence of the institutional context on corporate illegality. Accounting, Organizations, and Society, 38 (6-7), 484-504.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Gaertner, F. B. (2013). CEO After-Tax Incentives and Corporate Tax Avoidance. Contemporary Accounting Research, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Gallemore, J., Maydew, E. L., &amp; Thornock, J. (2013). The reputational costs of tax avoidance. Contemporary Accounting Research, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Ge, W., Matsumoto, D., &amp; Zhang, J. (2011). Do CFOs have style? An empirical investigation of the effect of individual CFOs on accounting practices. Contemporary Accounting Research, 28, 1141-1179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Goel, A. M., &amp; Thakor, A. V. (2008). Overconfidence, CEO selection, and corporate governance. Journal of Finance, 63 (6), 2737-2784.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Goh, B. W., Lee, J., Lim, C. Y., &amp; Shevlin, T. (2013). The effect of corporate tax avoidance on the cost of equity capital. Working paper: Singapore Management University and University of California-Irvine.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Graham, J. R., Harvey, C. R., &amp; Puri, M. (2013). Managerial attitudes and corporate actions. Journal of Financial Economics, 109 (1), 103-121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Graham, J. R., &amp; Tucker, A. L. 2006. Tax shelters and corporate debt policy. Journal of Financial Economics, 81 (3), 563-594.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Griffin, D., &amp; Tversky, A. (1992). The weighing of evidence and the determinants of confidence. Cognitive Psychology, 24 (3), 411-435.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Gupta, S., &amp; Newberry, K. (1997). Determinants of the Variability in Corporate Effective Tax Rates: Evidence from Longitudinal Data. Journal of Accounting &amp; Public Policy, 16 (1), 1-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Hambrick, D., &amp; Finkelstein, S. (1987). Managerial discretion: A bridge between polar views of organizational outcomes. Research in Organizational Behavior, 9, 369-406.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Hambrick, D., &amp; Mason, P. (1984). Upper echelons: The organization as a reflection of its top managers. The Academy of Management Review, 9 (2), 193-206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Hanlon, M., &amp; Heitzman, S. (2010). A review of tax research. Journal of Accounting &amp; Economics, 50 (2/3), 127-178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Hayes, R., &amp; Schaefer, S. (2009). CEO pay and the Lake Wobegon effect. Journal of Financial Economics, 94 (2), 280-290.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Heaton, J. B. (2002). Managerial optimism and corporate finance. Financial Management, 31 (2), 33-45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Hilary, G., &amp; Menzly, L. (2006). Does past success lead analysts to become overconfident? Management Science, 52 (4), 489-500.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Hirshleifer, D., A. Low, and S. H. Teoh. 2012. Are Overconfident CEOs Better Innovators? Journal of Finance 67 (4):1457-1498.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Hribar, P., &amp; Yang, H. (2013). CEO Overconfidence and Management Forecasting. Working Paper: University of Iowa and University of Pennsylvania.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Hutchens, M., &amp; Rego, S. (2013). Tax risk and the cost of equity capital. Working paper: Indiana University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Kahneman, D., Slovic, P., &amp; Tversky, A. (Eds.). (1982). Judgment under Uncertainty: Heuristics and Biases. Cambridge, U.K.: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Kim, J., Li, Y., &amp; Zhang, L. (2011). Corporate tax avoidance and stock price crash risk: Firm-level analysis. Journal of Financial Economics, 100 (3), 639-662.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Larcker, D., &amp; Rusticus, T. (2010). On the use of instrumental variables in accounting research. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 49, 186-205.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Libby, R., &amp; Rennekamp, K. (2012). Self-serving attribution bias, overconfidence, and the issuance of management forecasts. Journal of Accounting Research, 50 (1), 197-231.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Lisowsky, P., Robinson, L., &amp; Schmidt, A. (2013). Do Publicly Disclosed Tax Reserves Tell Us About Privately Disclosed Tax Shelter Activity? Journal of Accounting Research, 51 (3), 583-629.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Malmendier, U., &amp; Tate, G. (2005). CEO Overconfidence and Corporate Investment. Journal of Finance, 60 (6), 2661-2700.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Malmendier, U., &amp; Tate, G. 2008. Who makes acquisitions? CEO overconfidence and the market's reaction. Journal of Financial Economics, 89 (1), 20-43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Malmendier, U., Tate, G., &amp; Yan, J. O. N. (2011). Overconfidence and early-life experiences: The effect of managerial traits on corporate financial policies. Journal of Finance, 66 (5), 1687-1733.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">McGuire, S. T., Omer, T. C., &amp; Wang, D. (2012). Tax avoidance: Does tax-specific industry expertise make a difference? Accounting Review, 87 (3), 975-1003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <mixed-citation id="c62">Mills, L. M. (1998). Book-tax differences and Internal Revenue Service audit adjustments. Journal of Accounting Research, 36 (2), 343-356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Mills, L, M., Erickson, M., &amp; Maydew, E. L. (1998). Investments in tax planning. Journal of the American Taxation Association, 20 (1), 1-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Law, K., &amp; Mills, L. M. (2013). Doing the right thing: Military experience and corporate tax avoidance. Working Paper: Tilburg University and University of Texas at Austin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r65">
            <mixed-citation id="c65">Law, K., &amp; Mills, L. M. (2014). Measuring aggressive tax planning activities from linguistic cues. Working Paper: Tilburg University and University of Texas at Austin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r66">
            <mixed-citation id="c66">Oskamp, S. (1965). Overconfidence in Case Study Judgments. Journal of Consulting Psychology, 29 (3), 261-265.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r67">
            <mixed-citation id="c67">Peecher, M., Solomon, I., &amp; Trotman, K. (2013). An accountability framework for financial statement auditors and related research questions. Accounting, Organizations, and Society, 38, 596-620.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r68">
            <mixed-citation id="c68">Phillips, J. D. (2003). Corporate Tax-Planning Effectiveness: The Role of Compensation-Based Incentives. Accounting Review, 78 (3), 847-874.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r69">
            <mixed-citation id="c69">Rego, S. O., &amp; Wilson, R. (2012). Equity Risk Incentives and Corporate Tax Aggressiveness. Journal of Accounting Research, 50 (3), 775-810.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r70">
            <mixed-citation id="c70">Robinson, J. R., Sikes, S. A., &amp; Weaver, C. D. (2010). Performance measurement of corporate tax departments. Accounting Review, 85 (3), 1035-1064.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r71">
            <mixed-citation id="c71">Roll, R. (1986). The Hubris Hypothesis of Corporate Takeovers. Journal of Business, 59 (2), 197-216.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r72">
            <mixed-citation id="c72">Scholes, M., &amp; Wolfson, M. (1992). Taxes and business strategy: A planning approach. Engelwood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice-Hall.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r73">
            <mixed-citation id="c73">Schrand, C. M., &amp; Zechman, S. L. C. (2012). Executive overconfidence and the slippery slope to financial misreporting. Journal of Accounting &amp; Economics, 53 (1/2), 311-329.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r74">
            <mixed-citation id="c74">Shevlin, T. (2002). Commentary: Corporate tax shelters and book-tax differences. Tax Law Review, New York University School of Law, 55 (3), 427-443.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r75">
            <mixed-citation id="c75">Spatt, C. (2007). Chief Economist and Director of the Office of Economic Analysis speech: The economics of FIN 48: Accounting for uncertainty in income taxes. March 8. Washington, DC: SEC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r76">
            <mixed-citation id="c76">Svenson, O. (1981). Are we all less risky and more skillful than our fellow drivers? Acta Psychologica, 47 (2), 143-148.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r77">
            <mixed-citation id="c77">Taylor, S. E., &amp; Brown, J. D. (1988). Illusion and well-being: A social psychological perspective on mental health. Psychological Bulletin, 103 (2), 193-210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r78">
            <mixed-citation id="c78">Tversky, A., &amp; Kahneman, D. (1981). The framing of decisions and the psychology of choice. Science, 211 (4481), 453-458.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r79">
            <mixed-citation id="c79">Weinstein, N. D. (1980). Unrealistic optimism about future life events. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 39 (5), 806-820.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r80">
            <mixed-citation id="c80">Wilson, R. (2009). An examination of corporate tax shelter participants. Accounting Review, 84 (3), 969-999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r81">
            <mixed-citation id="c81">Wooldridge, R. (2002). Econometric analysis of cross section and panel data. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r82">
            <mixed-citation id="c82">Yoon, L. (2006). That uncertain something: FASB and taxes. CFO.com (January 16), Online edition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Sample Selection</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Descriptive Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Correlations</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>CEO Overconfidence, Tax Aggressiveness, and Uncertain Tax Positions</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Impact Threshold for a Confounding Variable Analysis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>CFO Overconfidence, Tax Aggressiveness, and Uncertain Tax Positions</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
