<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278171</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Study on Wear Progress of Plain Bearing under Mixed Lubrication Condition</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sano</surname>
                  <given-names>Takahiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nakasone</surname>
                  <given-names>Takeyuki</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Katagiri</surname>
                  <given-names>Takeshi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Okamoto</surname>
                  <given-names>Yutaka</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Daido Metal Co., Ltd.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>569</fpage>
         <lpage>580</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278171"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Recently, automotive engines have been operating under harsh conditions of high-power, low viscosity oil and increase of start-stop (e.g. idling stop). In plain bearing used within engine, as oil film thickness decreases, the frequency of direct contacts on the sliding surfaces between the shaft and the bearing are gradually increasing. In fact, the plain bearings for engines would tend to be used under mixed lubrication and the contacts of the surface roughness asperities sometimes occur between the shaft and the bearing. As a result, the bearing wear on the sliding surfaces is accelerated by the contacts of the roughness asperities. In order to predict the bearing performance exactly, it is very important to understand the change progress of the geometric shape of sliding surfaces caused by the wear.</p>
            <p>Therefore, in this study, to establish the theoretical analysis method of the wear progress of the bearing under mixed lubrication conditions, the following procedures were conducted on a static load:</p>
            <p>• The bearing performance analyses were carried out, based on the mixed lubrication theory which incorporates both the EHL theory with consideration of the surface roughness and the contact theory of the roughness asperities.</p>
            <p>• By the generated contact pressures between the roughness asperities, the wear depth in the bearing surface were calculated, and the wear progress of the bearing sliding surface was analyzed from calculated results.</p>
            <p>• The mixed lubrication analysis involved iteration of above two steps with consideration of the wear progress on the bearing surface.</p>
            <p>• Theoretical analysis results of the wear progress were verified by experiments on the rig tests.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rabinowicz, E., “Friction and Wear of Materials”, John Wiley and Sons Inc., 1965, 136-141.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Okamoto, Y., Kitahara, K., Ushijima, K., Aoyama, S., Xu, H. and Jones, G. J., “A Study for Wear and Fatigue of Engine Bearings on Rig Test by Using Elastohydrodynamic Lubrication Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0287, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0287.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ushijima, K., Arai, T., Goto, T. and Aoyama, S., “A Study on Engine Bearing Performance Using EHL analysis and Experimental Analysis”, The 13th Internal combustion engine symposium, Proceeding, 1996, 169-174.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Okamoto, Y., Kitahara, K., Ushijima, K., Aoyama, S., Jones, G.J. and Xu, H., “A Study for Wear and Fatigue on Engine Bearings by Using EHL Analysis”, Proceeding, 1999, JSAE No.9933934 (in Japanese).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miyauchi, Y., Hirobe, T., Kimura, S., Gondai, A. and Hirota, T., “Wear Prediction calculation of Bearing and Correlation Using Thin Layer Activation Technique”, Mazda Technical Review, 26, 2008, 147-152 (in Japanese).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shiokawa, S., Gekkan-Tribology, Shinjusha, 2008.10, 20 (in Japanese).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fatu, A. and Bonneau, D., “Wear prediction models for automotive bearings”, 7th EDF &amp; LMS Poitiers Workshop: Operational Limits of Bearings Improving of Performance through Modeling and Experimentation, 2008, C.1-C.7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, H., “STOCHASTIC MODELS FOR HYDRODYNAMIC LUBRICATION OF ROUGH SURFACES”, Proc. Instn. Mech. Engrs., 184, Pt1, 1969, 1013-1022.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greenwood, J.A. and Tripp, J.H., “THE CONTACT OF TWO NOMINALLY FLAT ROUGH SURFACES”, Proc. Instn. Mech. Engrs., 185, 1970, 625-633.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sakai, K., Zushi, K., Sugita, M. and Ishikawa, H., “Development of Lead Free Copper Based Alloy for Three Layers Bearings under Higher Load Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1600, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-1600.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kagohara, Y., Niwa, N., Ono, N. and Ishikawa, H., “Basic Characteristics of Lead-free Aluminum Alloy Bearing with Low Frictional Property of Adhered Molybdenum Disulfide,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1570, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-1570.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
