<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278135</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Non-Intrusive Investigation in a Small GDI Optical Engine Fuelled with Gasoline and Ethanol</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sementa</surname>
                  <given-names>Paolo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori CNR</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Vaglieco</surname>
                  <given-names>Bianca Maria</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori CNR</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Catapano</surname>
                  <given-names>Francesco</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Università Di Napoli Federico II</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>50</fpage>
         <lpage>66</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278135"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The aim of this paper is the experimental investigation of the effect of direct fuel injection on the combustion process and pollutant formation in a spark ignition (SI) two-wheel engine. The engine is a 250cc single cylinder, four-stroke spark-ignition firstly equipped with a four-valve PFI head and then with GDI one operating with European commercial gasoline and Bio-ethanol. It is equipped with a wide sapphire window in the bottom of the chamber and quartz cylinder. In the combustion chamber, optical techniques based on 2D-digital imaging were used to follow the injection and flame propagation and spectroscopic measurements were carried out in order to evaluate the main radical species. Radical species such as OH and CH were detected and used to follow the chemical phenomena related to the fuel quality. Measurements were carried out at different engine speeds and combustion strategies based on different injection pressures. They were chosen in order to allow both optical measurements and to test the engine in real conditions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Emission Control of Two- and Three-Wheel Vehicles- Manufacturers of Emission Controls Association www.meca.org August 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">American Petroleum Institute, Alcohols and Ethers: a Technical Assessment of Their Application as Fuels and Fuel Components, API Publication 4261, 3rd edition, June 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Varde, K., Jones, A., Knutsen, A., Mertz, D., and Yu, P. “Exhaust Emissions and Energy Release Rates from a Controlled Spark Ignition Engine using Ethanol Blends” Proc. ImechE Vol. 221, N.8 Part D: J. Autom. Eng, 933- 941(2007)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Price, P., Twiney, B., Stone, R., Kar, K., Walmsley, H., “Particulate and Hydrocarbon Emissions from a Spray Guided Direct Injection Spark Ignition Engine with Oxygenate Fuel Blends,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01- 0472, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0472.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H., “Advanced Direct Injection Combustion Engine Technologies and Development” Vol. 1:Gasoline and Gas Engines, Woodhead Publishing, (2010).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gao, J., Jiang, D., Huang, Z., “Spray Properties of Alternative Fuels: A Comparative Analysis of Ethanolgasoline Blends and Gasoline” Fuel 86, 1645-1650, (2007)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aleiferis, P.G., Serras-Pereira, J., van Romunde, Z., Caine, J., Wirth, M., “Mechanisms of Spray Formation and Combustion from a Multi-Hole Injector with E85 and Gasoline” Combustion and Flame 157 735-756 (2010)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catapano, F., Sementa, P., Vaglieco, B.M. “Optical Investigation in a GDI Engine Operating in Homogeneous and Stratified Charge Mixture Conditions Fuelled with Gasoline and Ethanol”, pp. 2224-2231, 23rd Int. Conf. on Eff., Cost, Opt., Sim.n and Env. Impact of En. Syst. - ECOS 2010, Lousanne (CH), (2010).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H., Ladommatos, N. Engine Combustion Instrumentation and Diagnostics. SAE Int., 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaydon, A.G., The Spectroscopy of Flames, Chapman and Hall ltd., 1957.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals., New York: McGraw-Hill, 1988</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">User manual firm of AVL, AVL Graz, Austria 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mörsch, O., Sorsche, P., “Investigation of Alternative Methods to Determine Particulate Mass Emissions”, http://www.oica.net/htdocs/Main.htm</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Drake, M.C., Fansler, T.D., Solomon, A.S., Szekely, G.A.Jr, “Piston Fuel Films as a Source of Smoke and Hydrocarbon Emissions from a Wall-Controlled Spark- Ignited Direct-Injection Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0547, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0547.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Garland, N., Crosley, D. “On the Collisional Quenching of Electronically Excited OH, NH and CH in flames”. Twenty-first symposium (International) on Combustion, pag. 1693-1702 (1986).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamazaki, M., Ohya, M., Tsuchiya, K. “Detection of the Air Equivalence Ratio of a Burner from the Flameemission Spectra” Int. Chemical Engineering, 30:160-168, (1990).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nogi, T., Ohyama, Y., Yamauchi, T. and Kuroiwa, H., “Mixture Formation of Fuel Injection Systems in Gasoline Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 880558, 1988, doi: 10.4271/880558.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, Y., Alger, T., Matthews, R., Ellzey, J., “The Effects of Fuel Volatility and Structure on HC Emissions from Piston Wetting in DISI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1205, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1205.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, Y., Matthews, R., Ellzey, J., Dai, W., “Effects of Fuel Volatility, Load, and Speed on HC Emissions Due to Piston Wetting,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-2024, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-2024.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stanglmaier, R.H., Roberts, C. E., Moses, C. A., “Vaporization of Individual Fuel Drops on a Heated Surface: A Study of Fuel-Wall Interactions within Direct- Injected Gasoline (DIG) Engines” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0838, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0838.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urban, B. D., Kroenlein, K., Kazakov, A., Dryer, F. L. et. al: Sooting Behavior of Ethanol Droplet Combustion at Elevated Pressures, Microgravity Sci. Technol. XV/3 (2004)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
