<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830845</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830851</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>INFLATION AND STOCK MARKET PERFORMANCE: A CASE STUDY FOR PAKISTAN</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Khalid Nadeem</given-names>
                  <surname>Khan</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2004</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>87</fpage>
         <lpage>101</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830851"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Financial institutions are the most critical factor to keep economies on the trajectory of economic growth and development. Their smooth functioning can guarantee efficient and effective allocation of savings. Therefore, factors detrimental to their efficient functioning should be identified, and policy makers should try to control their deleterious consequences. One important issue, though relatively ignored, is to quantify the impact of inflation on the size and functioning of the stock market. Close observation of literature reveals that inflation creates uncertainty about future rates of return and exacerbates the stock market frictions. It could also provide incentives for the government to repress the financial sector to collect inflation tax revenue. Nevertheless, there are very few studies, which gauges inflation-stock market relationship—the studies are limited to cross-section comparisons. This study tries to disentangle the relationship and uses cointegration theory and (Error Correction Model) ECM to test the presence of long run relationship—between inflation and financial sector performance indicators—in Pakistan. Though the results are not all unambiguous, there are substantial evidences that the variables are cointegrated and bilateral causality exists between them. The findings are consistent with the interpretation that inflation strengthens frictions in the stock market, decreases real rate of return on financial assets, and consequently decreases trading and capitalization in the stock markets. The second interpretation of financial sector repression seems valid because government collets inflation tax by printing money. Thus, on the basis of results it can be concluded that inflation matters to stock market performance. Therefore, it is neutral and almost obvious that much of the international community's policy focus should be directed to ensure that finance can make its most effective contribution to economic prosperity through sound, market-driven allocation of saving/ investable resources, and policy makers should devise policies to keep inflation in reasonable limits.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d15e144a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e148" publication-type="other">
Barnes, Michelle L, "Threshold Relationship Among Inflation, Financial Market Development and Growth," Center
for International Economic Studies, Policy Discussion Paper, No. 0036, 2000.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e158a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e162" publication-type="other">
Boyd, John H., Ross, Levine, and Bruce, D. Smith, "Inflation and Financial Market Performance," Federal Reserve
Bank of Minneapolis, Working Paper, 573D, 1996 (October).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e172a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e176" publication-type="other">
Boyd, John H., Ross Levine, and Bruce D. Smith, "The Impact of Inflation On financial Sector Performance,"
Journal of Monetary Economics, Vol. 47, 2001, pp. 221-248.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e186a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e190" publication-type="other">
Demirguc-Kunt A., and Levine R, "Stock Market Development and Financial Intermediaries: Stylized Facts", World
Bank Economic Review 10, 1996, pp. 291-322.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e201a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e205" publication-type="other">
Engle, R. R, and Granger, C. W. J., "Cointegration and Error Correction: Representation, Estimation and Testing",
Econometrica, 55, 1987, pp. 251-276.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e215a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e219" publication-type="other">
Feldstein, Martin, "Inflation and Stock Market," American Economic Review, 1980, pp. 839-847.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e226a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e230" publication-type="other">
Hensen, Bruce, "Threshold Effects in Non-Dynamic Panels: Estimation, Testing, and Inference", Journal of
Econometrics, Vol. 93, No. 2, 1999, pp. 345-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e240a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e244" publication-type="other">
Hung Fu-Sheng, "Inflation and Economic Growth in Financial Markets with Adverse Selection and Costly State
Verification," Academic Economic Papers, Vol. 29, No 1, 2000 (March).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e254a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e258" publication-type="other">
Johansen, S. Likelihood-based Inference in Cointegrated Vector Autoregressive Models. Oxford: Oxford University
Press, 1995.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e268a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e272" publication-type="other">
Khan, Mohsin S., Abdelhak S. Senhadji, and Bruce D. Smith, "Inflation and Financial Depth," IMF working paper
(April), No. 2001.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e283a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e287" publication-type="other">
Levine, R., "Financial Development and Economic Growth: Views and Agenda," Journal of Economic Literature,
Vol. 35, 1997, pp. 688-726.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e297a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e301" publication-type="other">
Marquis, H. Milton, "Inflation Tax, Financial Intermediation and Home Production," Federal Reserve Bank of San
Francisco, Working Paper No. 17, 2000.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e311a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e315" publication-type="other">
Rousseau Peter L., and Paul Wachtel, "Inflation Thresholds and Finance-Growth Nexus," Paper Presented at X
Tor Vergata Financial Conference, Rome, 2001 (November 25).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e325a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e329" publication-type="other">
Stock J. H.( and Watson M. W., "Variable Trends in Economic Time Series", Journal of Economic Perspective, 2
(3), 1988 (summer), pp. 147-174.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e339a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e343" publication-type="other">
Yakov, Amihud, "Unexpected Inflation and Stock Market Revisited: Evidence from Israel," Journal on money, cre-
dit and banking vol. 28(1), 1996, pp. 22-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


