<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285093</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investigation of Early and Late Intake Valve Closure Strategies for Load Control in a Spark Ignition Ethanol Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Lanzanova</surname>
                  <given-names>Thompson</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Brunel University London</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Nora</surname>
                  <given-names>Macklini Dalla</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Federal University of Santa Maria</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Zhao</surname>
                  <given-names>Hua</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Brunel University London</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>June 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285080</issue-id>
         <fpage>858</fpage>
         <lpage>872</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285093"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The more strict CO₂ emission legislation for internal combustion engines demands higher spark ignition (SI)engine efficiencies. The use of renewable fuels, such as bioethanol, may play a vital role to reduce not only CO₂ emissions but also petroleum dependency. An option to increase SI four stroke engine efficiency is to use the so called over-expanded cycle concepts by variation of the valve events. The use of an early or late intake valve closure reduces pumping losses (the main cause of the low part load efficiency in SI engines) but decreases the effective compression ratio. The higher expansion to compression ratio leads to better use of the produced work and also increases engine efficiency. This paper investigates the effects of early and late intake valve closure strategies in the gas exchange process, combustion, emissions and engine efficiency at unthrottled stoichiometric operation. A four-valve four-stroke single cylinder camless engine running with port fuel injection of anhydrous ethanol was employed. Early and late intake valve closure (EIVC and LIVC) strategies with a fixed maximum valve lift were compared to a conventional throttled SI valve event strategy for loads from 2.0 to 9.0 bar IMEP at 1500 rpm. The consequences and benefits to implement the unthrottled operation with each strategy were discussed. To better understand the effect of the maximum valve lift at a specific load, the valve lift was varied from 1.5 to 5.0 mm and its effects were discussed for EIVC strategy. Comparatively, the EIVC strategy presented better overall performance than the LIVC. Both unthrottled strategies provided higher engine efficiency than the conventional throttled SI strategy.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. R. E. C. (EREC), Renewable Energy in Europe: Markets, Trends, and Technologies, Second Ed. London: Earthscan Ltd, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maroun M. R. and La Rovere E. L., “Ethanol and food production by family smallholdings in rural Brazil: Economic and socio-environmental analysis of micro distilleries in the State of Rio Grande do Sul,” Biomass and Bioenergy, vol. 63, pp. 140–155, Apr. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The European Union Parliament, “L 140/88,” no. April, pp. 88–113, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walter A., Dolzan P., Quilodrán O., de Oliveira J. G., da Silva C., Piacente F., and Segerstedt A., “Sustainability assessment of bio-ethanol production in Brazil considering land use change, GHG emissions and socio-economic aspects,” Energy Policy, vol. 39, no. 10, pp. 5703–5716, Oct. 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jeuland N., Montagne X., and Gautrot X., “Potentiality of Ethanol As a Fuel for Dedicated Engine,” Oil Gas Sci”. Technol., vol. 59, no. 6, pp. 559–570, Nov. 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakata, K., Utsumi, S., Ota, A., Kawatake, K. , “The Effect of Ethanol Fuel on a Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3380, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3380.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stein, R., House, C., and Leone, T., “Optimal Use of E85 in a Turbocharged Direct Injection Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1):670–682, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1490.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Szybist, J., Foster, M., Moore, W., Confer, K. , “Investigation of Knock Limited Compression Ratio of Ethanol Gasoline Blends,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0619, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0619.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Costa R. C. and Sodré J. R., “Compression ratio effects on an ethanol/gasoline fuelled engine performance,” Appl. Therm. Eng., vol. 31, no. 2–3, pp. 278–283, Feb. 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kreuter, P., Heuser, P., and Schebitz, M., “Strategies to Improve SIEngine Performance by Means of Variable Intake Lift, Timing and Duration,” SAE Technical Paper 920449, 1992, doi:10.4271/920449.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pischinger, M., Salber, W., van der Staay, F., Baumgarten, H. , “Benefits of the Electromechanical Valve Train in Vehicle Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1223, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diana, S., Iorio, B., Giglio, V., and Police, G., “The Effect of Valve Lift Shape and Timing on Air Motion and Mixture Formation of DISI Engines Adopting Different VVA Actuators,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3553, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3553.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cleary, D. and Silvas, G., “Unthrottled Engine Operation with Variable Intake Valve Lift, Duration, and Timing,” SAE Technical Paper 2007- 01-1282, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1282.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stansfield, P., Wigley, G., Garner, C., Patel, R. , “Unthrottled Engine Operation using Variable Valve Actuation: The Impact on the Flow Field, Mixing and Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1414, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1414.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battistoni M. and Mariani F., “Fluid Dynamic Study of Unthrottled Part Load SI Engine Operations with Asymmetric Valve Lifts,” 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patel R., Ladommatos N., Stansfield P. A. , Wigley G., Garner C. P., Pitcher G., Turner J. W. G., Nuglisch H., and Helie J., “Un-throttling a direct injection gasoline homogeneous mixture engine with variable valve actuation,” Int. J. Engine Res., vol. 11, no. 6, pp. 391–411, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borgqvist, P., Tunestål P., and Johansson, B., “Investigation and Comparison of Residual Gas Enhanced HCCI using Trapping (NVO HCCI) or Rebreathing of Residual Gases,” SAE Technical Paper 2011- 01-1772, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1772.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalighi, B., “Intake-Generated Swirl and Tumble Motions in a 4-Valve Engine with Various Intake Configurations-Flow Visualization and Particle Tracking Velocimetry,” SAE Technical Paper 900059, 1990, doi:10.4271/900059.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hadded, O. and Denbratt, I., “Turbulence Characteristics of Tumbling Air Motion in Four-Valve S.I. Engines and their Correlation with Combustion Parameters,” SAE Technical Paper 910478, 1991, doi:10.4271/910478.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benjamin S. F., “A phenomenological model for ‘barrel’ swirl in reciprocating engines,” Arch. Proc. Inst. Mech. Eng. Part D J. Automob. Eng. 1989–1996 (vols 203–210), vol. 206, no. 14, pp. 63–71, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kang, K. and Baek, J., “Tumble Flow and Turbulence Characteristics in a Small Four-Valve Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 960265, 1996, doi:10.4271/960265.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, Y., Zhao, H., Peng, Z., and Ladommatos, N., “Analysis of Tumble and Swirl Motions in a Four-Valve SI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3555, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3555.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hill P. G. and Zhang D., “The effects of swirl and tumble on combustion in spark-ignition engines,” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci., vol. 20, no. 5, pp. 373–429, Jan. 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Floch, A., Van Frank, J., and Ahmed, A., “Comparison of the Effects of Intake-Generated Swirl and Tumble on Turbulence Characteristics in a 4-Valve Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 952457, 1995, doi:10.4271/952457.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urushihara, T., Murayama, T., Takagi, Y., and Lee, K., “Turbulence and Cycle-by-Cycle Variation of Mean Velocity Generated by Swirl and Tumble Flow and Their Effects on Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 950813, 1995, doi:10.4271/950813.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang T., Liu D., Tan B., Wang G., and Peng Z., “An investigation into incylinder tumble flow characteristics with variable valve lift in a gasoline engine,” Flow, Turbul”. Combust., vol. 94, no. 2, pp. 285–304, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Le Coz, J., Henriot, S., and Pinchon, P., “An Experimental and Computational Analysis of the Flow Field in a Four-Valve Spark Ignition Engine-Focus on Cycle-Resolved Turbulence,” SAE Technical Paper 900056, 1990, doi:10.4271/900056.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee K., Bae C., and Kang K., “The effects of tumble and swirl flows on flame propagation in a four-valve S.I. engine,” Appl. Therm. Eng., vol. 27, no. 11–12, pp. 2122–2130, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bücker, I., Karhoff, D., Klaas, M., and Schröder, W., “Engine In- Cylinder Flow Control via Variable Intake Valve Timing,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0055, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0055.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dalla Nora, M., Lanzanova, T., Zhang, Y., and Zhao, H., “Engine Downsizing through Two-Stroke Operation in a Four-Valve GDI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0674, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0674.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lanzanova T. D. M., Nora M. Dalla, and Zhao H., “Performance and economic analysis of a direct injection spark ignition engine fueled with wet ethanol,” Appl. Energy, vol. 169, pp. 230–239, May 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Melo, T., de Brito, M., Machado, G., and Paiva, C., “Procedure for Uncertainty of Measurement Determination of Spark Ignition Engine Emission Tests,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-36-0488, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-36-0488.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Munsin R., Laoonual Y., Jugjai S., and Imai Y., “An experimental study on performance and emissions of a small SI engine generator set fuelled by hydrous ethanol with high water contents up to 40%,” Fuel, vol. 106, pp. 586–592, Apr. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kar K., Tharp R., Radovanovic M., Dimou I., and Cheng W. K., “Organic gas emissions from a stoichiometric direct injection spark ignition engine operating on ethanol/gasoline blends,” Int. J. Engine Res., vol. 11, no. 6, pp. 499–513, Dec. 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wallner T., “Correlation Between Speciated Hydrocarbon Emissions and Flame Ionization Detector Response for Gasoline/Alcohol Blends,” J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power, vol. 133, no. 8, p. 82801, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Economic Commission for Europe of the United Nations, “Regulation No 49 of the Economic Commission for Europe of the United Nations (UN/ECE),” Off. J. Eur. Union, no. 171, pp. 1–390, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caton J. A., “Combustion phasing for maximum efficiency for conventional and high efficiency engines,” Energy Convers. Manag., vol. 77, pp. 564–576, Jan. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aleiferis P., Taylor A., Ishii K., and Urata Y., “The nature of early flame development in a lean-burn stratified-charge spark-ignition engine,” Combust. Flame, vol. 136, no. 3, pp. 283–302, Feb. 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood J. B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, 1st ed., vol. 21. McGraw-Hil, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
