<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revueconfina</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50010274</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Revue d'économie financière</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Association d'Economie Financière</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">09873368</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">17775744</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">44649630</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Les autres canaux de mobilisation de l'épargne</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Les marchés financiers chinois</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Bruno</given-names>
                  <surname>CABRILLAC</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Jean-Patrick</given-names>
                  <surname>YANITCH</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2004</year>
         </pub-date>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">77</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i40194346</issue-id>
         <fpage>275</fpage>
         <lpage>297</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44649630"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Cet article présente les deux systèmes coexistants en Chine : les marchés de la Chine Continentale et la Place de Hong-Kong. La capitalisation sur les premiers est limitée et les dérivés, cantonnés aux métaux et produits agricoles. Des scandales à répétition, l'effet d'éviction par les entreprises publiques et une supervision encore insuffisante nourrissent la défiance des investisseurs. En revanche, la Place de Hong-Kong a confirmé sa prééminence en Asie Continentale en devenant le marché international privilégié des grandes sociétés et investisseurs continentaux. Cependant, des réformes doivent être envisagées : amélioration de la gouvernance et de la transparence des marchés continentaux ; renforcement de la place des investisseurs institutionnels ; assainissement des marchés et sélection des participants ; résolution du problème des titres non échangeables... La Chine Continentale étant aujourd'hui le moteur du développement de la Place de Hong-Kong, elle devra également adapter son fonctionnement. This article presents the 2 existing financial systems in China: Continental China's markets and The Hong Kong stock exchange. The market capitalization of the first system is low and derivatives markets are limited to metal and agricultural products. Several scandals, the eviction effect of public firms and a still inadequate supervision keep the investors' mistrust alive. However, the Hong Kong stock exchange has strengthened its pre-eminence in Continental Asia since it had been becoming the international preferred market of big firms and continental investors. But some reforms must be considered: transparency and governance improvement on continental markets, strengthening of institutional investors' role, markets clearing and selection of interest, solving of non exchangeable security... Continental China is today the driving force behind the Hong Kong stock exchange which so must adapt its functioning.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>fre</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list>
         <title>NOTES</title>
         <ref id="d1636e202a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e209" publication-type="other">
« Chinese stock investors make huge losses », Shanghai Daily, 26 septembre 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1636e216a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e223" publication-type="other">
J-P. Yanitch, site Internet de la Mission économique de Pékin, http://www.missioneco.org/
Chine/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1636e233a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e240" publication-type="other">
China's securities
and Futures Markets, CSRC, avril 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1636e250a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e257" publication-type="other">
Shenyang Hejin Holding CO Ltd (SZA 000633),
l'entreprise d'agroalimentaire Xinjiang Tunhe Investment Co Ltd (SHA 600737)</mixed-citation>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e266" publication-type="other">
Torch Investment Co Ltd (SZA 000349).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1636e274a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e281" publication-type="other">
Hongkong, world number 2 warrant market, HKEx planning and research unit, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1636e288a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e295" publication-type="other">
The implication of CEPA for Hong Kong securities industry, Matthew Harrison, HKEx, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1636e302a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e309" publication-type="other">
Understanding investors in the Hong Kong listed securities and derivatives market, Essie Tsoi, bulletin de
la SFC, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1636e319a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e326" publication-type="other">
Bruno Cabrillac, Perpectives chinoises, août 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1636e333a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e340" publication-type="other">
« Developing Institutional Investors in People's Republic of China », Banque mondiale, 24 octobre
2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1636e350a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e357" publication-type="other">
China's pension reform and
capital market development, Xin Wang, China and World Economy, vol 12, number 3-2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1636e368a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e375" publication-type="other">
« Enterprise reform and stock market development in mainland China », Stephen Green, Deutsche
Bank, 25 mars 2004;</mixed-citation>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e384" publication-type="other">
« Can a capitalist equity market help reform of Chinese state-owned entreprises?
», Huang, S. et Song F., University of Hongkong, Working paper, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1636e394a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e401" publication-type="other">
« Hongkong SAR, meeting the challenges of the integration with the Mainland »,
Financial market developments, William Lee et Ida Liu, FMI, occasional Paper 226, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1636e411a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e418" publication-type="other">
Impact of the issuance of A Shares on the turnover of H Shares, Joseph Lee et Yan Yuhong, HKEx, décembre
2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1636e428a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1636e435" publication-type="other">
Techfaith Wireless Communication Technology, une société chinoise qui a préféré le NASDAQ au
GEM, South China Moning Post du 22 septembre 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
