<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939352</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Health Insurance: New Evidence from Policy Changes</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Health insurance mandates and traffic fatalities</article-title>
            <subtitle>The effects of substance use disorder parity laws</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Popovici</surname>
                  <given-names>Ioana</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Maclean</surname>
                  <given-names>Johanna Catherine</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>French</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael T.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>51</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939352"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We investigate whether state-specific health insurance parity laws for substance use disorder (SUD) treatment reduce traffic fatalities. Parity laws compel private insurers to cover SUD treatment more generously. We employ 26 years of administrative data from the Fatality Analysis Reporting System coupled with a differences-in-differences design to study this question. Our findings indicate that passage of a parity law is associated with a 7.6 to 8.2% reduction in traffic fatality rates. These findings suggest that government regulations requiring insurers to cover SUD treatment can significantly improve traffic safety, possibly by reducing the number of impaired drivers on roadways.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References:</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Abadie, Alberto, and Javier Gardeazabal. 2003. "The economic costs of conflict: A case study of the Basque Country." American Economic Review 93 (1):113-132.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Abouk, Rahi, and Scott Adams. 2013. "Texting bans and fatal accidents on roadways: Do they work? Or do drivers just react to announcements of bans?" American Economic Journal: Applied Economics 5 (2):179-199.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Adams, Scott, McKinley L Blackburn, and Chad D Cotti. 2012. "Minimum wages and alcohol-related traffic fatalities among teens." Review of Economics and Statistics 94 (3):828-840.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Adams, Scott, Chad Cotti, and Nathan Tefft. 2015. "Seatbelt use among drunk drivers in different legislative settings." Economic Inquiry 53 (1):758-772.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Ali, Mir M, William N Dowd, Timothy Classen, Ryan Mutter, and Scott P Novak. 2017. "Prescription drug monitoring programs, nonmedical use of prescription drugs, and heroin use: Evidence from the National Survey of Drug Use and Health." Addictive Behaviors 69:65-77.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Anderson, Mark D, Benjamin Hansen, and Daniel I Rees. 2013. "Medical marijuana laws, traffic fatalities, and alcohol consumption." Journal of Law and Economics 56 (2):333-369.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Angrist, Joshua D., and J Pischke. 2009. Mostly Harmless Econometrics: An Empiricist's Companion. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press. Book. Original edition, Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Autor, David H. 2003. "Outsourcing at will: The contribution of unjust dismissal doctrine to the growth of employment outsourcing." Journal of Labor Economics 21 (1):1-42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Bailey, James. 2014. "The effect of health insurance benefit mandates on premiums." Eastern Economic Journal 40 (1):119-127.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Bailey, James, and Nathan Blascak. 2016. "The effect of state health insurance benefit mandates on premiums and employee contributions." Applied Economics Letters 23 (14):1042-1046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Barry, Colleen L, and Jody L Sindelar. 2007. "Equity in private insurance coverage for substance abuse: A perspective on parity." Health Affairs 26 (6):w706-w716.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Bound, John, Charles Brown, and Nancy Mathiowetz. 2001. "Measurement error in survey data." Handbook of Econometrics 5:3705-3843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Center for Substance Abuse Treatment. 2004. Clinical Guidelines for the Use of Buprenorphine in the Treatment of Opioid Addiction. Treatment Improvement Protocol (TIP) Series 40. In Series 40. DHHS Publication No. (SMA) 04-3939. , edited by Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration. Rockville, MD: Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2015. "http://www.cdc.gov/vitalsigns/drinkinganddriving/." accessed May 27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2016. "10 Leading Causes of Injury Deaths by Age Group Highlighting Unintentional Injury Deaths, United States - 2016." accessed October 9. https://www.cdc.gov/injury/images/lc-charts/leading_causes_of_injury_deaths_unintentional_injury_2015_1050w760h.gif.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Dave, Dhaval, and Swati Mukerjee. 2011. "Mental health parity legislation, cost-sharing and substance-abuse treatment admissions." Health Economics 20 (2):161-183.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Eisenberg, Daniel. 2003. "Evaluating the effectiveness of policies related to drunk driving." Journal of Policy Analysis and Management 22 (2):249-274.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Elvik, Rune. 2013. "Risk of road accident associated with the use of drugs: a systematic review and meta-analysis of evidence from epidemiological studies." Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention 60:254-267.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Eoh, Hong J., Min K. Chung, and Seong-Han Kim. 2005. "Electroencephalographic study of drowsiness in simulated driving with sleep deprivation." International Journal of Industrial Ergonomics 35 (4):307-320.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Flood, Sarah, Miriam King, Steven Ruggles, and J Robert Warren. 2015. "Integrated public use microdata series, Current Population Survey: Version 4.0.[Machine-readable database]." Minneapolis: University of Minnesota.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Freeborn, Beth A, and Brian McManus. 2010. "Substance abuse treatment and motor vehicle fatalities." Southern Economic Journal 76 (4):1032-1048.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">French, Michael T, and Gulcin Gumus. 2014. "Macroeconomic fluctuations and motorcycle fatalities in the US." Social Science &amp; Medicine 104:187-193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">French, Michael T, and Gulcin Gumus. 2015. "Fast times during spring breaks: Are traffic fatalities another consequence?" Economic Inquiry 53:745-757.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">French, Michael T, Ioana Popovici, and Lauren Tapsell. 2008. "The economic costs of substance abuse treatment: Updated estimates and cost bands for program assessment and reimbursement." Journal of Substance Abuse Treatment 35 (4):462-469.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Governors Highway Safety Association. 2017. Drug-imparired Driving.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Grossman, Michael. 1972. "On the concept of health capital and the demand for health." Journal of Political Economy 80 (2):223-255.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Hack, M. A., S. J. Choi, P. Vijayapalan, R. J. O. Davies, and J. R. Stradling. 2001. "Comparison of the effects of sleep deprivation, alcohol and obstructive sleep apnoea (OSA) on simulated steering performance." Respiratory Medicine 95 (7):594-601.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Hamersma, Sarah, and Johanna Catherine Maclean. 2018. "Title." National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper Series, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Jensen, Gail A, and Michael A Morrisey. 1999. "Employer-sponsored health insurance and mandated benefit laws." Milbank Quarterly 77 (4):425-459.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Kline, Patrick. 2011. "The impact of juvenile curfew laws on arrests of youth and adults." American Law and Economics Review 14 (1):44-67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Koehler, Steven A, and Peggy A Brown. 2009. Forensic Epidemiology: CRC Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Kunz, F Michael, Michael T French, and Shahrzad Bazargan-Hejazi. 2004. "Cost-effectiveness analysis of a brief intervention delivered to problem drinkers presenting at an inner-city hospital emergency department." Journal of Studies on Alcohol 65 (3):363-370.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Levintova, Hannah. 2018. "Paul Ryan says Republicans will take another run at Obamacare after the midterms." Mother Jones. https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2018/09/paul-ryan-obamacare-reform-2018-midterm-elections/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Lovenheim, Michael F. 2009. "The effect of teachers’ unions on education production: Evidence from union election certifications in three midwestern states." Journal of Labor Economics 27 (4):525-587.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Lu, Mingshan, and Thomas G McGuire. 2002. "The productivity of outpatient treatment for substance abuse." Journal of Human Resources 37 (2):309-335.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Maclean, Johanna Catherine, M. Oney, J. Marti, and Jody L Sindelar. 2018. "What factors predict the passage of state-level e-cigarette regulations?" Health Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Maclean, Johanna Catherine, Ioana Popovici, and Elisheva Stern. 2018. "Health insurance expansions and provider behavior: Evidence from substance use disorder providers." Journal of Law &amp; Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Maclean, Johanna Catherine, and Brendan Saloner. 2018a. "The effect of public insurance expansions on substance use disorder treatment: Evidence from the Affordable Care Act." Journal of Policy Analysis and Management.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Maclean, Johanna Catherine, and Brendan Saloner. 2018b. "Substance use treatment provider behavior and healthcare reform: Evidence from Massachusetts." Health Economics 27 (1):76-101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">McGinty, Emma E, Susan H Busch, Elizabeth A Stuart, Haiden A Huskamp, Teresa B Gibson, Howard H Goldman, and Colleen L Barry. 2015. "Federal parity law associated with increased probability of using out-of-network substance use disorder treatment services." Health Affairs 34 (8):1331-1339.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">McLellan, A Thomas, David C Lewis, Charles P O'brien, and Herbert D Kleber. 2000. "Drug dependence, a chronic medical illness: Implications for treatment, insurance, and outcomes evaluation." JAMA 284 (13):1689-1695.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Meara, Ellen, Ezra Golberstein, Rebecca Zaha, Shelly F Greenfield, William R Beardslee, and Susan H Busch. 2014. "Use of hospital-based services among young adults with behavioral health diagnoses before and after health insurance expansions." JAMA Psychiatry 71 (4):404-411.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Meinhofer, Angélica, and Allison E Witman. 2018. "The role of health insurance on treatment for opioid use disorders: Evidence from the Affordable Care Act Medicaid expansion." Journal of Health Economics 60:177-197.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">National Center for Statistics and Analysis. 2016. State alcohol-impaired-driving estimates: 2014 data. edited by National Highway Traffic Safety Administration. Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">National Highway Traffic Safety Administration. 2002. Transitioning to multiple imputation-A new method to estimate missing blood alcohol concentration (BAC) values in FARS. edited by Department of Transportation. Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">National Highway Traffic Safety Administration. 2010. Drug involvement of fatally injured drivers. In US Department of Transportation Report No. DOT HS: National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">National Institute on Drug Abuse. 2012. "Principles of drug addiction treatment: A research-based guide.", accessed December 21. https://d14rmgtrwzf5a.cloudfront.net/sites/default/files/podat_1.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Pascale, Joanne, Michel Boudreaux, and Ryan King. 2016. "Understanding the new Current Population Survey health insurance questions." Health Services Research 51 (1):240-261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Patashnik, Eric, and Jonathan Oberlander. 2018 "Republicans are still trying to repeal Obamacare. Here’s why they are not likely to succeed." The Washington Post.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Popovici, Ioana, and Michael T French. 2013a. "Binge drinking and sleep problems among young adults." Drug and Alcohol Dependence 132 (1-2):207-15.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Popovici, Ioana, and Michael T French. 2013b. "Economic evaluation of substance abuse interventions: Overview of recent research findings and policy implications." In Addictions: A comprehensive guidebook, edited by Barbara S McCrady and Elizabeth E Epstein. Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Popovici, Ioana, Michael T French, and J. R. McKay. 2008. "Economic evaluation of continuing care interventions in the treatment of substance abuse: recommendations for future research." Evaluation Review 32 (6):547-68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Popovici, Ioana, Johanna Catherine Maclean, Bushra Hijazi, and Sharmini Radakrishnan. 2018. "The effect of state laws designed to prevent nonmedical prescription opioid use on overdose deaths and treatment." Health Economics 27 (2):294-305. doi: 10.1002/hec.3548.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Prendergast, Michael L, Deborah Podus, Eunice Chang, and Darren Urada. 2002. "The effectiveness of drug abuse treatment: A meta-analysis of comparison group studies." Drug and Alcohol Dependence 67 (1):53-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Rajkumar, Andrew S, and Michael T French. 1997. "Drug abuse, crime costs, and the economic benefits of treatment." Journal of Quantitative Criminology 13 (3):291-323.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Reuter, Peter, and Harold Pollack. 2006. "How much can treatment reduce national drug problems?" Addiction 101 (3):341-347.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Robinson, Gail K, Jerome B Connolly, Melanie Whitter, and Candy A Magana. 2006. State Mandates for Treatment for Mental Illness and Substance Abuse Disorders. Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Sabia, Joseph J, and Thanh Tam Nguyen. 2016. The Effect of Medical Marijuana Laws on Labor Market Outcomes. In Discussion Paper No. 9831 Bonn, Germany: IZA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Slater, Megan E, I-Jen P Castle, Barry K Logan, and Ralph W Hingson. 2016. "Differences in state drug testing and reporting by driver type in US fatal traffic crashes." Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention 92:122-129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Sommers, B. D., E. Arntson, G. M. Kenney, and A. M. Epstein. 2013. "Lessons from early Medicaid expansions under health reform: interviews with Medicaid officials." Medicare Medicaid Research Review 3 (4). doi: 10.5600/mmrr.003.04.a02.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Starr, Sonja B. 2002. "Simple fairness: ending discrimination in health insurance coverage of addiction treatment." The Yale Law Journal 111 (8):2321-2365.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <mixed-citation id="c62">Stewart, Duncan, Michael Gossop, and John Marsden. 2002. "Reductions in non-fatal overdose after drug misuse treatment: Results from the National Treatment Outcome Research Study (NTORS)." Journal of Substance Abuse Treatment 22 (1):1-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration. 2014. Results from the 2013 National Survey on Drug Use and Health: Summary of National Findings. In NSDUH Series H-48, edited by Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration. Rockville, MD.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration. 2016. Receipt of Services for Substance Use and Mental Health Issues among Adults: Results from the 2015 National Survey on Drug Use and Health.: Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r65">
            <mixed-citation id="c65">Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration. 2017. Key substance use and mental health indicators in the United States: Results from the 2016 National Survey on Drug Use and Health. Rockville, MD: Center for Behavioral Health Statistics and Quality, Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r66">
            <mixed-citation id="c66">Swensen, Isaac D. 2015. "Substance-abuse treatment and mortality." Journal of Public Economics 122:13-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r67">
            <mixed-citation id="c67">Terán-Santos, J., A. Jimenez-Gomez, and J. Cordero-Guevara. 1999. "The association between sleep apnea and the risk of traffic accidents." New England Journal of Medicine 340 (11):847-851.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r68">
            <mixed-citation id="c68">Thalmayer, Amber Gayle, Sarah A Friedman, Francisca Azocar, Jessica M Harwood, and Susan L Ettner. 2016. "The Mental Health Parity and Addiction Equity Act (MHPAEA) evaluation study: Impact on quantitative treatment limits." Psychiatric Services 68 (5):435-442.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r69">
            <mixed-citation id="c69">United States Environmental Protection Agency. 2018. "Mortality Risk Valuation." https://www.epa.gov/environmental-economics/mortality-risk-valuation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r70">
            <mixed-citation id="c70">Wen, Hefei, J. R. Cummings, J. M. Hockenberry, L. M. Gaydos, and B. G. Druss. 2013. "State parity laws and access to treatment for substance use disorder in the United States: Implications for federal parity legislation." JAMA Psychiatry 70 (12):1355-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r71">
            <mixed-citation id="c71">Wen, Hefei, Jason M Hockenberry, and Janet R Cummings. 2017. "The effect of Medicaid expansion on crime reduction: Evidence from HIFA-waiver expansions." Journal of Public Economics 154:67-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r72">
            <mixed-citation id="c72">Zaloshnja, Eduard, Ted R Miller, and Lawrence J Blincoe. 2013. "Costs of alcohol-involved crashes, United States, 2010." Annals of Advances in Automotive Medicine 57:3-12.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>States that passed a parity law during the study period: 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Descriptive statistics for the full sample and by type of parity law, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Effects of state parity laws for SUD treatment on traffic fatality rates using an event study model, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Effects of lagged parity laws for SUD treatment on traffic fatality rates, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5.</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Effects of state parity laws for SUD treatment on alcohol poisoning and drug overdose death rate, NVSM 1999-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6.</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Effects of state parity laws for SUD treatment on insurance status, Annual Social and Economic Supplement to the Current Population Survey, 1988-2012</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7.</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Effects of state parity laws for specialty SUD treatment on SUD facility rate, County Business Patterns, 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Effects of lagged parity laws for SUD treatment on traffic fatality rates, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Effects of state parity laws for SUD treatment on traffic fatality rates using the contemporaneous parity law, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Effects of lagged parity laws for SUD treatment on traffic fatality rates using event study sample, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Effects of lagged parity laws for SUD treatment on traffic fatality rates assigning the date of January 1<sup>st</sup> of the implementation year for states with unavailable implementation dates, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 5.</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Effects of lagged parity laws for SUD treatment on traffic fatality rates using division by year fixed effects, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Effect of state parity laws for SUD treatment on total traffic fatality rates using an event study, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Effect of state parity laws for SUD treatment on BAC &gt;= 0.08 traffic fatality rates using an event study, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Effect of state parity laws for SUD treatment on BAC &gt;= 0.15 traffic fatality rates using an event study, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Effect of state parity laws for SUD treatment on total traffic fatality rates using a placebo simulation exercise, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5.</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Effect of state parity laws for SUD treatment on BAC &gt;= 0.08 traffic fatality rates using a placebo simulation exercise, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6.</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Effect of state parity laws for SUD treatment on BAC &gt;= 0.15 traffic fatality rates using a placebo simulation exercise, FARS 1988-2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
