<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277810</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Improving the Understanding of Intake and Charge Effects for Increasing RCCI Engine Efficiency</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Splitter</surname>
                  <given-names>Derek</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wissink</surname>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>DelVescovo</surname>
                  <given-names>Dan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Rolf</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Wisconsin</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277784</issue-id>
         <fpage>913</fpage>
         <lpage>927</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277810"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The present experimental engine efficiency study explores the effects of intake pressure and temperature, and premixed and global equivalence ratios on gross thermal efficiency (GTE) using the reactivity controlled compression ignition (RCCI) combustion strategy. Experiments were conducted in a heavy-duty single-cylinder engine at constant net load (IMEP<sub>n</sub>) of 8.45 bar, 1300 rev/min engine speed, with 0% EGR, and a 50% mass fraction burned combustion phasing (CA50) of 0.5°CA ATDC. The engine was port fueled with E85 for the low reactivity fuel and direct injected with 3.5% 2-ethylhexyl nitrate (EHN) doped into 91 anti-knock index (AKI) gasoline for the high-reactivity fuel. The resulting reactivity of the enhanced fuel corresponds to an AKI of approximately 56 and a cetane number of approximately 28.</p>
            <p>The engine was operated with a wide range of intake pressures and temperatures, and the ratio of low- to high-reactivity fuel was adjusted to maintain a fixed speed-phasing-load condition. This allowed for the investigation of several combinations of intake temperature, intake pressure, and charge stratification at otherwise constant thermodynamic conditions. The results show that sources of engine inefficiency compete as functions of premixed and global equivalence ratios. Losses are minimized through proper balancing of intake pressure and temperature, such that the global equivalence ratio (Φ<sub>global</sub>) is as lean as possible without overly lean regions of the stratified charge causing an increase in incomplete combustion. The explored speed-load-phasing combination shows that losses are minimized at conditions where approximately 2/3 of the fuel is fully premixed. The results exhibit a pathway for achieving simultaneous increases in combustion and fuel efficiency through proper fuel reactivity and initial condition management.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sellnau, M., Sinnamon, J., Hoyer, K., Kim, J. et al., “Part- Load Operation of Gasoline Direct-Injection Compression Ignition (GDCI) Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0272, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0272.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Zander, C., Johansson, B., Tunestal, P. et al., “An Advanced Internal Combustion Engine Concept for Low Emissions and High Efficiency from Idle to Max Load Using Gasoline Partially Premixed Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2198, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2198.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alger, T., Mangold, B., Roberts, C., and Gingrich, J., “The Interaction of Fuel Anti-Knock Index and Cooled EGR on Engine Performance and Efficiency,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1229-1241, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Experiments and Modeling of Dual-Fuel HCCI and PCCI Combustion Using In-Cylinder Fuel Blending,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):24-39, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2647.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Reitz, R., Splitter, D., and Musculus, M., “Investigation of Fuel Reactivity Stratification for Controlling PCI Heat-Release Rates Using High-Speed Chemiluminescence Imaging and Fuel Tracer Fluorescence,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):248-269, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0375.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R. and Reitz, R., “Transient RCCI Operation in a Light- Duty Multi-Cylinder Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(3):1694-1705, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0050.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., and Reitz, R., “Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Heavy-Duty Engine Operation at Mid-and High-Loads with Conventional and Alternative Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0363, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0363.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter D.A., Wissink M.L., Hendricks T.L., Ghandhi J.B., and Reitz R.D., “Comparison of RCCI, HCCI, and CDC Operation from Low to Full Load”, THIESEL 2012 Conference on Thermo- and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Direct Injection Engines, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, S.J., Hanson R.M., Wagner R.M., “Reactivity controlled compression ignition combustion on a multi-cylinder light-duty diesel engine.” International Journal of Engine Research 13, no. 3 (2012): 216-225.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Szybist, J.P., Kalyana C., and Daw C.S., “Analysis of the impact of selected fuel thermochemical properties on internal combustion engine efficiency.” Energy &amp; Fuels 26, no. 5 (2012): 2798-2810.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caton J.A., “On the destruction of availability (exergy) due to combustion processes -with specific application to internalcombustion engines”, Energy, Volume 25, Issue 11, November 2000, Pages 1097-1117, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caton J.A. “A Review of Investigations Using the Second Law of Thermodynamics to Study Internal- Combustion Engines” SAE Transactions 2000, vol. 109, no. 3, pp.1252-1266, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saxena, S, Shah N., Bedoya I., and Phadke A., “Understanding optimal engine operating strategies for gasoline-fueled HCCI engines using crank-angle resolved exergy analysis.” Applied Energy 114 (2014): 155-163.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos C.D., and Giakoumis E.G., “Second-law analyses applied to internal combustion engines operation” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science volume 32, pages 2-47, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hendricks TL, Splitter DA, Ghandhi JB., “Experimental investigation of piston heat transfer under conventional diesel and reactivity controlled compression ignition combustion regimes.” International Journal of Engine Research, 2014, doi:10.1177/1468087413512310.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S. L., Hanson R. M. Splitter D. A. and Reitz R. D.. “Fuel reactivity controlled compression ignition (RCCI): a pathway to controlled high-efficiency clean combustion.” International Journal of Engine Research 12, no. 3 (2011): 209-226.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edo, T., and Foster, D.E., VI International Symposium on Alcohol Fuels Technology, Ottawa Canada, 1984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Foster D.E., “Low Temperature Combustion- A Thermodynamic Pathway to High Efficiency Engines”, National Petroleum Council Fuels Study, prepared March 2012, http://www.npc.org/FTF_Topic_papers/6-Low_Temperature_Combustion.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edwards D., “Defining Engine Efficiency Limits”, 17 annual Directions in Engine-Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER) conference presentation, presented October 5, 2011, available at http://www1.eere.energy.gov/vehiclesandfuels/pdfs/deer_2011/wednesday/presentations/deer11_edwards.pdf, accessed Nov 15, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lavoie, George A., Ortiz-Soto Elliott, Babajimopoulos Aristotelis, Martz Jason B., and Assanis Dennis N.. “Thermodynamic sweet spot for high-efficiency, dilute, boosted gasoline engines.” International Journal of Engine Research 14, no. 3 (2013): 260- 278.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng J.A., “Characterization of pressure waves in HCCI combustion”, SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wissink, M., Wang, Z., Splitter, D., Shahlari, A. et al., “Investigation of Pressure Oscillation Modes and Audible Noise in RCCI, HCCI, and CDC,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1652, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1652.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Syrimis, M., Shigahara, K., and Assanis, D., “Correlation Between Knock Intensity and Heat Transfer Under Light and Heavy Knocking Conditions in a Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 960495, 1996, doi:10.4271/960495.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu, J., Ezekoye, D., Iiyama, A., Greif, R. et al., “Effect of Knock on Time-Resolved Engine Heat Transfer,” SAE Technical Paper 890158, 1989, doi:10.4271/890158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grandin, B., Denbratt, I., Bood, J., Brackmann, C. et al., “The Effect of Knock on the Heat Transfer in an SI Engine: Thermal Boundary Layer Investigation using CARS Temperature Measurements and Heat Flux Measurements,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2831, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-2831.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turns, S.R., “An introduction to combustion: Concepts and Applications”, New York, McGraw-Hill inc., 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus M.P., Miles P.C., and Pickett L.M., “Conceptual models for partially premixed low-temperature diesel combustion.” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science (2013).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Yang, Y., “Boosted HCCI for High Power without Engine Knock and with Ultra-Low NOx Emissions - using Conventional Gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):750-767, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjoberg, M. and Dec, J., “Ethanol Autoignition Characteristics and HCCI Performance for Wide Ranges of Engine Speed, Load and Boost,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):84-106, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010- 01-0338.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehl, M., Pitz, W., Sarathy, M., Yang, Y. et al., “Detailed Kinetic Modeling of Conventional Gasoline at Highly Boosted Conditions and the Associated Intermediate Temperature Heat Release,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1109, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1109.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Kokjohn, S., Rein, K., Hanson, R. et al., “An Optical Investigation of Ignition Processes in Fuel Reactivity Controlled PCCI Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):142-162, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0345.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A., Walker, N., and Reitz, R., “Effect of Cetane Improvers on Gasoline, Ethanol, and Methanol Reactivity and the Implications for RCCI Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(1):170-187, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1678.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgens B, Siebers D., Mueller C, and Aradil A., “Effects of an Ignition-Enhancing, Diesel-Fuel Additive on Diesel-Spray Evaporation, Mixing, Ignition, and Combustion”, Twenty-Seventh Symposium (International) on Combustion/The Combustion Institute, 1998/pp. 1873-1880.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Reitz, R., and Hanson, R., “High Efficiency, Low Emissions RCCI Combustion by Use of a Fuel Additive,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(2):742-756, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2167.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Fuel Effects on Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Combustion at Low Load,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):394-411, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter D.A., and Reitz R.D. “Fuel reactivity effects on the efficiency and operational window of dual-fuel compression ignition engines.” Fuel 118 (2014): 163-175.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Wissink, M., Kokjohn, S., and Reitz, R., “Effect of Compression Ratio and Piston Geometry on RCCI Load Limits and Efficiency,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0383, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0383.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shahlari, A., Hocking, C., Kurtz, E., and Ghandhi, J., “Comparison of Compression Ignition Engine Noise Metrics in Low-Temperature Combustion Regimes,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):541-552, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1659.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kar, K. and Cheng, W., “Speciated Engine-Out Organic Gas Emissions from a PFI-SI Engine Operating on Ethanol/Gasoline Mixtures,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(2):91-101, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2673.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eyidogan M., Ozsezen A.N., Canakci M., Turkcan A., “Impact of alcohol-gasoline fuel blends on the performance and combustion characteristics of an SI engine”, Fuel, Volume 89, Issue 10, October 2010, Pages 2713-2720, ISSN 0016-2361, 10.1016/j.fuel.2010.01.032.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oxley J.C., Smith J.L., Rogers E., Ye W., Aradi A. A., and Henly T.J., “Heat-Release Behavior of Fuel Combustion Additives”, Energy &amp; Fuels 2001, 15, 1194-1199, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, Derek A. “High efficiency RCCI combustion.” PhD Thesis, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., “Auto-Ignition Quality of Practical Fuels and Implications for Fuel Requirements of Future SI and HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0239, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., Wissink, M. et al., “Injection Effects in Low Load RCCI Dual-Fuel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0047, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, S., Prikhodko, V., Cho, K., Sluder, C. et al., “In-Cylinder Fuel Blending of Gasoline/Diesel for Improved Efficiency and Lowest Possible Emissions on a Multi-Cylinder Light-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2206, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “An Experimental Investigation of Fuel Reactivity Controlled PCCI Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):700-716, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0864.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Wissink, M., DelVescovo, D., and Reitz, R., “RCCI Engine Operation Towards 60% Thermal Efficiency,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0279, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0279.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Milam D., “DOE Final Report DE-FC05-00OR22806 Heavy Truck Engine Program Final Report for Caterpillar/DOE Heavy Truck Clean Diesel Cooperative Research Program, DOE contract No. DE-FC05- 00OR22806”, Published March 31, 2007, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, John B. Internal combustion engine fundamentals. Vol. 930. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kar, K., Roberts, S., Stone, R., Oldfield, M. et al., “Instantaneous Exhaust Temperature Measurements Using Thermocouple Compensation Techniques,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1418, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1418.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoyer, K., Sellnau, M., Sinnamon, J., and Husted, H., “Boost System Development for Gasoline Direct-Injection Compression- Ignition (GDCI),” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):815-826, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0928.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edwards, K., Wagner, R., and Briggs, T., “Investigating Potential Light-duty Efficiency Improvements through Simulation of Turbocompounding and Waste-heat Recovery Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2209, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2209.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
