<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">ctbuhj</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016544</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CTBUH Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Council on Tall Buildings and Urban Habitat</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19461186</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19461194</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90021074</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Research</subject>
               <subj-group>
                  <subject>Structural Engineering</subject>
               </subj-group>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Applying Ancient Structural Principles To a New Prefabricated Steel System</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Yu</surname>
                  <given-names>Derry</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Derry Yu received his PhD from Kyoto University of Japan in 1992. He is a chartered structural engineer and project director with more than 25 years of experience in mixed-use, high-rise projects, in the fields of structural design, research, analysis, value engineering, and overall project management. He is familiar with several structural systems, including reinforced concrete and steel, and has rich experience in seismic analysis and design.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kong</surname>
                  <given-names>Ivan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Ivan Kong has been a chartered structural engineer in the United Kingdom since 2009 and a registered professional engineer (structural) in Hong Kong since 2011. Kong has a total of 14 years’ structural design and project management experience on mixed-use, hotel, office, and residential projects, in projects across China, Hong Kong, and the Middle East. He excels at both RC and steel structural design for severe wind and seismic load conditions.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Lu</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Michael Lu has been a China Class One Registered structural engineer since 2010, a China Registered geotechnical engineer since 2013, and a chartered structural engineer in the United Kingdom since 2015. Lu has nine years of structural design and project management experience. He has solid structural design experience on China’s high-rise and large-scale projects, including office, retail, hotel, and residential buildings, most of which exceed local code limits.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <aff>
               <addr-line>New World China Land Limited</addr-line>
               <addr-line>16/F, New World Tower 1</addr-line>
               <addr-line>18 Queen’s Road Central</addr-line>
               <addr-line>Hong Kong</addr-line>
               <addr-line>China</addr-line>
            </aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e90021065</issue-id>
         <fpage>36</fpage>
         <lpage>43</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2018 Council on Tall Buildings and Urban Habitat</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90021074"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Numerous ancient timber structures located in high seismic zones of China are still standing today, long after experiencing strong earthquakes over hundreds of years. One of the important factors in their longevity is the adoption of the mortise-andtenon joint as the main connection system. The seismic deformation and sliding friction between the tenons and mortises of timber structures can transfer and absorb seismic energy, such that timber structures exhibit excellent seismic performance. Based on the same concept, the authors propose applying a similar joint within a steel frame structure: a new prefabricated steel structure system that adopts connections similar to those of the mortise-and-tenon joints in timber structures.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>Mortise-and-Tenon Joint</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Seismic Performance</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Steel Structure</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Prefabrication</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Modularization</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Bolt/Weld-Less Installation</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Structural Steel Adhesive</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GAO, D. F.; H. T. ZHAO, and J. Y. XUE. 2008. Study on Chinese Ancient Timber Structure and its Seismic Performance. [In Chinese]. Beijing: China Science Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">YUE, Q. R. 2016. “Resolve the Excess Steel Production Capacity, and Promote the Building Construction Industrialization with Steel Structure.” [In Chinese]. China Economic Weekly 14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ZHANG, A. L. and Y. X. ZHANG. 2016. “Study and Overview of Critical Problems for the New System of Industrialized Prefabricated Tall Steel Structure.” [in Chinese]. Journal of Beijing University of Civil Engineering and Architecture 3: 21–8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ZHUANG, Y. G. and M. M. TANG. 2009. “Overcoming Hardness with Softness - Seismic Characteristics of Chinese Traditional Timber Structure.” [in Chinese]. Sichuan Cultural Relics 2: 88–90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ZHOU, Q., W. M. YAN, H. Z. GUAN, and J. B. JI. 2013. “Analysis of Aseismic Constitutions of Tai-he Palace in the Forbidden City.” [in Chinese]. Journal of Fuzhou University (Natural Science Edition) 4: 652–57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article> 

