<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284862</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Controlling Low-Speed Pre-Ignition in Modern Automotive Equipment Part 3</article-title>
            <subtitle>Identification of Key Additive Component Types and Other Lubricant Composition Effects on Low-Speed Pre-Ignition</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ritchie</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrew</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Boese</surname>
                  <given-names>Doyle</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Young</surname>
                  <given-names>Anne W.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Infineum USA LP</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>June 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284847</issue-id>
         <fpage>832</fpage>
         <lpage>840</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284862"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Market demand and evolving global legislation are forcing OEMs to improve fuel consumption and reduce CO₂ emissions. Downsizing in direct injection gasoline engines has been a common strategy towards achieving this goal, but this requires increased boost pressures to maintain power. The increased boost pressures are creating a new abnormal combustion phenomenon known as Low-Speed Pre-Ignition (LSPI).</p>
            <p>Lubricants and fuels have been implicated as significant influencers of LSPI frequency and intensity. Part 1 of the series described the development of a statistical approach for measuring and quantifying LSPI activity. This statistical approach was shown to be consistent and repeatable. Part 2 of the series further refined the methodology from Part 1 to reduce the frequency of false positives and negatives. A baseline lubricant was used in both of these papers to demonstrate the robustness of this methodology.</p>
            <p>This paper explores major lubricant components in order to assess their impact on LSPI activity as promoters, quenchers or having no effect (neutral) on LSPI based on this baseline lubricant, with a strong focus on the most common metal detergent cations used in modern automotive lubricants. It also raises concerns about using general LSPI prediction equations, particularly concerning their accuracy with poor quality fuels.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Welling, O., Collings, N., Williams, J., and Moss, J., "Impact of Lubricant Composition on Low-speed Pre-Ignition," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1213, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1213.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dingle, S., Cairns, A., Zhao, H., Williams, J. et al., "Lubricant Induced Pre-Ignition in an Optical SI Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01- 1222, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1222.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boese, D. and Ritchie, A., “Controlling low-speed pre-ignition in modern automotive equipment: Defining approaches to and methods for analyzing data in new studies of lubricant-and fuel-related effects.” Presentation at 20th International Colloquium Tribology, Germany, January 12-14, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boese, D., Ritchie, A. and Young, A., “Controlling low-speed preignition in modern automotive equipment: Defining approaches to and methods for analyzing data in new studies of lubricant-and fuel-related effects (Part 2).” Presentation at SAE World Congress, USA, April 12- 14, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miyamoto, N., Hou, Z., and Ogawa, H., "Catalytic Effects of Metallic Fuel Additives on Oxidation Characteristics of Trapped Diesel Soot," SAE Technical Paper 881224, 1988, doi:10.4271/881224.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zahdeh, A., Rothenberger, P., Nguyen, W., Anbarasu, M. et al., "Fundamental Approach to Investigate Pre-Ignition in Boosted SI Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):246-273, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0340.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takeuchi, K., Fujimoto, K., Hirano, S., and Yamashita, M., "Investigation of Engine Oil Effect on Abnormal Combustion in Turbocharged Direct Injection - Spark Ignition Engines," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(3):1017-1024, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1615.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hirano, S., Yamashita, M., Fujimoto, K., and Kato, K., "Investigation of Engine Oil Effect on Abnormal Combustion in Turbocharged Direct Injection - Spark Ignition Engines (Part 2)," SAE Technical Paper 2013- 01-2569, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2569.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Z., Liu, H., Song, T., Xu, Y. et al., "Investigation on Pre-ignition and Super-Knock in Highly Boosted Gasoline Direct Injection Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1212, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amann, M., Mehta, D., and Alger, T., "Engine Operating Condition and Gasoline Fuel Composition Effects on Low-Speed Pre-Ignition in High-Performance Spark Ignited Gasoline Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):274-285, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0342.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Y., Zheng, R., Qin, Y., Peng, J., Li, M., Lei, J., Wu, Y., Hu, M., and Shuai, S., “The impact of fuel compositions on the particulate emissions of direct injection gasoline engine.” Fuels, 166 (15): 543-552, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2015.11.019</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Onodera, K., Nemoto, S., Kato, T., Fujimoto, K. and Yamashita, M., Lubricating Oil Composition. WO 2015114920 A1, August 5, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fujimoto, K., Yamashita, M., Hirano, S., Kato, K. et al., "Engine Oil Development for Preventing Pre-Ignition in Turbocharged Gasoline Engine," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 7(3):869-874, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014- 01-2785.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Welling, O., Moss, J., Williams, J., and Collings, N., "Measuring the Impact of Engine Oils and Fuels on Low-Speed Pre-Ignition in Downsized Engines," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 7(1):1-8, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miyasaka, T., Miura, K., Hayakawa, N., Ishino, T. et al., "A Study on the Effect of a Calcium-Based Engine Oil Additive on Abnormal SI Engine Combustion," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(1):206-213, 2015, doi:10.4271/2014-32-0092.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hayakawa, N., Miura, K., Miyasaka, T., Ishino, T. et al., "A Study on the Effect of Zn- and Mo-Based Engine Oil Additives on Abnormal SI Engine Combustion using In-Cylinder Combustion Visualization," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(1):214-220, 2015, doi:10.4271/2014-32-0096.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tamura, K., Utaka, T., Kamano, H., Hayakawa, N. et al., "Abnormal Combustion Induced by Combustion Chamber Deposits Derived from Engine Oil Additives in a Spark-Ignited Engine," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(1):200-205, 2015, doi:10.4271/2014-32-0091.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mosier, P., Dietz, J. and Sammut, A., Lubricant compositions for direct injection engines. WO 2015042341 A1, March 26, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mosier, P., Dietz, J. and Sammut, A., Lubricant compositions for direct injection engines. WO 2015042337 A1, March 26, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Okada, Y., Miyashita, S., Izumi, Y., and Hayakawa, Y., "Study of Low-Speed Pre-Ignition in Boosted Spark Ignition Engine," SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):584-594, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1218.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ohtomo, M., Miyagawa, H., Koike, M., Yokoo, N. et al., "Pre-Ignition of Gasoline-Air Mixture Triggered by a Lubricant Oil Droplet," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 7(3):673-682, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2627.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goto, S., Moriya, K., Kosaka, H., Akita, T. et al., "Development of Free Piston Engine Linear Generator System Part 2 - Investigation of Control System for Generator," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1193, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
