<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023220</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Policymaking in the Face of Uncertainty</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>In Good Times and Bad</article-title>
            <subtitle>Designing Legislation That Responds to Fiscal Uncertainty</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kamin</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>
                  <addr-line>Assistant Professor of Law</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>New York University</addr-line>
               </aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>41</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023220"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Congress often moves slowly to change tax and spending laws when circumstances change, but there are ways to design legislation to anticipate and prevent the tendency towards “policy drift.”</p>
            <p>Enactment of major pieces of legislation tends to be followed by periods of legislative stasis, even when economic conditions change. Policies during the Great Recession are an example of this. The Great Recession proved significantly deeper than forecasters had predicted, when the American Recovery And Reinvestment Act was enacted, but as new information became available, Congress did little to alter the fiscal stimulus in response, other than to continue some expiring provisions.</p>
            <p>There are ways to design legislation to anticipate and prevent the tendency towards “policy drift.” This paper identifies four mechanisms: delegation of legislative authority to administrative agencies, triggers that either automatically adjust policy for changed circumstances or try to force an issue onto Congress’s agenda, expirations of legislation that sunset laws on a predetermined date, and indexing to adjust policy in discrete increments in response to changes in conditions.</p>
            <p>Each has its advantages and disadvantages, but on balance, triggers that automatically adjust policy to new circumstances tend to be most effective in preventing policy drift, particularly for countercyclical policy and Social Security. When economic conditions deteriorate, triggers could be in place that would automatically adjust levels of aid to states and federal infrastructure spending, provide tax cuts, and adjust the length of eligibility for unemployment benefits. In order to maintain the solvency of Social Security, benefits and taxes could be indexed to changes in estimates of the program’s solvency over 75 years. When there is a projected shortfall or surplus, the law could trigger adjustments in benefits and taxes to compensate.</p>
            <p>With respect to Medicare, a combination of indexing on the revenue side, and increased delegation on the spending side is recommended. Medicare revenues would be indexed to health cost growth through a combination of payroll taxes and income taxes in order to maintain the current mixed financing system. To keep payments in check, mechanisms like the Independent Payment Advisory Board could be expanded and strengthened.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J. 2012. “The Fall and Rise of Keynesian Fiscal Policy,” Asian Economic Policy Review 7, pp. 157–175.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J. 2014. “Fiscal Uncertainty and How to Deal With It.” Forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., and William G. Gale. 2009. “Activist Fiscal Policy to Stabilize Economic Activity,” Financial Stability and Macroeconomic Policy, Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City, pp. 327–374.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., and Ronald Lee. 2011. “Welfare and Generational Equity in Sustainable Unfunded Pension Systems.” Journal of Public Economics 95, pp. 16–27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barber, Michael, and Nolan McCarty. 2013. “Causes and Consequences of Polarization,” Negotiating Agreement in Politics, edited by Cathie Jo Martin and Jane Mansbridge. December 2013. American Political Science Association. https://www.apsanet.org/media/PDFs/Publications/Chapter2Mansbridge.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barron, David J., and Todd D. Rakoff. 2013. “In Defense of Big Waiver,” Columbia Law Review 113(2), pp. 265–345.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baumgartner, Frank R., and Bryan D. Jones. 2005. The Politics of Attention: How Government Prioritizes Problems. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blue Chip Economic Indicators. 2008. “Special Questions.” Aspen Publishers Vol. 33(12), 12/10/2008, p. 14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bosworth, Barry P., and R. Kent Weaver. 2011. “Social Security on Auto-Pilot: International Experience with Automatic Stabilizer Mechanisms,” Center for Retirement Research at Boston College. CRR WP 2011-18. http://crr.bc.edu/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/wp_2011-18-508.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Breunig, Christian. 2006. “The More Things Change, the More Things Stay the Same: A Comparative Analysis of Budget Punctuations,” Journal of European Public Policy 13, pp. 1069–1085.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brock, William A. 2006. “Tipping Points, Abrupt Opinion Changes, and Punctuated Policy Change,” Punctuated Equilibrium and the Dynamics of U.S. Environmental Policy, edited by Robert Repetto, pp. 47–77. New Haven: Yale University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cable News Network (CNN). 2010. CNN Opinion Research Poll, CNN Opinion Research Corporation. January 8–10. http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/2010/images/01/29/rel1j.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Committee for a Responsible Federal Budget (CRFB). 2014. “Actually the SGR Has Slowed Health Care Cost Growth: 98% of Doc Fixes Since 2004 Have Been Fully Paid For, Resulting in $140 Billion in Deficit Reduction,” March 13. http://crfb.org/blogs/actually-sgr-has-slowed-health-care-cost-growth.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Congressional Budget Office (CBO). 2009. “Budget and Economic Outlook: Fiscal Years 2009–2019, Additional Data.” January. http://www.cbo.gov/publication/41753.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Congressional Budget Office (CBO) 2012. “The 2012 Long-Term Budget Outlook.” June.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Congressional Budget Office (CBO) 2014a. “The 2014 Long-Term Budget Outlook.” July.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Congressional Budget Office (CBO) 2014b. “2014 CBO Long-Term Budget Outlook.” Supplemental Data. http://www.cbo.gov/publication/45308</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Congressional Budget Office (CBO) 2014c. “Estimated Impact of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act on Employment and Economic Output in 2013.” February. http://www.cbo.gov/sites/default/files/cbofiles/attachments/45122-ARRA.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Council of Economic Advisers (CEA). 1962. Economic Report of the President. January.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Council of Economic Advisers (CEA) 2014. “The Economic Impact of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act Five Years Later, Final Report to Congress.” February. http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/docs/cea_arra_report.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davis, Patricia A. 2014. “Medicare: Part B Premiums,” Congressional Research Service. March.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D’Addio, Anna Cristina, and Edward Whitehouse. 2012. “Towards Financial Sustainability of Pension Systems: The Role of Automatic-Adjustment Mechanisms in OECD and EU Countries,” Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diamond, Peter A., and Peter R. Orszag. 2004. Saving Social Security: A Balanced Approach. The Brookings Institution Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). 2014. Press Release: “EPA Proposes First Guidelines to Cut Carbon Pollution from Existing Power Plants/Clean Power Plan is Flexible Proposal to Ensure a Healthier Environment, Spur innovation and Strengthen the Economy.” June 2. http://yosemite.epa.gov/opa/admpress.nsf/bd4379a92ceceeac8525735900400c27/5bb6d20668b9a18485257ceb00490c98!OpenDocument</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jones, Bryan D., Tracy Sulkin, and Heather Larsen. 2003. “Policy Punctuations and American Political Institutions,” American Political Science Review 97: 151–70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gersen, Jacob. E. 2007. “Temporary Legislation,” University of Chicago Law Review 74: 247–298.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gilmour, John. 1995. Strategic Disagreement: Stalemate in American Politics. Pittsburg: University of Pittsburgh Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greenspan Commission on Social Security Reform. 1983. “Appendix C: Findings and Recommendations.” http://www.ssa.gov/history/reports/gspan5.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hahn, Jim. 2014a. “Medicare Physician Payment Updates and the Sustainable Growth Rate System,” Congressional Research Service (Report R40907).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hahn, Jim 2014b. “The Sustainable Growth Rate (SGR) and Medicare Physician Payments: Frequently Asked Questions,” Congressional Research Service (Report R43430).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hamilton, Alexander. 1787. Federalist No. 26 (Clinton Rossiter ed., 1961).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heffler, Stephen K., Todd G. Caldis, and Sheila D. Smith. 2014. “The Long-Term Projection Assumptions for Medicare and Aggregate National Health Expenditures,” Office of the Actuary, Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services. August 26. http://www.cms.gov/Research-Statistics-Data-and-Systems/Statistics-Trends-and-Reports/ReportsTrustFunds/Downloads/ProjectionMethodology2014.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Howlett, Michael, and Andrea Migone. 2011. “Charles Lindblom is alive and well and living In punctuated equilibrium land,” Policy and Society 30(1), pp. 53–62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jones, Jeffrey M. 2009. “Many Americans See Stimulus’ Costs, Not Benefits: Slim Majority Thinks it Would be Better to Spend Less on Stimulus.” Gallup. August 18. http://www.gallup.com/poll/122372/Americans-Stimulus-Costs-Not-Benefits.aspx</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klein, Ezra. 2011a. “Could this time have been different?” The Washinton Post. October 8. http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/post/could-this-time-have-been-different/2011/08/25/gIQAiJo0VL_blog.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klein, Ezra 2011b. “Larry Summers: ‘I think Keynes mistitled his book.’” The Washington Post. July 26. http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/post/larry-summers-i-think-keynes-mistitled-his-book/2011/07/11/gIQAzZd4aI_blog.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Logue, Kyle D., and James R. Hines, Jr. 2014. “Delegating Tax,” University of Michigan Law and Economics Research Paper No. 14-005. October 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Macey, Jonathan R. 1991. “Separated Powers and Positive Political Theory: The Tug of War Over Administrative Agencies,” Georgetown Law Journal 80, pp. 671–703.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matoon, Richard H., Vanessa Haleco-Meyer, and Taft Foster. 2010. “Improving the Impact of Federal Aid to the States,” Economic Perspectives, Chicago: Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McCubbins, Mathew D., and Thomas Schwartz. 1984. “Congressional Oversight Overlooked: Police Patrols Versus Fire Alarms,” American Journal of Political Science 28(1), pp. 165–179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McGarity, Thomas O. 1992. “Some Thoughts on ‘Deossifying’ the Rulemaking Process.” Duke Law Journal 41, pp. 1385–1462.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, Vic. 2007. “Stabilizing Medicaid Funding During Economic Downturns,” Georgetown University Health Policy Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nelson, Robert H. 2008. Review of Punctuated Equilibrium and the Dynamics of U.S. Environmental Policy, ed. Robert Repetto. The Independent Review. Spring. http://www.independent.org/publications/tir/article.asp?a=683.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Newport, Frank. 2009. “Obama Signs Stimulus Into Law With Majority Support: Support for Bill among American Public is Highly Partisan.” Gallup. February 17. http://www.gallup.com/poll/114691/Obama-Signs-Stimulus-Law-Majority-Support.aspx</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OASDI Board of Trustees. 1982. Annual Report of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance and Federal Disability Insurance Trust Funds, Social Security Administration.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OASDI Board of Trustees 1983. Annual Report of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance and Federal Disability Insurance Trust Funds, Social Security Administration.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OASDI Board of Trustees 2014. Annual Report of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance and Federal Disability Insurance Trust Funds, Social Security Administration.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Office of Management and Budget. 2013. “Analytical Perspectives, Budget of the United States Government, Fiscal Year 2014.” Available at http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/BUDGET-2014-PER/pdf/BUDGET-2014-PER.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Office of Management and Budget 2014. “Analytical Perspectives, Budget of the United States Government, Fiscal Year 2015.” http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/omb/budget/fy2015/assets/spec.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Orszag, Peter. 2013. “Critics are Wrong about the Medicare Payment Board.” Bloomberg View. July 30. http://www.bloombergview.com/articles/2013-07-30/critics-are-wrong-about-the-medicare-payment-board</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pierce, Jr., Richard J. 1995. “Seven Ways to Deossify Agency Rulemaking.” Admin. L. Rev. 47, pp. 59–95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruffing, Kathy A., and Paul N. Van de Water. 2014. “Congress Needs to Boost Disability Insurance Share of Payroll Tax by 2016: Traditional Step Would Avert Trust Fund Depletion, Benefit Cuts,” Center on Budget and Policy Priorities.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shuren, Jeffrey. 2001. “The Modern Regulatory Administrative State: A Response to Changing Circumstances.” Harvard Journal on Legislation 38, pp. 291–329.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taylor, John B. 2000. “Reassessing Discretionary Fiscal Policy,” Journal of Economic Perspectives 14, pp. 21–36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner, John A. 2009. “Social Security Financing: Automatic Adjustments to Restore Solvency,” Public Policy Institute, American Association of Retired Persons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van de Water, Paul N. 2010. “The Sustainable Growth Rate and Health Reform,” Center on Budget and Policy Priorities.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article> 

