<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277525</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Valve Profile Adaptation, Stratification, Boosting and 2-Stroke Strategies for Raising Loads of Gasoline HCCI Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dahl</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chalmers Univ. of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Denbratt</surname>
                  <given-names>Ingemar</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chalmers Univ of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>1033</fpage>
         <lpage>1045</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277525"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The development of high efficiency powertrains is a key objective for car manufacturers. One approach for improving the efficiency of gasoline engines is based on homogeneous charge compression ignition, HCCI, which provides higher efficiency than conventional strategies. However, HCCI is only currently viable at relatively low loads, primarily because at high loads it involves rapid combustion that generates pressure oscillations in the cylinder (ringing), and partly because it gives rise to relatively high NO<sub>X</sub>emissions.</p>
            <p>This paper describes studies aimed at increasing the viability of HCCI combustion at higher loads by using fully flexible valve trains, direct injection with charge stratification (SCCI), and intake air boosting. These approaches were complemented by using EGR to control NO<sub>X</sub>emissions by stoichiometric operation, which enables the use of a three-way catalyst. Experiments were carried out using a single-cylinder engine of passenger car size running on gasoline and controlled with negative valve overlap. By adapting the valve profiles (lift, duration and phasing) for high loads, a fuel saving of 3% at constant load or a load increase of 6% could be achieved for lean HCCI compared to those obtained using camshafts that were not adapted for high load operation. Further, using intake pressures up to 180 kPa provided almost linear increases in load for lean HCCI, stoichiometric HCCI and stoichiometric SCCI. However, lean SCCI did not profit from boosting because the charge became too lean and stratification lost its effect as a ringing inhibitor. At intake pressures exceeding 140 kPa, stoichiometric HCCI operation becomes redundant since NO<sub>X</sub>ceases to be a limiting factor.</p>
            <p>Additionally, promising results were obtained in initial tests of two-stroke operation, which yielded higher maximum loads, lower fuel consumption and lower NO<sub>X</sub>emissions than the other strategies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">European Commission (2011). “Reducing CO2 Emissions from Passenger Cars”. Available from http://ec.europa.eu/clima/policies/transport/vehicles/cars_en.htm (updated 9 December 2010; cited 24 May 2011).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Onishi, S., Jo, S., Shoda, K., Jo, P. et al., “Active Thermo-Atmosphere Combustion (ATAC) - A New Combustion Process for Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 790501, 1979, doi: 10.4271/790501.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noguchi, M., Tanaka, Y., Tanaka, T., and Takeuchi, Y., “A Study on Gasoline Engine Combustion by Observation of Intermediate Reactive Products during Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 790840, 1979, doi: 10.4271/790840.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Najt, P. and Foster, D., “Compression-Ignited Homogeneous Charge Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 830264, 1983, doi: 10.4271/830264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Willand, J., Nieberding, R., Vent, G., and Enderle, C., “The Knocking Syndrome - Its Cure and Its Potential,” SAE Technical Paper 982483, 1998, doi: 10.4271/982483.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Denbratt, I. “Method of Controlling the Process of Combustion in an Internal Combustion Engine with Means for Controlling the Engine Valves”. Volvo Car Corporation, Sweden, patent no. SE521782, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koopmans, L. and Denbratt, I., “A Four Stroke Camless Engine, Operated in Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Mode with Commercial Gasoline,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3610, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-3610.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahl, D., Denbratt, I., and Koopmans, L., “An Evaluation of Different Combustion Strategies for SI Engines in a Multi-Mode Combustion Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):324-335, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-0426.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McMahon, K., Selecman, C., Botzem, F., and Stablein, B., “Lean GDI Technology Cost and Adoption Forecast: The Impact of Ultra-Low Sulfur Gasoline Standards,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1226, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1226.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J., “Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahl, D., Andersson, M., Denbratt, I., “The Origin of Pressure Waves in High Load HCCI Combustion: A High-Speed Video Analysis”. Comb. Sci. Technol., Vol. 183, Iss. 11, pp. 1266-1281, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahl, D., and Denbratt, I., “HCCI/SCCI Load Limits and Stoichiometric Operation in a Multicylinder Naturally Aspirated Spark Ignition Engine Operated on Gasoline and E85”. Int. J. Eng. Res., 12(1), pp. 58-68, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Z., Wang, J., Shuai, S., and Ma, Q., “Effects of Spark Ignition and Stratified Charge on Gasoline HCCI Combustion With Direct Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0137, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-0137.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ozaki, J. and Iida, N., “Effect of Degree of Unmixedness on HCCI Combustion Based on Experiment and Numerical Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-32-0046, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-32-0046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, Y., Zhao, H., Brouzos, N., Ma, T. et al., “Effect of Injection Timing on Mixture and CAI Combustion in a GDI Engine with an Air-Assisted Injector,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0206, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berntsson, A. and Denbratt, I., “HCCI Combustion Using Charge Stratification for Combustion Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0210, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “Smoothing HCCI Heat-Release Rates Using Partial Fuel Stratification with Two-Stage Ignition Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0629, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0629.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J. E., Dronniou, N., Sjöberg, M., “Tailoring HCCI Heat- Release Rates With Partial Fuel Stratification: Comparison of Two- Stage and Single-Stage-Ignition Fuels”. Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, Volume 33, Issue 2, Pages 3047-3055, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., Yang, Y., and Dronniou, N., “Boosted HCCI - Controlling Pressure-Rise Rates for Performance Improvements using Partial Fuel Stratification with Conventional Gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1): 1169-1189, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0897.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Yang, Y., “Boosted HCCI for High Power without Engine Knock and with Ultra-Low NOx Emissions - using Conventional Gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):750-767, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-1086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yap, D., Wyszynski, M., Megaritis, A., and Xu, H., “Applying boosting to gasoline HCCI operation with residual gas trapping,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2121, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cairns, A. and Blaxill, H., “Lean Boost and External Exhaust Gas Recirculation for High Load Controlled Auto-Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3744, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3744.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johansson, T., Johansson, B., Tunestål, P., and Aulin, H., “HCCI Operating Range in a Turbo-charged Multi Cylinder Engine with WT and Spray-Guided DI,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0494, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0494.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
