<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90007062</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Turbine Power Production Sensitivity to Coastal Sheared and Turbulent Inflows</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Smith</surname>
                  <given-names>Jamie C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Carriveau</surname>
                  <given-names>Rupp</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ting</surname>
                  <given-names>David S-K</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Turbulence and Energy Laboratory, Ed Lumley Centre for Engineering Innovation, University of Windsor, Ontario, Canada</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>39</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e90007056</issue-id>
         <fpage>183</fpage>
         <lpage>191</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90007062"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Inflows with identical wind speeds at turbine hub height can generate varying amounts of power, depending on parameters such as vertical shear and turbulence intensity. At a commercial wind farm located in Southwestern Ontario off the shores of Lake Erie, the wind profile approaching a multi-megawatt horizontal-axis turbine has been characterized by a meteorological mast and then correlated with resulting power production across a range of hub height speeds. Using data collected over a six-month measurement campaign, inferences have been drawn on the sensitivity of turbine performance to sheared and turbulent inflows for both land and lake-influenced winds at the coastal site under study.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Electrotechnical Commission, IEC 61400-12-1 Wind Turbines - Part 12-1: Power Performance Measurements of Electricity Producing Wind Turbines, 1st edn., IEC, Geneva, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sumner, J. and Masson, C., Influence of Atmospheric Stability on Wind Turbine Power Performance Curves, Journal of Solar Energy Engineering, 2006, 128(4), 531–538.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Antoniou, I., Pedersen, S. M. and Enevoldsen, P. B., Wind Shear and Uncertainties in Power Curve Measurement and Wind Resources, Wind Engineering, 2010, 33(5), 449–468.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner, R., Courtney, M., Gottschall, J. and Lindelöw-Marsden, P., Accounting for the Speed Shear in Wind Turbine Power Performance Measurement, Wind Energy, 2011, 14(8), 993–1004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner, R., Antoniou, I., Pedersen, S. M., Courtney, M. S. and Jørgensen, H. E., The Influence of the Wind Speed Profile on Wind Turbine Performance Measurements, Wind Energy, 2009, 12(4), 348–362.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner, R., Jørgensen, H. E., Paulsen, U. S., Larsen, T. J., Antoniou, I. and Thesbjerg, L., Remote Sensing Used for Power Curves, 14th Interntational Symposium for the Advancement of Boundary Layer Remote Sensing, IOP, Copenhagen, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Frehlich, R. and Kelley, N., Measurements of Wind and Turbulence Profiles with Scanning Doppler Lidar for Wind Energy Applications, IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing, 2008, 1(1), 42–47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barber, S., Chokani, N. and Abhari, R. S., Assessment of Wind Turbine Performance in Alpine Environments, Wind Engineering, 2011, 35(3), 313–328.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pasquill, F., The Estimation of the Dispersion of Windborne Material, The Meteorological Magazine, 1961, 90, 33–49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wharton, S. and Lundquist, J. K., Assessing Atmospheric Stability and its Impacts on Rotor-Disk Wind Characteristics at an Offshore Wind Farm, Wind Energy, 2012, 15(4), 525–546.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Banta, R. M., Pichugina, Y. L., Kelley, N. D., Jonkman, B. and Brewer, W. A., Doppler Lidar Measurements of the Great Plains Low-Level Jet: Applications to Wind Energy, 14th International Symposium for the Advancement of Boundary Layer Remote Sensing, IOP, Copenhagen, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rohatgi, J. and Barbezier, G., Wind Turbulence and Atmospheric Stability - Their Effect on Wind Turbine Output, Renewable Energy, 1999, 16, 908–911.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rareshide, E., Tindal, A., Johnson, C., Graves, A. M., Simpson, E., Bleeg, J., Harris, T. and Schoborg, D., Effects of Complex Wind Regimes on Turbine Performance, Proceedings of the AWEA WINDPOWER 2009 Conference, AWEA, Chicago, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vanderwende, B. J. and Lundquist, J. K., The Modification of Wind Turbine Performance by Statistically Distinct Atmospheric Regimes, Environmental Research Letters, 2012, 7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>[15]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wharton, S. and Lundquist, J. K., Atmospheric Stability Affects Wind Turbine Power Collection, Environmental Research Letters, 2012, 7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>[16]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Independent Electricity System Operator, Wind Power Generation in Ontario, April 10 2014, https://www.ieso.ca/imoweb/siteShared/windtracker.asp?sid=ic.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>[17]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McKay, P., Carriveau, R. and Ting, D. S-K., Wake Impacts on Downstream Wind Turbine Performance and Yaw Alignment, Wind Energy, 2013, 16(2), 221–234.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>[18]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sutton, O. G., Atmospheric Turbulence, Methuen &amp; Co., London, 1949.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>[19]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burton, T., Sharpe, D., Jenkins, N. and Bossanyi, E., Wind Energy Handbook, John Wiley &amp; Sons, Chicester, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>[20]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Electrotechnical Commission, IEC 61400-1 Wind Turbines - Part 1: Design Requirements, 3rd edn., IEC, Geneva, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>[21]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van den Berg, G. P., Wind Turbine Power and Sound in Relation to Atmospheric Stability, Wind Energy, 2008, 11(2), 151–169.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>[22]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">National Instruments, Wind Turbine Control Methods, Austin, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
