<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278020</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Study on a Versatile Liquid Dosing Device for IC Engine After-Treatment System</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yang</surname>
                  <given-names>Yanxiang</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tianjin Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tan</surname>
                  <given-names>Bingqian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tianjin Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Liu</surname>
                  <given-names>Changwen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tianjin Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
                  <given-names>Ping</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Zhejiang Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Xi</surname>
                  <given-names>Daguang</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Zhejiang FAI Electronics Co. Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>June 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277995</issue-id>
         <fpage>1207</fpage>
         <lpage>1218</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278020"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A versatile liquid dosing device along with its metering theory, which can be applied to both SCR dosing system and DPF regeneration system of IC engine after-treatment system, is presented in this paper. The device is composed of a solenoid driven plunger pump, a nozzle and a pressure tube, and is pump-end controlled by PWM signals. Both electrically resistive and conductive liquids including DEF for SCR system, fuel for DPF regeneration, and gasoline for spark ignition engine, can be dispensed quantitatively with this device.</p>
            <p>A metering theory determining the liquid discharged per injection is developed by studying the system using a physical-mathematical model. The study shows that the liquid discharge can be well correlated with a measurable variable<italic>T3</italic>, which is associated with the net output energy. Experimental investigations verified that the metering results were independent of the state changes. The developed device was able to work at a frequency from 0 to 80Hz with largest dosing range of 0 to14 L/h at 24 volt.</p>
            <p>The liquid dosing device was applied and tested on a SCR system as a verification example. The pump was so compact that it could be located at the bottom inside the DEF tank, which greatly simplified the anti-freeze design consideration and the SCR system. Tested results on a diesel engine with the SCR system showed good capability to reduce the engine NOx emission with high maximal NOx conversion rate and good controllability to achieve a NOx emission target with high reliability and high DEF efficiency.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skaf, Z., Aliyev, T., Shead, L., and Steffen, T., “The State of the Art in Selective Catalytic Reduction Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01- 1533, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1533.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skovgaard, M. and Babu, K., “Application Experiences with Current Generations of SCR Dosing Systems in Euro 4, 5 and 6,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-28-0027, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-28-0027.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Willems, F., Cloudt, R., van den Eijnden, E., van Genderen, M. et al., “Is Closed-Loop SCR Control Required to Meet Future Emission Targets?,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1574, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1574.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dimopoulos Eggenschwiler, P., Schreiber, D., and Liati, A., “Active Regeneration Characteristics in Diesel Particulate Filters (DPFs),” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0185, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0185.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, N., Rutland, C., Foster, D., Narayanaswamy, K. et al., “Investigation into Different DPF Regeneration Strategies Based on Fuel Economy Using Integrated System Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1275, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cordtz, R., Ivarsson, A., and Schramm, J., “Steady State Investigations of DPF Soot Burn Rates and DPF Modeling,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0181, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0181.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bosch, “Automotive Handbook”, ISBN 978-0-7680-1953-7, Published by Robert Bosch GmbH, 7th Edition, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, McGraw Hill, Inc. 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Needham, D., Spadafora, P., and Schiffgens, H.J., “Delphi SCR Dosing System - An alternative approach for close-coupled SCR catalyst systems”, SIA Diesel International Conference, Rouen, June 2012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shovel, M. L., et al, “Reductant injection control system”, United States Patent 8635854, 2014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, J. and Richardson, A., “Study of Vapor Generation from Fuel System Components,” SAE Technical Paper 952788, 1995, doi:10.4271/952788.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fitzgerald A.E., Kingsley Charles, Jr. and Umans Stephen D., “Electric Machinery (sixth edition)”, McGraw-Hill, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hayakawa, Kunihiko (Odawara, JP), “Fuel injection control method and fuel-injection control device”, United States Patent 7273038, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">China Standard GB17691-2005 “Limits and measurement methods for exhaust pollutants from compression ignition and gas fueled positive ignition engines of vehicles (III, IV, V)”, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
