<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">35</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186156</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44429112</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Automobile Headlamp Problem</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>P. J.</given-names>
                  <surname>Kent</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1940</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>229</fpage>
         <lpage>232</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44429112"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>MR. KENT points out that there are two distinct phases involved in the headlamp problem — the engineering phase and the maintenance and usage phase. He presents evidence to show that the maintenance and usage phase has been neglected and urges the automotive industry and motor-vehicle manufacturers to concentrate more effort on the solution of these problems. Other important phases of the problem discussed by Mr. Kent are the aiming of the beam and that of attempting to "divorce the objectionable property of glare from the desirable property of illumination." Early in this paper the development of the sealed-beam headlighting system is reviewed. The following three improvements in automobile electrical systems are claimed for this system: 1. Almost universal adoption of the shunt-type voltage-regulated generator with sufficient capacity to carry the full lighting and accessory load without drawing current from the battery. 2. Improvement in car wiring through simplification and larger cables in the headlamp and battery-charging circuits. 3. Improvement in headlamp and beam-control switches through the use of silver contacts. In conclusion, the possibilities of polarization are appraised, and the problems that must be solved before this system could be applied to automobile headlighting are set forth.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


