<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169240</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Tradeoffs in the Evaluation of Light Vehicle Pre-Collision Systems</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>LeBlanc</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Michigan - UMTRI</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gilbert</surname>
                  <given-names>Mark</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Michigan - UMTRI</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Stachowski</surname>
                  <given-names>Stephen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Michigan - UMTRI</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sherony</surname>
                  <given-names>Rini</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Motor Engineering &amp; Mfg NA Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>April 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169238</issue-id>
         <fpage>8</fpage>
         <lpage>19</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169240"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Pre-collision systems (PCS) use forward-looking sensors to detect the location and motion of vehicles ahead and provide a sequence of actions to help the driver either avoid striking the rear-end of another vehicle or mitigate the severity of the crash. The actions include driver alerts, amplification of driver braking as distance decreases (dynamic brake support, DBS), and automatic braking if the driver has not acted or has not acted sufficiently (crash imminent braking, CIB).</p>
            <p>Recent efforts by various organizations have sought to define PCS objective test procedures and test equipment in support of consumer information programs and potential certification. This paper presents results and insights from conducting DBS and CIB tests on two production vehicles sold in the US. Eleven scenarios are used to assess the systems' performance. The two systems' performance shows that commercial systems can be quite different. Also demonstrated is the experience with test equipment, including a towable target that has been designed for resiliency and radar signature, a braking robot, and bumper guard.</p>
            <p>While improvements continue in evaluation procedures, the community may still be a distance away from an ability to test these systems with realistic surrogate targets in speed conditions similar to those that lead to serious injury and fatalities. Recommendations are offered to help improve PCS evaluation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LeBlanc, D., Gilbert, M., Stachowski, S., Blower, D., Flannagan, C., Karamihas, S., Buller, W. T., and Sherony, R, “Advanced surrogate target development for evaluating pre-collision systems.” Proceedings of 23rd International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles (ESV), Seoul, Korea, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA): Dynamic Brake Support System Performance Evaluation, June 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA): Crash Imminent Braking System Performance Evaluation, June 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Crash Avoidance Metrics Partnership (2010). Crash imminent braking (CIB) second annual report. US Department of Transportation report DOT HS 811 341, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aoki, H., Aga, M., Miichi, Y., Matsuo, Y. et al., “Safety Impact Methodology (SIM) for Effectiveness Estimation of a Pre- Collision System (PCS) by Utilizing Driving Simulator Test and EDR Data Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1003, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kusano K. D. and Gabler H. C. (2012). “Safety Benefits of Forward Collision Warning, Brake Assist, and Autonomous Braking Systems in Rear-end Collisions”, IEEE Transactions - Intelligent Transportation Systems, 13(4), pp. 1546-1555.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buller, W., Wilson, B., van Nieuwstadt, L. Ebling, J., Sherony, R., and LeBlanc, D. “Radar scattering design elements for a precollision system surrogate target.” Proc. IEEE 77th Vehicular Technology Conference, Dresden, Germany, June 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sayer, J., Bogard, S., Buonarosa, M. L., LeBlanc, D., Funkhouser, D., Bao, S., Blankespoor, A., and Winkler, C. (2010). Integrated Vehicle-Based Safety Systems Light- Vehicle Field Operational Test, Key Findings Report. Report DOT HS 811 416, U.S. Department of Transportation, Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aparicio, A., Lesemann, M., and Eriksson, H., “Status of Test Methods for Autonomous Emergency Braking Systems - Results from the Active Test Project,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0725, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0725.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Insurance Institute for Highway Safety, “Comments on Research Report: Advanced Braking Technologies that Rely on Forward- Looking Sensors. US Docket No. NHTSA-2012-0057, September 2012/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
