<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">17</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830341</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830349</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE INSTITUTIONAL FRAMEWORK AND PUBLIC FINANCE IN DEVELOPING COUNTRIES: THE AFRICAN CASE / STRUCTURE POLITIQUE ET FINANCES PUBLIQUES DANS LES PAYS EN VOIE DE DEVELOPPEMENT: LE CAS DE L'AFRIQUE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>John Mukum</given-names>
                  <surname>Mbaku</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1993</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>319</fpage>
         <lpage>330</lpage>
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830349"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Since the 1970s, the level of external borrowing by developing countries, especially those in Africa, has risen significantly. Researchers have become interested in examining the impact of the institutional framework on the ability of governments to borrow externally. In 1988, Anderson found preliminary evidence to support the hypothesis that political democracy constraints the ability of governments to raise their external debt levels. The present study uses data from Africa to test the hypothesis that the institutional framework has a significant effect on the ability of governments to increase their national debt levels. The results show that there is preliminary evidence of a significantly strong negative relationship between increasing levels of political democracy in Africa and the ability of continental governments to raise levels of public debt. African dictators appear better able to increase their national debt levels than governments in countries in which there are greater levels of political democracy. Depuis les années 70 le taux d'emprunt externe a considérablement augmenté dans les pays en voie de développement, surtout dans les pays africains. Les spécialistes cherchent de plus en plus à cemer le lien qui pourrait exister entre le système gouvernemental et le penchant vers les prêts de l'extérieur. En 1988, Anderson a trouvé de l'évidence soutenant l'hypothèse que sur le plan politique, la démocratie apporte des restrictions à la tendance à accumuler des dettes externes de la part des gouvernements. Notre analyse se sert des données touchant à l'Afrique pour démontrer qu'il y a en effet un tien assez étroit entre la démocratisation et la limitation des dettes nationales. Les gouvernements dictatures africains semblent plus libres à contracter des dettes tandis que cette tendance va en décroissant plus un pays est démocratisé.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d29e135a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e139" publication-type="other">
Anderson, G.M. (1988). Public finance in autocratic process: An empirical note. Public Choice 57: 25-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e146a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e150" publication-type="other">
Auster, R.D., and Silver, M. (1979). The state as a firm. Boston: Martinus Nijhoff.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e157a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e161" publication-type="other">
Balkan, E.M. (1988). Country risk, probability of default and optimal lending. Unpublished doctoral dissertation.
State University of New York at Binghamton.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e171a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e175" publication-type="other">
Balkan, E.M., and Greene, K.V. (1990). On democracy and debt. Public Choice 67: 201-211.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e183a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e187" publication-type="other">
Bollen, K.A. (1980). Issues in the comparative measurement of political democracy. American Sociological Review
45: 370-390.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e197a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e201" publication-type="other">
Bollen, K.A. (1983). World system position, dependency, and democracy: The cross-national evidence. American
Sociological Review 48: 468-479.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e211a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e215" publication-type="other">
Bollen, K.A. (1991). Liberal democracy: Validity and source biases in cross-national measures. Working paper,
Department of Sociology, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e225a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e229" publication-type="other">
Bollen, K.A., and Grandjean, B.D. (1981). The dimension(s) of democracy: Further issues in the measurement
and effects of political democracy. American Sociological Review 46: 651-659.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e239a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e243" publication-type="other">
Brennan, G., and Buchanan, J.M. (1980). The power to tax: Analytical foundations of a fiscal constitution. New
York: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e253a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e257" publication-type="other">
Brough, W.T., and Kimenyi, M.S. (1986). On the inefficient extraction of rents by dictators. PublicChoice 48:37-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e265a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e269" publication-type="other">
Hayek, F.A. von. (1960). The constitution of libery. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e276a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e280" publication-type="other">
Kurian, G.T. (1984). The new book of world rankings. New York: Facts on File, Inc.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e287a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e291" publication-type="other">
Laband, D.N. (1984). Is there a relationship between economic conditions and political pressure? Public Choice
42: 25-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e301a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e305" publication-type="other">
Muller, E.N. (1988). Democracy, economic development, and income inequality. American Sociological Review
53: 50-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e319" publication-type="other">
Scully, G.W. (1988). The institutional framework and economic development. Journal of Political Economy 96
(3): 652-662.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e329a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e333" publication-type="other">
Tullock, G. (1986). Autocracy. Boston: Martinus Nijhoff.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e341a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e345" publication-type="other">
United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency. (1984). World military expenditures and arms transfers,
1972-1982. Washington, D.C.: U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e355a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e359" publication-type="other">
World Bank. (1983). World development report, 1983. New York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e366a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e370" publication-type="other">
World Bank. (1983). World Tables, 1983. Baltimore: The Johns Hopkins University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e377a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e381" publication-type="other">
World Bank. (1984). World development report, 1984. New York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e388a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e392" publication-type="other">
World Bank. World tables, 1988-89. New York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


