<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275402</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Shift in Relevance of Fuel RON and MON to Knock Onset in Modern SI Engines Over the Last 70 Years</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mittal</surname>
                  <given-names>Vikram</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Heywood</surname>
                  <given-names>John B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Sloan Automotive Laboratory, Massachusetts Institute of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275401</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>10</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275402"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Since the advent of the spark ignition engine, the maximum engine efficiency has been knock limited. Knock is a phenomena caused by the rapid autoignition of fuel/air mixture (endgas) ahead of the flame front. The propensity of a fuel to autoignite corresponds to its autoignition chemistry at the local endgas temperature and pressure. Since a fuel blend consists of many components, its autoignition chemistry is very complex.</p>
            <p>The octane index (OI) simplifies this complex autoignition chemistry by comparing a fuel to a Primary Reference Fuel (PRF), a binary blend of iso-octane and n-heptane. As more iso-octane is added into the blend, the PRF is less likely to autoignite. The OI of a fuel is defined as the volumetric percentage of iso-octane in the PRF blend that exhibits similar knocking characteristics at the same engine conditions.</p>
            <p>Since the OI is dependent on the engine operating conditions, it is typically measured at two standard test conditions: the Research and Motor Octane Number (RON and MON) tests. These tests are intended to bracket the knock-limited operating range, and the OI is taken to be a weighted average of RON and MON:</p>
            <p>OI = K MON + (1-K) RON = RON – KS</p>
            <p>where K is the weighing factor and S is the fuel sensitivity (RON-MON). When the tests were established in 1932, the MON test matched the OI on the road, hence the average value of K was 1; however, recent studies have found that the average value of K is negative.</p>
            <p>The parameter K, which is independent of a fuel, can be used to show the relevancy of the RON and MON tests. When K = 0.5, the average of the RON and MON tests is a good indicator of a fuel’s antiknock performance. However, when K is negative, for a given RON, fuels with a higher sensitivity have better antiknock performance; therefore, an increase in RON or MON does not necessarily correlate to better antiknock performance.</p>
            <p>In the decades following the development of the octane number, tests were performed to determine the value of K. However, as K approached a value of 0.5, these tests ceased to be performed.</p>
            <p>The Coordinated Research Council (CRC) collected data from 1951 to 1991 to determine the required fuel octane number to avoid fleet vehicles from knocking. The tests typically included both PRFs and reference fuels representative of commercial gasoline, the latter having a non-zero sensitivity. Therefore, a value of K can be determined for each test. Using the data from 1951, 1961, 1971, 1981, and 1991, the average values of K were found for each year.</p>
            <p>The study then explores the changes in the engine operating conditions that would cause these changes. To better understand these relationships, the values of K for modern and historic engines were determined by WAVE engine models. The models found that the average value of K is positive for a historic engine, but is negative for modern engines.</p>
            <p>This study found that for domestic engines, K is now negative, having decreased from a value of 1 in 1930. This decrease in K is primarily due to better engine cooling, better engine breathing, and the usage of fuel injectors.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw-Hill, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">American Society for Testing Materials: Designation: D 2699 – 03a, “Standard Test Method for Research Octane Number of Spark-Ignition Fuel”, Annual book of ASTM Standards, vol. 5.05, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">American Society for Testing Materials: Designation: D 2700 – 03a, “Standard Test Method for Motor Octane Number of Spark-Ignition Fuel”, Annual book of ASTM Standards, vol. 5.05, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leppard, W.R., “The Chemical Origin of Fuel Octane Sensitivity”, SAE paper 902137, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G.T., “Fuel Anti-Knock Quality – Part 1, Engine Studies”, SAE paper 2001-01-3584, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G.T., “Fuel Anti-Knock Quality – Part 2, Vehicle Studies—How Relevant is Motor Octane Number (MON) in Modern Engines”, SAE paper 2001-01-3585, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mittal, V. and Heywood, J.B., “The Relevance of Fuel RON and MON to Knock Onset in Modern SI Engines”, SAE paper 2008-01-2414, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B. and Welling, O.Z., “Trends in Performance Characteristics of Modern Automobile SI and Diesel Engines”, SAE International Powertrains, Fuels &amp; Lubricants Meeting, Florence, Italy, June 15-17, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taylor, C.F., The Internal-Combustion Engine in Theory and practice, vol 2, MIT Press, 1968.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Octane Number Requirement Survey 1951. CRC Report CRC-266, 1952.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Octane Number Requirement Survey 1961. CRC Report CRC-357, 1961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Octane Number Requirement Survey 1971. CRC Report CRC-448, 1971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">1981 CRC Octane Number Requirement Survey. CRC Report CRC-525, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">1991 CRC Octane Number Requirement Survey. CRC Report CRC-580, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Palucka, T., “The Wizards of Octane”, Invention and Technology, Winter 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amann, C.A., “The Automotive Engine—a Future Perspective”, SAE Paper 891666, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chon, D.M. and Heywood, J.B., “Performance Scaling of Spark-Ignition Engines: Correlation and Historical Analysis of Production Engine Data”, SAE paper 2000-01-0565, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bartholomew, E., “New Knock-Testing Methods Needed to Match Engine and Fuel Progress.” SAE Paper 610200, 1961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brooks, D.R., “A Review of the Development of Reference Fuel Scales for Knock Rating”, SAE Trans., Vol. 54, 1946.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“New Tests for Gasoline Octane Ratings are Coming,” Oil and Gas Journal, Vol 58, 1960.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coordinated Research Council Website. www.crcao.org.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
