<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284803</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effects of Ignition Environment and Discharge Waveform Characteristics on Spark Channel Formation and Relationship between the Discharge Parameters and the EGR Combustion Limit</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shiraishi</surname>
                  <given-names>Taisuke</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nissan Motor. Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Teraji</surname>
                  <given-names>Atsushi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nissan Motor. Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Moriyoshi</surname>
                  <given-names>Yasuo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chiba University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284791</issue-id>
         <fpage>171</fpage>
         <lpage>178</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE Japan and Copyright © SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284803"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In order to realize the high compression ratio and high dilution combustion toward improvement in thermal efficiency, the improvement in stability of ignition and initial phase of combustion under the high gas flow field is the major challenge. In terms of the shift on the higher power side of the operating point by downsizing and improvement of real world fuel consumption, the improvement of ignitability is increasingly expected in the wide operating range also including high load and high engine speed region. In this study, the effects of the gas pressure, gas flow velocity near the spark gap at ignition timing, and discharge current characteristics on spark channel formation were analyzed, focusing on restrike event and spark channel stretching in the spark channel formation process. And the relationship between the average discharge current until 1 ms and the EGR combustion limit was considered.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lucchini, T., Cornolti, L., Montenegro, G., D'Errico, G., Fiocco, M., Teraji, A., Shiraishi, T., “A Comprehensive Model to Predict the Initial Stage of Combustion in SI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01- 1087, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1087.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shichida, T., Yoshizaki, H., Tsuga, S., Sugimoto, N. et al., “Numerical Simulation for Ignitability of Spark Plug using Detailed Chemical Kinetics,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1234, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014- 01-1234.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shiraishi, T., Kakuho, A., Urushihara, T., Cathey, C. et al., “A Study of Volumetric Ignition Using High-Speed Plasma for Improving Lean Combustion Performance in Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):399-408, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0466.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanoue, K., Kuboyama, T., Moriyoshi, Y., Hotta, E. et al., “Development of a Novel Ignition System Using Repetitive Pulse Discharges: Application to a SI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):298-306, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shiraishi, T., Urushihara, T., Gundersen, M., “A trial of ignition innovation of gasoline engine by nanosecond pulsed low temperature plasma ignition,” J. Phys. D: Appl. Phys., 42 (2009) 135208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shiraishi, T. and Urushihara, T., “Fundamental Analysis of Combustion Initiation Characteristics of Low Temperature Plasma Ignition for Internal Combustion Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01- 0660, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0660.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alger, T., Gingrich, J., Mangold, B., and Roberts, C., “A Continuous Discharge Ignition System for EGR Limit Extension in SI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):677-692, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0661.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nishiyama, A. and Ikeda, Y., “Improvement of Lean Limit and Fuel Consumption Using Microwave Plasma Ignition Technology,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1139, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1139.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kono, M., Hatori, K., Iinuma, K., “Analysis of Parameters in Spark Ignition of Flowing Mixtures,” Transactions of the Japan Society of Mechanical Engineers (B), 51(461), 248-256 (1985), (in Japanese).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pashley, N., Stone, R., and Roberts, G., “Ignition System Measurement Techniques and Correlations for Breakdown and Arc Voltages and Currents,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0245, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000- 01-0245.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, M., Hall, M., Ezekoye, O., and Matthews, R., “Voltage, and Energy Deposition Characteristics of Spark Ignition Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0231, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0231.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, J. and Anderson, R., “Spark Anemometry of Bulk Gas Velocity at the Plug Gap of a Firing Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 952459, 1995, doi:10.4271/952459.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, A., Cung, K., Lee, S., Naber, J. et al., “The Impact of Spark Discharge Pattern on Flame Initiation in a Turbulent Lean and Dilute Mixture in a Pressurized Combustion Vessel,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):435-446, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1627.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, W., Madison, D., Dice, P., Naber, J. et al., “Impact of Ignition Energy Phasing and Spark Gap on Combustion in a Homogenous Direct Injection Gasoline SI Engine Near the EGR Limit,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1630, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1630.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matsumoto, O., Kuboyama, T., Moriyoshi, Y., Shiraishi, T., “Effect of Spark Discharge Characteristics on Initial Flame Kernel Growth under Highly Diluted with Strong Gas Motion Fields,” The 22nd Internal Combustion Engine Symposium, 20117025 (2011), (in Japanese).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakai, M., et al., “A Study on Combustion Stability using Longdischarge Plasma Ignition,” Nissan Technical Review, 20, 1-14 (1984), (in Japanese).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gardiner, D., Wang, G., Bardon, M., et al., “An Experimental Study of Spark Anemometry for In-Cylinder Velocity Measurements,” J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power, 130(4), 042801 (2008)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
