<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284870</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effects of End-of-Injection Transients on Combustion Recession in Diesel Sprays</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Knox</surname>
                  <given-names>Benjamin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Genzale</surname>
                  <given-names>Caroline</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Georgia Institute of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>June 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284847</issue-id>
         <fpage>932</fpage>
         <lpage>949</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284870"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>End-of-injection transients have recently been shown to be important for combustion and emissions outcomes in diesel engines. The objective of this work is to develop an understanding of the coupling between end-of-injection transients and the propensity for second-stage ignition in mixtures upstream of the lifted diesel flame, or combustion recession. An injection system capable of varying the end-of-injection transient was developed to study single fuel sprays in a newly commissioned optically-accessible spray chamber under a range of ambient conditions. Simultaneous high-speed optical diagnostics, namely schlieren, OH* chemiluminescence, and broadband luminosity, were used to characterize the spatial and temporal development of combustion recession after the end of injection. As ambient conditions become cooler or contain less oxygen (i.e. less reactive), combustion recession transitions from strong sequential ignition, to weak separated pockets of ignition, and finally to the absence of combustion recession altogether. At ambient conditions that do not favor combustion recession, increasing the end-of-injection transient duration promotes combustion recession. At high temperatures and/or oxygen concentrations, and also with longer end-of-injection transients, soot recession was observed, suggesting a trade-off in the emissions impact of combustion recession. Combustion recession under relatively lean conditions can help to reduce unburned hydrocarbons, but if mixtures are too rich, combustion recession can promote increased soot emissions. A previously developed reduced-order model was also used to provide further insight. The model shows that the shape of the end-ofinjection transient is important. In particular, the minimum pressure at time of needle closing has a strong impact on combustion recession.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M., Lachaux, T., Pickett, L., and Idicheria, C., "End-of- Injection Over-Mixing and Unburned Hydrocarbon Emissions in Low-Temperature-Combustion Diesel Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0907, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eagle, Walter Ethan, Musculus Mark P., Malbec Louis-Marie, and Bruneaux Gilles. Measuring transient entrainment rates of a confined vaporizing diesel jet. No. SAND2014-2708C. Sandia National Laboratories (SNL-CA), Livermore, CA (United States), 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, Lyle M., and Siebers Dennis L.. "Soot in diesel fuel jets: effects of ambient temperature, ambient density, and injection pressure." Combustion and Flame 138, no. 1 (2004): 114-135. doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2004.04.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, D., Ekoto, I., Colban, W., and Miles, P., "In-cylinder CO and UHC Imaging in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine during PPCI Low- Temperature Combustion," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):933-956, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1602.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S., Bae, C., Miles, P., Choi, D. et al., "The Influence of Charge Dilution and Injection Timing on Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion and Emissions," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3837, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3837.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Badock, C., Wirth R., Fath A., and Leipertz A.. "Investigation of cavitation in real size diesel injection nozzles." International journal of heat and fluid flow 20, no. 5 (1999): 538-544. doi:10.1016/S0142- 727X(99)00043-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, Won Geun, and Reitz Rolf D.. "A numerical investigation of transient flow and cavitation within minisac and valve-covered orifice diesel injector nozzles." Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 132, no. 5 (2010): 052802. doi:10.1115/1.4000145.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swantek, A. B., Duke D., Tilocco F. Z., Sovis N., Powell C. F., and Kastengren A. L.. "End of Injection, Mass Expulsion Behaviors in Single Hole Diesel Fuel Injectors." In 26th Annual Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray System. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Manin, J., Payri, R., Bardi, M. et al., "Transient Rate of Injection Effects on Spray Development," SAE Technical Paper 2013- 24-0001, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battistoni, Michele, Xue Qingluan, and Som Sibendu. "Large-Eddy Simulation (LES) of Spray Transients: Start and End of Injection Phenomena." Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology- Revue d’IFP Energies nouvelles 71, no. 1 (2016): 4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M. and Kattke, K., "Entrainment Waves in Diesel Jets," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1170-1193, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knox, Benjamin W., and Genzale Caroline L.. "Reduced-order numerical model for transient reacting diesel sprays with detailed kinetics." International Journal of Engine Research (2015): doi: 10.1177/1468087415570765</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knox, B., Genzale, C., Pickett, L., Garcia-Oliver, J. et al., "Combustion Recession after End of Injection in Diesel Sprays," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(2):679-695, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0797.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koci, C., Martin, G., Bazyn, T., Morrison, W. et al., "The Influence of Diesel End-of-Injection Rate Shape on Combustion Recession," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(2):647-659, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0795.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meijer, Maarten, Somers Bart, Johnson Jaclyn, Naber Jeffrey, Lee Seong-Young, Malbec Louis Marie, Bruneaux Gilles et al. "Engine Combustion Network (ECN): Characterization and comparison of boundary conditions for different combustion vessels." Atomization and Sprays 22, no. 9 (2012). DOI:10.1615/AtomizSpr.2012006083.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lillo, P., Pickett, L., Persson, H., Andersson, O. et al., "Diesel Spray Ignition Detection and Spatial/Temporal Correction," SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1330-1346, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S., Pickett, L., and Musculus, M., "Influence of Diesel Injection Parameters on End-of-Injection Liquid Length Recession," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1194-1210, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knox BW, Franze MJ, Genzale CL. Diesel Spray Rate-of-Momentum Measurement Uncertainties and Diagnostic Considerations. ASME. J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power. 2015;138(3):031507-031507-9. doi:10.1115/1.4031432.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Falcone, JA, Knox BW, Genzale CL. Identifying Uncertainties in Diesel Spray Rate-of-Momentum Transients under Elevated Back Pressure. ASME 2015 Internal Combustion Engine Division Fall Technical Conference. American Society of Mechanical Engineers, 2015. doi:10.1115/ICEF2015-1137.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skeen Scott A., Manin Julien, and Pickett Lyle M.. "Simultaneous formaldehyde PLIF and high-speed schlieren imaging for ignition visualization in high-pressure spray flames." Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 35, no. 3 (2015): 3167-3174. doi:10.1016/j.proci.2014.06.040.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kastengren, Alan, Powell Christopher F., Liu Zunping, Moon Seoksu, Gao Jian, Zhang Xusheng, and Wang Jin. "End-of-Injection Behavior of Diesel Sprays Measured With X-Ray Radiography." ASME. J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power. 2012;134(9), 094501. doi:10.1115/1.4006981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engine Combustion Network. http://www.sandia.gov/ecn/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, Jesús, Payri Raúl, Bardi Michele, and Martí-Aldaraví Pedro. "Experimental characterization of diesel ignition and lift-off length using a single-hole ECN injector." Applied Thermal Engineering 58, no. 1 (2013): 554-563. doi:10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2013.04.044.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. M., Caton J. A., Musculus M. P. B., and Lutz A. E.. "Evaluation of the equivalence ratio-temperature region of diesel soot precursor formation using a two-stage Lagrangian model." International Journal of Engine Research 7, no. 5 (2006): 349-370. DOI: 10.1243/14680874JER00606.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Hu, Ra Youngchul, Jia Ming, and Reitz Rolf D.. "Development of a reduced n-dodecane-PAH mechanism and its application for n-dodecane soot predictions." Fuel 136 (2014): 25-36. doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2014.07.028</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cai L., Kröger L., Pitsch H., in preparation (brief communication)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ranzi, E., Frassoldati A., Grana R., Cuoci A., Faravelli T., Kelley A. P., and Law C. K.. "Hierarchical and comparative kinetic modeling of laminar flame speeds of hydrocarbon and oxygenated fuels." Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 38, no. 4 (2012): 468-501. doi:10.1016/j.pecs.2012.03.004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pei, Yuanjiang, Hawkes Evatt R., Kook Sanghoon, Goldin Graham M., and Lu Tianfeng. "Modelling n-dodecane spray and combustion with the transported probability density function method." Combustion and Flame 162, no. 5 (2015): 2006-2019. doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2014.12.019</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
