<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="other"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">3663796</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/323509</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB750107</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Books Received</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>01</month>
            <year>2002</year>
            <string-date>January 2002</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>75</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2002.75.issue-1</issue-id>
         <fpage>191</fpage>
         <lpage>192</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/323509"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <title>Accounting</title>
         <p>Adler, Matthew D., and Posner, Eric A., eds. Cost‐Benefit Analysis: Legal, Economic, and Philosophical Perspectives. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 2001. Pp. v+351. $39.00 (cloth); $20.00 (paper).</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <title>Business Ethics</title>
         <p>Klein, Daniel B. A Plea to Economists Who Favor Liberty: Assist the Everyman. London: Institute of Economic Affairs, 2001. Pp. 107. £11.00.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <title>Business Finance and Investment</title>
         <p>United Nations Conference on Trade and Development. World Investment Report 2000: Cross‐Border Mergers and Acquisitions and Development. New York and Geneva: United Nations, 2000. Pp. xxviii+337. $45.00.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <title>Information Systems</title>
         <p>Devlin, Keith. Infosense: Turning Information into Knowledge. New York: W. H. Freeman, 2001. Pp. 215. $14.95.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc5">
         <title>International Trade and Finance</title>
         <p>UNCTAD (United Nations Conference on Trade and Development). The Competitiveness Challenge: Transnational Corporations and Industrial Restructuring in Developing Countries. New York and Geneva: United Nations, 2000. Pp. 283.</p>
         <p>UNCTAD. Environment. UNCTAD Series on Issues in International Investment Agreements. New York and Geneva: United Nations, 2000. Pp. 283.</p>
         <p>UNCTAD. FDI Determinants and TNC Strategies: The Case of Brazil. New York and Geneva: United Nations, 2000. Pp. 195. $35.00.</p>
         <p>UNCTAD. Investment Policy Review: Peru. New York and Geneva: United Nations, 2000. Pp. 108. $22.00.</p>
         <p>UNCTAD. Measures of the Transnationalization of Economic Activity. New York and Geneva: United Nations, 2001. Pp. 93.</p>
         <p>UNCTAD. The Role of Publicly Funded Research and Publicly Owned Technologies in the Transfer and Diffusion of Environmentally Sound Technologies. New York and Geneva: United Nations, 2000. Pp. 445. $45.00.</p>
         <p>UNCTAD. Taking of Property. UNCTAD Series on Issues in International Investment. New York and Geneva: United Nations, 2000. Pp. 75. $12.00.</p>
         <p>UNCTAD. Transfer of Funds. UNCTAD Series on Issues in International Investment Agreements. New York and Geneva: United Nations, 2000. Pp. 68. $12.00.</p>
         <p>UNCTAD. Transitional Corporations. Vol. 9, no. 3. Geneva: United Nations, 2001. Pp. 243.</p>
         <p>UNCTAD. World Investment Directory. Vol. 7, pt. 1: Asia and the Pacific. New York and Geneva: United Nations, 2000. Pp. 332; pt. 2: Pp. 305.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc6">
         <title>Management Organization Theory and Practice</title>
         <p>DePamphilis, Donald. Mergers, Acquisitions, and Other Restructuring Activities: An Integrated Approach to Process, Tools, Cases, and Solutions. San Diego, Calif.: Academic Press, 2001. Pp. xix+643. $79.95.</p>
         <p>Flood, Patrick; MacCurtain, Sarah; and West, Michael. Effective Top Management Teams. Dublin and Los Angeles: Blackhall Publishing, 2001. Pp. xv+128.</p>
         <p>Vives, Xavier, ed. Corporate Governance: Theoretical and Empirical Perspectives. New York: Cambridge University Press, 2000. Pp. viii+238. $49.95.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc7">
         <title>Personnel, Industrial Relations, Labor, and Manpower</title>
         <p>Fung, Archon; Hebb, Tessa; and Rogers, Joel, eds. Working Capital: The Power of Labor's Pensions. Ithaca, N.Y.: Cornell University Press, 2001. Pp. x+273. $35.00.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc8">
         <title>Social Issues and Public Policy</title>
         <p>Lewis, James A., project director. Computer Exports and National Security in a Global Era: New Tools for a New Century. A Report of the Center for Strategic and International Studies, 2001. Washington, D.C.: Center for Strategic and International Studies, 2001. Pp. xxii+46. $21.95.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc9">
         <title>Miscellaneous</title>
         <p>Alford, Helen J., and Naughton, Michael J. Managing as if Faith Mattered: Christian Social Principles in the Modern Organization. Notre Dame, Ind.: University of Notre Dame Press, 2001. Pp. 360. $38.95 (cloth); $21.95 (paper).</p>
         <p>Bennett, Chris. Practical WAP: Developing Applications for the Wireless Web. New York: Cambridge University Press, 2001. Pp. xix+424. $34.95.</p>
         <p>Håkansson, Håkan, and Johanson, Jan. Business Network Learning. Oxford: Elsevier Science, 2001. Pp. 306. $75.00.</p>
         <p>Hamre, John J., project chair. Technology and Security in the Twenty‐First Century: U.S. Military Export Control Reform. Washington, D.C.: CSIS (Center for Strategic and International Studies), 2001. Pp. 76. $21.95.</p>
      </sec>
   </body>
</article>
