<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26926441</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Control Strategy for Hybrid Electric Vehicle Based on Online Driving Pattern Classification</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yao</surname>
                  <given-names>Zhengyu</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yoon</surname>
                  <given-names>Hwan-Sik</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>


         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2019</year>
            <string-date>2019</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26926440</issue-id>
         <fpage>91</fpage>
         <lpage>102</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2019 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26926441"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Hybrid Electric Vehicles (HEVs) are gaining popularity these days mainly due to their high fuel economy. While conventional HEV controllers can be classified into rule-based control and optimization-based control, most of the production vehicles employ rule-based control due to their reliability. However, once the rule is optimized for a given driving pattern, it is not necessarily optimal for other driving patterns. In order to further improve fuel economy for HEVs, this article investigates the feasibility of optimizing control algorithm for different driving patterns so that the vehicle maintains a high level of optimality regardless of the driving patterns. For this purpose, a two-level supervisory control algorithm is developed where the top-level algorithm classifies the current driving pattern to select optimal control parameters, and the lower level algorithm controls the vehicle power flow using the selected control parameters in a similar way to conventional supervisory controllers. To study the effectiveness of the proposed algorithm, a HEV model with a rule-based control algorithm is modified such that the control parameters are optimized for different driving patterns, and the simulation results obtained by the driving pattern-optimized control algorithm is compared with those with the original control algorithm with fixed control parameters.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Wei, Z., Xu, J., and Halim, D., “HEV Power Management Control Strategy for Urban Driving,” Applied Energy 194:705-714, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Enang, W. and Bannister, C., “Modelling and Control of Hybrid Electric Vehicles (A Comprehensive Review),” Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 74:1210-1239, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Ehsani, M., Gao, Y., and Miller, J.M., “Hybrid Electric Vehicles: Architecture and Motor Drives,” Proceedings of the IEEE 95(4):719-728, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Becerra, G., Alvarez-Icaza, L., and Pantoja-Vázquez, A., “Power Flow Control Strategies in Parallel Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering 230(14):1925-1941, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Tate, E.D. and Boyd, S.P., “Finding Ultimate Limits of Performance for Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-3099, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-3099.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Chen, H., Kessels, J., and Weiland, S., “Adaptive ECMS: A Causal Set-Theoretic Method for Equivalence Factor Estimation,” IFAC-PapersOnLine 48(15):78-85, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Pisu, P. and Rizzoni, G., “A Comparative Study of Supervisory Control Strategies for Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology 15(3):506-518, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Wirasingha, S.G. and Emadi, A., “Classification and Review of Control Strategies for Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology 60(1):111-122, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Jalil, N., Kheir, N.A., and Salman, M., “A Rule-Based Energy Management Strategy for a Series Hybrid Vehicle,” in Proceedings of the 1997 American Control Conference, Albuquerque, NM, Cat. No. 97CH36041, 1997, IEEE.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Lin, C.-C. et al., “Power Management Strategy for a Parallel Hybrid Electric Truck,” IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology 11(6):839-849, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Wang, R. and Lukic, S.M., “Review of Driving Conditions Prediction and Driving Style Recognition Based Control Algorithms for Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” in 2011 IEEE Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference, Chicago, IL, 2011, IEEE.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Feng, L., Liu, W., and Chen, B., “Driving Pattern Recognition for Adaptive Hybrid Vehicle Control,” SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains 1(1):169-179, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0742.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Lei, Z. et al., “Dynamic Energy Management for a Novel Hybrid Electric System Based on Driving Pattern Recognition,” Applied Mathematical Modelling 45:940-954, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Gu, B. and Rizzoni, G., “An Adaptive Algorithm for Hybrid Electric Vehicle Energy Management Based on Driving Pattern Recognition,” in ASME 2006 International Mechanical Engineering Congress and Exposition, Chicago, IL, 2006, American Society of Mechanical Engineers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Lin, C.-C. et al., “Control of a Hybrid Electric Truck Based on Driving Pattern Recognition, in Proceedings of the 2002 Advanced Vehicle Control Conference, 2002, Hiroshima, Japan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Zhang, S. and Xiong, R., “Adaptive Energy Management of a Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicle Based on Driving Pattern Recognition and Dynamic Programming,” Applied Energy 155:68-78, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Higuchi, N., Sunaga, Y., Tanaka, M., and Shimada, H., “Development of a New Two-Motor Plug-In Hybrid System,” SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 2(1):135-145, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1476.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Mathworks, “Powertrain Blockset Reference,” https://www.mathworks.com/help/releases/R2017a/pdf_doc/autoblks/autoblks_ref.pdf, accessed Sep. 2019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Wang, H., Zhang, X., and Ouyang, M., “Energy Consumption of Electric Vehicles Based on Real-World Driving Patterns: A Case Study of Beijing,” Applied Energy 157:710-719, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">US Environmental Protection Agency, “New Fuel Economy and Environment Labels for a New Generation of Vehicles,” Regulatory Announcement EPA-420-F-11-017, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">United States Census Bureau, “Commuting Times, Median Rents and Language other than English Use in the Home on the Rise,” 2017, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Alpaydin, E., Introduction to Machine Learning (Cambridge, MA: MIT Press, 2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Specifications of FHEV and environmental parameters.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>FHEV powertrain configurations for three different operation modes.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Specifications of battery pack.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Specifications of P4 electric motor.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>P4 motor efficiency map.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Specifications of engine.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Engine BSFC (g/kWh) map [18].</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Specifications of electric generator.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>P0 generator efficiency map.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Rule-based HEV control strategy.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Design variables used in the threshold value optimization.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Cost-function reduction during optimization for SC03 cycle.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Speed profile of three representative driving patterns and US06: (a) urban, (b) highway normal, (c) highway aggressive, (d) full US06 drive cycle.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Optimization results with initial SOC of 65%.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Optimization results for SC03 drive cycle with different driving times.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Optimization results for SC03 drive cycle with different driving times.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Feature vector used for driving pattern classification.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Distribution of three selected drive cycles in a 2D feature plane.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Driving pattern classification for COM3 cycle using SVM.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Driving pattern classification for COM3 using Decision Tree.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Two-level approach for driving patterndependent HEV control.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Comparison of fuel consumption (gal) for two different control approaches with 3000 s driving time for three representative driving cycles and the 6000 s COM3 cycle.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Comparison of fuel consumption (gal) for two different control approaches for the SC03 cycle with different lengths.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Power flow mode-switching pattern for SC03 of 600 s: (a) two cases using Param #1 and Param #4, (b) difference between the two cases.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>Power flow mode-switching pattern for SC03 of 1800 s: (a) two cases using Param #1 and Param #4, (b) difference between the two cases.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Speed profile and classified driving pattern for T-City.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>Speed profile and classified driving pattern for T-HW.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>Speed profile and classified driving pattern for T-IS.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>Comparison of fuel consumption (gal) for real-world driving cases with 2000 s driving time.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-30">
            <p>Comparison of fuel consumption (gal) for real-world driving cases with 3000 s driving time.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
