<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">trasocauteng</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50020000</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Transactions (Society of Automobile Engineers)</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automobile Engineers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">25767763</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">11</volume>
         <issue-id>i40191516</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44579839</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>AUTOMOBILE EXPERIENCES IN THE GREAT WAR</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>W. F.</given-names>
                  <surname>Bradley</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1916</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>336</fpage>
         <lpage>352</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright, 1917, The Society of Automobile Engineers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44579839"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The author outlines the constructions that have performed cially that four-cylinder engines carried under a hood are the most satisfactory. The defects revealed by war service are given in considerable detail, the author finding that all of the trucks used had developed some weak point. Radiators and springs are specified as a general source of trouble. The author outlines a number of operating troubles developed under the existing conditions of operation and gives examples of the way these have been remedied. Considerable attention is paid to the methods of operating trucks away from made roads. The methods of fitting chains to the wheels, and the use of caterpillar attachments are described. Dimensions are given for bodies and a number of suggestions made as to their proper construction. Although practically all the general transportation is done by rear-driven trucks the four-wheel-driven vehicle is used to a limited extent, mainly for operation off the main roads or on no roads at all. A description is given of tractors developed for this service and of the trailers now being used behind all kinds of automobiles, both for the transportation of men working in the rear of the lines and for general haulage work around the depots. In conclusion the author considers the arguments heard in the war zone in favor of standardization and gives in detail a number of fit subjects for standardization. He also mentions the necessity for uniform nomenclature inasmuch as a great deal of confusion has been created by the difference in the names of American truck parts, not to mention the trouble caused by the variation in English and French terms.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


