<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285074</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Physically Motivated Model for Efficient Dynamic Simulation of Chain Tensioners with Labyrinth Seals</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Huber</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Clauberg</surname>
                  <given-names>Jan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Technische Universitaet Muenchen</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285020</issue-id>
         <fpage>656</fpage>
         <lpage>667</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285074"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The object of this study is a new chain tensioner with two labyrinth seals. For the simulation of chain tensioners within the framework of multi-body dynamics, a physically orientated model to describe the fluid dynamics of the labyrinth seals is derived. The easiest way to describe labyrinth seals is to use maps obtained from measurements. As this is very time-consuming, methods of 1D and 2D fluid-mechanics are used in this work to model the labyrinth seals. The seals are characterized by physically motivated parameters e.g. coefficients of resistance or friction. As these parameters can be derived from geometric data, a very good forecast feasibility without experimental investigations is provided. For high accuracy simulations model parameters can be refined by experimental data. As many and highly complex parameters have to be identified, this refinement is very time-consuming and requires lots of experiments. Therefore, a third approach for modeling a labyrinth sealing is derived. Using dimensional analysis the labyrinth can be described by a non-dimensional equation. Only a few coefficients have to be determined by measurements. Hence, the effort for parameter identification as well as the number of necessary experiments is significantly reduced. All three approaches are validated with experimental data. Next, a dynamic model of a complete chain tensioner including labyrinth seals was built up. A comparison between simulation and measured data of the flow characteristics as well as of the dynamic behavior is presented to prove accuracy, benefits and practicability of the presented approach. Furthermore, the influence of fluid inertia in the hydraulic lines is analyzed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krueger, K., Engelhardt, T., Ginzinger, L., and Ulbrich, H., "Dynamical Analysis of Hydraulic Chain Tensioners - Experiment and Simulation," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1461, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1461.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krueger, K., Ginzinger, L., and Ulbrich, H., "Influences of Leakage Gap Variations on the Dynamics of Hydraulic Chain Tensioners - Experiment and Simulation," SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0294, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0294.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pfeiffer, F., “Mechanical System Dynamics,” Lecture Notes in Applied and Computational Mechanics, Vol. 40, Springer, Berlin, ISBN 978-3- 540-79435-6, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borchsenius, F., “Simulation ölhydraulischer Systeme,” VDI Fortschrittsberichte, Reihe 8, 1005, VDI Verlag, Düsseldorf, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engelhardt, T., Hoesl, A., Lebrecht, W., Ulbrich, H., and Pfeiffer, F., ”Simulation of Timing Chain Drives using KETSIM,” Proceedings of the ASME Internal Combustion Engine Technical Conference, Long Beach, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Idelchik, I. E., “Handbook of Hydraulic Resistance”, Jaico Publishing House, 3rd edition, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Totten, G. E., “Handbook of Hydraulic Fluid Technology”, CRC Press, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huber, R., “Dynamics of Variable Valve Trains and Extrapolation Methods for Time-Stepping Schemes”, Verlag Dr. Hut, Munich, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sutera, S. P., and Skalak, R., “The history of Poiseuille's law”, Annual Review of Fluid Mechanics 25:1-19, 1993, doi:10.1146/annurev. fl.25.010193.000245.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hartnett, J. P., and Kostic, M., “Heat Transfer to Newtonian and Non- Newtonian Fluids in Rectangular Ducts”, Advances in Heat Transfer 19:247-356, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deutsches Institut für Normung (German National Standard), “Testing of Mineral Oils and Related Materials - Determination of Viscosity Temperature Relation”, DIN 51563:2011-04, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Totten, G. E., editor, “Handbook of Hydraulic Fluid Technology”, CRC Press, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eck, B., “Technische Strömungslehre”, Springer Verlag, 1966.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matthies, H. J., “Einführung in die Ölhydraulik“, Teubner Verlag, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Findeisen, D., and Findeisen, F., “Ölhydraulik“, Springer Verlag, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chaimowitsch, E.M., “Ölhydraulik - Grundlagen und Anwendungen“, Technik Verlag, Berlin, 1961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
