<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277871</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>An Update and Comparative Study of Acoustic Modeling and Solver Technologies in View of Pass-By Noise Simulation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Vansant</surname>
                  <given-names>Koen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>LMS</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bériot</surname>
                  <given-names>Hadrien</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>LMS</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bertolini</surname>
                  <given-names>Claudio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>AUTONEUM</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Miccoli</surname>
                  <given-names>Giuseppe</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IMAMOTER</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>August 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277829</issue-id>
         <fpage>1593</fpage>
         <lpage>1609</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277871"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>As the legislation for pass-by noise (PBN) has recently become more stringent, car manufacturers face again a challenging task to reach the new SPL objective (70dB(A)). A good design of the engine bay is therefore required to sufficiently attenuate the noise coming from sources as the engine and the intake. This involves proper design of the engine bay's panels including apertures, and a good selection of the type and location of acoustic treatments.</p>
            <p>For a given engine bay design, the PBN SPL results can be obtained with a PBN test or by an equivalent simulation. Using simulation models it is possible to create the perfect test environment virtually and moreover to obtain acoustic results for a large number of designs upfront of any actual testing or prototype. The challenge for simulation models is however that, as the results should typically be available from 20 Hz up to 4 or 5 kHz and overall SPL results should be retrieved from a narrow band response over this large frequency range, the CAE models required can become very large and many frequencies need to be computed resulting in long solving times.</p>
            <p>This paper will discuss on Boundary Element Method (BEM) and Finite Element Method (FEM) acoustic technologies available to predict powertrain exterior Acoustic Transfer Functions (ATFs) for a mock-up model of an engine bay. A comparison with Test results is provided to judge on the models' accuracy. Special focus is given to a comparative performance study for the different simulation approaches.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miccoli, G., Parise, G. and Totaro, N., “Simulation of the effect of the absorbing treatments in the engine compartment on the acoustic transfer functions from the powertrain surface to exterior receivers”, ATZ Automotive Acoustic Conference, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miccoli, G., Parise, G., Bertolini, C. and Tinti, F., “Vehicle Exterior Noise Field Analysis Methods &amp; Simulation Models”, ICSV 18, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miccoli, G., Bertolini, C. and Bihhadi, A., “Comparative analysis of different deterministic methods for the simulation of exterior noise acoustic transfer functions”, AIA-DAGA, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huijssen, J., Hallez, R., Pluymers, B., Donders, S. et al., “Synthesis of Drive-by Noise Based on Numerically Evaluated Source-Receiver Transfer Functions Employing the FMBEM,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1610, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1610.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vansant, K., “Latest developments in solving large simulation models in view of pass-by noise”, AIA-DAGA, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hallez, R. and De Langhe, K., “Solving large industrial acoustic models with the fast multipole method”, ICSV 16, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vansant, K., Hallez, R., Bériot, H., Tournour, M. et al., “Simulating Acoustic Engine Performance Over a Broad Frequency Range,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-26-0019, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-26- 0019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bériot, H. and Tournour, M., “On the locally-conformal perfectly matched layer implementation for Helmholtz equation”, NOVEM Noise and Vibration, Emerging Methods, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babuska I. and Sauter S.A., “Is the pollution effect of the FEM avoidable for the Helmholtz equation considering high wavenumbers?”, SIAM Journal of Numerical Analysis, 34, 2392- 2423, 1997</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen S., Dreyer D. and von Estorff O., “Assessment of finite and spectral element shape functions for efficient iterative simulations of interior acoustics”, Computers Methods in Applied Mechanics and Engineering, 195, 6463-6478, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vos P.E.J., Sherwin S.J. and Kirby R.M., “From h to p Efficiently: Implementing finite and spectral/hp element discretization to achieve optimal performance at low and high order approximations”. Journal of Computational Physics, 229, 5161- 5181, (2010).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beriot H., Prinn A, Gabard G., “On the performance of high-order FEM for solving large scale industrial acoustic problems.”, ICSV 20, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bériot, H., Tournour, M. and Massa, G., “On a few recent advances of Finite Element Methods for the Helmholtz equation”, ICSV 16, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amestoy, P.R., Duff, I.S. and L'Excellent, J.-Y., “Multifrontal parallel distributed symmetric and unsymmetric solvers”, Computational Methods in Applied Mechanical Engineering, 184:501-520, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bihhadi A., Bertolini C., Miccoli G., “Simulation of exterior powertrain Acoustic Transfer Functions using IFEM and other deterministic simulation methods”, ATZ Automotive Acoustics Conference, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
