<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000452</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40008416</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Combining Corpus and Machine-Readable Dictionary Data for Building Bilingual Lexicons</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Judith</given-names>
                  <surname>Klavans</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Evelyne</given-names>
                  <surname>Tzoukermann</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1995</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>185</fpage>
         <lpage>218</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1995 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40008416"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper describes and discusses some theoretical and practical problems arising from developing a system to combine the structured but incomplete information from machine readable dictionaries (MRDs) with the unstructured but more complete information available in corpora for the creation of a bilingual lexical data base, presenting a methodology to integrate information from both sources into a single lexical data structure. The Bicord system (Bilingual CORpus-enhanced Dictionaries) involves linking entries in Collins English-French and French-English bilingual dictionary with a large English-French and French-English bilingual corpus. We have concentrated on the class of action verbs of movement, building on earlier work on lexical correspondences specific to this verb class between languages (Klavans and Tzoukermann, 1989), (Klavans and Tzoukermann, 1990a), (Klavans and Tzoukermann, 1990b).¹ We first examine the way prototypical verbs of movement are translated in the Collins-Robert (Atkins, Duval, and Milne, 1978) bilingual dictionary, and then analyze the behavior of some of these verbs in a large bilingual corpus. We incorporate the results of linguistic research on the theory of verb types to motivate corpus analysis coupled with data from MRDs for the purpose of establishing lexical correspondences with the full range of associated translations, and with statistical data attached to the relevant nodes.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>Notes</title>
            <ref id="d2102596e205a1310">
               <label>2</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e212" publication-type="other">
(Neff and Boguraev, 1989).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d2102596e228a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e232" publication-type="other">
Atkins, Beryl T. 1987. Semantic ID tags: Corpus evidence for dictionary senses. In
Proceedings of the Third Conference of the University of Waterloo. Centre for the
New Oxford English Dictionary and Text Research: Electronic Text Research.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e245a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e249" publication-type="other">
Atkins, Beryl T., Alain Duval, and Rosemary C. Milne. 1978. Collins Robert
French Dictionary: French-English. English-French. Collins Publishers, London.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e259a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e263" publication-type="other">
Atkins, Beryl T., Judith Kegl, and Beth Levin. 1988. Anatomy of a verb en-
try: from linguistics theory to lexicographic practice. International Journal of
Lexicography, 1:84-126.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e276a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e280" publication-type="other">
Boguraev, Branimir. 1991. Building a lexicon: The contribution of computers.
International Journal of Lexicography, 4(3).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e291a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e295" publication-type="other">
Boguraev, Branimir, Roy Byrd, Judith Klavans, and Mary Neff. 1989. From
structural analysis of lexical resources to semantics in a lexical knowledge base.
In First International Lexical Acquisition Workshop, Detroit, Michigan. Interna-
tional Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e311a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e315" publication-type="other">
Brent, Michael R. 1993. From grammar to lexicon: Unsupervised learning of lexical
syntax. Computational Linguistics, 19(2):243-262.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e325a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e329" publication-type="other">
Brill, Eric. 1992. A simple rule-based part of speech tagger. In Third Conference
on Applied Computational Linguistics, Trento, Italy.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e339a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e343" publication-type="other">
Brown, P., J. Cocke, S. Della Pietra, V. Della Pietra, F. Jelinek, R. Mercer, and
P. Roossin. 1988. A statistical approach to language translation. In Proceedings
of the Twelfth International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Budapest,
Hungary.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e359a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e363" publication-type="other">
Brown, P., J. Cocke, S. Della Pietra, V. Della Pietra, F. Jelinek, R. Mercer, and
P. Roossin. 1990. A statistical approach to machine translation. Computational
Linguistics, 16(2):79-85.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e376a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e380" publication-type="other">
Brown, P., J. Lai, and R. Mercer. 1991. Aligning sentences in parallel corpora. In
Proceedings of the Twenty-ninth Annual Meeting of the Association for Compu-
tational Linguistics, pages 169-176, Berkeley, California.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e394a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e398" publication-type="other">
Brown, P., S. Della Pietra, V. Della Pietra, M. Goldsmith, J. Hajic, R. Mercer,
and S. Mohanty. 1993. But dictionaries are data too. In Proceedings of DARPA,
Princeton, New Jersey.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e411a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e415" publication-type="other">
Byrd, Roy, Nicoletta Calzolari, Martin Chodorow, Judith Klavans, Mary Neff, and
Omneya Rizk. 1987. Tools and methods for computational lexicology. Computa-
tional Linguistics, 13(3):219-240.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e428a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e432" publication-type="other">
Calzolari, Nicoletta and Remo Bindi. 1990. Acquisition of lexical information from
a large textual Italian corpus. In Proceedings of the Thirteenth International
Conference on Computational Linguistics, Helsinki, Finland.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e445a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e449" publication-type="other">
Carter, Richard. 1988. On movement (written in 1984). In Beth Levin and Carol
Tenny, editors, On Linking: Papers by Richard Carter, volume 25 of Lexicon
Project Working Papers. MIT Press, pages 231-252.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e462a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e466" publication-type="other">
Catizone, Robert, Graham Russell, and Susan Warwick, 1989. Deriving Translation
Data from Bilingual Text. ISSCO, Geneva, Switzerland, unpublished manuscript.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e476a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e480" publication-type="other">
Chodorow, Martin S., Roy J. Byrd, and George E. Heidorn. 1985. Extracting
semantic hierarchies from a large on-line dictionary. In Proceedings of the Twenty-
third Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, pages
299-304.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e497a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e501" publication-type="other">
Church, Kenneth W. 1989. A stochastic parts program noun phrase parser for
unrestricted text. In IEEE Proceedings of the ICASSP, pages 695-698, Glasgow.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e511a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e515" publication-type="other">
Church, Kenneth W. 1993. Char-align: A program for aligning parallel texts
at the character level. In Proceedings of the Thirty-first Annual Meeting of the
Association for Computational Linguistics, pages 1-8.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e528a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e532" publication-type="other">
Church, Kenneth W. and Patrick Hanks. 1990. Word association norms, mutual
information and lexicography. Computational Linguistics, 16(1):22-29.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e542a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e546" publication-type="other">
Church, Kenneth W., Patrick Hanks, D. Hindle, and W. Gale. 1991. Using statis-
tics in lexical analysis. In Uri Zernik, editor, Lexical Acquisition: Using on-line
Resources to Build a Lexicon. Lawrence Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e559a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e563" publication-type="other">
Cruse, D. Alan. 1986. Lexical Semantics. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge,
England.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e573a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e577" publication-type="other">
DeRose, Stephen. 1988. Grammatical category disambiguation by statistical opti-
mization. Computational Linguistics, 14(1):31-39.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e588a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e592" publication-type="other">
Dorr, Bonnie J. 1992. The use of lexical semantics in interlingual machine transla-
tion. Machine Translation, 7(3):135-193.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e602a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e606" publication-type="other">
Dowty, David. 1979. Word Meaning and Montague Grammar. Reidel, Dordrecht.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e613a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e617" publication-type="other">
Gove, Philip B., editor. 1963. Webster's Seventh New Collegiate Dictionary. G.&amp;
C. Merriam Company, Springfield, Mass.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e627a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e631" publication-type="other">
Grishman, Ralph and Richard Kittredge, editors. 1986. Analyzing language in
restricted domains: Sublanguage description and processing. Lawrence Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e641a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e645" publication-type="other">
Gruber, J. S. 1965. Studies in Lexical Relations. Ph.D. thesis, The Massachusetts
Institute of Technology, Department of Linguistics, Cambridge, Massachusetts.
published later 1976 as Lexical Structures in Syntax and Semantics, North-
Holland, Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e661a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e665" publication-type="other">
Hale, Kenneth and Jay Keyser. 1986. Some Transitivity Alternations in English.
Center for Cognitive Science, The Massachusetts Institute of Technology.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e676a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e680" publication-type="other">
Jackendoff, Ray S. 1987. The status of thematic relations in linguistic theory.
Linguistic Inquiry, 18(3):369-411.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e690a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e694" publication-type="other">
Jackendoff, Ray S. 1990. Semantic Structures. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e701a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e705" publication-type="other">
Kay, Martin and Martin Röscheisen. 1993. Text translation alignment. Computa-
tional Linguistics, 19(1):75-102.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e715a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e719" publication-type="other">
Klavans, Judith L. 1988. Complex: A computational lexicon for natural language
systems. In Proceedings of the Twelfth International Conference on Computa-
tional Linguistics, Budapest, Hungary.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e732a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e736" publication-type="other">
Klavans, Judith L., Martin Chodorow, and Nina Wacholder. 1990. From dictionary
to knowledge base via taxonomy. In Proceedings of the Sixth Conference of the
University of Waterloo. Centre for the New Oxford English Dictionary and Text
Research: Electronic Text Research.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e752a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e756" publication-type="other">
Klavans, Judith L. and Philip Resnik, editors. 1996. The Balancing Act: Com-
bining Symbolic and Statistical Approaches to Language. MIT Press, Cambridge,
Mass.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e770a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e774" publication-type="other">
Klavans, Judith L. and Evelyne Tzoukermann. 1989. Corpus-based lexical acqui-
sition for translation systems. In Proceedings of the Sixth Israeli Conference of
Artificial Intelligence and Computer Vision, Tel Aviv, Israel.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e787a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e791" publication-type="other">
Klavans, Judith L. and Evelyne Tzoukermann. 1990a. Linking bilingual corpora
and machine readable dictionaries with the Bicord system. In Proceedings of
the Sixth Conference of the University of Waterloo. Centre for the New Oxford
English Dictionary and Text Research: Electronic Text Research.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e807a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e811" publication-type="other">
Klavans, Judith L. and Evelyne Tzoukermann. 1990b. The Bicord system: Com-
bining lexical information from bilingual corpora and machine readable dictionar-
ies. In Proceedings of the Thirteenth International Conference on Computational
Linguistics, Helsinki, Finland.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e827a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e831" publication-type="other">
Kupiec, Julian. 1989. Augmenting a hidden markov model for phrase-dependent
word tagging. In Proceedings of the 1989 DARPA Speech and Natural Language
Workshop, pages 92-98, San Mateo, California. Morgan Kaufmann.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e844a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e848" publication-type="other">
Leech, Geoffrey, Roger Garside, and Erik Atwell. 1983. Automatic grammatical
tagging of the LOB corpus. ICAME News, 7:13-33.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e858a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e862" publication-type="other">
Levin, Beth and Malka Rappaport. 1988. On the nature of unaccusativity. In
Proceedings of New England Linguistic Society.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e873a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e877" publication-type="other">
Merialdo, Bernard. 1994. Tagging English text with a probabilistic model. Com-
putational Linguistics, 20(2):155-172.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e887a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e891" publication-type="other">
Neff, Mary and Bran Boguraev. 1989. Dictionaries, dictionary grammars and
dictionary entry parsing. In Proceedings of the Twenty-seventh Annual Meeting
of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Vancouver, Canada.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e904a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e908" publication-type="other">
Neff, Mary S., Roy J. Byrd, and Omneya A. Rizk. 1988. Creating and querying
hierarchical lexical data bases. In Proceedings of the Second Applied Association
for Computational Linguistics Conference, pages 84-92, Austin, Texas.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e921a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e925" publication-type="other">
Pustejovsky, James, Sabine Bergler, and Peter Anick. 1993. Lexical semantic
techniques for corpus analysis. Computational Linguistics, 19(2):331-358.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e935a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e939" publication-type="other">
Rizk, Omneya, 1989. Sense Disambiguation of Word Translation in Bilingual Dic-
tionaries: Trying to Solve the Mapping Problem Automatically. Unpublished
M.A. thesis, Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, New York University,
New York.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e955a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e959" publication-type="other">
Sadler, Victor, 1989. The Bilingual Knowledge Bank: A New conceptual basis for
MT. BSO/Research, unpublished manuscript, Utrecht.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e970a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e974" publication-type="other">
Smadja, Frank, Kathleen McKeown, and Vasileios Hatzivassiloglou. in press.
Translating collocations for bilingual lexicons: A statistical approach. Computa-
tional Linguistics.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e987a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e991" publication-type="other">
Talmy, Leonard. 1975. Semantics and syntax of motion. In J.P. Kimball, editor,
Syntax and Semantics, volume 4. Academic Press, New York, NY, pages 181-238.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e1001a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e1005" publication-type="other">
Talmy, Leonard. 1985. Lexicalization patterns: Semantic structure in lexical forms.
In T. Shopen, editor, Language Typology and Syntactic Description: Grammatical
categories and the Lexicon. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge UK.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e1018a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e1022" publication-type="other">
Tenny, Carol L., 1992. How Motion Verbs are Special. University of Pittsburgh,
Department of Linguistics, unpublished manuscript.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e1032a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e1036" publication-type="other">
Tenny, Carol L. 1994. Aspectual Roles and the Syntax-Semantics Interface. Kluwer
Academic Publishers, Dordrecht.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2102596e1046a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2102596e1050" publication-type="other">
Tzoukermann, Evelyne and Bernard Merialdo, 1989. Some Statistical Approaches
for Tagging Unrestricted Text. IBM, T. J. Watson Research Center, Yorktown
Heights, New York, unpublished manuscript.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
