<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278174</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Evaluation of Solid Particle Emissions from Hybrid and Conventional Gasoline Vehicles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wei</surname>
                  <given-names>Qiang</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Porter</surname>
                  <given-names>Scott</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Horiba Instruments Inc.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>610</fpage>
         <lpage>618</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278174"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Solid particle emissions from a modern gasoline hybrid electrical vehicle (HEV) and a conventional gasoline vehicle were studied under diverse transient drive cycles on a chassis dynamometer.</p>
            <p>It is found that solid particle emissions from the conventional gasoline vehicle which has a 3.8-liter engine are sensitive to vehicle temperatures. Over 90% of solid particles are emitted during the first 250 seconds of transient cycles. Spikes for solid particle emissions from the HEV during a transient cycle are mainly caused by engine starts, hard accelerations after engine starts, and the engine running harder at high vehicle speeds. The engine and vehicle temperature status on the HEV doesn’t show a strong correlation to the solid particle emission.</p>
            <p>While the conventional gasoline vehicle is cold, it emits over 2 times less solid particles than the HEV although it is larger and has heavier curb weight; and, while it is fully warmed up, it emits over 30 times less solid particles than the HEV. It is likely that frequent engine starts and a relatively higher percentage of maximum engine torque and power caused by engine downsize are contributing factors to increasing solid particle emissions from the HEV.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Public workshop on proposed revisions to the lowemission vehicle program: emission limits for particle mass, solid particle number, and black carbon, California air resources board, El Monte, California, May 18, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Health assessment document for diesel exhaust, EPS/600/8-90/057E, July 2000, SAB review</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersson, Jon, Giechaskiel, Barouch, Munoz-Bueno, Rafael, Sandbach, Emma, Dilara, Panagiota, Particle measurement programme (PMP) light-duty inter-laboratory correlation exercise (ILCE_LD) final report, Joint Research Centre, GRPE-54-08-Rev. 1, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montajir, R.M., Kusaka, T., Kaori, I., Kihara, N. et al., “Soot Emission Behavior from Diverse Vehicles and Catalytic Technologies Measured by a Solid Particle Counting System,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0317, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0317.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, S., McMahon, W., Toutoundjian, H., Cruz, M. et al., “Particulate Mass and Number Emissions from Lightduty Low Emission Gasoline Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0795, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0795.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei, Q., Oestergaard, K., Porter, S., Ichiro, A. et al., “Real-Time Measuring System for Engine Exhaust Solid Particle Number Emission - Design and Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0864, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0864.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Conclusions on improving particulate mass measurement procedures and new particle number measurement procedures relative to the requirements of the 05 series of amendments to regulation No. 83, GRPE-48-11-Rev. 1, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amendments to UNECE regulations, Regulation No. 83, submitted by the expert from the United Kingdom, ECE/TRANS/WP.29/GRPE/2008/, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herner, J.D., Robertson, W.H., Ayala, A. “Investigation of Ultrafine Particle Number Measurements from a Clean Diesel Truck Using the European PMP Protocol,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1114, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Horiba solid particle counting system MEXA-2000SPCS instruction manual, June 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graham, Lisa A., Christenson, Martha, The transient nature of particle emissions from light duty hybrid vehicles, 9th ETH-Conference on Combustion Generated Nanoparticles, August 15th - 17th, 2005 ETH Hönggerberg, Zürich, Switzerland</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei, Q., Akard, M., Porter, S., and Nakamura, H., “The Effect of Drive Cycles on PM Emission Characteristics from a Gasoline Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1119, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1119.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graskow, B.R., Kittelson, D.B., Abdul-Khalek, I.S., Ahmadi, M.R. et al., “Characterization of Exhaust Particulate Emissions from a Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 980528, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980528.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei, Q., Ichiro, A., Adachi, M., Montajir, R.M. et al., “Real-Time Measuring System for Engine Exhaust Solid Particle Number Emission - Performance and Vehicle Tests,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0865, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0865.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. Code of Federal Regulations, e-CFR</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">California air resources board, emission inventory, http://www.arb.ca.gov/ei/emissiondata.htm</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
