<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440059</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Apply with Caution: Introducing UK-Style In-Work Support in Germany</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Peter</given-names>
                  <surname>Haan</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Michał</given-names>
                  <surname>Myck</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2007</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440056</issue-id>
         <fpage>43</fpage>
         <lpage>72</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2007</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440059"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Estimates of the labour supply effects of recent UK reforms in the area of direct taxes and benefits show that policy can have significant influence on the level of employment. We confirm this in a simulation of an in-work support system introduced into the German tax and benefit system. Our simulation results suggest that introducing in-work tax credits in Germany would increase the employment of single individuals by over 105,000 but would result in a reduction of labour supply among individuals living in couples by about 70,000, among both women and men. The result found for men is especially important as it is markedly different from all results for the UK, where the net response among men has always been found to be positive. Our estimation results call for a high degree of caution as far as 'importing' UK-style tax credits to Germany is concerned. In-work support based on family income would reinforce the existing work disincentives for secondary earners, reducing the employment levels of both men and women living in couples.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1e272a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e279" publication-type="other">
Submitted February 2006.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e286a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e293" publication-type="other">
Steiner and Wrohlich (2004) discuss in detail positive and negative work incentives for first and
secondary earners in married couples induced by joint taxation in Germany. They find that the
employment rate of secondary earners in Germany would markedly increase following a move from joint
to individual taxation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e309a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e316" publication-type="other">
In this paper, 'in-work support' refers to government transfers that are conditional on employment. In
Germany, people can receive government transfers while working, but there are no transfers that are
strictly conditional on being employed (the only minor exception to this is the so-called child supplement
(.Kinderzuschlag); see Section IV. 1).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e332a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e339" publication-type="other">
The comparison of labour markets focuses on employment rates rather than on unemployment or
labour force participation rates, which are the two most obvious alternative measures, to limit the effect
of the definitional and institutional differences between Britain and Germany concerning the
unemployed. Employment levels found in the data used here are consistent with OECD statistics on
employment for the two countries (see OECD (2005a)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e359a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e366" publication-type="other">
A description of GSOEP can be downloaded from www.diw.de/soep; see also Haisken-DeNew and
Frick (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e376a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e383" publication-type="other">
For Germany, we use the data collected in 2003 as they contain the information about fiscal year
2002. The FRS data are collected to overlap with the government budget calendar, i.e. from April to
March. When we refer to a 2002-03 data-set for the FRS, it means that we are considering the data-set
for April 2002 to March 2003.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e399a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e406" publication-type="other">
The higher employment rate for women is mainly due to the higher labour market participation of
women in east Germany. As documented in previous literature, due to the different histories, the labour
market behaviour of women is still quite different between east and west Germany (see, for example,
Haan and Steiner (2006)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e422a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e429" publication-type="other">
For details, see Haan and Myck (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e436a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e443" publication-type="other">
Monetary values used for comparative purposes are expressed in euros using the purchasing power
parity (PPP) corrected exchange factor of €/£ = 0.6365 (calculated as the ratio of the UK PPP factor to
the German PPP factor from the OECD PPP tables at www.oecd.org/std/ppp). To express weekly values
of net incomes and benefits (as is standard practice in the UK) in monthly terms (as is standard in
Germany), we multiply weekly values by a factor of 4.35 - the average number of weeks in a month
(= 365.25/12/7).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e466a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e473" publication-type="other">
Note that this comparison needs to be interpreted carefully as we focus only on the tax and benefit
system but leave out a comparison of important institutions, such as labour market institutions, the
education system, childcare, the generosity and quality of public healthcare and other types of public
expenditure. Further, for better comparison, we assume in all examples for Germany that individuals are
not eligible for the insurance-based unemployment benefit (Arbeitslosengeld) as this is not a permanent
transfer. Instead, households receive means-tested social benefits that are the equivalent of the UK's
income support.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e500a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e507" publication-type="other">
The same applies to lone-parent families with one child (not shown on Figure 1).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e514a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e521" publication-type="other">
As well as relating to income splitting for one-earner couples, the higher disposable incomes of
families with children in Germany relate to receipt of the universal Kindergeld, which in 2002 was €154
for each of the two children per month. The universal child benefit in the UK in 2002 was lower, at
€107.65 for the first child and €72.10 for each subsequent child in the family.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e537a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e544" publication-type="other">
Haan and Steiner (2006) provide a detailed description of the reforms and simulate their labour
supply and employment effects. They show that the reforms significantly increased labour supply
incentives, in particular for households with relatively high income.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e557a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e564" publication-type="other">
This reform is described in detail in Steiner and Wrohlich (2005), and its effects on work incentives
have been estimated by, for example, Steiner and Wrohlich (2005) and Bargain et al. (2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e574a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e581" publication-type="other">
For more detail, see Steiner (2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e588a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e595" publication-type="other">
The UK system also includes a generous childcare credit and additional premiums for families with
newborn babies and for working disabled people. These are not modelled in our paper. For more details
of the recent UK reforms, see Brewer (2003). More details concerning the design of the UK system in
2005 can be found in Haan and Myck (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e612a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e619" publication-type="other">
As far as generosity of the tax credits is concerned, we have decided to exclude the family premium
element of the UK's CTC (see, for example, Haan and Myck (2005)). This is done on the grounds that
such extension of child-related support so far up the income distribution in the system with an already
high level of universal support (see footnote 11) would be very costly and therefore unlikely to be
implemented. Moreover, because of systemic differences in the way childcare is organised in Germany
and the UK, and how it is supported through various channels, we do not include childcare subsidies in
the tax credits. Such subsidies used to be an element of the WFTC and continue to be a part of the in-
work support system in the UK. As mentioned above, average childcare costs are relatively low in
Germany compared with the UK. The problem in Germany is the low availability of childcare places, and
modelling childcare supply constraints goes beyond the scope of this paper. We think that given these
supply constraints and already low childcare costs, such additional childcare subsidies would, in reality,
have only a modest effect on employment in Germany.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e661a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e668" publication-type="other">
We assume that working hours can be described by a distribution with six discrete points. We define
on hours intervals 0, (0,12), [12,20), [20,34), [34,40] and &gt;40 according to the empirical distribution in
the data (GSOEP 2003). The empirical mean of the distribution describes the discrete hours points. For
couples, we assume a joint labour supply model and specify 6x6 discrete points. For more details, see
Bargain et al. (2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e687a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e694" publication-type="other">
For further information with descriptive statistics and a discussion of the main results, see Bargain et
al. (2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e704a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e711" publication-type="other">
We have estimated the effect of tax credits on couples where one spouse is self-employed, in
education or retired, or older than 59. We find that the effects for both men and women are negligible.
Simulation results for these groups can be obtained from the authors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e724a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e731" publication-type="other">
We cannot estimate preferences directly for 2005 as the data for fiscal year 2005 are not yet
available.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e741a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e748" publication-type="other">
Labour supply effects induced by the fiscal reforms between 2002 and 2005 are not discussed here.
In general, the 2005 system induces higher labour supply incentives, mainly due to the income tax
reform. Haan and Steiner (2006) estimate an employment effect of the tax reform of about 150,000
additional participants. Estimated labour supply effects of the Hartz Reform (for example, the Minijob
reform) are of negligible size; see Steiner and Wrohlich (2005) or Bargain et al. (2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e768a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e775" publication-type="other">
Note that this does not necessarily mean that these would then become two-earner couples since we
cannot say much, on the basis of Table 6, about the employment status of the men in this case under the
simulated system.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e788a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e795" publication-type="other">
For a summary of results, see Blundell and Reed (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e802a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e809" publication-type="other">
We do not report labour supply effects separately by the age of children here. Results can be
obtained from the authors on request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e819a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e826" publication-type="other">
A system of individual tax credits could replace the Minijob subsidies, which support employment at
very low hours of work.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d1e845a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e849" publication-type="other">
Bargain, O., Caliendo, M., Haan, P. and Orsini, K. (2006), 'Making work pay in a rationed
labour market', IZA, Discussion Paper no. 2033.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e859a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e863" publication-type="other">
— and Orsini, K. (2006), 'In-work policies in Europe: killing two birds with one stone?',
Labour Economics, vol. 13, pp. 667-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e873a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e877" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R., Brewer, M. and Shephard, A. (2005), Evaluating the Labour Market Impact of
Working Families' Tax Credit using Difference-in-DiJferences, London: HM Revenue
and Customs.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e890a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e894" publication-type="other">
—, Duncan, A., McCrae, J. and Meghir, C. (2000), 'The labour market impact of the working
families' tax credit', Fiscal Studies, vol. 21, pp. 75-103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e905a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e909" publication-type="other">
— and Reed, H. (2000), The Employment Effects of the Working Families' Tax Credit,
Briefing Note no. 6, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e919a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e923" publication-type="other">
Bonin, H., Kempe, W. and Schneider, H. (2003), 'Household labor supply effects of low-
wage subsidies in Germany', Journal of Applied Social Sciences Studies, vol. 123, pp.
199-208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e936a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e940" publication-type="other">
Brewer, M. (2003), The New Tax Credits, Briefing Note no. 35, London: Institute for Fiscal
Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e950a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e954" publication-type="other">
—, Duncan, A., Shephard, A. and Suarez, M. J. (2005), Did Working Families' Tax Credit
Work? The Final Evaluation of the Impact of In-Work Support on Parents' Labour
Supply and Take-Up Behaviour in the UK, London: HM Revenue and Customs.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e967a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e971" publication-type="other">
Creedy, J. and Duncan, A. (2002), 'Behavioural microsimulation with labour supply
responses', Journal of Economic Surveys, vol. 16, pp. 1-39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e981a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e985" publication-type="other">
Gregg, P., Johnson, P. and Reed, H. (1999), Entering Work and the British Tax and Benefit
System, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e996a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1000" publication-type="other">
Haan, P. (2006), 'Much ado about nothing: conditional logit vs. random coefficient models
for estimating labour supply elasticities', Applied Economics Letters, vol. 13, no. 4, pp.
251-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1013a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1017" publication-type="other">
— and Myck, M. (2005), 'Apply with caution: introducing UK-style in-work support in
Germany', DIW, Discussion Paper no. 555.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1027a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1031" publication-type="other">
— and Steiner, V. (2006), 'Labor market effects of the German tax reform', in C. Dreger, H.
P. Galler and U. Walwei (eds), Determinants of Employment: The Macroeconomic View,
Baden-Baden: Nomos.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1044a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1048" publication-type="other">
Haisken-DeNew, J. and Frick, J. (2005), Desktop Companion to the German Socio-Economic
Panel Study (GSOEP), Berlin: DIW.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1058a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1062" publication-type="other">
Immervoll, H. and Barber, D. (2006), 'Can parents afford to work? Childcare costs, tax-
benefit policies and work incentives', IZA, Discussion Paper no. 1932.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1072a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1076" publication-type="other">
McFadden, D. (1974), 'Conditional logit analysis of qualitative choice behavior', in P.
Zarembka (ed.), Frontiers in Econometrics, New York: Academic Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1087a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1091" publication-type="other">
Myck, M. and Reed, H. (2005), Disabled People in a Dynamic Model of Labour Supply and
Labour Market Transitions, DWP Research Report no. 274, London: Department for
Work and Pensions.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1104a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1108" publication-type="other">
Ochel, W. (2003), 'Welfare to work in the US: a model for Germany?', FinanzArchiv, vol. 59,
pp. 91-119.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1118a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1122" publication-type="other">
OECD (2005a), Employment Outlook 2005: Statistical Annex, Paris: Organisation for
Economic Cooperation and Development.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1132a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1136" publication-type="other">
— (2005b), Society at a Glance: OECD Social Indicators, Paris: Organisation for Economic
Cooperation and Development.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1146a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1150" publication-type="other">
Steiner, V. (2004), 'Social welfare reform and the low-wage labor market in Germany: what
works and what doesn't?', Applied Economics Quarterly, Supplement, vol. 55, pp. 57-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1160a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1164" publication-type="other">
—, Haan, P. and Wrohlich, K. (2005), Dokumentation des Steuer-Transfer
Mikrosimulationsmodells STSM - Version 1999-2002, DIW Data Documentation 2005-
09, Berlin: DIW.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1178a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1182" publication-type="other">
— and Wrohlich, K. (2004), 'Household taxation, income splitting and labor supply
incentives: a microsimulation study for Germany', CESifo Economic Studies, vol. 50, pp.
541-68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1195a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1199" publication-type="other">
— and — (2005), 'Work incentives and labor supply effects of the "Mini-Jobs Reform" in
Germany', Empirica, vol. 32, pp. 91-116.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1209a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1213" publication-type="other">
Van Soest, A. (1995), 'Structural models of family labor supply: a discrete choice approach',
Journal of Human Resources, vol. 30, pp. 63-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1223a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1227" publication-type="other">
Wrohlich, K. (2005), 'The excess demand for subsidised child care in Germany', IZA,
Discussion Paper no. 1515.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
