<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277774</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Ultra Boost for Economy</article-title>
            <subtitle>Extending the Limits of Extreme Engine Downsizing</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Turner</surname>
                  <given-names>J.W.G.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Jaguar Land Rover</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Popplewell</surname>
                  <given-names>A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Jaguar Land Rover</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Patel</surname>
                  <given-names>R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Jaguar Land Rover</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johnson</surname>
                  <given-names>T.R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Jaguar Land Rover</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Darnton</surname>
                  <given-names>N.J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Jaguar Land Rover</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Richardson</surname>
                  <given-names>S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Jaguar Land Rover</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bredda</surname>
                  <given-names>S.W.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>GE Precision Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tudor</surname>
                  <given-names>R.J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lotus Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bithell</surname>
                  <given-names>C.I.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lotus Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jackson</surname>
                  <given-names>R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lotus Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Remmert</surname>
                  <given-names>S.M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Shell Global Solutions (UK)</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cracknell</surname>
                  <given-names>R.F.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Shell Global Solutions (UK)</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fernandes</surname>
                  <given-names>J.X.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>CD-adapco</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lewis</surname>
                  <given-names>A.G.J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bath</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Akehurst</surname>
                  <given-names>S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bath</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Brace</surname>
                  <given-names>C.J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bath</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Copeland</surname>
                  <given-names>C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bath</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Martinez-Botas</surname>
                  <given-names>R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Imperial College London</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Romagnoli</surname>
                  <given-names>A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Imperial College London</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Burluka</surname>
                  <given-names>A.A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Leeds</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>May 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277742</issue-id>
         <fpage>387</fpage>
         <lpage>417</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277774"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The paper discusses the concept, design and final results from the ‘Ultra Boost for Economy’ collaborative project, which was part-funded by the Technology Strategy Board, the UK's innovation agency. The project comprised industry- and academia-wide expertise to demonstrate that it is possible to reduce engine capacity by 60% and still achieve the torque curve of a modern, large-capacity naturally-aspirated engine, while encompassing the attributes necessary to employ such a concept in premium vehicles.</p>
            <p>In addition to achieving the torque curve of the Jaguar Land Rover naturally-aspirated 5.0 litre V8 engine (which included generating 25 bar BMEP at 1000 rpm), the main project target was to show that such a downsized engine could, in itself, provide a major proportion of a route towards a 35% reduction in vehicle tailpipe CO₂ on the New European Drive Cycle, together with some vehicle-based modifications and the assumption of stop-start technology being used instead of hybridization. In order to do this vehicle modelling was employed to set part-load operating points representative of a target vehicle and to provide weighting factors for those points. The engine was sized by using the fuel consumption improvement targets and a series of specification steps designed to ensure that the required full-load performance and driveability could be achieved.</p>
            <p>The engine was designed in parallel with 1-D modelling which helped to combine the various technology packages of the project, including the specification of an advanced charging system and the provision of the necessary variability in the valvetrain system. An advanced intake port was designed in order to ensure the necessary flow rate and the charge motion to provide fuel mixing and help suppress knock, and was subjected to a full transient CFD analysis. A new engine management system was provided which necessarily had to be capable of controlling many functions, including a supercharger engagement clutch and full bypass system, direct injection system, port-fuel injection system, separately-switchable cam profiles for the intake and exhaust valves and wide-range fast-acting camshaft phasing devices.</p>
            <p>Testing of the engine was split into two phases. The first usied a test bed Combustion Air Handling Unit to enable development of the combustion system without the complication of a new charging system being fitted to the engine. To set boundary conditions during this part of the programme, heavy reliance was placed on the 1-D simulation. The second phase tested the full engine.</p>
            <p>The ramifications of realizing the engine design from a V8 basis in terms of residual friction versus the fuel consumption results achieved are also discussed. The final improvement in vehicle fuel economy is demonstrated using a proprietary fuel consumption code, and is presented for the New European Drive Cycle, the FTP-75 cycle and a 120 km/h (75 mph) cruise condition.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, McGraw-Hill Book Company, New York, USA, 1988, ISBN 0-07- 100499-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Osborne, R., Stokes, J., Ceccarini, D., Jackson, N., Lake, T., Joyce, M., Visser, S., Miche, N., Begg, S., Heikal, M., Kalian, N., Zhao, H. and Ma, T., “The 2/4SIGHT Project - Development of a Multi-Cylinder Two-Stroke/Four-Stroke Switching Gasoline Engine”, JSAE paper number 20085400 and JSAE 2008 Proceedings No. 79-08, pp. 11-16, ISSN 0919-1364, JSAE 2008 Congress, Yokohama, Japan, 21st-23rd May, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner, J.W.G. and Pearson R.J., “The turbocharged directinjection spark-ignition engine”, in Zhao H. (ed.), Direct injection combustion engines for automotive applications: Science and technology. Part 1: spark-ignition engines, Woodhead Publishing Limited, Cambridge CB21 6AH, UK, 2009, ISBN 1-84569-389-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steinparzer, F., Unger, H., Brüner, T. and Kannenberg, D., “The new BMW 2.0 litre 4-cylinder S.I. engine with Twin Power Turbo Technology”, 32nd Vienna Motor Symposium, Vienna, Austria, 5th- 6th May, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steinparzer, F., Klüting, M. and Poggel, J., “The new BMW V8 Powertrains: Customer Value through Turbocharging and Fully Variable Valvetrain”, 33rd International Vienna Motor Symposium, Book 1 pp. 72-84, Vienna, Austria, 26th-27th April, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borrman, D., Kuhlbach, K., Friedfeldt, R., Mehring, J. and Fritsche, R., “Cylinder Head Integrated Exhaust Manifold IEM Applied for Gasoline Downsizing Concepts”, 17th Aachen Colloquium, pp. 1001-1017, Aachen, Germany, 6th-8th October, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Helduk, T., Dornhöfer, R., Eiser, A., Grigo, M., Pelzer, A. and Wurms, R., “The new generation of the R4 TFSI engine from Audi”, 32nd Vienna Motor Symposium, Vienna, Austria, 5th-6th May, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ernst, R., Friedfeldt, R., Lamb, S., Lloyd-Thomas, D., Phlips, P., Russell, R. and Zenner, T., “The New 3 Cylinder 1.0L Gasoline Direct Injection Turbo Engine from Ford”, 20th Aachen Colloquium, pp. 53-72, Aachen, Germany, 11-12th October, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coltman, D., Turner, J., Curtis, R., Blake, D. et al., “Project Sabre: A Close-Spaced Direct Injection 3-Cylinder Engine with Synergistic Technologies to Achieve Low CO2 Output,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):129-146, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krebs, R., Szengel, R., Middendorf, H., Fleiß, M., Laumann, A. and Voeltz, S., “The New Dual-Charged FSI Petrol Engine by Volkswagen Part 1: Design”, MTZ 11/2005, Volume 66, pp. 2-7, November 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Möller, C., Johansson, P., Grandin, B., and Lindström, F., “Divided Exhaust Period - A Gas Exchange System for Turbocharged SI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1150, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1150.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roth, D., Keller, P., and Sisson, J., “Valve-Event Modulated Boost System,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1222, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1222.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hu, B., Akehurst, S., Brace, C., Copeland, C. et al., “1-D Simulation Study of Divided Exhaust Period for a Highly Downsized Turbocharged SI Engine - Scavenge Valve Optimization,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(3):in press, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1656.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krebs, R., Szengel, R., Middendorf, H., Sperling, H., Siebert, W., Theobald, J. and Michels, K., “The New Dual-Charged FSI Petrol Engine by Volkswagen Part 2: Thermodynamics”, MTZ 12/2005, Volume 66, pp. 23-26, December 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McAllister, M.J. and Buckley D.J., “Future gasoline engine downsizing technologies - CO2 improvements and engine design considerations”, paper number C684/018, pp. 19-26, Institution of Mechanical Engineers Internal Combustion Engines Conference, London, UK, 8th-9th December, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hancock, D., Fraser, N., Jeremy, M., Sykes, R. et al., “A New 3 Cylinder 1.2l Advanced Downsizing Technology Demonstrator Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0611, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0611.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salamon, C., McAllister, M., Robinson, R., Richardson, S., Martinez-Botas, R., Romagnoli, A., Copeland, C. and Turner, J.W.G., “Improving Fuel Economy by 35% through combined Turbo and Supercharging on a Spark Ignition Engine”, 21st Aachen Colloquium, pp. 1317-1346, Aachen, Germany, 8th-10th October, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sandford, M., Page, G., and Crawford, P., “The All New AJV8,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1060, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01- 1060.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wurms, R., Budack, R., Böhme, J., Dornhöfer, R., Eiser, A. and Hatz, W., “The New 2.0L TFSI with the Audi Valvelift System for the Audi A4 - The Next Generation of the Audi TFSI Technology”, 17th Aachen Colloquium, pp. 1067-1089, Aachen, Germany, 6th-8th October, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Copeland, C., Martinez-Botas, F., Turner, J.W.G., Pearson, R., Luard, N., Carey, C., Richardson, S., di Martino, P. and Chobola, P., “Boost System Selection for a Heavily Downsized Spark Ignition Prototype Engine”, 10th International Conference on Turbochargers and Turbocharging, London, UK, 15th-16th May, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robson, G., “Rallying - The Four-Wheel Drive Revolution”, G T Foulis &amp; Co Ltd, 2nd Ed., 1st September, 1988, ISBN 0854297235.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner, J., Pearson, R., Curtis, R., and Holland, B., “Improving Fuel Economy in a Turbocharged DISI Engine Already Employing Integrated Exhaust Manifold Technology and Variable Valve Timing,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2449, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2449.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lewis, A., Akehurst, S., Turner, J., Patel, R. et al., “Observations on the Measurement and Performance Impact of Catalyzed vs. Non- Catalyzed EGR on a Heavily Downsized DISI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(1):458-467, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1196.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Remmert, S., Cracknell, R., Head, R., Schuetze, A. et al., “Octane Response in a Downsized, Highly Boosted Direct Injection Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 7(1):in press, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1397.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahnz, C., Han, K., Spicher, U., Magar, M. et al., “Investigations on Pre-Ignition in Highly Supercharged SI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):214-224, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zahdeh, A., Rothenberger, P., Nguyen, W., Anbarasu, M. et al., “Fundamental Approach to Investigate Pre-Ignition in Boosted SI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):246-273, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0340.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Palaveev, S., Magar, M., Kubach, H., Schiessl, R. et al., “Premature Flame Initiation in a Turbocharged DISI Engine - Numerical and Experimental Investigations,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):54-66, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0252.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner, J.W.G., Pearson, R.J., Milovanovic, N. and Taitt, D., “Extending the knock limit of a turbocharged gasoline engine via turboexpansion”, 8th Institution of Mechanical Engineers Conference on Turbochargers and Turbocharging, London, UK, May 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner, J.W.G., “Interactions Between Charge Conditioning, Knock and Spark-Ignition Engine Architecture”, Ph.D. Thesis, Loughborough University, Loughborough, UK, April 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taylor, J., Fraser, N., and Wieske, P., “Water Cooled Exhaust Manifold and Full Load EGR Technology Applied to a Downsized Direct Injection Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):225-240, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smith, P. and Cheng, W., “Assessing the Loss Mechanisms Associated with Engine Downsizing, Boosting and Compression Ratio Change,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0929, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0929.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hart, M., Gindele, J., Ramsteiner, Th., Thater, G., Tschamon, B., Karres, M., Keiner, B. and Fischer J., “The New High-performance 4-cylinder Engine with Turbocharging from AMG”, 34th International Vienna Motor Symposium, Vienna, Austria, 25th-26th April, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuhlbach, K., Brinkmann, F., Bartsch, G., Weber, C., Do, G. and Jeckel, D., “Parallel sequential twin turbo boosting system applied to a 1.6 l DI gasoline engine”, paper number 108, 18th Supercharging Conference, Dresden, Germany, 12th-13th September, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuhlbach, K., Brinkmann, F., Werner, J., Kiener, T. and Becker, M., “Innovative Two-Stage Turbocharging System with Cooled Regulating Valve for Gasoline Engines”, 22nd Aachen Colloquium, pp. 951-974, Aachen, Germany, 8th-9th October, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ardey, N., Wichtl, R., Steinmayr, T., Kaufmann, M., Hiemesch, D. and Stütz, W., “The All New BMW Top Diesel Engines”, 33rd International Vienna Motor Symposium, Book 1, pp. 111-136, Vienna, Austria, 26th-27th April, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
