<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816517</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Behavioral Retirement Savings Models (Behavioral)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Reference Dependence and The Social Security System</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Park</surname>
                  <given-names>Hyeon</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>21</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816517"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper studies an inter-temporal model to understand the role of social security in determining intergenerational distribution and welfare when consumers have reference-dependent preferences. To explore the effect of social security on consumer welfare, this paper introduces a parametric model of a unified social security system, by which different social security plans are represented via different degrees of fundedness. Using this unified social security system in an environment of OLG production economy, this paper analyzes the intergenerational distribution of consumption and welfare, and examines the effects of a transition from a less funded system to more funded one on savings, consumption, and capital accumulation for an economy populated by loss-averse agents. By deriving closed form solutions for the variables, this paper finds that an increase in the intensity of fundedness unambiguously increases capital accumulation and increase savings, but decreases consumption, when the population growth rate is greater than the net return on capital. This paper also finds that increases in tax rates increase savings unambiguously, whereas the effect on consumption is not conclusive.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>[1]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Bellettini, G.,Ceroni, C.B.,1999. Is social security really bad for growth? Review of Economic Dynamics 2, 796–819.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>[2]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Diamond, P., Orszag, P.R., 2005. Saving social security. Journal of Economic Perspectives 19 (2), 11–32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>[3]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Feldstein, M., 2005. Structural reform of social security. Journal of Economic Perspectives 19 (2), 33–55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>[4]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Groth, C., 2011. Lecture notes in Macroeconomics. Mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>[5]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Gyárfás, G., Marquardt, M., 2001. Pareto improving transition from a pay-as-you-go to a fully funded pension system in a model of endogenous growth. Journal of Population Economics 14, 445–454.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>[6]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Hines, J.R.,Taylor,T., 2005. Short falls in the long run: predictions about the social security trust fund. Journal of Economic Perspectives19, 3–9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>[7]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Kaganovich, M. and Zilcha, I., 2012, Pay-as-you-go or funded social security? A general equilibrium comparison. Journal of Economic Dynamics &amp; Control, 36, 455–467.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>[8]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Kahneman, D. and A. Tversky, 1979, Prospect Theory: An Analysis of Decision under Risk. Econometrica 47: 263–291.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>[9]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Konrad, K.,1995. Social security and strategic inter-vivos transfers of social capital. Journal of Population Economics 8,315–326.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>[10]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">K½oszegi, B., and M. Rabin, 2006, A Model of Reference-Dependent Preferences. Quarterly Journal of Economics 121: 1133–1165.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>[11]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">K½oszegi, B. and M. Rabin, 2007, Reference-Dependent Risk Attitudes. American Economic Review 97: 1047-1073.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>[12]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">K½oszegi, B. and M. Rabin, 2009, Reference-Dependent Consumption Plans. American Eco- nomic Review 99: 909-936.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>[13]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Kunze, L., 2012, Funded social security and economic growth. Economics Letters, 115, 180-183.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>[14]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Lambrecht, S., Michel, P., Vidal, J.-P., 2005. Public pensions and growth. European Economic Review 49, 1261–1281.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>[15]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Pecchenino, R.A.,Utendorf,K.R.,1999.Social security, social welfare and the aging population. Journal of Population Economics 12, 607–623.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>[16]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Zhang, J., 1995. Social security and endogenous growth. Journal of Public Economics 58, 185–213.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>[17]</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Zhang, J.,Zhang,J.,1998.Social security, intergenerational transfers, and endogenous growth. Canadian Journal of Economics 31,1225–1241.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>The following table shows the steady state profile of capital level, consumption, and saving for the two models regarding the three plans of social security system.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Next, I simulate the model to demonstrate the e¤ect of tax on various policy variables.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>From both of the .gures I .nd that increases in tax rates decrease savings unambiguously for all plans considered, whereas the e¤ect on consumption is not conclusive.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
