<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">18</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830381</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830386</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>FORGING COLLABORATION BETWEEN FORMAL AND INFORMAL FINANCIAL MARKETS: SOME THOUGHTS / NOUER LA COLLABORATION ENTRE MARCHÉS FINANCIERS INSTITUTIONNEL ET NON-INSTITUTIONNEL: QUELQUES RÉFLEXIONS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Gladson I.</given-names>
                  <surname>Nwanna</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1994</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>323</fpage>
         <lpage>334</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830386"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>It is widely acknowledged that future economic growth and development of Less Developed Countries (LDCs) will depend in part on efforts made in developing the rural sector and in improving the plight of rural inhabitants through support for their activities. Incidentally, the lack of accessibility to financial services is commonly, and increasingly, being cited as one of the major constraints to the development of the rural sector of LDCs. It comes as no surprise, therefore, at the heightened interest and efforts on the part of LDC governments and Development Assistance Agencies to explore avenues to improve, as well as, increase such access. In response to this challenge, various approaches and strategies have emerged. One such strategy places emphases on the need to forge collaboration between the formal and informal financial markets. It is believed that by upgrading informal financial arrangements and linking them to Formal Financial Institutions, financial services, particularly to the rural sector, the poor, and to microenterprises will be expanded and deepend. This paper explores avenues for forging that collaboration and linkage between the formal and informal financial markets. The importance of a linkage stems from the fact that in most LDCs, despite the many Informal Financial Institutions in operation and the active role played by these institutions in resource allocation and resource mobilization, not many of them have links with formal financial institutions. Il est communément reconnu que le futur de la croissance économique et le développement des Pays Moins Développés (PMD), dépend, en partie, des efforts qui seront déployés en vue de developper le secteur rural et d'améliorer la situation des paysans en leur donnant le soutien nécessaire pour leurs activités. Le manque d'accès aux services financiers est de plus en plus cité comme étant l'un des majeurs obstacles au développement du secteur rural dans les P.M.D. Il n'est donc pas surprenant de voir l'intérêt et les efforts sans cesse croissants des gouvernements des PMD et des agences d'aide au développement à explorer des voies qui puissent les aider à améliorer et à accroître un tel accès. Pour faire face à un tel défi, plusieurs approches et stratégies ont été proposées. L'une d'elles insiste sur la nécessité de promouvoir la collaboration entre les marchés financiers formel et informel. La croyance générale, est que, en améliorant les arrangements financiers informels et en les unissant aux institutions financières formelles, les services financiers, particulièrement le faible secteur rural, et aux microentreprises, sera élargi et approfondi. Cette communication explore les voies visant à promouvoir la collaboration et l'union entre les marchés financiers formel et informel. L'importance de cette union provient du fait que dans la plupart des pays moins développés malgré l'existence de nombreuses institutions financières informelles et le rôle actif de ces institutions dans l'allocation et la mobilisation de resources, peu d'entre elles ont des liens avec les institutions financières formelles.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d36e107a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e114" publication-type="other">
Gladson Nwanna, "Stimulating Savings
in the Informal Financial Sector of Less Developed Countries" The Journal of Social, Political and Economic Studies,
Washington D. C. (Vol. 14 No. 3, Fall 1989</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e126" publication-type="other">
Anan G. Chandavarkar, "The Non-institutional Financial Sector in
Developing Countries: Macroeconomic Implications for Savings Policies," Savings and Development, No. 2,1985.
p. 129.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e139a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e146" publication-type="other">
World Bank, World Development Report 1989, p. 119.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>Bibliography</title>
        <ref id="d36e162a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e166" publication-type="other">
Adams, Dale W. and Ghate, P.B.. Where to From Here in Informal Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e173a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e177" publication-type="other">
Adams, Dale W. and Vogel, Robert. Rural Financial Markets in Low-Income Countries: Recent Controversies and
Lessons, World Development. Vol. 14. No. 4,1986. pp. 477-487.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e187a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e191" publication-type="other">
Aryeetey, Ernest and Steel, William F. Incomplete Linkage Between Informal and Formal Finance in Ghana. May
1992 (Draft).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e201a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e205" publication-type="other">
Bhatia, R., and Khatkate, D.R. "Financial Intermediation, Savings Mobilization, and Entrepreneurial Development:
The African Experience," IMF Staff Papers, Vol. XII, Washington D.C. 1975.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e216a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e220" publication-type="other">
Braverman, Avishay and Guasch, J.L., "Rural Credit Markets and Institutions in Developing Countries: Lessons for
Policy Analysis from Practice and Modern Theory." World Development, Vol. 14, No. 10/11.1986.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e230a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e234" publication-type="other">
Chandavarkar, Anan G., "The Non-institutional Financial Sector in Developing Countries: Macroeconomic implica-
tions for Savings Policies," Savings and Development. No. 2, 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e244a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e248" publication-type="other">
Chipeta, C. and Mkandawire M.L.C. Mobilizing Domestic Savings for African Development and Diversification. A
case study of Malawi. 1989.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e258a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e262" publication-type="other">
Chipeta, C. and Mkandawire M.L.C. "The Informal Financial Sector in Malawi," African Review of Money, Finance
and Banking. No. 2, 1992.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e272a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e276" publication-type="other">
Duggleby Tamara J. Aryeetey, Ernest and Steel, William F. Formal and Informal Finance For Small Enterprises in
Ghana. April 1992 (Draft).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e286a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e290" publication-type="other">
Fry, M. J. "Financial Development: Theories and Recent Experience," Oxford Review of Economic Policy, Vol. V,
No. 4. 1989.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e301a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e305" publication-type="other">
Germidis, Dimitri. "Interlinking the Formal and Informal Financial Sectors in Developing Countries," Savings and
Development, No. 1, 1990-xiv.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e319" publication-type="other">
Hettige, Mala. Toward Financial Deepening in Sub-Saharan Africa: An Analytical Framework World Bank, May
1992 (Draft).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e329a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e333" publication-type="other">
Mauri, Arnaldo. "The role of Financial Intermediation in the Mobilisation and Allocation of Household Savings in
Developing Countries: Interlinks Between Organized and Informal circuits, The Case of Ethiopia." Paper
presented at the International Experts Meeting on Domestic Savings Mobilisation through Formal and
Informal Sectors: Comparative Experiences in Asia and African Developing Countries. East-West Center,
Honolulu, 2-4 June 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e352a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e356" publication-type="other">
Miracle, Marvin P., Diana S. Miracle, and Lauri Cohen. "Informal Savings Mobilization in Africa," Economic
Development and Cultural Change, Vol. 28, 1980.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e366a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e370" publication-type="other">
Nwanna, Gladson I., "Stimulating Savings in the informal Financial sector of Less Developed Countries," The
Journal of Social, Political and Economic Studies, Washington D.C., Vol. 14, No. 3, Fall 1989.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e380a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e384" publication-type="other">
Seibel, H.D. "Linking Informal and Formal Financial Institutions in Africa and Asia," in J. Levitsky.ed., Microenterprises
in Developing Countries, Intermediate Technology Publications, London. 1989.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e395a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e399" publication-type="other">
Seibel, H.D. and Marx, M.T. "Linking Formal and Informal Financial Institutions: A Saving and Credit Scheme for
Small Producers in Rural Areas", Journal of Financial Management and Analysis. 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e409a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e413" publication-type="other">
Shaw, E.S. "Financial Deepening in Economic Development,"Oxford University Press London. 1973.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e420a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e424" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz, J.E. "Financial Markets and Development," Oxford Review of Economic Policy, Vol V, No. 4.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e431a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e435" publication-type="other">
Wai, U.T. "The Role of Unorganized Financial Markets in Economic Development and the formulation of Monetary
Policy," Savings and Development, No A, 1980-iv.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e445a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e449" publication-type="other">
Von Pischke, J.D. Finance at the Frontier: Debt Capacity and the Role of Credit in the Private Economy, EDI
Development Studies, The World Bank, Washington D.C. 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e459a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e463" publication-type="other">
Von Pischke, J.D., Adams, Dale W. and Donald Gordon. Rural Financial Markets in Developing Countries.
Baltimore, The Johns Hopkins University Press 1983.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e474a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e478" publication-type="other">
World Bank, World Development Report 1989: Financial Systems and Development, Oxford University Press, New
York. 1989.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e488a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e492" publication-type="other">
World Bank, Financial Sector Study, Report No. 9889-MAI, 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e499a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e503" publication-type="other">
Yaron, Jacob. Successful Rural Finance Institutions, volume 1, The World Bank, August 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


