<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308472</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development and Testing of an Innovative Oil Condition Sensor</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Basu</surname>
                  <given-names>Amiyo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ruona</surname>
                  <given-names>Will</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zawacki</surname>
                  <given-names>Garry</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gangopadhyay</surname>
                  <given-names>Arup</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Scholl</surname>
                  <given-names>Dave</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Visser</surname>
                  <given-names>Jaco</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dobrinski</surname>
                  <given-names>Heiko</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Hella Fahrzeugkomponenten GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Doebrich</surname>
                  <given-names>Marco</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Hella Fahrzeugkomponenten GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>1327</fpage>
         <lpage>1334</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308472"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In order to detect degradation of engine oil lubricant, bench testing along with a number of diesel-powered Ford trucks were instruments and tested. The purpose of the bench testing was primarily to determine performance aspects such as repeatability, hysteresis effects and so on. Vehicle testing was conducted by designing and installing a separate oil reservoir along with a circulation system which was mounted in the vicinity of the oil pan. An innovative oil sensor was directly installed on the reservoir which can measure five (5) independent oil parameters (viscosity, density, permittivity, conductance, temperature). In addition, the concept is capable of detecting the oil level continuously during normal engine operation. The sensing system consists of an ultrasonic transducer for the oil level detection as well as a Tuning Fork mechanical resonator for the oil condition measurement. Also, the sensor includes an intelligent Oil Condition Algorithm (OCA) which evaluates the incoming signals from the sensor and calculates the current oil quality considering additional information from the engine. The OCA can detect contaminants and extreme oil conditions at an early stage. The vehicles tests are conducted by utilizing a drive cycle that includes city as well as highway driving. The output generated by the sensor is processed via an on-board Data Acquisition Platform (DAP) on a real-time basis. The data collected was uploaded via telematics to a server for subsequent analysis. The results thus obtained and the performance of the sensor will be presented in this paper.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Basu, Amiyo, et. al., "Smart Sensing" of Oil Degradation and Oil Level Measurements in Gasoline Engines, SAE 2000 World Congress, March 2000, Paper Number 2000-01-1366</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matsiev, L. F., Bennett, J. W., McFarland, E. W., Application of Low Frequency Mechanical Resonators to Liquid Property Measurements, 1998 IEEE Ultrasonics Symposium; pp. 459-462, s. a. Patent EP0943091B1, US6336353, US6494079.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matsiev, L. F., Application of Flexural Mechanical Resonators to High Throughput Liquid Characterization, Proceedings of 2000 IEEE Ultrasonics Symposium; pp. 427-434.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buhrdorf, A., Dobrinski, H., Lüdtke, O., Bennett, J.W., Matsiev, L.F., Uhrich, M., Kolosov, O., Multiparametric Oil Condition Sensor based on the Tuning Fork Technology for Automotive Applications, AMAA 2005 Yearbook, pp. 289-298.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bennett, J. W., Matsiev, L. F., Uhrich, M., Kolosov, O., Bryning, Z., New Solid State Oil Condition Sensor for Real Time Engine Oil Condition Monitoring, SAE 2006 World Congress &amp; Exhibition, April 2006, Detroit, MI, USA Proceedings, Document No. 2006-01- 1324.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dobrinski, H., Buhrdorf, A., Lüdtke, O., Knipper, U., Multiparameter Oil Condition Sensor based on the Tuning Fork Principle, SAE 2007 World Congress &amp; Exhibition, April 2007, Detroit, MI, USA Proceedings, Document No. 2007-01-0392.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dobrinski, H., Buhrdorf, A., Lindemann, M., Lüdtke, O., Combi-sensor for Oil Level and Oil Quality Management, SAE 2008 World Congress &amp; Exhibition, April 2008, Detroit, MI, USA Proceedings, Document No. 2008-01-0906.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jakoby, B., Vellekoop, M. J., Viscosity sensing using a Love-wave device, Sensors and Actuators A68, 1998, pp. 275-281.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Dommelen, I., Plastic Packaging for Various Sensor Applications in the Automotive Industry, AMAA 2002 Yearbook, pp. 289-296.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oil analysis performed by Intertek of the oil samples collected from two test vehicles during April – December, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
