<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica, Centre for Financial Assistance to African Countries</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i40209586</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44944817</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE ROLE OF COMMERCIAL BANKS IN FUNDING AGRICULTURE IN NIGERIA, (1960-1984)</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Aja</given-names>
                  <surname>Okorie</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1988</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>17</fpage>
         <lpage>35</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44944817"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Inadequate capital and production credit have been identified as major constraints to increased agricultural output as well as agricultural development in Nigeria. Thus, this paper examines the role of commercial banks in financing agricultural production credit in the past twenty-five years from independence (1960-1984). The commercial banks' lending to agriculture has been on the increase since independence, rising from N22.6 million in 1960 to N462.2 million in 1980, and N1,052.0 million in 1984. However, greater proportion of this has been channelled to financing of agricultural exports. The setting up of the Agricultural Credit Guarantee Scheme has resulted in increased channelling of funds to agricultural production by the commercial banks, though, more than 60 percent of this has been concentrated on livestock. Therefore, a lot still needs to be done to increase banks' funding to the food and tree sub-sectors. Major problems encountered by commercial banks in financing agricultural production credit are high rate of loan delinquency by farmers, high administrative cost resulting from small sizes of loans farmers demand, non-competitive interest rate prescribed for the agricultural sector by monetary authorities, lack of adequate and relevantly trained manpower to handle agricultural loans in commercial banks, and other problems arising from government policy instability. Improving the farmers' attitude and repayment ability and banking environment, as well as formulating more consistent government policies on agricultural development will enhance greater flow of funds from the commercial banks to agriculture. Le faible taux d'investissement et de crédit à court terme ont été considérés comme les goulots d'étranglement les plus importants pour la croissance de la production agricole et pour le développement du secteur agricole au Nigéria. Partant de cette constatation, cet article analyse le rôle joué par les banques commerciales dans le financement du crédit à la production dans les 25 années qui ont suivi l'indépendance du pays (1960-84). Le montant des crédits des banques commerciales destiné au secteur agricole a enregistré après l'indépendance une progression croissante: de 22,6 millions (1960) à 462,2 (1980) et enfin à 1.052,0 millions (1984). Il faut toutefois remarquer que la plus grande partie de ces crédits a été canalisée vers l'agriculture d'exportation. L'établissement de l'“Agricultural Credit Guarantee Scheme” a provoqué une augmentation des fonds des banques commerciales en direction de la production agricole. Comme plus de 60% de ce montant a déjà été consacré à l'élevage, on doit s'efforcer maintenant d'augmenter les fonds destinés aux secteurs de l'alimentation et des plantations. Les problèmes les plus graves que les banques commerciales ont dû affronter pour le financement de la production agricole sont ceux relatifs: 1) au pourcentage élevé des prêts non remboursés, 2) aux coûts administratifs très élevés dûs à une demande de crédit provenant des exploitations agricoles de petite dimension, 3) aux taux d'intérêt non concurrentiels fixés par les autorités monétaires pour les prêts au secteur agricole, 4) au manque de personnel capable et bien formé pour gérer les prêts agricoles dans les banques commerciales et pour résoudre les autres problèmes découlant de l'instabilité des politiques économiques des pouvoirs publics. Pour accroître considérablement le flux de fonds des banques commerciales destinés au secteur agricole il faudra améliorer le comportement et la capacité de remboursement des exploitants agricoles, moderniser l'environnement bancaire et enfin formuler avec plus de précision les politiques publiques pour le développement du secteur agricole.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1382982e153a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e160" publication-type="other">
Ahaiwe, M.O. «A Critical Evaluation of Imo State Supervised Agricultural Scheme (1977-1984)». Unpublished
Postgraduate Diploma Project, Department of Agricultural Economics, University of Nigeria, Nsukka, 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e170a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e177" publication-type="other">
Arene, C.J. «An Appraisal of Supervised Agricultural Credit Scheme in Anambra State, Nigeria». Unpublished
M.Sc. Thesis, Department of Agricultural Economics, University of Nigeria, Nsukka, May, 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e187a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e194" publication-type="other">
Adesoye, A.K.A. «The Role of Commercial Banks in Financing Agricultural Production Credit in Nigeria
(1960-1980)». B.Sc. Research Project, Department of Agricultural Economics, University of Ibadan, June
1982.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e207a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e214" publication-type="other">
Ahanor, B.U. «Manpower Development in the Banking Industry». The Bullion Vol. 5, No. 4, Central Bank
of Nigeria, Lagos, pp. 32-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e225a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e232" publication-type="other">
Aneke, S.O. «Sources, Uses and Problems of Small-Scale Farmers in Nkanu and Udi Local Government
Areas of Anambra State». B.Sc. Research Project, Department of Agricultural Economics, University of
Ibadan, June, 1981.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e245a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e252" publication-type="other">
Cardoso, F.B. «Commercial Banking in Nigeria: Functions, Organization and Major Problems» in Anniver-
sary Bulletin Part II, Central Bank of Nigeria, Lagos, pp. 73-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e262a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e269" publication-type="other">
Central Bank of Nigeria. Annual Report and Statement of the Year Ended 31 December, 1984.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e276a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e283" publication-type="other">
Central Bank of Nigeria. Agricultural Credit Guarantee Scheme Fund: Third Annual Report and Statement
of Accounts for the Year Ended December, 1980, Lagos.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e293a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e300" publication-type="other">
Federal Office of Statistics. Rural Agricultural Sample Survey 1980/81 (Survey Report No. FOS/RASS/83/1.
Agrie. Surveys Unit, January, 1983.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e310a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e317" publication-type="other">
Godwin, J.B. and R. Selley, «Review of Small Farmer Credit in Ghana». U.S.A. I.D. Spring Review of Small
Farmer Credit, Vol. VI, 1973.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e328a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e335" publication-type="other">
Ike, D.N. «A Financial Appraisal of the Agricultural Credit Guarantee Scheme Fund (ACGSF) in Nigeria».
Nigerian Journal of Financial Management, Vol. 3, No. 1, June 1984, pp. 94-104.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e345a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e352" publication-type="other">
Nwankwo, G.O. «Agricultural Finance: Policy and Strategy in 1980s». The Bullion Vol. 6, No. 4, October-
December, 1981. Central Bank of Nigeria, Lagos, pp. 8-14.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e362a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e369" publication-type="other">
Miller, L.F. «Present and Potential Use of Credit by Small Maize and Rice Farmers in Western and Kwara
States, Nigeria». Technical Report AETR/75.3 Department of Agrie. Econs. and Extension, University of
Ibadan, March, 1975.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e382a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e389" publication-type="other">
Obi, A.A., « Methods, Costs Efficiency and Improvement of Agricultural Credit Supervision». Unpublished
B.Sc. Project. Department of Agricultural Economics, University of Nigeria, Nsukka, June, 1980.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e399a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e406" publication-type="other">
Ogundipe, S.O. «Banking in Nigeria». A Paper Presented at the 13th Annual Banking Seminar, Institute of
Bankers, Lagos, 1978.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e416a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e423" publication-type="other">
Ogwuma, P.A. «The Role of Banks in Agricultural Financing». A Paper Presented during the Quarterly Lun-
cheon/Conference of the Lagos Chamber of Commerce, Lagos, 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e434a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e441" publication-type="other">
Okorie, Aja. «Major Determinants of Small-Holder Loan Repayment in a Developing Economy: An Empirical
Evidence from Ondo State». Journal of Administration (forthcoming). Applied Science Publishers.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e451a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e458" publication-type="other">
Okorie, Aja. «Government Budgetary Allocations: A Case Study of the Performance of the Commercial and
Merchant Banks' Prescribed Allocation of Credit to the Agricultural Sector». A Paper Presented at the
Second Biennial Conference of the Nigerian Association of Agricultural Economists, holding at University
of Nigeria, May 4-6, 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e474a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e481" publication-type="other">
Okorie, Aja. «Procedures, Terms and Structure of Commercial Banks' Lending to Agriculture in Nigeria».
Mimeograph, Department of Agrie. Econs., University of Nigeria, Nsukka, December, 1984.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e491a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e498" publication-type="other">
Olieh, C.N.E. «Financing Agricultural Development: Issues and Problems». The Bullion, July-September,
1980, Central Bank of Nigeria, Lagos, pp. 16-20.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e508a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e515" publication-type="other">
Patel, A.U. «Problems of Credit Faced in the Pilot Project on Rural Development». Paper Prepared for the
Course for Credit Supervisors of Western State Agricultural Credit Corporation, December 1975.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e525a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e532" publication-type="other">
Semowo, B.I., «Financing Agriculture». The Bullion, Vol. 4, No. 2, Jan.-March, 1979. Central Bank of Nigeria,
Lagos, pp. 12-16.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e543a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e550" publication-type="other">
Times International, «Supplement on Banking». Vol. 6, No. 43, July, 1985. Daily Times of Nigeria, Lagos.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1382982e557a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1382982e564" publication-type="other">
Von Pischke, J.D. Credit and Rural Finance in Africa: «Agrie. Successful Experiences». The Bullion, Vol.
6, No. 4, Oct.-Dec., 1981. Central Bank of Nigeria, Lagos, pp. 15-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


