<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26168970</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Inverter Dead-Time Compensation up to the Field Weakening Region with Respect to Low Sampling Rates</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sworowski</surname>
                  <given-names>Eugen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ZF Lenksysteme GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pötzl</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ZF Lenksysteme GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reuss</surname>
                  <given-names>Hans-Christian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Stuttgart</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>June 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26168958</issue-id>
         <fpage>112</fpage>
         <lpage>118</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26168970"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This report presents a new compensation method for distortions related to dead time, caused by B6-inverters with pulse-width-modulated output voltages. In spite of low sampling rates, the new method of compensation is effective at all ranges of rotation speed up to the field weakening region. No additional hardware is required for its implementation. The effectiveness of the new method has been shown experimentally. A description of the relevant distortions is given first to provide a basis for the development. This considers the field weakening region, and offers an illustrative method of quantifying the distortions. It is also shown that the use of compensation methods that do not take the sampling time into account leads to additional distortions. It is even possible that they exceed the distortions in an equivalent system without compensation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sworowski, E.; Pötzl, T.; Reuss, H.-C. (2011): Systematische Betrachtung von Störungen im Leistungsfluss elektromechanischer Lenkungen. In: 15. Internationaler Kongress, Elektronik im Kraftfahrzeug, VDI Baden-Baden Germany</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urasaki, N.; Senjyu, T.; Uezato, K.; Funabashi, T. (2005): An Adaptive Dead-Time Compensation Strategy for Voltage Source Inverter Fed Motor Drives. In: IEEE Trans. Power Electron 20 (5), Page(s): 1150-1160</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attaianese, C.; Tomasso, G. (2001): Predictive compensation of deadtime Effects in VSI Feeding Induction Motors. In: IEEE Trans. Industry Applications, Volume: 37, Issue: 3, Page(s): 856-863</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blaabjerg, F.; Pedersen, J.K.; Thoegersen, P. (1997): Improved Modulation Techniques for PWM-VSI Drives. In: IEEE Trans. Industrial Electronics Volume: 44, Issue: 1 Page(s): 87-95</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Choi, J.-W.; Yong, S.I.; Sul, S.-K. (1994): Inverter output voltage synthesis using novel dead time compensation. APEC ′94. Conference Proceedings 1994., Ninth Annual Page(s): 100-106 vol.1</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Choi, J.-W.; Sul, S.-K. (1995): A new compensation strategy reducing voltage-current distortion in PWM VSI systems operating with low output voltages, In: IEEE Trans. Industry Applications, Volume: 31, Issue: 5, Page(s): 1001-1008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, G.L.; Xu, D.G.; Yu, Y. (2008): A Novel Strategy of Dead-Time Compensation for PWM Voltage-Source Inverter. In: Twenty-Third Annual IEEE Applied Power Electronics Conference and Exposition, APEC 2008, Page(s): 1779-1783</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hwang, S.-H.; Kim, K.M. (2010): A Dead Time Compensation Method in Voltage-Fed PWM Inverter, In: IEEE Trans. Energy Conversion, Volume: 25, Issue: 1, Page(s): 1-10</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, H.-S.; Moon, H.-S.; Youn, M.-J. (2003): On-line dead-time compensation method using disturbance observer. In: IEEE Trans. Power Electron 18 (6), S. 1336-1345</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, J. (2002): A new approach of dead-time compensation for PWM voltage inverters, In: IEEE Trans. Circuits and Systems I: Fundamental Theory and Applications, Volume: 49, Issue: 4, Page(s): 476-483</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leggate, D.; Kerkman, R.J. (1995): Pulse Based Dead Time Compensator for PWM Voltage Inverters, In: Proceedings of the 1995 IEEE IECON 21st International Conference on Industrial Electronics, Control, and Instrumentation, Volume: 1, Page(s): 474-481</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Munoz-Garcia, A.; Lipo, T.A. (1998): Online dead-time compensation technique for open-loop PWM-VSI drives, In: Applied Power Electronics Conference and Exposition, 1998. APEC ′98. Conference Proceedings, Volume: 1, Page(s): 95-100</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murai, Y.; Watanabe, T.; Iwasaki, H. (1987): Waveform distortion and Correction Circuit for PWM Inverters with Switching Lag-Times, In: IEEE Trans. Industry Applications, Volume: IA-23, Issue: 5, Page(s): 881-886</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sepe, R.B.; Lang, J.H. (1994): Inverter Nonlinearities And Discrete- Time Vector Current Control. In: IEEE Trans. Industry Applications, Volume: 30, Issue: 1 Page(s): 62-70</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sukegawa, T.; Kamiyama, K.; Matsui, T.; Okuyama, T. (1991): Fully Digital, Vector-Controlled PWM VSI-Fed ac Drives with an Inverter Dead-Time Compensation Strategy, In: Conference Record of the 1988 IEEE Industry Applications Society Annual Meeting, Page(s): 463-469 vol.1</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urasaki, N.; Senjyu, T.; Kinjo, T.; Funabashi, T.; Sekine, H. (2005): Dead-time compensation strategy for permanent magnet synchronous motor drive taking zero current clamp and parasitc capacitance effects into account, In: IEE Proceedings Electric Power Applications, Volume: 152, Issue: 4, Page(s): 845-853</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H.; Wu, Q.M.J.; Kawamura, A. (2004): An accurate approach of nonlinearity compensation for VSI inverter output voltage, In: IEEE Trans. Power Electronics, Volume: 19, Issue: 4, Page(s): 1029-1035</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schröder, D.: Elektrische Antriebe 2 - Regelung von Antrieben. Berlin, Heidelberg, New York: Springer Verlag 1995</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
