<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">7</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466894</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466899</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Modeling Credit Contagion via the Updating of Fragile Beliefs</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Luca</given-names>
                  <surname>Benzoni</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Pierre</given-names>
                  <surname>Collin-Dufresne</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Robert S.</given-names>
                  <surname>Goldstein</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Jean</given-names>
                  <surname>Helwege</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1960</fpage>
         <lpage>2008</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466899"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We propose an equilibrium model for defaultable bonds that are subject to contagion risk. Contagion arises because agents with "fragile beliefs" are uncertain about the underlying economic state and its probability. Estimation on sovereign European credit default swaps (CDS) data shows that agents require a time-varying risk premium for bearing state uncertainty. The model outperforms affine specifications with the same number of state variables, suggesting that there are important nonlinearities in credit spreads that are captured by our model. Contagion drives most of the variation in CDS spreads, especially before the crisis. However, economic fundamentals account for a significant fraction during the crisis.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1305502e269a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e276" publication-type="other">
Examples include "Contagion fears hit bonds, euro," Wall Street Journal, November 30, 2010; "The Euro crisis:
A contagious Irish disease," The Economist, November 25, 2010; "Contagion fears push the Euro to fresh low,"
The Financial Times, November 29, 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e289a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e296" publication-type="other">
For example, John Cochrane writes, "The bailout is being justified on grounds of containing 'contagion.' This is
nonsense. The notion is that news of an Irish restructuring would scare investors in Spanish bonds, who would
start looking at Spain's ability to repay its debts and then demand higher interest rates. But haven't investors in
Spanish bonds already noticed that there's a bit of a problem? And wouldn't news of a giant bailout make these
investors question Spanish finances as much as would news of debt restructuring?" (" 'Contagion' and other euro
myths," Wall Street Journal, December 2, 2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e319a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e326" publication-type="other">
Decision theory in the presence of model ambiguity focuses on two sources of misspecification: (i) model
uncertainty conditional on the state, and (ii) uncertainty regarding the correct posterior distribution of the state
itself. The first channel, preference for robustness regarding model parameters, has been more extensively studied
in the literature. For example, it is well understood that, in a representative agent framework, the decision rule of
a log-utility investor who uses an entropy penalty is observationally equivalent to that of an agent with recursive
utility of the Epstein-Zin-Kreps-Porteus type (see, e.g., Barillas, Hansen, and Sargent 2009). However, the second
channel, which can be interpreted as a preference for robustness toward misspecification in their beliefs, is less
understood. One exception is the contemporaneous paper by Boyarchenko (2012) that investigates the impact
of ambiguity aversion on the U.S. financial crisis of 2007-08.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e358a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e365" publication-type="other">
The definition of rationality is perhaps debatable, since "fragile beliefs" preferences of Hansen and Sargent
(2007, 2010) are not considered "mainstream." As we discuss below, these preferences represent only a small
departure from the classic time-separable expected utility framework and are similar to using recursive utility of
the Epstein-Zin (EZ) form. (Barillas, Hansen, and Sargent [2009] investigate the connection between recursive
EZ utility and robust control.) Effectively, the model adds only one additional parameter, which governs tolerance
to model misspecification, relative to the standard time-separable log utility. The advantage relative to using the
more standard EZ preferences is that, in our context, fragile beliefs preferences are more tractable.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e392a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e399" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Duffie et al. (2003), Edwards (1984), Hilscher and Nosbusch (2010), Longstaff et al. (2010),
Min (1998), and Pan and Singleton (2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e409a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e418" publication-type="other">
Collin-Dufresne, Goldstein, and Hugonnier (2004) simplify the bond-pricing formula of Duffie, Schroeder,
and Skiadas (1996). Note, however, that the formula itself does not identify a tractable framework for pricing
contagion risk. Other models of contagion include Davis and Lo (2001), Schönbucher and Schubert (2001), and
Giesecke (2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e434a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e441" publication-type="other">
See also Aït-Sahalia, Cacho-Diaz, and Laeven (Forthcoming), and Benzoni, Collin-Dufresne, and Goldstein
(2011).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e451a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e458" publication-type="other">
Since the process X defined by Equation (3) is Gaussian, the conditional default intensity kis f in Equation (2)
can in theory turn negative. To minimize this problem, during estimation we add a penalty to the likelihood
function that is positive if, at any time t, kis. &lt; 0 for some country i and state s. We confirm that at the optimum
the conditional default intensities are indeed positive.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e474a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e481" publication-type="other">
The updating equation for the posterior probability from the purely continuous signals (which obtains if dMt =0
above) is well known in the literature (e.g., Detemple 1986; Gennotte 1986; David 1997; and Veronesi 1999).
The updating equation for the posterior probability of the state from pure jump signals (which obtains if dZt =0
in the above) follows from a direct application of Theorem 19.6 in Liptser and Shiryaev (2001, 332) (see also
their example 1, p. 333).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e500a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e507" publication-type="other">
This last result follows from the fact that we assumed the hidden state is fixed once and for all. It is possible to
extend our contagion model construction to a time-varying hidden state, for example, that follows a continuous-
time Markov chain, as in David (1997) and Veronesi (1999). This would make the uncertainty stationary. Instead,
in our model investors will eventually learn the "true" model of the world, which in long data sets will introduce
non-stationarity (e.g., in uncertainty premia). Given the relatively short time series we use in our empirical
application, this is not an issue, however, so we focus here on the simpler case.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e531a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e538" publication-type="other">
As we discuss in the online Appendix, using a time-separable utility function in the first step is closely related to
time consistency and thus to the tractability of our model.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e548a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e555" publication-type="other">
In the online Appendix we give an example of more general fragile beliefs preferences for which the state
prices derived from the two-stage process give rise to dynamic arbitrage opportunities. In that example, the
representative agent is not time-consistent. At time zero all claims, short- and long-dated, are valued such that
she does not want to trade given his current and anticipated future consumption. However, at future dates, if
markets reopen for trading at the prices consistent with time-zero state prices, the representative agent would
like to trade, implying that the initial state prices do not support a no-trade equilibrium.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e578a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e585" publication-type="other">
An alternative to having expected consumption growth carry a risk premium is to rely on long-run risk; see,
e.g., Benzoni, Collin-Dufresne, and Goldstein (2011), Drechsler and Yaron (2011), and Eraker and Shaliastovich
(2008). However, this setting no longer admits a closed-form solution.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e598a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e605" publication-type="other">
See, e.g, Beber, Brandt, and Luisi (2014) for an alternative approach to extract factors from a panel dataset of
macroeconomic news that help explain sovereign Euro-zone bond yields.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e615a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e622" publication-type="other">
Similar to Aruoba, Diebold, and Scotti (2009), we also considered an extension that allows the error term n. in
the MCI transition Equation (42) to be autocorrelated. We did not find statistical support for this specification
and therefore ruled it out.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e635a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e642" publication-type="other">
Specifically, we assume that each ßi s vector in the expression for the conditional default intensity of country i
(Equation (2)) has only two non-zero coefficients loading on the country-specific MCI,- and on the VIX.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e653a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e660" publication-type="other">
It is important to realize that Ç is not a scale-independent parameter, as its value depends on the particular
normalization of the value function chosen. For instance, if we divide the conditional value function everywhere
by ß, then the fragile beliefs value function (Equation (20)) is identical if we rewrite it in terms of £=£/£. Of
course, except for the magnitude of the estimate of the tolerance parameter, none of the empirical predictions
change. For example, the likelihood functions and the detection probabilities will be unchanged if we divide the
value function by a constant.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e683a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e690" publication-type="other">
With our current model specification absent model uncertainty there is no channel for time-varying risk premia.
It would be interesting to extend the model to allow for distinct channels of time-varying risk and risk premia
(such as long-run risk or habit formation) in addition to fragile beliefs. We leave this for future research.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e703a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e710" publication-type="other">
Recent work by Bidder and McKenna (2014) and Breuer and Csiszâr (2013) incorporates robustness against
misspecification of risk scenarios in stress tests for the banking system.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305502e720a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305502e727" publication-type="other">
On October 27, 2011, euro-zone leaders agreed upon a new package of measures aimed at containing the crisis.
The deal included a "voluntary" restructuring of Greek debt held by the private sector with a 50% haircut on the
bonds' value. Yet, the International Swaps and Derivatives Association ruled that such "voluntary" renegotiation,
no matter how much arm-twisting by European governments was involved, did not constitute a default event
and, therefore, would not trigger CDS protection. These events cast doubt on the effectiveness of CDS contract
as a means to hedge sovereign default risk. This legal uncertainty could add yet another component to the CDS
basis.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1305502e762a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e766" publication-type="other">
Acharya, V., I. Drechsler, and P. Schnabl. 2014. A Pyrrhic victory? Bank bailouts and sovereign credit risk.
Journal of Finance 69:2689-739.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e776a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e780" publication-type="other">
Aït-Sahalia, Y., J. Cacho-Diaz, and R. Laeven. Forthcoming. Modeling financial contagion using mutually
exciting jump processes. Journal of Financial Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e790a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e794" publication-type="other">
Aruoba, S. B., F. X. Diebold, and C. Scotti. 2009. Real-time measurement of business conditions. Journal of
Business and Economic Statistics 27:417-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e804a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e808" publication-type="other">
Bae, K.-H., A. Karolyi, and R. Stulz. 2003. Anew approach to measuring financial contagion. Review of Financial
Studies 16:717-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e819a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e823" publication-type="other">
Bai, J., P. Collin-Duffesne, R. Goldstein, and J. Helwege. 2015. On bounding credit-event risk premia. Review
of Financial Studies. Advance Access published March 13, 2015, 10.1093/rfs/hhv022.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e833a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e837" publication-type="other">
Barillas, F., L. P. Hansen, and T. J. Sargent. 2009. Doubts or variability? Journal of Economic Theory
144:2388-418.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e847a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e851" publication-type="other">
Beber, A., M. W. Brandt, and M. Luisi. 2014. Eurozone sovereign yield spreads and diverging economic
fundamentals. Working Paper, Cass Business School, Duke University, and Bloomberg.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e861a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e865" publication-type="other">
Benzoni, L., P. Collin-Dufresne, and R. Goldstein. 2011. Explaining asset pricing puzzles associated with the
1987 market crash. Journal of Financial Economics 101:552-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e875a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e879" publication-type="other">
Berndt, A., R. Douglas, D. Duffie, M. Ferguson, and D. Schranz. 2005. Measuring default risk premia from
default swap rates and EDFs. Working Paper, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e889a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e893" publication-type="other">
Bhamra, H., L.-A. Kuehn, and I. A. Strebulaev. 2010. The aggregate dynamics of capital structrure and
macroeconomic risk.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e904a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e908" publication-type="other">
Bidder, R., and A. McKenna. 2014. Robust stress testing. Working Paper, Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e915a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e919" publication-type="other">
Boyarchenko, N. 2012. Ambiguity shifts and the 2007-2008 financial crisis. Journal of Monetary Economics
59:493-507</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e929a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e933" publication-type="other">
Breuer, T., and I. Csiszâr. 2013. Systematic stress tests with entropie plausibility constraints. Journal of Banking
and Finance 37:1552-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e943a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e947" publication-type="other">
Calvo, G 1988. Servicing the public debt: The role of expectations. American Economic Review 78:647-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e954a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e958" publication-type="other">
Chen, H. 2010. Macroeconomic conditions and the puzzles of credit spreads and capital structure. Journal of
Finance 65:2171-212.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e968a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e972" publication-type="other">
Chen, L., P. Collin-Duffesne, and R. Goldstein. 2009. On the relation between the credit spread puzzle and the
equity premium puzzle. Review of Financial Studies 22:3367-409.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e983a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e987" publication-type="other">
Christoffersen, P. F., K. Jacobs, L. Karoui, and K. Mimouni. Forthcoming. Nonlinear filtering in affine term
structure models: Evidence from the term structure of swap rates. Management Science.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e997a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1001" publication-type="other">
Collin-Dufresne, P., R. Goldstein, and J. Hugonnier. 2004. A general formula for the valuation of defaultable
securities. Econometrica 72:1377-407.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1011a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1015" publication-type="other">
Das, S., D. Duffie, N. Kapadia, and L. Saita. 2007. Common failings: How corporate defaults are correlated.
Journal of Finance 62:93-117.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1025a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1029" publication-type="other">
Das, S., L. Freed, G Geng, and N. Kapadia. 2006. Correlated default risk. Journal of Fixed Income 16:1-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1036a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1040" publication-type="other">
David, A. 1997. Fluctuating confidence in stock markets: Implications for returns and volatility. Journal of
Financial and Quantitative Analysis 32:427-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1050a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1054" publication-type="other">
. 2008. Inflation uncertainty, asset valuations, and the credit spreads puzzle. Review of Financial Studies
21:2487-534.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1065a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1069" publication-type="other">
David, A., and P. Veronesi. 2002. Option prices with uncertain fundamentals: Theory and evidence on the
dynamics of implied volatilities. Working Paper, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1079a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1083" publication-type="other">
Davis, M., and V. Lo. 2001. Infectious defaults. Quantitative Finance 1:382-7.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1090a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1094" publication-type="other">
De Grauwe, P., and Y. Ji. 2013. Self-fulflling crises in the eurozone: An empirical test. Journal of International
Money and Finance 34:15-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1104a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1108" publication-type="other">
Detemple, J. 1986. Asset pricing in a production economy with incomplete information. Journal of Finance
41:383-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1118a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1122" publication-type="other">
Doshi, H., J. Ericsson, K. Jacobs, and S. M. Turnbull. Forthcoming. On pricing credit default swaps with
observable covariates. Review of Financial Studies.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1132a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1136" publication-type="other">
Drechsler, I., and A. Yaron. 2011. What's vol got to do with it. Review of Financial Studies 24:1-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1144a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1148" publication-type="other">
Driessen, J. 2005. Is default event risk priced in corporate bonds? Review of Financial Studies 18:165-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1155a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1159" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., A. Eckner, G Horel, and L. Saita. 2009. Frailty correlated default. Journal of Finance 64:2089-123.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1166a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1170" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., and R. Kan. 1996. A yield-factor model of interest rates. Mathematical Finance 6:379-406.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1177a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1181" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., L. Pedersen, and K. J. Singleton. 2003. Modeling sovereign yield spreads: A case study of Russian
debt. Journal of Finance 58:119-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1191a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1195" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., M. Schroder, and C. Skiadas. 1996. Recursive valuation of defaultable claims and the timing of
resolution of uncertainty. Annals of Applied Probability 6:1075-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1205a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1209" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., and K. J. Singleton. 1999. Modeling term structures of defaultable bonds. Review of Financial Studies
12:687-720.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1220a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1224" publication-type="other">
Edwards, S. 1984. LDC foreign borrowing and default risk: An empirical investigation, 1976-80. American
Economic Review 74:726-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1234a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1238" publication-type="other">
Eraker, B., and I. Shaliastovich. 2008. An equilibrium guide to designing affine pricing models. Mathematical
Finance 18:519-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1248a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1252" publication-type="other">
Feldman, D. 1989. The term structure of interest rates in a partially observable economy. Journal of Finance
44:789-812.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1262a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1266" publication-type="other">
Gennotte, G 1986. Optimal portfolio choice under incomplete information. Journal of Finance 41:733-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1273a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1277" publication-type="other">
Giesecke, K. 2004. Correlated default with incomplete information. Journal of Banking and Finance 28:1521-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1284a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1288" publication-type="other">
Granger, C. W. J., and P. Newbold. 1974. Spurious regressions in econometrics. Journal of Econometrics
2:111-20.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1299a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1303" publication-type="other">
Hansen, L. P. 2007. Beliefs, doubts and learning: Valuing macroeconomic risk. American Economic Review,
Papers and Proceedings 97:1-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1313a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1317" publication-type="other">
Hansen, L. P., R. Mayer, and T. Sargent. 2010. Robust hidden markov LQG problems. Journal of Economic
Dynamics and Control 34:1951-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1327a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1331" publication-type="other">
Hansen, L. P., and T. J. Sargent. 2007. Recursive robust estimation and control without commitment. Journal of
Economic Theory 136:1-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1341a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1345" publication-type="other">
. 2010. Fragile beliefs and the price of uncertainty. Quantitative Economics 1:129-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1352a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1356" publication-type="other">
Harvey, A. C. 1990. Forecasting, structural time series models and the kalman filter. Cambridge: University
Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1366a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1370" publication-type="other">
Hilscher, J., and Y. Nosbusch. 2010. Determinants of sovereign risk: Macroeconomic fundamentals and the
pricing of sovereign debt. Review of Finance 14:235-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1381a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1385" publication-type="other">
Jaramillo, L. 2010. Determinants of investment grade status in emerging markets. Working Paper, International
Monetary Fund.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1395a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1399" publication-type="other">
Jarrow, R., D. Lando, and F. Yu. 2005. Default risk and diversification: Theory and application. Mathematical
Finance 15:1-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1409a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1413" publication-type="other">
Jarrow, R., and F. Yu. 2001. Counterparty risk and the pricing of defaultable securities. Journal of Finance
56:1765-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1423a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1427" publication-type="other">
Jorion, P., and G Zhang. 2007. Good and bad credit contagion: Evidence from credit default swaps. Journal of
Financial Economics 84:860-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1437a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1441" publication-type="other">
. 2009. Credit contagion and counterparty risk. Journal of Finance 64:2053-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1448a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1452" publication-type="other">
King, M. A., and S. Wadhwani. 1990. Transmission of volatility between stock markets. Review of Financial
Studies 3:5-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1463a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1467" publication-type="other">
Kodres, L. E., and M. Pritsker. 2002. A rational expections model of financial contagion. Journal of Finance
57:769-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1477a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1481" publication-type="other">
Lando, D. 1998. On cox processes and credit risky securities. Review of Derivatives Research 2:99-120.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1488a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1492" publication-type="other">
Lando, D., and M. S. Nielsen. 2010. Correlation in corporate defaults: Contagion or conditional independence?
Journal of Fixed Income 19:355-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1502a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1506" publication-type="other">
Lang, L., and R. Stulz. 1992. Contagion and competitive intra-industry effects of bankruptcy announcements.
Journal of Financial Economics 32:45-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1516a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1520" publication-type="other">
Liptser, R., and A. Shiryaev. 2001. Statistics of random processes, 2 vols., trans. A. B. Aries. New York, NY:
Springer-Verlag.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1530a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1534" publication-type="other">
Longstaff, F., J. Pan, L. Pedersen, and K. J. Singleton. 2010. How sovereign is sovereign credit risk? American
Economic Journal: Macroeconomics 3:75-103.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1545a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1549" publication-type="other">
Maeshiro, A., and S. Vali. 1988. Pitfalls in the estimation of a differenced model. Journal of Business and
Economic Statistics 6:511-5.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1559a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1563" publication-type="other">
Min, H. 1998. Determinants of emerging market bond spread: Do economic fundamentals matter? Working
Paper, World Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1573a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1577" publication-type="other">
Pan, J., and K. J. Singleton. 2008. Default and recovery implicit in the term structure of sovereign cds spreads.
Journal of Finance 63:2345-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1587a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1591" publication-type="other">
Pavlova, A., and R. Rigobon. 2005. Wealth transfers, contagion and portfolio constraints Working Paper, MIT
and LBS.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1601a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1605" publication-type="other">
Protter, P. 2005. Stochastic integration and differential equations, 2nd ed. New York, NY: Springer.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1612a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1616" publication-type="other">
Schönbucher, P. J., and D. Schubert. 2001. Copula-dependent default risk in intensity models. Working Paper,
Bonn University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1627a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1631" publication-type="other">
Stock, J. H., and M. W. Watson. 1989. In Macroeconomics Annual O. J. Blanchard S. Fischer, eds., New indexes
of coincident and leading economic indicators, vol. 4, 351-409. M.I.T. Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1641a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1645" publication-type="other">
. 1991. In Leading Economic Indicators: New Approaches and Forecasting Records K. Lahiri G Moore,
eds., A probability model of the coincident economic indicators, chap. 4, 63-85. Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1655a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1659" publication-type="other">
Theocharides, G 2007. Contagion: Evidence from the bond market. Working Paper, SKK Business School,
Korea.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1669a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1673" publication-type="other">
Veronesi, P. 1999. Stock market overreactions to bad news in good times: a rational expectations equilibrium
model. Review of Financial Studies 12:975-1007.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1683a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1687" publication-type="other">
. 2000. How does information quality affect stock returns? Journal of Finance 55:807-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305502e1694a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305502e1698" publication-type="other">
Wan, E. A., and R. van der Merwe. 2001. The unscented Kaiman filter. In S. Haykin, ed., Kaiman Filtering and
Neural Networks, chap. 7, 221-80. New York: Wiley.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


