<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">8</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466874</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466879</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>What's in a Name? Mutual Fund Flows When Managers Have Foreign-Sounding Names</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alok</given-names>
                  <surname>Kumar</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alexandra</given-names>
                  <surname>Niessen-Ruenzi</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Oliver G.</given-names>
                  <surname>Spalt</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2281</fpage>
         <lpage>2321</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466879"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We show that name-induced stereotypes affect the investment choices of U.S. mutual fund investors. Managers with foreign-sounding names have about 10% lower annual fund flows, and this effect is stronger among funds with investor clienteles more likely to be suspicious of foreigners. Foreign-named managers experience lower appreciation (greater decline) in flows following good (bad) performance. Following 9/11, flows to funds with managers with Middle-Eastern-sounding names declined abnormally. In an experimental setting in which skill differences are absent, individuals allocate 11% less money to an index fund managed by a foreign-named manager. This gap widens following the Boston marathon bombings.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d623306e275a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e282" publication-type="other">
In a related study, Fryer and Levitt (2004) show that distinctively African-American names are correlated with
parental behavior, which in turn is negatively related to the child's productivity.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e292a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e299" publication-type="other">
A growing number of studies in economics and psychology use AMT (e.g., Horton, Rand, and Zeckhauser
2011; Amir, Rand, and Gal 2012; Chandler and Kapelner 2013; Goodman, Cryder, and Cheema 2013). To our
knowledge, our study is the first to use AMT in the finance literature.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e312a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e319" publication-type="other">
We find similar results when we control for other measures of past performance, including raw returns and
performance quintiles.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e329a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e336" publication-type="other">
Motivated by Green and Jame (2013), we define a name fluency dummy that is equal to one if the number of
characters in the name is below the median number of characters or the name does not appear in the 10,000 most
commonly used names in the United States, and zero otherwise.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e350a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e357" publication-type="other">
We obtain data on media mentions of fund managers from Niessen-Ruenzi and Ruenzi (2013) and refer readers
to their paper for details about the data collection procedure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e367a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e374" publication-type="other">
Other performance measures, such as the raw returns, Sharpe ratios, or appraisal ratios, also yield similar results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e381a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e388" publication-type="other">
Our full sample results are not driven by September 2001 alone. In fact, our results are most consistent with a
permanent negative effect on the perceptions of Middle Eastern foreigners. This finding is consistent with survey
evidence from the Gallup poll as reported by Margulies (2013), suggesting that U.S. citizens have a progressively
less favorable view of Islam from 2001 until today.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e404a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e411" publication-type="other">
Since both the GSS and the ARDA denominations surveys are not conducted every year, we extrapolate the
yearly values between the different survey waves before matching it to our mutual fund dataset.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e421a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e428" publication-type="other">
More specifically, their findings suggest that the overall positive relation between churchgoing and strength of
ethnic prejudice is driven mainly by to those churchgoers with an extrinsic motivation, that is individuals "disposed
to use religion for their own ends." Their evidence also suggests that intrinsically motivated churchgoers, that is
individuals who "find their master motive in religion," are often less prejudiced.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e444a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e451" publication-type="other">
One potential alternative interpretation of our location-based results is that the geographical patterns we
observe reflect taste-based discrimination at the fund management company level. Such a management company
discrimination channel, if it exists, would further strengthen our argument that flow differences are induced by
taste-based discrimination and complement the investor channel. However, because the flow results are robust
to including fund family fixed effects, it is not entirely obvious how an alternative channel would operate.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e471a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e478" publication-type="other">
The experiment was conducted in three different batches of 100, 100, and 200 individuals. The first group was
contacted in April 2012, and the second and third groups were surveyed in April 2013.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e488a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e495" publication-type="other">
The FBI released photographs of the suspects at 5:00 p.m. EDT on April 18. Source:
http://www.fbi.gov/boston/press-releases/2013/remarks-of-special-agent-in-charge-richard-deslauriers-at-
press-conference-on-bombing-investigation-1. All subjects in this group completed their AMT task well before
5:00 p.m. EDT on April 18.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e511a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e518" publication-type="other">
Additional details about the individual investor database are available from Barber and Odean (Barber and Odean
2000, Barber and Odean 2001). See Bailey, Kumar, and Ng (2011) for additional information about the mutual
funds sample.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e531a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e538" publication-type="other">
If we require 75% of all workers to define a fund as foreign, as in our main flow-based tests, only 1.64% fund
managers and 0.85% of all observations in the brokerage sample are associated with foreign funds. Even with this
small sample of observations associated with managers with foreign-sounding names, we find that the coefficient
estimates of the Foreign75 variable in Table 8, panel A, remain significant. The Foreign75 coefficient estimates in
the inflow, outflow, and net flow columns are —0.802 (/-statistic = —4.64), 1.312 (/-statistic =6.82), and —1.677
(/-statistic = -3.07), respectively. In panel B, the main coefficient estimates have similar signs, but they lose their
statistical significance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e564a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e571" publication-type="other">
We find similar results when we estimate the probability of investing in a foreign fund.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e578a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e585" publication-type="other">
The threat of a lawsuit is more than a theoretical possibility. For example, in 2008, Texas-based American State
Bank agreed to pay $225,000 to settle allegations of the Department of Labor that the bank engaged in hiring
discrimination against minority applicants. American State Bank claims that the Department of Labor's decision
was based solely on a "statistical shortfall in hiring of minority applicants for office and clerical positions" even
though "[...] no employee, applicant, or any other person actually complained of discrimination or wrongdoing
by American State Bank." Source: http://www.kcbd.com/Global/story.asp?S=8373627&amp;nav=menu69_l_4.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623306e609a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623306e616" publication-type="other">
As an example, the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (P.L. 111-203, §342) contains
new diversity requirements for federal agencies involved in the financial sector, as well as the businesses that
deal with those agencies. Specifically, each contractor doing business with an agency is required to submit a
written statement indicating that it has "ensure[d], to the maximum extent possible, the fair inclusion of women
and minorities in [its] workforce... and, as applicable, [the workforce of] subcontractors."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d623306e644a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e648" publication-type="other">
Abrams, D., M. Bertrand, and S. Mullainathan. 2012. Do judges vary in their treatment of race? Journal of Legal
Studies 41:347-383.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e658a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e662" publication-type="other">
Allport, G W. 1954. The Nature of Prejudice. Boston: Addison-Wesley Publishing Co.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e669a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e673" publication-type="other">
Allport, G W., and J. M. Ross. 1967. Personal religious orientation and prejudice. Journal of Personality and
Social Psychology 5:432-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e683a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e687" publication-type="other">
Amir, O., D. G Rand, and Y. K. Gal. 2012. Economic games on the internet: The effect of $1 stakes. PLoS ONE
7:1-*.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e698a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e702" publication-type="other">
Bailey, W., A. Kumar, and D. Ng. 2011. Behavioral biases of mutual fund investors. Journal of Financial
Economics 102:1-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e712a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e716" publication-type="other">
Barber, B. M., and T. Odean. 2000. Trading is hazardous to your wealth: The common stock investment
performance of individual investors. Journal of Finance 55:773-806.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e726a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e730" publication-type="other">
Barber, B. M., and T. Odean. 2001. Boys will be boys: Gender, overconfidence, and common stock investment.
Quarterly Journal of Economics 116:261-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e740a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e744" publication-type="other">
Becker, G S. 1957. The Economics of Discrimination. Chicago: Chicago University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e751a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e755" publication-type="other">
Bertrand, M., and S. Mullainathan. 2004. Are Emily and Greg more employable than Lakisha and Jamal?
American Economic Review 94:991-1013.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e765a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e769" publication-type="other">
Chandler, D., and A. Kapelner. 2013. Breaking monotony with meaning: Motivation in crowdsourcing markets.
Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization 90:123-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e780a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e784" publication-type="other">
Chevalier, J., and G Ellison. 1997. Risk taking by mutual funds as a response to incentives. Journal of Political
Economy 105:1167-200.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e794a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e798" publication-type="other">
Choi, D., B. Kahraman, and A. Mukherjee. 2013. Perfomance-chasing behavior and mutual funds: New evidence
from multi-fund managers. Working Paper; Available at SSRN: http://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=2219846.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e808a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e812" publication-type="other">
Cooper, M. J., H. Gulen, and P. R. Rau. 2006. Changing names with style: Mutual fund name changes and their
effects on fund flows. Journal of Finance 60:2825-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e822a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e826" publication-type="other">
Cornell B. and I. Welch. 1996. Culture, information, and screening discrimination. Journal of Political Economy
104:542-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e836a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e840" publication-type="other">
Coval, J. D., and T. J. Moskowitz. 1999. Home bias at home: Local equity preference in domestic portfolios.
Journal of Finance 54:2045-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e850a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e854" publication-type="other">
Coval, J. D., and T. J. Moskowitz. 2001. The geography of investment: Informed trading and asset prices. Journal
of Political Economy 109:811—41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e865a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e869" publication-type="other">
Deli, D. N. 2002. Mutual fund advisory contracts: An empirical investigation. Journal of Finance 57:109-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e876a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e880" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and K. R. French. 1993. Common risk factors in returns on stocks and bonds. Journal of Financial
Economics 33:3-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e890a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e894" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and J. D. MacBeth. 1973. Risk, return, and equilibrium: Empirical tests. Journal of Political Economy
81:607-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e904a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e908" publication-type="other">
Fryer, R. G, and S. D. Levitt. 2004. The causes and consequences of distinctively black names. Quarterly Journal
of Economics 119:767-805.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e918a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e922" publication-type="other">
Goodman, J. K., C. E. Cryder, and A. Cheema. 2013. Data collection in a flat world: The strengths and weaknesses
of mechanical turk samples. Journal of Behavioral Decision Making 26:213-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e932a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e936" publication-type="other">
Green, C. T., and R. E. Jame. 2013. Company name fluency, investor recognition, and firm value. Journal of
Financial Economics 109:813-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e947a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e951" publication-type="other">
Hewstone, M., M. Rubin, and H. Willis. 2002. Intergroup bias. Annual Review of Psychology 53:575-604.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e958a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e962" publication-type="other">
Horton, J. J., D. G Rand, and R. J. Zeckhauser. 2011. The online laboratory: Conducting experiments in a real
labor market. Experimental Economics 14:399—425.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e972a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e976" publication-type="other">
Ivkoviö, Z., and S. Weisbenner. 2005. Local does as local is: Information content of the geography of individual
investors' common stock investments. Journal of Finance 60:267-306.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e986a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e990" publication-type="other">
Kaniel, R., L. T. Starks, and V. Vasudevan. 2007. Headlines and bottom lines: Attention and learning effects from
media coverage of mutual funds. Working Paper; Available at SSRN: http://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=687103.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e1000a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e1004" publication-type="other">
Kumar, A. 2010. Self-selection and the forecasting abilities of female equity analysts. Journal of Accounting
Research 48:393—435.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e1014a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e1018" publication-type="other">
Kumar, A., J. Page, and O. Spalt. 2011. Religious beliefs, gambling attitudes, and financial market outcomes.
Journal of Financial Economics 102:671-708.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e1029a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e1033" publication-type="other">
Kunda, Z. 1999. Social Cognition: Making Sense of People. Cambridge: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e1040a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e1044" publication-type="other">
Margulies, J. 2013. What Changed When Everything Changed: 9/11 and the Making of National Identity. New
Haven, CT: Yale University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e1054a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e1058" publication-type="other">
Massa, M., J. Reuter, and E. Zitzewitz. 2010. When should firms share credit with employees? Evidence from
anonymously managed mutual funds. Journal of Financial Economics 95:400-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e1068a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e1072" publication-type="other">
Massey, D. S. 2010. New Faces in New Places: The Changing Geography of American Immigration. New York:
Russell Sage Foundation.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e1082a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e1086" publication-type="other">
Nardinelli, C., and C. Simon. 1990. Customer racial discrimination in the market for memorabilia: The case of
baseball. Quarterly Journal of Economics 105:575-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e1096a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e1100" publication-type="other">
Niessen-Ruenzi, A., and S. Ruenzi. 2013. Sex matters: Gender and prejudice in the mutual fund industry. Working
Paper; Available at SSRN: http://ssrn.com/abstract= 1957317.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e1111a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e1115" publication-type="other">
Ouellet, J.-F. 2007. Consumer racism and its effects on domestic cross-ethnic product purchase: An empirical
test in the United States, Canada, and France. Journal of Marketing 71:113-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e1125a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e1129" publication-type="other">
Parsons, C., J. Sulaeman, M. C. Yates, and D. S. Hamermesh. 2011. Strike three: Discrimination, incentives, and
evaluation. American Economic Review 101:1410-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e1139a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e1143" publication-type="other">
Price, J., and J. J. Wolfers. 2010. Racial discrimination among NBA referees. Quarterly Journal of Economics
125:1859-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e1153a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e1157" publication-type="other">
Tajfel, H. 1982. Social psychology of intergroup relations. Annual Review of Psychology 33:1-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623306e1164a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623306e1168" publication-type="other">
Wolfers, J. 2006. Diagnosing discrimination: Stock returns and CEO gender. Journal of the European Economic
Association 4:531-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


