<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26167735</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>An Intelligent Alternator Control Mechanism for Energy Recuperation and Fuel Efficiency Improvement</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lakshminarasimhan</surname>
                  <given-names>Venkatnarayanan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tata Motors Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Athani</surname>
                  <given-names>Gopal</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tata Technologies Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26167713</issue-id>
         <fpage>217</fpage>
         <lpage>225</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26167735"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>With the current state of ever rising fuel prices and unavailability of affordable alternate technologies, significant research and development efforts have been invested in recent times towards improving fuel efficiency of vehicles powered with conventional internal combustion engines. To achieve this, a varied approach has been adopted by researchers to cover the entire energy chain including fuel quality, combustion quality, power generation efficiency, downsizing, power consumption efficiency, etc. Apart from energy generation, distribution and consumption, another domain that has been subjected to significant scrutiny is energy recuperation or recovery.</p>
            <p>A moving vehicle and a running engine provide a number of opportunities for useful back-recovery and storage of energy. The most significant sources for recuperation are the kinetic energy of the moving vehicle or running engine and to a lesser extent the thermal energy from medium such as exhaust gas. This paper describes and analyzes a method to recuperate electrical energy from a portion of the vehicle kinetic energy through an intelligent alternator control mechanism. The intelligent alternator control system, its implementation on a demonstrator vehicle including the control logics, and measurements of recuperated energy and fuel saving under different test conditions are presented as part of this paper.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bosch R. “Automotive Electrics Automotive Electronics”, GmbH Fourth Edition, Plochingen, Germany, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lakshminarasimhan, V., Thivaharan, S., and Parthasarthy, S., “Micro Hybrid Battery Management - A Novel System to Augment Engine Restart Reliability and Battery Life,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0791, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0791.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montalto, I., Tavella lng, D., Casavola PhD, A., and De Cristofaro, F., “Intelligent Alternator Employment To Reduce Co2 Emission and to Improve Engine Performance,” SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 1(1):1-11, 2012, doi:10.4271/2011-01-2444.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schöllmann, M., Rosenmayr, M., and Olk, J., “Battery Monitoring with the Intelligent Battery Sensor During Service, Standby and Production,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0561, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0561.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosenmayr, M., Schmidt, R., and Naumann, R., “Battery Management and Controls,” 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heim, A. and Streibl, T., “The Intelligent Battery Sensor: Key Component for a Scaleable Motor-Vehicle-Independent Energy Management System,” 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
