<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440297</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Abolishing the Tax-Free Threshold in Australia: Simulating Alternative Reforms</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
                  <surname>Creedy</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Nicolas</given-names>
                  <surname>Hérault</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Guyonne</given-names>
                  <surname>Kalb</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">30</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440093</issue-id>
         <fpage>219</fpage>
         <lpage>246</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2009</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440297"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper examines the role of the tax-free income tax threshold in a complex tax and transfer system consisting of a range of taxes and benefits, each with its own taper rates and thresholds. Considering a tax and benefit system with benefit taper rates whereby some benefits are received by income groups other than those at the bottom of the distribution, it is suggested that a tax-free threshold is not a necessary requirement to achieve redistribution. Four alternative policy changes, each involving the elimination of the tax-free threshold in Australia and designed to achieve approximate revenue neutrality, were examined using the Melbourne Institute Tax and Transfer Simulator. A range of implications were examined, including labour supply responses to tax changes and the effects of policy changes on inequality and social welfare. The results demonstrate that it is possible to eliminate the tax-free threshold under approximate overall revenue and distribution neutrality, but that it is impossible to improve labour supply incentives at the same time. In order to achieve improved incentives, either revenue or distribution neutrality has to be sacrificed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d15e220a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e227" publication-type="other">
Submitted August 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e234a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e241" publication-type="other">
This statement, as in many policy debates, clearly attaches much weight to the status quo, whereby the
existing system is implicitly judged to have desirable properties.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e251a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e258" publication-type="other">
For example, Saunders (2006, p. xxvi) stated that 'At the same time as the top marginal rate is
reduced, the tax-free threshold should be raised to a level above the welfare minimum (subsistence) level
... it would mean that all taxpayers enjoyed a substantial tax cut'. He did not mention compensating
changes to other forms of revenue or expenditure along with this revenue-reducing reform, so it is unclear
how this policy change would be financed and what the impact of an alternative revenue-generating
process would be.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e281a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e288" publication-type="other">
MITTS is described briefly in Appendix A and in detail in Creedy et al. (2002). Creedy and Kalb
(2006) describe some of the more recently introduced features of MITTS, and Kalb and Lee (2007 and
2008) report updated wage and labour supply estimates underlying the labour supply responses in the
behavioural simulations. Labour supply responses based on MITTS simulations generally look sensible
and according to expectation. Recently, a comparison of MITTS results with experimental evaluation
results of the same policy change was made for single parents in Cai et al. (2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e312a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e319" publication-type="other">
For example, Saunders and Maley (2006, p. 113) argue that 'The principled case for raising the
threshold is that workers should be allowed to earn and retain enough money to meet their own
subsistence needs before any tax is taken away from them'. However, the principle involved (whether of
a basic value judgement or an efficiency criterion) is not actually mentioned. A similar argument for
raising the threshold was made by Veit-Wilson (1999), who showed that in practice in the UK there had
been no coordination between those responsible for tax thresholds and those responsible for setting
benefit levels.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e345a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e352" publication-type="other">
An early clear statement of this view was made by Hicks (1946, p. 150), who dated its realisation
from the last quarter of the nineteenth century: 'Instead of regarding each tax separately, and attempting
the impossible task of choosing only those taxes which would pass all the tests, it was suddenly realized
that any desired distributional result could be obtained by a compensatory structure of taxes, in which the
faults of one would be offset by the virtues of another'. Hicks then made the point that expenditures, as
well as taxes, also need to be taken into account.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e375a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e382" publication-type="other">
There was a brief period of tax indexation under the Fraser government in the late 1970s.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e389a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e396" publication-type="other">
This would amount to a simplification of the existing tax system. Although this could imply an
increase in the number of tax returns to be filed (for individuals below the tax-free threshold), in practice
this extra administrative burden can be avoided when introducing an additional tax rebate to replace the
tax-free range for low-income individuals. Individuals with income below the former tax-free thresholds
could be treated in the same way as before the change. That is, no tax would be taken out of their pay and
thus no tax return would have to be filed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e419a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e426" publication-type="other">
This is obtained by replacing gross income by zero in the equation defining section BC; see left-hand
side of equation (1).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e436a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e443" publication-type="other">
This is not a necessary constraint but it limits the number of parameters involved.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e451a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e458" publication-type="other">
On labour supply with highly non-linear budget constraints, and integration in behavioural
microsimulation models, see Creedy and Kalb (2005a and 2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e468a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e475" publication-type="other">
The costs of reducing separately each of the marginal tax rates by 1 percentage point were found to
be approximately AU$1.4 billion for the 17 per cent tax rate, AU$1.5 billion for the 30 per cent tax rate,
AU$200 million for the 42 per cent tax rate and AU$500 million for the 47 per cent tax rate. These are
only indicative values at the margin and they assume fixed labour supply. The cost of further reducing the
marginal tax rates is not expected to be linear.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e494a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e501" publication-type="other">
These aggregate amounts are obtained by multiplying the sample numbers by their sample weights,
provided by the Survey of Income and Housing Costs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e511a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e518" publication-type="other">
See Appendix B for details. For details of the wide range of benefits in Australia, see Australian
Government Department of Family and Community Services (2004). For details on taxes and rebates, see
Australian Taxation Office (2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e531a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e538" publication-type="other">
The unweighted number in the SIHC is 187.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e545a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e552" publication-type="other">
More detail on the approach can be found in Creedy and Kalb (2005b) and in Creedy, Hérault and
Kalb (2007).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e563a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e570" publication-type="other">
For individuals whose labour supply is fixed - for example, those who are not in the labour market -
the money measure of the welfare change is equal to the net income change.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e580a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e587" publication-type="other">
The weight of the first adult in each income unit is 1. The weight of each additional adult member is
0.56, and each child (under 18) is given a weight of 0.32. It is recognised that the results can be
influenced by the choice of adult equivalence scales and unit of analysis, but these are of secondary
importance here.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e603a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e610" publication-type="other">
0n the other hand, if changes at the bottom end of the income range are larger than changes at the top
end, the absolute percentage changes in the Atkinson index should increase with s.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e620a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e627" publication-type="other">
That is. Policy 3 is revenue neutral assuming fixed labour supply and Policy 4 is revenue neutral
allowing for labour supply changes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e637a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e644" publication-type="other">
For an overview of refereed publications and books relating to the MITTS model, see http://
www.melbourneinstitute.com/labour/behavioural/mitts_related_pubs.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e654a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e661" publication-type="other">
Any position can be regarded as being generated by a linear virtual constraint c = wh+[i, where c is
consumption (assumed to be equal to net income).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e672a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e679" publication-type="other">
For each hours point, hj, c° and ci can be determined, after which t/(c°,fy) can be calculated.
Then w'0l is the virtual wage in the optimal point A, associated with utility level U'0 and ju'0 j = c° - w'0,A,.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e689a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e696" publication-type="other">
Determine c\2 needed to reach U\ in h2 by solving for c in U(c,h2) = U\ and then use nl2 =
^0,2 ~W0,2^2 •</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d15e715a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e719" publication-type="other">
Australian Government Department of Family and Community Services (2004), Annual
Report 2003-04, Canberra (http://www.facsia.gov.au/about/publicationsarticles/corp/
Documents/2004%20Annual%20Report/index.htm).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e732a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e736" publication-type="other">
Australian Taxation Office (2006), Taxation Statistics 2003-04: A Summary of Tax Returns
for the 2003-04 Income Year and Collections for the 2004-05 Financial Year, Canberra
(http://www.ato.gov.au/content/downloads/70906_2004TAXSTATS.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e749a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e753" publication-type="other">
Binh, T. N. and Whiteford, P. (1990), 'Household equivalence scales: new Australian
estimates from the 1984 Household Expenditure Survey', Economic Record, vol. 66, pp.
221-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e766a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e770" publication-type="other">
Cai, L., Kalb, G., Tseng, Y-P. and Vu, H. (2008), 'The effect of financial incentives on labour
supply: evidence for lone parents from microsimulation and quasi-experimental
evaluation', Fiscal Studies, vol. 29, pp. 285-325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e784a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e788" publication-type="other">
Creedy, J., Duncan, A. S., Harris, M. and Scutella, R. (2002), Microsimulation Modelling of
Taxation and the Labour Market: The Melbourne Institute Tax and Transfer Simulator,
Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e801a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e805" publication-type="other">
—, Hérault, N. and Kalb, G. (2007), 'Comparing welfare change measures with income
change measures in behavioural policy simulations', Melbourne Institute of Applied
Economic and Social Research, Working Paper no. 21/07.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e818a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e822" publication-type="other">
— and Kalb, G. (2005a), 'Discrete hours labour supply modelling: specification, estimation
and simulation', Journal of Economic Surveys, vol. 19, pp. 697-734.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e832a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e836" publication-type="other">
— and — (2005b), 'Measuring welfare changes in labour supply models', Manchester
School, vol. 73, pp. 664—85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e846a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e850" publication-type="other">
— and — (2006), Labour Supply and Microsimulation, Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e857a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e861" publication-type="other">
Freebaim, J. (1998), 'Efficiency issues', in P. Abelson (ed.), The Tax Reform Debate, Sydney:
Allen and Unwin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e872a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e876" publication-type="other">
Hicks, U. K. (1946), Public Finance, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e883a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e887" publication-type="other">
Kalb, G. and Lee, W-S. (2007), Wage and Labour Force Participation in Australia:
Accounting for Categorised Observations on Wages, Final Report for Treasury.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e897a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e901" publication-type="other">
— and — (2008), Labour Supply in the Australian Population: Using Data from 1999 to
2004, Final Report for Treasury.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e911a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e915" publication-type="other">
Saunders, P. (ed.) (2006), Taxploitation: The Case for Income Tax Reform, Sydney: Centre
for Independent Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e925a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e929" publication-type="other">
— and Maley, B. (2006), 'Tax reform to make work pay', in P. Saunders (ed.), Taxploitation-.
The Case for Income Tax Reform, Sydney: Centre for Independent Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e939a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e943" publication-type="other">
Veit-Wilson, J. (1999), 'The tax threshold: policy, principles, and poverty', Twentieth Century
British History, vol. 10, pp. 218-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
